<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H468F670979AE4231977688244258B375" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1004 IH: Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Reauthorization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1004</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150213">February 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reauthorize the Enhancing Education Through Technology Act of 2001.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA2DAD0243D4A45C09426CD759D0BF695" style="OLC">
 <section id="H019A4DB3A91D405D97F7FBD852C9A4CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA704854A97384D79BBF3216AA12A9B50"><enum>2.</enum><header>Achievement through technology and innovation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6751">20 U.S.C. 6751 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H727AD0B3DA9741C9AB35F47F62D81F28" style="OLC">
				<part id="H435A6E4A04B34C02AD9567CCEE5FC92F"><enum>D</enum><header>Achievement through technology and innovation</header>
 <section id="H257B6C61B4AD48F1B298D11CA73F12A7"><enum>2401.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This part may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ATTAIN Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD15D3BCBC4F347FBA46B082DDCA26E60"><enum>2402.</enum><header>Purposes and goals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes and goals of this part are—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8B3BCD423DEE41A3883B2EA08C4E2651"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure that States have high-quality technology plans to promote effective and innovative uses of technology and to ensure that every student has access to personalized, rigorous, and relevant learning to meet the goals of this Act to raise student achievement, close the achievement gap, and ensure highly effective teaching, and to prepare all students to be technology literate and college and career ready for the 21st century digital economy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H164761DE64CA4C668DD8C44DA1D5311B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to evaluate, build upon, and increase the use of evidence-based and innovative systemic school redesigns that center on the use of technology that leads to school improvement, improved productivity, and increased student achievement;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD82AD2C756EE4B339B9AAB36DC826309"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to ensure that all educators are connected in an ongoing manner to technology-based and online resources and supports, including through enhanced ongoing, meaningful professional development to ensure that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H15A1F4171A3442568C3ACD17CD6A6BE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all educators are technology literate and effectively use technology to improve instruction and student outcomes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01A463B2000A49019828BC8C35C63161"><enum>(B)</enum><text>education administrators possess the capacity to—</text> <clause id="H23C3A092C751492BA75178E61B4FCAF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide leadership in the use of technology for systemic redesign of curriculum, instruction, and the education enterprise; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6FBA0EADE8914F54B9A25F2D6FA16113"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve educational productivity;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7686F0373B7843308F9F001C2D1A440B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to improve student performance, engagement, opportunity, attendance, graduation rates, and technology access through enhanced or redesigned curriculum or instruction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF789DBD20A741438945A88B4D27CCCF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to more effectively collect and use student performance and other data in a timely manner to inform instruction, address individualized student needs, support school decisionmaking, and support school improvement and increased student achievement, including through delivery of computer-based and online assessments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA837AA6C20F947D6AF2206DBF83C3C6D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to enhance the use of technology, online and blended learning for systemic education transformation, including curricula redesign and new instructional strategies to personalize learning; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD09BABD42E24AF796BCFE1950D10E70"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to increase education productivity and reduce costs through the use of technology, blended and online learning, including for the delivery of online assessments.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HB8445D12ED144560846B24A8C13EFBF9"><enum>2403.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text> <paragraph id="H90ACCA5F4F8442769372942DD15CD6BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> includes a consortium of local educational agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D14F6ECDB6C46C8ACC5AA01106BE5D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student technology literacy</header><text>The term <term>student technology literacy</term> means student knowledge and skills in using contemporary information, communication, and learning technologies in a manner necessary for successful employment, life-long learning, and citizenship in the knowledge-based, digital, and global 21st century, as further defined by the State educational agency, which includes, at a minimum, the ability—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB491949B7D8745F7894A948ADFAA11F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to effectively communicate and collaborate;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H893D978772644D9492AE7DBC26F28DFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to analyze and solve problems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2495FAB4A16441AF9C5FC7105EEA763A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to access, evaluate, manage, and create information and otherwise gain information literacy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H948252DEA9A3412D8CAF7065C578F5DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to demonstrate creative thinking, construct knowledge, and develop innovative products and processes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF18D05ABFBE49C8AFB75DE4A9258C1D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to do so in a safe and ethical manner.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04C302718B4E41D984A62E5E595CD32F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High-quality technology plan</header><text>The term <quote>high-quality technology plan</quote> means a plan that supports student learning powered by technology, and includes goals in a minimum of five areas: learning, assessment, teaching, infrastructure, and communication. Such a plan shall also include specific metrics for evaluating outcomes.</text>
						</paragraph></section><section id="H698EAFA2E1F147379278985E5FD7E198"><enum>2404.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="H251F3DF8CA9C40278A05FA71C56D1BB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part, $1,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2015, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H03DCB99A61EA45929027A4D123085542"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National technology activities</header><text>Of the funds made available under subsection (a), the Secretary may reserve up to 2 percent to support national evaluation, technical assistance, and dissemination of effective practice to support States in adopting evidence-based best practices for using technology to transform learning.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3576E7E001B940F7A4EC8BAC623F3985"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocation of funds between State and local initiatives</header><text>The remaining funds made available under subsection (a) shall be available to carry out this part, as described in subsection (d).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H30C520CE37C7425AA835AE2ACBB6D754"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header>
 <paragraph id="H81415038142C4A39B1B2B9037B987CC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local administrative costs</header><text>Of the funds made available to a local educational agency under this part for a fiscal year, not more than 3 percent may be used by the local educational agency for administrative costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H101BDEC7D0D346E6B97913B69ED2450F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State administrative costs</header><text>Of the funds made available to a State educational agency under section 2406(a)(1)(A), not more than 30 percent may be used by the State educational agency for administrative costs.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0E02321692E04B88B420449EB923F28E"><enum>2405.</enum><header>Allotment and reallotment</header>
 <subsection id="HFBE495B427E8461D92CE85E98D047385"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservations and allotment</header><text>From the amount made available to carry out this part under section 2404(a) for a fiscal year—</text> <paragraph id="H595D6AA6163C48C8A4B5D77B4D33DC4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary shall reserve—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H742F56A86DD140909D0C895B5AFE0A93"><enum>(A)</enum><text><fraction>3/4</fraction> of 1 percent for the Secretary of the Interior for programs under this part for schools operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Affairs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBAE2A04131B482684F9705E6EEF7650"><enum>(B)</enum><text><fraction>½</fraction> of 1 percent to provide assistance under this part to the outlying areas; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H211E13544903481D8B6352ACB9F7E247"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to subsection (b), the Secretary shall use the remainder to award grants by allotting to each State educational agency an amount that bears the same relationship to such remainder for such year as the amount received under part A of title I for such year by such State educational agency bears to the amount received under such part for such year by all State educational agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05F8BC5A40CC414395C02189944241F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum allotment</header><text>The amount of any State educational agency's allotment under subsection (a)(2) for any fiscal year shall not be less than <fraction>½</fraction> of 1 percent of the amount made available for allotments to State educational agencies under this part for such year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0A5C3A3D25314B2FA1EDCA4F5B854D24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reallotment of Unused Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any State does not apply for an allotment under this subsection for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall reallot the amount of the allotment to the remaining States in accordance with this subsection.</text>
						</subsection></section><section id="HFE164BEAF5524A0AB774565DCCFD18C9"><enum>2406.</enum><header>Use of allotment by State</header>
						<subsection id="HBE07A977BDC6482298762EC3E7C2092F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H2704F3B5A47E407A8AFA780F9D0C1E07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the amount provided to a State educational agency under section 2405(a)(2) for a fiscal year—</text> <subparagraph id="HAAEBDC6398F14936A18A71389D38073A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State educational agency may use not more than 5 percent of such amount or $200,000, whichever amount is greater, to carry out activities under section 2408; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2E01721B64945B596B44F1DBB1B2439"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State educational agency shall distribute the remainder in accordance with paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H492A497C39FE444690E88DFFB92356C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution of remainder</header><text>The State educational agency shall use the remainder to award subgrants, through a State-determined competitive process, to local educational agencies having applications approved under section 2409 for the activities described in section 2410.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CA9A6B6B7F047E480191051C352D75E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sufficient amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding subgrants under subsection (a)(2) the State educational agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H79349D185BC1419ABBAE76673B507FFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure the subgrants are of sufficient size and scope to be effective, consistent with the purposes of this part; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0889E0DBB4AE45FFA565EE86174D949B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure subgrants are of sufficient duration to be effective, consistent with the purposes of this part, including by awarding subgrants for a period of not less than 2 years that may be renewed for not more than an additional 1 year, based on performance;</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F63006BA67945288A6CB71954B3BEED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>give preference in the awarding of subgrants, and the providing of all technical assistance, to local educational agencies that serve schools in need of improvement, as identified under section 1116, including those schools with high populations of—</text>
 <clause id="H97D99C59275643EAB423C00BC20EFAF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>students who are English Language Learners;</text> </clause><clause id="H3EC4A00F288C45DDAA1A865BBD35E8AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>students with disabilities; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD3939C90F70A4FA697253184E635AB61"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other subgroups of students who have not met the State's student academic achievement standards; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA77C2A37132147BD8CC0ECDC19C9DEFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure an equitable distribution among urban and rural areas of the State, according to the demonstrated need for assistance under this part of the local educational agencies serving the areas, with a priority for those areas with technology infrastructure in place that employ educational practices supported by rigorous evidence.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDE9C83E546F74C54BEC7FB7B9336A696"><enum>2407.</enum><header>State applications</header>
 <subsection id="HF6B22BE18ED541F0BACACB348E05D4C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this part, a State educational agency shall submit to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may specify, an application containing the contents described in subsection (b) and such other information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H00012C30761744E5BCCF829A027E28B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each State educational agency application submitted under subsection (a) shall include each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9A0CF09E6A9A4A58AE2D8FB7A57416A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the State’s high-quality technology plan, as defined under section 2403(3), details on how the State educational agency will support local educational agencies that receive subgrants under this part in meeting the purposes and goals of this part and the requirements of this part, including through technical assistance in using technology to redesign curriculum and instruction, improve educational productivity, and deliver computer-based and online assessment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FDECB8103374767BAF4276874625599"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the State educational agency's long-term goals and strategies for improving student academic achievement, including student technology literacy, through the effective use of technology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD0D1C3053BB4800B4BBE37962A6565A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the priority area upon which the State educational agency will focus its assistance under this part, which shall be identified from among the core academic subjects, grade levels, and student subgroup populations that may be causing the most number of local educational agencies in the State to not make adequate yearly progress, as defined in section 1111(b)(2)(C).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9865BB8B4454A12B2F63D2C47FDEB90"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of how the State educational agency will support local educational agencies to implement professional development programs pursuant to section 2410(2)(A).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H012AD983DD3D4853BC84987E49425F25"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of how the State educational agency will ensure that teachers, paraprofessionals, school librarians, and administrators in the State possess the knowledge and skills to use technology—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9BD93E2418024D89BC4FB470A93BE94E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for curriculum redesign to change teaching and learning and improve student achievement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4F286E5EBA3431AB644FED5AC5AC609"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for assessment, data analysis, and to personalize learning;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2E2D56DBD264CDEBB69F130C2A5EB19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to improve student technology literacy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F9DC630E92C437D8E9F56ECF31B76C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for their own ongoing professional development and for access to teaching resources and tools.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5057678B14FE4A768F15FFB68F9F0354"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of the process, activities, and performance measures that the State educational agency will use to evaluate the impact and effectiveness of activities described in section 2408.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49218EC0F1F44EC1BA44224A6F14362F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Identification of the State challenging academic content standards and challenging student academic achievement standards that the State educational agency will use to ensure that each student is technology literate consistent with the definition of student technology literacy, and a description of how the State educational agency will assess student performance in gaining technology literacy, including through embedding such assessment items in other State tests or performance-based assessments portfolios, or through other valid and reliable means. Nothing in this part shall be construed to require States to develop a separate test to assess student technology literacy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B171924980645678AC888996A4EADBC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An assurance that financial assistance provided under this part will supplement, and not supplant, State and local funds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5DE76BCF2BD43548959E8F1266BD8D4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A description of how the State educational agency will, in providing technical and other assistance to local educational agencies, give priority to those identified by the State as being in the highest need of assistance, including those with the highest percentage or number of students from families with incomes below the poverty line, students not achieving at the State proficiency level with student populations identified under section 2406(b)(2)(A), or schools identified as in need of improvement under section 1116.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3E03C7889BF4086BEFFAF9C9971ADA2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A description of how the State educational agency consulted with local educational agencies in the development of the State application.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDB25BE1B89DB4CCB9714B00027BE0474"><enum>2408.</enum><header>State activities</header>
 <subsection id="HBD4C47F86BF547AF96641515F286AF15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory activities</header><text>From funds made available under section 2406(a)(1)(A), a State educational agency shall carry out each of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3AD301B061C748F0942C1482F1129684"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identify the State challenging academic content standards and challenging student academic achievement standards that the State educational agency will use to ensure that each student is technology literate consistent with the definition of student technology literacy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90ABD231E02F45FC834EDA8F7F014E25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assess student performance in gaining technology literacy consistent with paragraph (1), including through embedding such assessment items in other State tests, performance-based assessments, or portfolios, or through other means, except that such assessments shall be used only to track student technology literacy and shall not be used to determine adequate yearly progress, and widely disseminate such results.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEDA252B975B4AA1825196671B70C0BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Provide guidance, technical assistance, and other assistance, including in the priority area identified by the State pursuant to section 2407(b)(3), in using technology to improve teaching and redesign curriculum and instruction, improve educational productivity, and deliver computer-based and online assessment, and in submitting applications for funding under this part to high-need local educational agencies—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCB9589AAB5F1499582F05ADF22FC0C77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with the highest percentage or number of—</text> <clause id="HB060AB6735CE404FB0F0F750EEFA1A6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>students not achieving at the State proficiency level; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0F56463DD223428EABF69DB787B7F353"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>student populations described in section 2406(b)(2)(A); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25D20D031969472FA96642AC4EBE4BEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serving schools identified as in need of improvement under section 1116.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFC0ABDB5ABB43A4893B51C8A6CBC51D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permissive activities</header><text>From funds made available under section 2406(a)(1)(A), a State educational agency may carry out 1 or more of the following activities that assist local educational agencies:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1AB50F03787241A888467FCAD4840733"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State leadership activities and technical assistance that support achieving the purposes and goals of this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46264BC9FBC14588B24FC25ADC20DB2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Developing and evaluating or utilizing research-based or innovative strategies for the delivery of specialized or rigorous academic courses and curricula through the use of technology, including distance learning technologies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75ECE84A4BA446F9BF2E7747F5A57DD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing, or supporting local educational agencies in providing sustained and intensive, high-quality professional development pursuant to section 2410(2)(A).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D844B8FB9AF47ECB642E389CA513695"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Assessing student performance in gaining technology literacy consistent with subsection (a)(2), including through embedding such assessment items in other State tests, performance-based assessments, or portfolios, or through other means.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDE8349240E364A13ACB4B1CB566CFFAC"><enum>2409.</enum><header>Local applications</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each local educational agency desiring a subgrant under this part shall submit to the State educational agency an application containing a new or updated local long-range strategic educational technology plan, and such other information as the State educational agency may reasonably require that shall include each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC464AF37B0E945F7824DD10FCE2B6463"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of how the local educational agency will align and coordinate the local educational agency's use of funds under this part with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCAD8A07864DF4B0DBF39B491F82970EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the school district technology plan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4076FE503FEB428D91A19555927C0C4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the school district plans and activities for improving student achievement, including plans and activities under sections 1111, 1112, 1116, and 2123, as applicable; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H855BC980604B41BBB69D8CDC71FA2E30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>funds available from other Federal, State, and local sources.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FA70EF9EC9646B4AFD9AEAC307B34FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assurance that financial assistance provided under this part will supplement, and not supplant, other funds available to carry out activities assisted under this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB102CCCED631432DB3B67A68C380E0AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the process used to assess and, as needed, update technologies throughout the local educational agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63B61A28640F416F8DC7482F00265948"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such other information as the State educational agency may reasonably require.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1838A3319A747F2BF69AB7C679CDBA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of how the local educational agency will use the subgrant funds to implement systemic school redesign, which is a comprehensive set of programs, practices, and technologies that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H541BF3A134744B21968D278E6D15211F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collectively lead to school or school district change and improvement, improve educational productivity, and improve student achievement and technology literacy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H128C167EB06E476EBBA8B042E5F09F14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate all of the following elements:</text> <clause id="H76366C91FDE54ABF909AA056D148136E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Reform or redesign of curriculum, instruction, assessment, use of data, or other practices through the use of technology in order to increase student learning opportunity, and engagement in learning.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H868C9C92BDFE4D6BABF719C06CA1194E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Improvement of educator quality, knowledge and skills, and effectiveness through ongoing, sustainable, timely, and contextual professional development described in section 2410(2)(A)(i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBA1D0AF7E8AA43F4957893D4075BF89E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Ongoing use of formative and other assessments and other timely data sources and data systems to more effectively identify individual student learning needs and personalize learning.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF3C79493113443F4A98CDC950440D80E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Engagement of school district leaders, school leaders, and classroom educators.</text> </clause><clause id="HDABFFA1FFAC44C339E81FA2D0950CBB0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Programs, practices, and technologies that are based on a review of the best available research evidence or on development and use of new and innovative designs, programs, practices, and technologies.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3726EAA11624422FA87EE5708F80F1FE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assurance that the local educational agency will use not less than 40 percent of the subgrant funds to implement a program of professional development described in section 2410(2)(A).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96FE6C2ED8C84A6C95D9B352955BE70C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of how the local educational agency will evaluate the impact of 1 or more programs or activities carried out under this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13769CE3D2684962BD25F6DACFB38481"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A description of the use of technology tools, applications, and other resources to improve student learning and achievement in the area of priority identified under paragraph (5).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H997C381535234752BD729D96521E69F9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A description of the priority area subgrant funds will target, identified from among the core academic subjects, grade levels, and student subgroup populations in which the most number of students served by the local educational agency are not proficient.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89385E7BB9B840D59C883913AE13BCCF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A description of how funds will be used to integrate technology to redesign curriculum or instruction, implement computer-based and online assessments, improve use of data to personalize learning, or improve education productivity.</text>
						</paragraph></section><section id="H6CC8484BDF1A44C6A79AFD9D5BE34E19"><enum>2410.</enum><header>Local activities</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">A local educational agency that receives funds through a subgrant under section 2406(a)(2), shall carry out activities to improve student learning, technology literacy, and achievement, as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0DD95C90BFD74E1C9987A000FC62B7C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Use not less than 5 percent of such funds to evaluate the impact of 1 or more programs or activities carried out under the subgrant as identified in the local educational agency's application and approved by the State educational agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05703A1015FB476E85D79A64069DCC47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Use funds remaining after carrying out paragraph (1) to implement a plan for systemic school redesign in 1 or more schools, in accordance with section 2409(b)(1), including each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB5D7C2D67F354D809E17C0D32D56FF02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Using not less than 40 percent of subgrant funds to ensure educators, including teachers and administrators, are technology literate, prepared to use technology to improve curriculum and instruction, and are connected online to supports and resources, including through the following:</text>
 <clause id="H86FF04CA29B44400AF6DC6D5DF87951E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Professional development activities supported under section 2123 to improve educator quality and skills through support for the following:</text>
 <subclause id="HF3C069F664E0497E8ADC8A75962039CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>training that is ongoing, sustainable, timely, and directly related to up-to-date teaching content areas;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB1FA819BC2594738BEA78E48A01C5B8D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>training in strategies and pedagogy in the core academic subjects that involve use of technology and curriculum redesign as key components of changing teaching and learning and improving student achievement and technology literacy;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0BA1E10300374D34A85A1F1DE02E741F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>training in the use of computer-based and online assessments, and in the use of student performance and other data to individualize and personalize instruction; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H27D07031A2B1409C94CE43B76FE94D2F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>training that includes ongoing communication and follow-up with instructors, facilitators, and peers; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HDA1D4F1D647E4669AD451C537DC8B516"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include—</text> <subclause id="HD196EAB8C4F347079B957008832DC1D4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the use of, and training of, instructional technology specialists, mentors, master teachers, or coaches to serve as experts and train other teachers in the effective use of technology; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6F8D5F832C7C4228AF42010A133D3A67"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the use of technology, such as distance learning and online virtual educator-to-educator peer communities, as a means for delivering professional development.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE38363B2C4E64627ADF78C3726BD09C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Acquiring and effectively implementing technology tools, applications, and other resources in conjunction with enhancing or redesigning the curriculum or instruction in order to—</text>
 <clause id="HE3DDEB677321428D8F7A353BCB0C9102"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increase student learning opportunity or access, student engagement in learning, or student attendance or graduation rates;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEA7EA1B90C734535BDA6366238FDD08D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve student achievement in 1 or more of the core academic subjects; and</text> </clause><clause id="H3BF294D211BD4210ADFB6E72BA96543B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improve student technology literacy.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C80A3190FAC44DCAFC4959D4FD739D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Acquiring and effectively implementing technology tools, applications, and other resources to—</text> <clause id="H5E0531566FB44C4ABF6395ED0B4B7E4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct ongoing formative and other assessments and rapid cycle evaluation techniques and use other timely data sources and data systems to more effectively identify and address individual student learning needs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC7FD6C45E5AD4B81B25E7359166B4FAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>support personalized student learning, including through instructional software and digital content, and encouraging the use of open-licensed digital content to the extent possible, that supports the learning needs of each student, or through providing access to high-quality courses and instructors otherwise not available except through technology and online learning; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4736BD6ADD884F01AEF7F26FBAD743A0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct other activities consistent with research-based or innovative systemic school redesign, including activities that increase parental involvement and enhance accountability, instruction, and data-driven decisionmaking through data systems that allow for management, analysis, and disaggregating of student, teacher, and school data.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


