<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC422DB18A2C54003A63774003EC7932F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3465 IH: Public-Private Partnership Infrastructure Investment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3465</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150909">September 9, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To enhance the services of the Office of Contracts and Procurement at the Department of Transportation to assist modal agencies, States, and grant recipients with certain design and procurement practices and contracts.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H48B5424DFF654AEA84377A4BDA2B38C5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H162042BF1E25414981979836D3041DD3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public-Private Partnership Infrastructure Investment Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H6DA04C1526A44661B3F2782CDD5C0C34"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assistance with procurement</header> <subsection id="H954440CD584642BF94F03C22C08E5B48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The senior procurement executive of the Department of Transportation shall enhance the services of the Office of Contracts and Procurement by—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC579AC5B95244146B80DE13A0C81B0B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">working with modal agencies, States, and other grant recipients on implementing design-bid-build, design-build, and public-private partnerships (P3s) procurement best practices, including model contracts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13F26C3807AA4A6A8339C2A4A245220B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall develop suggested best practices to encourage standardizing state P3 authorities and practices, including fair and balanced assumptions made in the calculations, consistency on unsolicited bids, non-compete clauses, and other major elements.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H63A576B0A38A40F5A69D5BBE26B4CBF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>P3</quote> means contractual agreements formed between a public agency and a private sector entity that allow for greater private sector participation in the delivery and financing of transportation projects.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

