<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3907F0A3A70F4A668E6E88E71D4FE4A6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 234 IH: Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 234</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150108">January 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="">Select Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the sharing of certain cyber threat intelligence and cyber threat information
			 between the intelligence community and cybersecurity entities, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2326F66865EA47BC9545F2973021D091" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3AE505B421934D39AD9277F6256CD09A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6BE81EF5F694752BBA9604F3FB6F31A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal Government coordination with respect to cybersecurity</header> <subsection id="H1FE1594AE32C438BB01469AC889C15FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordinated activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government shall conduct cybersecurity activities to provide shared situational awareness that enables integrated operational actions to protect, prevent, mitigate, respond to, and recover from cyber incidents.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8DD44779AFBC4E61BB9405D6BC95033C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordinated information sharing</header>
 <paragraph id="HADB982176F6A424E8D0FEC55DA9B5E44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of coordinating entity for cyber threat information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall designate an entity within the Department of Homeland Security as the civilian Federal entity to receive cyber threat information that is shared by a cybersecurity provider or self-protected entity in accordance with section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 3(a) of this Act, except as provided in paragraph (2) and subject to the procedures established under paragraph (4).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H701CDFE05584481681B74641ED39786C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation of a coordinating entity for cybersecurity crimes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall designate an entity within the Department of Justice as the civilian Federal entity to receive cyber threat information related to cybersecurity crimes that is shared by a cybersecurity provider or self-protected entity in accordance with section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 3(a) of this Act, subject to the procedures under paragraph (4).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA5953B05E7A4FAB8F8895F60EAFA424"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sharing by coordinating entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The entities designated under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall share cyber threat information shared with such entities in accordance with section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 3(a) of this Act, consistent with the procedures established under paragraphs (4) and (5).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E7CABD530C14ED5BEA85DAA9D7897E3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>Each department or agency of the Federal Government receiving cyber threat information shared in accordance with section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 3(a) of this Act, shall establish procedures to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE857EF27A1CC4770B2A33EDF75298ED3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that cyber threat information shared with departments or agencies of the Federal Government in accordance with such section 1104(b) is also shared with appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government with a national security mission in real time;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C3E343CCDD14EEDADDD08463DAEC715"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure the distribution to other departments and agencies of the Federal Government of cyber threat information in real time; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8A9B2B205EF4D50BF813AE3D3DF4BF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitate information sharing, interaction, and collaboration among and between the Federal Government; State, local, tribal, and territorial governments; and cybersecurity providers and self-protected entities.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37F4DE7603384254B5522AB470DE8AD7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Privacy and civil liberties</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFECED644529045AA8FD2DB6EF72FA6BA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Policies and procedures</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly establish and periodically review policies and procedures governing the receipt, retention, use, and disclosure of non-publicly available cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government in accordance with section 1104(b) of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 3(a) of this Act. Such policies and procedures shall, consistent with the need to protect systems and networks from cyber threats and mitigate cyber threats in a timely manner—</text>
 <clause id="H4628498F086C4CD6853E46554DCE05AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>minimize the impact on privacy and civil liberties;</text> </clause><clause id="H0D1A4F275E93469ABFDE8AE6020CB9DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonably limit the receipt, retention, use, and disclosure of cyber threat information associated with specific persons that is not necessary to protect systems or networks from cyber threats or mitigate cyber threats in a timely manner;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8DC49137AAC44D04985AF4CFF588F379"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>include requirements to safeguard non-publicly available cyber threat information that may be used to identify specific persons from unauthorized access or acquisition;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6EC7D2A81600406FAB1617768150B67E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>protect the confidentiality of cyber threat information associated with specific persons to the greatest extent practicable; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H546FE0F9CE0D4C329648423DEE88DC45"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not delay or impede the flow of cyber threat information necessary to defend against or mitigate a cyber threat.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAABD9AEB9107482DAB5D38D90FA7A023"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Secretary of Defense shall, consistent with the need to protect sources and methods, jointly submit to Congress the policies and procedures required under subparagraph (A) and any updates to such policies and procedures.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5AE94D9133E45C18C8300C0088DAA61"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The head of each department or agency of the Federal Government receiving cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government under such section 1104(b) shall—</text>
 <clause id="H909AFDDBD71D4B618A2BB4688B70AEAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>implement the policies and procedures established under subparagraph (A); and</text> </clause><clause id="HC23CBC75DC504027BBF97BE781C37045"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>promptly notify the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Defense, and the appropriate congressional committees of any significant violations of such policies and procedures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF472BEFABF14E25A9D17D1F5CB31398"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly establish a program to monitor and oversee compliance with the policies and procedures established under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DACF40FFC0A4F75B2E1FDC16E880482"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Information sharing relationships</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> <subparagraph id="H6CEE099E7D1C47529A52EAAD120DF629"><enum>(A)</enum><text>alter existing agreements or prohibit new agreements with respect to the sharing of cyber threat information between the Department of Defense and an entity that is part of the defense industrial base;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83C74FA4C15A445890228E5C09DF25C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>alter existing information-sharing relationships between a cybersecurity provider, protected entity, or self-protected entity and the Federal Government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B47A830E767463AB68A927CD3CA38C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prohibit the sharing of cyber threat information directly with a department or agency of the Federal Government for criminal investigative purposes related to crimes described in section 1104(c)(1) of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 3(a) of this Act; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38225E169F1643F2AFDD8C231C8E56EB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">alter existing agreements or prohibit new agreements with respect to the sharing of cyber threat information between the Department of Treasury and an entity that is part of the financial services sector.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA742B38908804AF38349F8E7A9550A39"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5B7DE540CD1C4DB5BFC32B915CB58C8E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Discussions and assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit any department or agency of the Federal Government from engaging in formal or informal technical discussion regarding cyber threat information with a cybersecurity provider or self-protected entity or from providing technical assistance to address vulnerabilities or mitigate threats at the request of such a provider or such an entity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6514CBAE7B5846BA96B5D0077694743A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any department or agency of the Federal Government engaging in an activity referred to in subparagraph (A) shall coordinate such activity with the entity of the Department of Homeland Security designated under paragraph (1) and share all significant information resulting from such activity with such entity and all other appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0DA6E38A5534041B33C21F45501BE43"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Sharing by designated entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the policies and procedures established under paragraph (5), the entity of the Department of Homeland Security designated under paragraph (1) shall share with all appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government all significant information resulting from—</text>
 <clause id="H535E8EFB199E455082C21C8C5BFE8EF6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>formal or informal technical discussions between such entity of the Department of Homeland Security and a cybersecurity provider or self-protected entity about cyber threat information; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H27AA27B716184BEDA061C0386EE5185D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any technical assistance such entity of the Department of Homeland Security provides to such cybersecurity provider or such self-protected entity to address vulnerabilities or mitigate threats.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04DB292692B64EE2B57AE8CC978D45EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports on information sharing</header>
 <paragraph id="H454ED724CCE542AAA8A26BCAC2C9B9D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department of Justice, the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense, and the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, shall annually submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a review of the use of information shared with the Federal Government under subsection (b) of section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 3(a) of this Act, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD6C607330E194529817B293EE12A4C88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a review of the use by the Federal Government of such information for a purpose other than a cybersecurity purpose;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H856AA2AFE3D241BB89536DFB1F3D02E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of the type of information shared with the Federal Government under such subsection;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19DDF4AC52904E0CA8783B7A377373E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a review of the actions taken by the Federal Government based on such information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1191DB002ACB4A8481A28803EB547E90"><enum>(D)</enum><text>appropriate metrics to determine the impact of the sharing of such information with the Federal Government on privacy and civil liberties, if any;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2C35F242B0D84F03BADF45DCE1C82383"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of the departments or agencies receiving such information;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9551B42537CD41F0909754AF6D7F3172"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a review of the sharing of such information within the Federal Government to identify inappropriate stovepiping of shared information; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0556CCF7C7694B33B19C4B07F6E761DF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security for improvements or modifications to the authorities under such section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33A49AE07B5B469D8886861EC868E133"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy and civil liberties officers report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, and the senior privacy and civil liberties officer of each department or agency of the Federal Government that receives cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government under such subsection (b), shall annually and jointly submit to Congress a report assessing the privacy and civil liberties impact of the activities conducted by the Federal Government under such section 1104. Such report shall include any recommendations the Civil Liberties Protection Officer and Chief Privacy and Civil Liberties Officer consider appropriate to minimize or mitigate the privacy and civil liberties impact of the sharing of cyber threat information under such section 1104.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43FBE5F1E69A487EAEAA153473E755E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) or (2) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C5D0C1142354679A3F21ACD606DC6D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE072BF3B8AB4425AB71C23AFED45F2C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBA0FDBEA5B9E4B6799825C4C8B1C9ABC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EFF29E2FFDF46E2A3C28E1B5CDDF801"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28975813FA9A4F0B9AD78407DA53913C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cyber threat information, cyber threat intelligence, cybersecurity crimes, cybersecurity provider,
 cybersecurity purpose, and self-protected entity</header><text>The terms <term>cyber threat information</term>, <term>cyber threat intelligence</term>, <term>cybersecurity crimes</term>, <term>cybersecurity provider</term>, <term>cybersecurity purpose</term>, and <term>self-protected entity</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 3(a) of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDABB81E3813A41158958EBA1FFF29DD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/401a">50 U.S.C. 401a(4)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0EF7792DEA948E4914EFF2F2024974B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Shared situational awareness</header><text>The term <term>shared situational awareness</term> means an environment where cyber threat information is shared in real time between all designated Federal cyber operations centers to provide actionable information about all known cyber threats.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1C53BC4A59794944B20D8CA4C75F04A6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cyber threat intelligence and information sharing</header>
 <subsection id="H0F2895F3FD4647B3842015ADA864E85B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XI of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/442">50 U.S.C. 442 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE42F5B70CFE24263954CDA9EBA00DF10" style="traditional">
					<section id="HF34C5147E77A4BABA6866BBF8A40BF13"><enum>1104.</enum><header>Cyber threat intelligence and information sharing</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5B51771B007147F88C3AD58F1216CFD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Intelligence community sharing of cyber threat intelligence with private sector and utilities</header>
 <paragraph id="HE7BA6D0D1B824F7984660BE8F2D78CF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of National Intelligence shall establish procedures to allow elements of the intelligence community to share cyber threat intelligence with private-sector entities and utilities and to encourage the sharing of such intelligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H292DA27C03BF4B43B355D5C57528E3DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sharing and use of classified intelligence</header><text>The procedures established under paragraph (1) shall provide that classified cyber threat intelligence may only be—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE8D3DDC4DA744F268223CAE5BBEC60B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shared by an element of the intelligence community with—</text> <clause id="H096881188C1D42389F98FBAF6D04E8E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a certified entity; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H787B025227214DBE89494340717F5809"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a person with an appropriate security clearance to receive such cyber threat intelligence;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D384C7F44CC487AAD1116F858CF0F59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shared consistent with the need to protect the national security of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE50BD8433554B92B751CE6C9B9082E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used by a certified entity in a manner which protects such cyber threat intelligence from unauthorized disclosure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F2BECA4CD864DE382725E70F1CBF670"><enum>(D)</enum><text>used, retained, or further disclosed by a certified entity for cybersecurity purposes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H54AEEF7858D44FA3917E538F6D9D912F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Security clearance approvals</header><text>The Director of National Intelligence shall issue guidelines providing that the head of an element of the intelligence community may, as the head of such element considers necessary to carry out this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8A7D432C460C4E9192338C09E78EA7FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grant a security clearance on a temporary or permanent basis to an employee, independent contractor, or officer of a certified entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B2311AECF01439886652734DC9F56B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grant a security clearance on a temporary or permanent basis to a certified entity and approval to use appropriate facilities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6400A5E11666484EAD24BC3D3B0317D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>expedite the security clearance process for a person or entity as the head of such element considers necessary, consistent with the need to protect the national security of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D11F82ABF2548F7BABB796BCD260E01"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No right or benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provision of information to a private-sector entity or a utility under this subsection shall not create a right or benefit to similar information by such entity or such utility or any other private-sector entity or utility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58CC52690EE9438BBA7557846B46F76D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Restriction on disclosure of cyber threat intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a certified entity receiving cyber threat intelligence pursuant to this subsection shall not further disclose such cyber threat intelligence to another entity, other than to a certified entity or other appropriate agency or department of the Federal Government authorized to receive such cyber threat intelligence.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7457B5D53324FC88753552B8C5577D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of cybersecurity systems and sharing of cyber threat information</header>
							<paragraph id="H98A43422644449359D052EFEFCBEE8F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC321F9DFAF06410A8BA0B77AB83CBA31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Cybersecurity providers</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a cybersecurity provider, with the express consent of a protected entity for which such cybersecurity provider is providing goods or services for cybersecurity purposes, may, for cybersecurity purposes—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H0342DBC64C47416AB6FF7EB6ADA05D6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use cybersecurity systems to identify and obtain cyber threat information to protect the rights and property of such protected entity; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5DA699CA1307451286B537186AFCCC97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">share such cyber threat information with any other entity designated by such protected entity, including, if specifically designated, the entities of the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Justice designated under paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 2(b) of the Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31ED7FD3A21D41C18C03DE4360260573"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Self-protected entities</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a self-protected entity may, for cybersecurity purposes—</text>
 <clause id="H66FB29821F324B68A2A50A05384E7419"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use cybersecurity systems to identify and obtain cyber threat information to protect the rights and property of such self-protected entity; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9B9DC37C1E0444D7BE0452A9C65EF7DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">share such cyber threat information with any other entity, including the entities of the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Justice designated under paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 2(b) of the Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69A9366016C54746ADD9490B4F56C2FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use and protection of information</header><text>Cyber threat information shared in accordance with paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HDAD870CAA61B4AC1815AC6B37C538283"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall only be shared in accordance with any restrictions placed on the sharing of such information by the protected entity or self-protected entity authorizing such sharing, including appropriate anonymization or minimization of such information and excluding limiting a department or agency of the Federal Government from sharing such information with another department or agency of the Federal Government in accordance with this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88AEE747D52948BFB0C5AB28EF18C6C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not be used by an entity to gain an unfair competitive advantage to the detriment of the protected entity or the self-protected entity authorizing the sharing of information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H280D795A68EA449A96A61F9D8A68AEA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only be used by a non-Federal recipient of such information for a cybersecurity purpose;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25F6346F5F14497D943081B2410B3FEB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if shared with the Federal Government—</text>
 <clause id="H4D5A9093DE9444329DE5932E5A0C2F13"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HEDDD94D4BB124750BC97AA6C8FD0057F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be considered proprietary information and shall not be disclosed to an entity outside of the Federal Government except as authorized by the entity sharing such information;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0FC5A3BDCCD5403290E0E5FFA7B77529"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall not be used by the Federal Government for regulatory purposes;</text> </clause><clause id="H3D07CB0EA9F84DFD9BA20CCA5A35B544"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be provided to another department or agency of the Federal Government under paragraph (2)(A) if—</text>
 <subclause id="H3E6E734AB8964237BEC228319ECF3CA7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity providing such information determines that the provision of such information will undermine the purpose for which such information is shared; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9CA1B624EC7347E1A240108F91B6C3B0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>unless otherwise directed by the President, the head of the department or agency of the Federal Government receiving such cyber threat information determines that the provision of such information will undermine the purpose for which such information is shared; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF8AB30195EAF4103B1932478F51E8CC2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>shall be handled by the Federal Government consistent with the need to protect sources and methods and the national security of the United States; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DA9D6F6C2AD48A4A0E6B780421AF826"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be exempt from disclosure under a law or regulation of a State, political subdivision of a State, or a tribe that requires public disclosure of information by a public or quasi-public entity.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB625F12A9FE548A5890DE61DC7213349"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemption from liability</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7AD2C4CCB4F347A4BAF7D18FBA212B8A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>No civil or criminal cause of action shall lie or be maintained in Federal or State court against a protected entity, self-protected entity, cybersecurity provider, or an officer, employee, or agent of a protected entity, self-protected entity, or cybersecurity provider, acting in good faith—</text>
 <clause id="H220585D2974E48A8B7A2A96B7F6F3ECE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for using cybersecurity systems to identify or obtain cyber threat information or for sharing such information in accordance with this section; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H56FC2AD4C39B470583B3C412D9F419F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for decisions made for cybersecurity purposes and based on cyber threat information identified, obtained, or shared under this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81D384078B7A4C95AB1A86B4AC7502C4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Lack of good faith</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the exemption from liability under subparagraph (A), a lack of good faith includes any act or omission taken with intent to injure, defraud, or otherwise endanger any individual, government entity, private entity, or utility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEF1BBE9C4EA44545848696C5B48DA14C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relationship to other laws requiring the disclosure of information</header><text>The submission of information under this subsection to the Federal Government shall not satisfy or affect—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H49CC5BF8D0914B2390EF7E1FC7A885AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any requirement under any other provision of law for a person or entity to provide information to the Federal Government; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAC141FBE9B04E63BA0689BAFB665BB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicability of other provisions of law, including section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>), with respect to information required to be provided to the Federal Government under such other provision of law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D966D8DF1494E1A9B50CCC8FCDEAA70"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to provide new authority to—</text> <subparagraph id="H8A813064777F4CCDB3EF5AE727BC8F0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a cybersecurity provider to use a cybersecurity system to identify or obtain cyber threat information from a system or network other than a system or network owned or operated by a protected entity for which such cybersecurity provider is providing goods or services for cybersecurity purposes; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7774674890848DB83084B45FCFE3388"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a self-protected entity to use a cybersecurity system to identify or obtain cyber threat information from a system or network other than a system or network owned or operated by such self-protected entity.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA62900F856AB4252A10DBD68012C4E3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal Government use of information</header>
 <paragraph id="H86D7D3D4E1684A4F98576A027F57E932"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government may use cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government in accordance with subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H88004575462945F9BFD4BEEC432B0D6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for cybersecurity purposes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A8C662D959645F085FCCBB253824559"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the investigation and prosecution of cybersecurity crimes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD5A8BB65BF34B1F9B87DABA5313AF18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for the protection of individuals from the danger of death or serious bodily harm and the investigation and prosecution of crimes involving such danger of death or serious bodily harm; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3DA54E31FD4435394CB68D864EA2160"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the protection of minors from child pornography, any risk of sexual exploitation, and serious threats to the physical safety of minors, including kidnapping and trafficking and the investigation and prosecution of crimes involving child pornography, any risk of sexual exploitation, and serious threats to the physical safety of minors, including kidnapping and trafficking, and any crime referred to in section 2258A(a)(2) of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C09A71732FD416B8B6616418466EDA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affirmative search restriction</header><text>The Federal Government may not affirmatively search cyber threat information shared with the Federal Government under subsection (b) for a purpose other than a purpose referred to in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00DC4E131A6940269466B5361921C5BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Anti-tasking restriction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Federal Government to—</text> <subparagraph id="H24A3360EE16C4A1CBD405CABE6D66C76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require a private-sector entity or utility to share information with the Federal Government; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85F61A2E408948B7B9944257098CE05D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>condition the sharing of cyber threat intelligence with a private-sector entity or utility on the provision of cyber threat information to the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2CE4C750D6904B43A81CB3BFACC8F681"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Protection of sensitive personal documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government may not use the following information, containing information that identifies a person, shared with the Federal Government in accordance with subsection (b):</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7147A4AEEC874E298BCC0CAD979D177C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Library circulation records.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5D5762C75CF94BB0BED8AFE66FA8FB2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Library patron lists.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H85FF915426C0452B8C30B89BDCE8969F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Book sales records.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBD58D945760C4CA78429F463680C7AA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Book customer lists.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB759C98A406A4797BB2AA52177996736"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Firearms sales records.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE7C7407DD06F4C72B2FE173E52531EE3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Tax return records.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H44F4629C822A401694C298505848ED26"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Educational records.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4756A478406B4AED868B63718AD18ED4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Medical records.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02FC2C2B71C545BC8F69B0618F0EE858"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notification of non-cyber threat information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a department or agency of the Federal Government receiving information pursuant to subsection (b)(1) determines that such information is not cyber threat information, such department or agency shall notify the entity or provider sharing such information pursuant to subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A2F464891434F81BA955BAB411B055F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Retention and use of cyber threat information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No department or agency of the Federal Government shall retain or use information shared pursuant to subsection (b)(1) for any use other than a use permitted under subsection (c)(1).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD08A90BA2A994DD9B477046825FBECAA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal Government liability for violations of restrictions on the disclosure, use, and protection
			 of voluntarily shared information</header>
 <paragraph id="H6661C6B05E2441CDBC7537C9ABD85F35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a department or agency of the Federal Government intentionally or willfully violates subsection (b)(3)(D) or subsection (c) with respect to the disclosure, use, or protection of voluntarily shared cyber threat information shared under this section, the United States shall be liable to a person adversely affected by such violation in an amount equal to the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDB75D6E442294F968A157E4DC61F80CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the actual damages sustained by the person as a result of the violation or $1,000, whichever is greater; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE33CB6B02C6A4D718334C068FBF2644B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the costs of the action together with reasonable attorney fees as determined by the court.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7226E339F0C341798B78808FA6BB9270"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>An action to enforce liability created under this subsection may be brought in the district court of the United States in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H636387EB6BA64BB7B7607612D886B01A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the district in which the complainant resides;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA01327F6DA074F4D816037AAD9ACB868"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the district in which the principal place of business of the complainant is located;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD822072641147129F51ED82F4817C8D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the district in which the department or agency of the Federal Government that disclosed the information is located; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0360173307AC492D8CCADC0683994C10"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the District of Columbia.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5636E420032947A8B3B0E38DBFF9136F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No action shall lie under this subsection unless such action is commenced not later than two years after the date of the violation of subsection (b)(3)(D) or subsection (c) that is the basis for the action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H741DB5AF3747447C8563D2B906DF2851"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusive cause of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A cause of action under this subsection shall be the exclusive means available to a complainant seeking a remedy for a violation of subsection (b)(3)(D) or subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7E2D63206734516985588447BDD79FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal preemption</header><text>This section supersedes any statute of a State or political subdivision of a State that restricts or otherwise expressly regulates an activity authorized under subsection (b).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HB160B938C52842188EDC13BA8152D212"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Savings clauses</header>
 <paragraph id="HB714AAF0BE334B1F97100C68F80893B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing authorities</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit any other authority to use a cybersecurity system or to identify, obtain, or share cyber threat intelligence or cyber threat information.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H6FDE75E94D494B01B209F3973CCA01FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on military and intelligence community involvement in private and public sector
 cybersecurity efforts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide additional authority to, or modify an existing authority of, the Department of Defense or the National Security Agency or any other element of the intelligence community to control, modify, require, or otherwise direct the cybersecurity efforts of a private-sector entity or a component of the Federal Government or a State, local, or tribal government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED1C34058F724398B590E78ADC01AE08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information sharing relationships</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF0A9DE708E0449A7A3546E93C61C3436"><enum>(A)</enum><text>limit or modify an existing information sharing relationship;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA28050D106D54C9A8E7E943636897CD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prohibit a new information sharing relationship;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09DD5988D8DF46EAA16ADC50681B9B83"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require a new information sharing relationship between the Federal Government and a private-sector entity or utility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB49597B98F744B99E8129D94E38AA31"><enum>(D)</enum><text>modify the authority of a department or agency of the Federal Government to protect sources and methods and the national security of the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F97F81A32444BCEA45CC79992AD1261"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preclude the Federal Government from requiring an entity to report significant cyber incidents if authorized or required to do so under another provision of law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0FDFCF3C794D7DAD7EEA4EEC8F787B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on Federal Government use of cybersecurity systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide additional authority to, or modify an existing authority of, any entity to use a cybersecurity system owned or controlled by the Federal Government on a private-sector system or network to protect such private-sector system or network.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBD8F5AC0C1014D5B9ABC508FFB05AA20"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No liability for non-participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to subject a protected entity, self-protected entity, cybersecurity provider, or an officer, employee, or agent of a protected entity, self-protected entity, or cybersecurity provider, to liability for choosing not to engage in the voluntary activities authorized under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DDE4975C82F4135AB9FA32D1999D941"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Use and retention of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize, or to modify any existing authority of, a department or agency of the Federal Government to retain or use information shared pursuant to subsection (b)(1) for any use other than a use permitted under subsection (c)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H208A876699164E2D8382D746EDC7548B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Limitation on surveillance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Department of Defense or the National Security Agency or any other element of the intelligence community to target a United States person for surveillance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD08D514C513F4474B1E4148AFB5BCBDD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4B9C98B9144E4044922FA6A3445CAE2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>availability</quote> means ensuring timely and reliable access to and use of information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58037D4B392F4E9F81250B614AA927B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certified entity</header><text>The term <term>certified entity</term> means a protected entity, self-protected entity, or cybersecurity provider that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H687217639B4049F6A0BB9CBD199279A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>possesses or is eligible to obtain a security clearance, as determined by the Director of National Intelligence; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDBC8B495959475A859F1C7F44FDE54A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is able to demonstrate to the Director of National Intelligence that such provider or such entity can appropriately protect classified cyber threat intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59D7C38A35344F2992AA27518B10BEE4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>confidentiality</quote> means preserving authorized restrictions on access and disclosure, including means for protecting personal privacy and proprietary information.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HFCFC2419A20047AA93ACFCCB65DE8440"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cyber threat information</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7292EEEE33EC4CD8958BA5C9D6C691B5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The term <quote>cyber threat information</quote> means information directly pertaining to—</text> <clause id="H4A726361313940468924BFF8F9BC013C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a vulnerability of a system or network of a government or private entity or utility;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3F2C8BBC54A5475E8230B55A66D36EA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a threat to the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of a system or network of a government or private entity or utility or any information stored on, processed on, or transiting such a system or network;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H11C8E05EE7574259AD531B80052975E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network of a government or private entity or utility; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC9B3499CCCB64C6FAE9D5243A7FE0C35"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network of a government or private entity or utility, including to gain such unauthorized access for the purpose of exfiltrating information stored on, processed on, or transiting a system or network of a government or private entity or utility.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60F33D4C7E37429C90E5CE07044EB114"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Such term does not include information pertaining to efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network of a government or private entity or utility that solely involve violations of consumer terms of service or consumer licensing agreements and do not otherwise constitute unauthorized access.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H572DC6ADEBDC4AC6AF08AAA3163C6665"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cyber threat intelligence</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD34E06C932254F1B9EFB40C86E7C03BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>cyber threat intelligence</quote> means intelligence in the possession of an element of the intelligence community directly pertaining to—</text>
 <clause id="H0EC093063E294BC2B5939D036B5CA986"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a vulnerability of a system or network of a government or private entity or utility;</text> </clause><clause id="HA94BAAB37EE046F4815D27E2D1863B8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a threat to the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of a system or network of a government or private entity or utility or any information stored on, processed on, or transiting such a system or network;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H89CE0F16395343349D0DFBA5C1D533F6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network of a government or private entity or utility; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5362B05EE5E249A89DC34D4CE50EC575"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network of a government or private entity or utility, including to gain such unauthorized access for the purpose of exfiltrating information stored on, processed on, or transiting a system or network of a government or private entity or utility.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9A8D2B40C6943FD979C40C9CF237F35"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Such term does not include intelligence pertaining to efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network of a government or private entity or utility that solely involve violations of consumer terms of service or consumer licensing agreements and do not otherwise constitute unauthorized access.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H82878945824649A9B62914E6E22ECAD9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cybersecurity crime</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>cybersecurity crime</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H86AB46E3C9D149BAA19B0E802D98462A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a crime under a Federal or State law that involves—</text>
 <clause id="H12FD91A740DB4E1FB3B0B02BD9F0E888"><enum>(i)</enum><text>efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network;</text> </clause><clause id="H1C1CD0CF08BD4219AB6930EAE017909D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1AF90B48DAF84902AB57463E4651B4FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>efforts to exfiltrate information from a system or network without authorization; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13A2D80300D64DDEABDB948FE1E1F287"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the violation of a provision of Federal law relating to computer crimes, including a violation of any provision of title 18, United States Code, created or amended by the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/474">Public Law 99–474</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0E7ADC39A214BA880D390D87DF25FC5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Cybersecurity provider</header><text>The term <term>cybersecurity provider</term> means a non-Federal entity that provides goods or services intended to be used for cybersecurity purposes.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HCD3E01C159454B9BAD68D0818EB19D6E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Cybersecurity purpose</header>
 <subparagraph id="H34627BA8D656480DB16FBC32BB037C53"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>cybersecurity purpose</quote> means the purpose of ensuring the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of, or safeguarding, a system or network, including protecting a system or network from—</text>
 <clause id="H3795A7C9CF0849D1964B0FAEF67A0B62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a vulnerability of a system or network;</text> </clause><clause id="H8A5B0F5988F04FD98236EE539BB93F79"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a threat to the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of a system or network or any information stored on, processed on, or transiting such a system or network;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H60785BD9EDBF4FC4A8DF04BD2FB58CEE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network; or</text> </clause><clause id="H2E5769B7FF5B4037A457D222DADFEDEA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network, including to gain such unauthorized access for the purpose of exfiltrating information stored on, processed on, or transiting a system or network.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE8F3723A9664003A6BE2B1A1D886C29"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Such term does not include the purpose of protecting a system or network from efforts to gain unauthorized access to such system or network that solely involve violations of consumer terms of service or consumer licensing agreements and do not otherwise constitute unauthorized access.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6E8068E72904F819835A318FCC6D651"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Cybersecurity system</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2E9B680F34EC457885CD90A8A946FF1A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>cybersecurity system</quote> means a system designed or employed to ensure the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of, or safeguard, a system or network, including protecting a system or network from—</text>
 <clause id="HEA8CB71E1B7C45D2B1E36AAB2E9317BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a vulnerability of a system or network;</text> </clause><clause id="H4A55C4DEF7AE478EBCD7FCD81FC8D085"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a threat to the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of a system or network or any information stored on, processed on, or transiting such a system or network;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE1DAE3752E234DFD9FB51C830015CEA7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to deny access to or degrade, disrupt, or destroy a system or network; or</text> </clause><clause id="H8763A6A735214BE388E68D0D8BF6B8DB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to gain unauthorized access to a system or network, including to gain such unauthorized access for the purpose of exfiltrating information stored on, processed on, or transiting a system or network.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21E438F41A7C45BE9FDCBC8AB8D89347"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Such term does not include a system designed or employed to protect a system or network from efforts to gain unauthorized access to such system or network that solely involve violations of consumer terms of service or consumer licensing agreements and do not otherwise constitute unauthorized access.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB4ABFCF770B460C82CF5CFB8559A6E3"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Integrity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>integrity</quote> means guarding against improper information modification or destruction, including ensuring information nonrepudiation and authenticity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6861B89B78A4DFBAB377D10FB706BAC"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Protected entity</header><text>The term <term>protected entity</term> means an entity, other than an individual, that contracts with a cybersecurity provider for goods or services to be used for cybersecurity purposes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2DFE6F16A67E40CBA04B1226709DD755"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Self-protected entity</header><text>The term <term>self-protected entity</term> means an entity, other than an individual, that provides goods or services for cybersecurity purposes to itself.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD4DD67834EC4141AB14B96741721D2D"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Utility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>utility</term> means an entity providing essential services (other than law enforcement or regulatory services), including electricity, natural gas, propane, telecommunications, transportation, water, or wastewater services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC006B808E114A4B85D12534E04BEC44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures and guidelines</header><text>The Director of National Intelligence shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6813A4446DFA46D892C4BD31F8471AA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, establish procedures under paragraph (1) of section 1104(a) of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by subsection (a) of this section, and issue guidelines under paragraph (3) of such section 1104(a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0D70E393C82441DA324C017021588E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in establishing such procedures and issuing such guidelines, consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security to ensure that such procedures and such guidelines permit the owners and operators of critical infrastructure to receive all appropriate cyber threat intelligence (as defined in section 1104(h)(5) of such Act, as added by subsection (a)) in the possession of the Federal Government; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAC0AD9E80C8A40FD84E8651D7BEAD8BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>following the establishment of such procedures and the issuance of such guidelines, expeditiously distribute such procedures and such guidelines to appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government, private-sector entities, and utilities (as defined in section 1104(h)(13) of such Act, as added by subsection (a)).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6075A43A35AE4D2C9898778133CCAA1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Privacy and civil liberties policies and procedures</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General, shall establish the policies and procedures required under section 1104(c)(7)(A) of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8C8445CBD394D728F7BAAD686175328"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Initial reports</header><text>The first reports required to be submitted under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (e) of section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by subsection (a) of this section, shall be submitted not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF92917B7A57946D0A5AD2DF0EBA86175"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in the first section of the National Security Act of 1947 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H935D59C4C36A4ACFA222F5B11B66B801" style="traditional">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1104. Cyber threat intelligence and information sharing.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H257486B2395642F5A9960F9F26CFD878"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBE6032756E104C7B9DF1DD443A1B13F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947, as added by section 2(a) of this Act, is repealed; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB3C6E94C370B4DA08A64AF23FCCEA166"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the table of contents in the first section of the National Security Act of 1947, as amended by section 2(d) of this Act, is amended by striking the item relating to section 1104, as added by such section 2(d).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H26F5F2EA09234008BE9F44AFD6017B51"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on international cooperation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that international cooperation with regard to cybersecurity should be encouraged wherever possible under this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H3432C80E07664896B69B0D62DB6D0875"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rule of construction relating to consumer data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to provide new or alter any existing authority for an entity to sell personal information of a consumer to another entity for marketing purposes.</text>
		</section><section id="H8F8E729DBBC1444E9B7651DF22A46584"><enum>7.</enum><header>Savings clause with regard to cybersecurity provider obligation to report cyber threat incident
 information to Federal Government</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to provide authority to a department or agency of the Federal Government to require a cybersecurity provider that has contracted with the Federal Government to provide information services to provide information about cybersecurity incidents that do not pose a threat to the Federal Government’s information.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


