<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="A1" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1872 IH: To authorize Energy Frontier Research Centers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1872</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize Energy Frontier Research Centers.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC78BCB947A4348F0BDCF551293F9A4D0">
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Energy Frontier Research Centers</header>
 <subsection id="id44B0A706F46A42AC8F6454B345EBD7E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall carry out a program to provide awards, on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, to multi-institutional collaborations or other appropriate entities to conduct fundamental and use-inspired energy research to accelerate scientific breakthroughs related to needs identified in—</text><paragraph id="idFED531A6D00A444DB694A9742B3B1C40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Grand Challenges report of the Department’s Basic Energy Sciences Advisory Committee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB22F5F37E5E74C8EB30E3F2FB218F8E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the report of the Department’s Basic Energy Sciences Advisory Committee entitled <quote>From Quanta to the Continuum: Opportunities for Mesoscale Science</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0545CFE3AEF840509C3F5151D9FBC27A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Basic Energy Sciences Basic Research Needs workshop report; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1258156D2FBE4709B4FC0EBDA612F16B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other relevant reports identified by the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAACA389F941440A199E637653CBAF88E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaborations</header><text>A collaboration receiving an award under this subsection may include multiple types of institutions and private sector entities.</text></subsection><subsection id="idE2D497FACDC8435ABFFF92BC1C80F953"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection and duration</header><paragraph id="id6A53D018536C477192674A35E9647529"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A collaboration under this subsection shall be selected for a period of 5 years. An Energy Frontier Research Center already in existence and supported by the Director on the date of enactment of this Act may continue to receive support for a period of 5 years beginning on the date of establishment of that center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69C97136157540C285A0C1DA713937B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reapplication</header><text>After the end of the period described in paragraph (1), an awardee may reapply for selection for a second period of 5 years on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19CFB495FD344F23BF96AD681F189CAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Consistent with the existing authorities of the Department, the Director may terminate an underperforming center for cause during the performance period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF58648C056D54F42B37327809ACE495F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No funding for construction</header><text>No funding provided pursuant to this subsection may be used for the construction of new buildings or facilities.</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


