<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H041BC36E59EE4788B0AC56F589433A4D" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 882 IH: No Child Left Inside Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 882</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150211">February 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 in order to improve environmental
			 literacy to better prepare students for postsecondary education and
			 careers, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBC9A8A45717E483F969B0CB0F7A0C596" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0710433EC31D4F91A716933EA6BD9FAE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HAF9A53FBAB4042038EBAD95F4B577D97"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Child Left Inside Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H1B44E2C96C1348F294F3866B336B8ACD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="H0710433EC31D4F91A716933EA6BD9FAE" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDF9153341C584C60952CE1A18F28B946" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA289291CA8C541B08F9C7D7E81452ABA" level="section">Sec. 3. References.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2BF404C4A33E4787AD3EBDB8C1F5117C" level="section">Sec. 4. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H93E895FDD7CB44E3AED5F71332384CCF" level="title">TITLE I—Environmental literacy</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3E48A6BEE3934F0FBCAA891B19588623" level="section">Sec. 101. Environmental literacy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 102. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4C1788E6AC484AA8A7B6C34401EC614B" level="title">TITLE II—Promoting environmental literacy in education programs</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6BD1A5D2D5BA4CAF8DBB85CB10049A21" level="section">Sec. 201. Amendments to part B of title II.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HAC9CDBF70E4A44F3AE7FF8BB6550F5C4" level="section">Sec. 202. Amendments to part B of title IV.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFABE84AEEBA04CE3A344640191738AD6" level="title">TITLE III—National activities</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H208B1E039C864B1386B78DAD2FB96B31" level="section">Sec. 301. Availability of other environmental literacy information.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDF94649DDF984A138901FAA4D46B9977" level="section">Sec. 302. Federal interagency coordination on environmental literacy.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDF9153341C584C60952CE1A18F28B946"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H70A6C1794A4948A4816EA74C09E98F04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Children and young adults are increasingly disconnected from the natural world around them, spending less time outside playing, exploring, and learning.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FF4A46FD31B4B40837CB47FD7BA60AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Play and learning in nature is important to the intellectual, social, and physical development of youth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4381EA4A9F8A4E48A98F8551D7B192BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Environmental education, as part of the formal prekindergarten through grade 12 school curriculum, provides opportunities for youth to get outside and learn about the natural world, has positive impacts on student achievement in all subjects and especially in science, reading, mathematics, and social studies, and improves critical thinking skills, enthusiasm for learning, stewardship, and healthy lifestyles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D6BBF4EBF454EE095C668267DBC1A2F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>By many indicators, the United States is falling behind other nations in preparing students with the educational tools necessary to compete for the growing opportunities in the sciences, including environmental, natural resource, and energy related careers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41C5177F3B224FDEB775096072A42938"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Reports by boards of the National Science Foundation, the National Environmental Education Advisory Council, and the National Council for Science and the Environment, among others, have called for a systemic approach to environmental education in the formal education system to improve the environmental literacy of youth and better prepare students for college and the 21st century workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58D0F6572D6743C9A0C07C40E71F5CA7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Forty-eight States have developed, or are in the process of developing, environmental literacy plans to effectively integrate environmental education into the prekindergarten through grade 12 curriculum and ensure that students graduate from high school environmentally literate. At the same time, most States are aligning curricula with the Common Core State Standards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE8222497E69477EA87700124962E9AF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Support from the Department of Education is needed to help State and local educational agencies, and the partners of such agencies, implement environmental literacy plans and advance State curriculum frameworks for environmental and natural resource education that meets new State academic content and student achievement standards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7EC977E9D8C4DBEBEF10EF8C99FBEC8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Federal science and natural resource agencies have important resources, including Federal lands and laboratories, content experts, data, and programs, that can inform and support State and local environmental literacy policies and programming.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HA289291CA8C541B08F9C7D7E81452ABA"><enum>3.</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise specifically provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or a repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
		</section><title id="H93E895FDD7CB44E3AED5F71332384CCF"><enum>I</enum><header>Environmental Literacy</header>
 <section id="H3E48A6BEE3934F0FBCAA891B19588623"><enum>101.</enum><header>Environmental Literacy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title V (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7201">20 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3A208871D4041FAB2C7B0C31849DCFA" style="OLC"> <subpart id="HA4AEC5ACD00B49A99718BFBC7680CAB6"><enum>22</enum><header>Environmental literacy</header> <section id="HE09CCBC7BAD04723B93176E2BA33ECEB"><enum>5621.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text>
 <paragraph id="H48215CBF71F04C368392CCEB01506623"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible partnership</header><text>The term <term>eligible partnership</term> means a partnership that includes a local educational agency and not less than 1 of the following partners:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H76FC4E66D2CF4B339C41E09990508649"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A teacher preparation program at an institution of higher education.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE873C0FFD2A449F987288604E919D85F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The environmental or life sciences department of an institution of higher education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E88402DCA6A4AAAB8918FA4741B016F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Another local educational agency, a public charter school, a public elementary school or secondary school, or a consortium of such schools.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00E56DDF7178428B8DA1ED42D999CC48"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A Federal, State, regional, or local environmental or natural resource management agency, or parks and recreation department, that has demonstrated effectiveness, expertise, and experience in the field of environmental literacy, including the professional development of teachers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40F015934899426CBA14506A5F514B6F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization that has demonstrated effectiveness, expertise, and experience in the field of environmental literacy, including the professional development of teachers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6634AECA54D746A9A51D657C87EC6910"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental literacy</header><text>The term <term>environmental literacy</term> means a fundamental understanding of ecological principles, the systems of the natural world, and the relationships and interactions between natural and man-made environments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61DC4AFE7D274C6EB75C11C08A4D801E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental literacy plan</header><text>The term <term>environmental literacy plan</term> means a plan developed, approved, or sponsored by the State educational agency in consultation with State environmental agencies, State environmental education associations, and State natural resource agencies, and with input from the public, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9075BDDFEB4E43189B57BFC3242A704D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prepares students to understand ecological principles, the systems of the natural world, and the relationships and interactions between natural and man-made environments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AF97134EF774F4B9EE89A68DC536D1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides field and hands-on experiences as part of the regular school curriculum and creates programs that contribute to healthy lifestyles through outdoor recreation and sound nutrition;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H080DD9E38DAE46B68CAA25F51127AE05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides environmental service learning opportunities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0EFBC76A97349939EDC58FE2BC5F827"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides targeted professional development opportunities for teachers that improves the teachers'—</text>
 <clause id="H5EE66201D0F34A19B4F1C677B4B80D00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>environmental and natural resource content knowledge; and</text> </clause><clause id="H086DB8C362A44264B9CEA8041FFAD967"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pedagogical skills in teaching about the environment, including the use of—</text>
 <subclause id="HFD25522B111F461686A957889FD092DB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>interdisciplinary, field-based, and research-based learning; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD8F744B1072A422CA1911608B273ECFD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>science, technology, engineering, and mathematics content knowledge and tools;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E75DAEFD4B49B2A554C1A5ABACFA4A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>describes the measures the State will use to assess the environmental literacy of students, including—</text>
 <clause id="HEC61460B26574B198C4D6A97437322E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relevant State academic content standards and content areas regarding environmental education, and courses or subjects where environmental education instruction will be integrated throughout the prekindergarten through grade 12 curriculum; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1B0A20856BC747848AC27249D5E1B186"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the relationship of the plan to the secondary school graduation requirements of the State;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAE28F616A7448F286D34DA773001A5A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>describes how the State educational agency will implement the plan, in partnership with nongovernmental organizations, Federal agencies, State environmental agencies, State environmental education associations, State natural resource agencies, and local educational agencies, including how the State educational agency will secure funding and other necessary support; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA71D8B10FFE04E388A4CAACDAD40E5E3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>is periodically updated by the State educational agency not less often than every 5 years.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H942D74A686DF4C62A5B063B46457ECDF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-need local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>high-need local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1B957EF774EE422D9A7C91812A2E4230"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for which not less than 20 percent of the children served by the agency are children from low-income families;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E1EE7834E7040CD830B381F2E21EF57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that serves not fewer than 10,000 children from low-income families;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20592E46D9D54C8DA184D7D23FEFA79D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that meets the eligibility requirements for funding under section 6211(b); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D4F876854B540B08E81E7872C5E727A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that meets the eligibility requirements for funding under section 6221(b).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H5B6B213D80E241F8A44BDBBD2977031A"><enum>5622.</enum><header>Grants for implementation of environmental literacy plans</header> <subsection id="H82962AAA65FE4D6C8E86947F27C4D816"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts appropriated for this section, the Secretary shall award grants to States to enable the States to award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships to support the implementation of the State environmental literacy plan.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H0D6A7345613A401AAEA28FAD31323E48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="H13ADFD990E8A400284098A810D77DE8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE948F5D3375C492D9DDC2480122619FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2080B721288404F84103BAE2ADE0674"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the State’s environmental literacy plan and information on the status of implementation of such plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EFD0A0237FC4A0B864D3255F96D95FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe how funds received under this subsection will assist the State in furthering the implementation of the State’s environmental literacy plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3776BD16F05F49EB839296D91EA26502"><enum>(C)</enum><text>describe the process the State will use to make subgrants to eligible partnerships; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43856900672945AC899A8E08EB85F6B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>describe the process the State will use to evaluate the impact of the activities assisted under this subpart.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA3BF5CBCC71B4B43A491596E4CDB056A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Peer review</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H469F90869541465BB1E6452E740F4839"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a peer review process to assist in the review of grant applications under this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H977010AC9A6946B9920291BF069F9C2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>appoint individuals to the peer review process who—</text> <subparagraph id="H334C0AF266964D608D5F5CBE72B85150"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are representative of parents, teachers, State educational agencies, State environmental agencies, State natural resource agencies, local educational agencies, and nongovernmental organizations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AAC9EA0C64746608492C1598D9580B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are familiar with national environmental issues and the health and educational needs of students; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCE02F6D9B82E419FB0952CF76CEE2D46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include, in the peer review process, appropriate representatives from the Department of Commerce, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, and other appropriate Federal agencies, to provide environmental expertise and background for evaluation of the State environmental literacy plan.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4CE6FECF7624FC786F9366D5A6FEE07"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>A State receiving a grant under this section may use not more than 2.5 percent of the grant funds for administrative expenses.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H5B42E346F01F48A0905E219A72372AD0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State Educational Agency Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H3C60B077E4854EF6A4FFC089B8AA6F39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State receiving a grant under this subpart shall prepare and submit an annual report to the Secretary containing information about—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7D768EED12D34527B72D6A6F30C62368"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the implementation of the environmental literacy plan; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F97EB1A5DD34D68BE9CD3F655EFF4A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the grant activities supported under this subpart.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB87FCC92A1D04C0AA5155D10DC8C003E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report requirements</header><text>The report required by this section shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H2735A764D07B4509B0BAD6A7BC21F07E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the form specified by the Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D9C31340F2F4A27B2AC7E19E24C1697"><enum>(B)</enum><text>based on the State's ongoing evaluation activities; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC503387B2F94D1C810FEFAF55600AA4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>made readily available to the public.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE31A871C71B742BE8B322572E47654AD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subgrants authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H0D0B14A4C1CB48958545E5C9071731F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Subgrants to eligible partnerships</header><text>From amounts made available to a State educational agency under subsection (a), the State educational agency shall award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships serving the State, to enable the eligible partnerships to carry out the authorized activities described in subsection (h).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AB25774F73B4E169DAF31D152EA81DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The State educational agency shall award each subgrant under this section for a period of not more than 3 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1ABA9D84C27742A19CEBC2D3B905B423"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making subgrants under this section, a State shall give priority to eligible partnerships that include a high-need local educational agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71297E99FCB84F9D8E0DEEE2B3BFDCA1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Funds provided to an eligible partnership under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, funds that would otherwise be used for activities authorized under this section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57A1574B3C8344D2B595AEB06A55A342"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HDE5FDB28E59E4A5E8CE9BA77CBC5B760"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible partnership desiring a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the State educational agency, at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the State educational agency may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51A28888E9D2412F9B557938BA94D5BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AA9F2375B9E4BE2B4C0A9B5B6FF3D0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of teacher professional development needs, with respect to the teaching and learning of environmental content;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H082705C30E4D4AD1AF0B1B6513B819CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an explanation of how the activities to be carried out by the eligible partnership are expected to improve student academic achievement and strengthen the quality of environmental instruction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8F69811F5A64AFC96EC0B2F0C699922"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how the activities to be carried out by the eligible partnership—</text> <clause id="H9D0A02518FE745C0B02104412A2A42A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>will be aligned with challenging State academic content standards and student academic achievement standards under section 1111(b)(1) in environmental education, to the extent such standards exist, and with the State's environmental literacy plan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H39D231BE87A14438AB8CF5E364AC1383"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>will advance the teaching of interdisciplinary courses that integrate the study of natural, social, and economic systems and that include strong field components in which students have the opportunity to directly experience nature through outdoor environmental learning;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H634C67DBAF024ED292279D560A0A71EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how the activities to be carried out by the eligible partnership will ensure that teachers are trained in the use of field-based or service learning to enable the teachers—</text>
 <clause id="H15ED557FEE5B472A8FCE22B7CA0CB0C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to use the local environment and community as a resource; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE21D4312AF71476391FE86E8A65B7C07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to improve student understanding of the environment and increase academic achievement;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E3708A77152496A90CD58992B70D2BB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <clause id="H7205AEA7EAD6445480CF36BC28704F03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how the eligible partnership will carry out the authorized activities described in subsection (h); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H07BEB437BBFF42059C90D9D04A702985"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the eligible partnership's evaluation and accountability plan described in subsection (i); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41FEB12ED30E44E8AC764B97CB710A6F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible partnership will continue the activities funded under this section after the grant period has expired.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BEC6D9CAEA4482FA20E0E92AE4FED1E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>An eligible partnership shall use the subgrant funds provided under this section for 1 or more of the following activities related to elementary schools or secondary schools:</text>
 <paragraph id="H523B0346ACA44DADA1B67119985B044C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Providing targeted, job-embedded professional development opportunities for teachers that improve the teachers' environmental content knowledge and pedagogical skills in teaching about the environment, including in the use of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3164C9F9917540749F85833B8A43A3D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interdisciplinary, research-based, and field-based learning; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC497ACB2F1AF4B988CA935E6422DC86E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>technology in the classroom.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD484B81442048758BE2E09C7772A030"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establishing and operating environmental education summer workshops or institutes, including follow-up professional development, for elementary and secondary school teachers, and preschool teachers, as appropriate, to improve pedagogical skills and content knowledge for the teaching of environmental education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H942078C52CDA48DC98D8D16FEBE50A40"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Developing or redesigning more rigorous environmental education curricula that—</text> <subparagraph id="H1E05E06A07E44F918887EC693115CB7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are aligned with challenging State academic content standards in environmental education, to the extent such standards exist, and with the State environmental literacy plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CFBFA0523B74FDC8926C6B50FA57379"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advance the teaching of interdisciplinary courses that integrate the study of natural, social, and economic systems and that include strong field components.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB24592741C1A4EC99550D3C17D255E68"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Designing programs to prepare teachers at a school to provide mentoring and professional development to other teachers at such school to improve teacher environmental education content knowledge and pedagogical skills.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33CDA399A37E48FF8C087A5DEAF2CBA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Establishing and operating programs to bring teachers and students into contact with working professionals in environmental fields to deepen such teachers' knowledge of environmental content and research practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0636CA1C7CB401789AD47621AB5433E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Creating initiatives that seek to incorporate environmental education within teacher training programs or accreditation standards consistent with the State environmental literacy plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE667B82F8C884B12A1989DA41896267B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Promoting the integration of outdoor environmental education lessons into the regular school curriculum and schedule in order to further the knowledge and professional development of teachers and help students directly experience nature.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5689FAA5F03846309883EB6691DE4CB0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Evaluation and accountability plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H2BADFE642DBD40A9AAE1EE2188BCB0B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible partnership receiving a subgrant under this section shall develop an evaluation and accountability plan for activities assisted under this section that includes rigorous objectives that measure the impact of such activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDD6D1F8AC654C18BAF2C2EF392592CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The plan developed under paragraph (1) shall include measurable objectives to increase the number of teachers who participate in environmental education content-based professional development activities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AFD3A850DF84CAF8E1B24E5EAAFBC05"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report by eligible partnerships</header><text>Each eligible partnership receiving a subgrant under this section shall report annually, for each year of the subgrant, to the State educational agency regarding the eligible partnership's progress in meeting the objectives described in the accountability plan of the eligible partnership under subsection (i).</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HC6F46EC6B3C444529F994C5C62C303CA"><enum>5623.</enum><header>Environmental education grant program to help build national capacity</header>
 <subsection id="H33958CADEEF940F1AFC1BC781D11A941"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph id="H9CC21BA0B1394E8B880C0442F15DFFA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to strengthen environmental education as an integral part of the elementary school and secondary school curriculum; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3583B1290F540069C4B62C3EA175FD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to disseminate information about best practices and resources available to support environmental literacy programs.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A6907379779461AA94A5FB2ED28E78F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="HCF14AE0C750E4E50A4C9711AEBE410A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships to enable the eligible partnerships to pay the Federal share of the costs of activities under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5830A1F4A2B9421F9DB5F8F5E95982D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each grant under this section shall be for a period of not less than 1 year and not more than 3 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA26A6744B546422EAD6C04C6893AABE3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible partnerships that include a high-need local educational agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59781C0C026F497EB3314F0052DF5F0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible partnership desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application that contains—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8808E0785C4747FC86D5967BCE049367"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to initiate, expand, or improve environmental education programs in order to make progress toward—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5946393D157B49C8B1663BE44A187A0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>challenging State academic content standards and student academic achievement standards in environmental education, to the extent such standards exist; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEECEFF6827A9457C8EE0C4F04DC29DB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meeting academic standards that are aligned with the State's environmental literacy plan; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D52E4DF518545818F0470653AED92C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation and accountability plan for activities assisted under this section that includes rigorous objectives that measure the impact of activities funded under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83DC25EEF99447468FB4D9EE7D516069"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds made available under this section shall be used for 1 or more of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD2C2A2F552414A419C9E7385A4635E20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing and implementing State curriculum frameworks for environmental education that meet—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5577F32ACBD54D05B034530A2F9B8761"><enum>(A)</enum><text>challenging State academic content standards and student academic achievement standards for environmental education, to the extent such standards exist; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21F8108BB14543AFB1B83FE16C82D9CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>academic standards that are aligned with the State's environmental literacy plan under section 5622.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45FF8A3B24D94C5E9EB9FF94EDC142ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Replicating or disseminating information about proven and tested model environmental education programs that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0DA9AA0BFC8547AB8DAF57DA00E496CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use the environment as an integrating theme or content throughout the curriculum; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H195B14D2BF83483885E9BEB1FBA74C8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide integrated, interdisciplinary instruction about natural, social, and economic systems along with field experience that provides students with opportunities to directly experience nature in ways designed to improve students' overall academic performance, personal health (including addressing child obesity issues), and understanding of nature.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2918DA6DF367480699714953DC6F651D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Developing and implementing new approaches to advancing environmental education, and to advancing the adoption and use of environmental education content standards, at the State and local levels.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38C933EC916144C89CBDB7EBE91991F7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible partnership report</header><text>In order to continue receiving grant funds under this section after the first year of a multiyear grant under this section, the eligible partnership shall submit to the Secretary an annual report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDDE16B900C7440D691658CC78D051AED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the activities assisted under this section that were conducted during the preceding year;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8785FA8FAD4F4158A2D4E8F1582DB6C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrates that progress has been made in helping schools to meet the State academic standards for environmental education described in subsection (d)(3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C83DB574E540AC8AC3F277640E3F18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describes the results of the eligible partnership's evaluation and accountability plan.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE298DEA5F3FF46D7A90724BDCB856F0E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header> <paragraph id="H9B87C0DB1A0A4E88A96D12C612F55223"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of a grant under this section shall not exceed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9919BF9754BB4AE7B6B5FD2C6777FBAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>90 percent of the total costs of the activities assisted under the grant for the first year for which the program receives assistance under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F134A3959094D5381EE94BEDBB6E1A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>75 percent of such costs for each of the second and third years.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB64E09310AA4456BBF9A28C621D615EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Not more than 7.5 percent of the grant funds made available to an eligible partnership under this section for any fiscal year may be used for administrative expenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD23DAC0503A34614A1D5AE8B38FC4659"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Amounts made available to the Secretary to carry out this section shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3A0178769E24618A3118C373FC9A815"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, any other Federal, State, or local funds available for environmental education activities.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H269B930D52004F3A91028EBBD6D8034F"><enum>5624.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>No Child Left Inside Act of 2015</short-title> and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H463107DB5CE44E5E8F4531D33372AE3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the programs assisted under this subpart;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD48371EEA309461AB432B973413526A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>documents the success of such programs in improving national and State environmental education capacity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A7A908797EE41A7B2788E4A35C4570A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>makes such recommendations as the Secretary determines appropriate for the continuation and improvement of the programs assisted under this subpart.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="H2BF404C4A33E4787AD3EBDB8C1F5117C"><enum>5625.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="H506A369132164C94B27B367F1F8D04C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subpart such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2016 and each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5E6125A07E9A4CD6B26E2EC410185466"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>With respect to any amount appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall use—</text>
 <paragraph id="H91D22C575076421B8BE920AE0882770F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than 70 percent of such amount to carry out section 5622; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC343CB59BB4F4684864DE128A5A87D1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 30 percent of such amount to carry out section 5623 for such fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="H4469AA2603F944009F7F382F3D262B2C"><enum>102.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subsection id="H1AF3EB7660DC4BC7AAD298692B10CC2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Section 5401 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7241">20 U.S.C. 7241</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>(except for subpart 22)</quote> after <quote>this part</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HA70AA1773AED47099B2C846FE746E4CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5618 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HE841B9DB1C9D4CB7B46E232A96585E84" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="HA4AEC5ACD00B49A99718BFBC7680CAB6" level="subpart">SUBPART 22—Environmental literacy</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HE09CCBC7BAD04723B93176E2BA33ECEB" level="section">Sec. 5621. Definitions.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H5B6B213D80E241F8A44BDBBD2977031A" level="section">Sec. 5622. Grants for implementation of environmental literacy plans.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HC6F46EC6B3C444529F994C5C62C303CA" level="section">Sec. 5623. Environmental education grant program to help build national capacity.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H269B930D52004F3A91028EBBD6D8034F" level="section">Sec. 5624. Report to Congress.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H2BF404C4A33E4787AD3EBDB8C1F5117C" level="section">Sec. 5625. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H4C1788E6AC484AA8A7B6C34401EC614B"><enum>II</enum><header>Promoting environmental literacy in education programs</header>
			<section id="H6BD1A5D2D5BA4CAF8DBB85CB10049A21"><enum>201.</enum><header>Amendments to part B of title II</header>
 <subsection id="H0E977C301D8D4F619FF6A673151A6BFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2201(b)(1)(B) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6661">20 U.S.C. 6661(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0C0B0BA4692A48728105E30F948E85BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iii), by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E56AB27FFF044C492804F19014353B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iv), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H43A01850748E47259774C6845BEB90CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD13AEC111C9477E9C1F5FE053BB2A6E" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H0F1D5BF3F98E4F488DF8FB248DD662B3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a Federal, State, regional, or local science, environmental, or natural resource management agency or a nonprofit environmental education organization that has demonstrated effectiveness in improving the quality of mathematics and science instruction.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEF1EE7FE88D4CB3A3D3E709DC772F49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>Section 2202 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6662">20 U.S.C. 6662</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H977642F0C7434DC7BF29532E418C03A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(B), by inserting <quote>, including any State environmental literacy plan described in section 5621,</quote> after <quote>reform activities</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08AAF4EB17AD41F69CC70C3FEE1A7F55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB39882BFE7BB404DA541D48BDCFFE079" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HFD1D9DFD2EAD46EB9D269D02C199E417"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Professional development in the use of field-based or service learning to enable teachers—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB10A6B4A91204503AA0AF6ABC479E7FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to use the local environment and community as a resource; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6BA62C1D6034527B0169C6C61B08AF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enhance student understanding of mathematics and science through environmental education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAC9CDBF70E4A44F3AE7FF8BB6550F5C4"><enum>202.</enum><header>Amendments to part B of title IV</header>
 <subsection id="HD1A7C64A0132430C877E03A8701352DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 4201(b)(1)(A) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7171">20 U.S.C. 7171(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>environmental literacy,</quote> after <quote>technology,</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H1D3FD8FC274848FA9E0913B5644DA27F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Local activities</header><text>Section 4205(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7175">20 U.S.C. 7175(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H96B61639F6964E4388CFEA1A6B63D33C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (12) as paragraphs (5) through (13), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A90655F7BBF47568A69883832C37952"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85844E33F8CD4D75A636D03A2279FBA6" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H7F3517B65EE145F0AE6D094665DCB783"><enum>(4)</enum><text>environmental literacy activities;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HFABE84AEEBA04CE3A344640191738AD6"><enum>III</enum><header>National activities</header> <section commented="no" id="H208B1E039C864B1386B78DAD2FB96B31"><enum>301.</enum><header>Availability of other environmental literacy information</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HBC20680FFF9C4A9EB4147EE04D1150B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Other Federal agency environmental literacy assistance programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall request that all Federal agencies provide information on any environmental literacy assistance program operated, sponsored, or supported by such Federal agency, including information about the application procedures, financial terms and conditions, and other relevant information for each program, and each Federal agency shall promptly respond to surveys or other requests from the Secretary of Education for the information described in this subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6EF7DCC8EE0D45839327C5813CA90A3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public Information</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall ensure that not later than 90 days after the Secretary of Education receives the information required under subsection (a), the eligibility requirements, application procedures, financial terms and conditions, and other relevant information for each environmental literacy assistance program offered by another Federal agency are searchable and accessible through the Department of Education’s website and cross-referenced with the United States Green Ribbon School application information, in a manner that is simple and understandable for local educational agencies and communities.</text>
				</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HDF94649DDF984A138901FAA4D46B9977"><enum>302.</enum><header>Federal interagency coordination on environmental literacy</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HD3ABDC685CAE4A1791A1FAD4403B58A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall coordinate environmental literacy activities between the Department of Education, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Commerce, including by carrying out the activities described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE0A0AB600F6A420BB210E9D65DD47C00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination activities</header><text>In coordinating environmental literacy activities, the Secretary of Education shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HAF3C04633E224A16A82800FFC366DC64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess current Federal environmental education programs, goals, and budget items across agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H431C60F5A85344C0A7ABA06D7D08525D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess environment-based science, technology, engineering, and mathematics achievement to demonstrate that learning about and in the environment is an effective strategy for increasing engagement in learning and academic achievement in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subject areas; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H324D415BC68B4B1688AD887C70C38177"><enum>(3)</enum><text>produce adaptable environmental literacy plan guidelines and identify coordinated resources across Federal agencies that States and local educational agencies can follow as States and local educational agencies work to develop environmental literacy plans and programs of their own.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H558B7B865C8B4A758E4BB9689F95C6F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advisory Panel</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall appoint an advisory panel of stakeholders, including representatives from State educational agencies, local educational agencies, businesses, and nonprofit organizations that are engaged in local environmental literacy efforts representing the geographic, economic, and cultural diversity of the United States, who shall meet quarterly to advise and support interagency planning and assessment regarding environmental literacy activities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H096BC04DCDA748E1AB84639A60486803"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Education, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Commerce shall prepare and submit a joint report to Congress containing information about the coordination of environmental literacy activities between Federal agencies.</text>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


