<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFCAEF045C5694BF7B19B304BA5E13D52" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3029 IH: Reducing the Effects of the Cyberattack on OPM Victims Emergency Response Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3029</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150710">July 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Office of Personnel Management to provide complimentary, comprehensive identity
			 protection coverage to all individuals whose personally identifiable
			 information was compromised during recent data breaches at Federal
			 agencies.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H159067785AEB4B28AFC0FB929F0CFD10" style="OLC">
 <section id="H639634A8BB3B411AA38C4965B48DC2C2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing the Effects of the Cyberattack on OPM Victims Emergency Response Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RECOVER Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4DE1E0B7611E44CDB43758F4414C1293"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identity protection coverage for individuals affected by Federal agency data breaches</header> <subsection id="H9501E3674EE248708654CE5804622A26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>affected individual</quote> means any individual whose personally identifiable information was compromised during—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF405EBD57B034123BECDCB50D633A296"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the data breach of personnel records of current and former Federal employees, at a network maintained by the Department of the Interior, that was announced by the Office of Personnel Management on June 4, 2015; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H440B805059A045338EDB369C250BB07F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the data breach of systems of the Office of Personnel Management containing information related to the background investigations of current, former, and prospective Federal employees, and of other individuals.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85EA60BCADC44925942D341D4AF393F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identity protection coverage</header><text>The Office of Personnel Management shall provide to each affected individual complimentary identity protection coverage that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H121D117F1DC744E9A06A646C9922FD07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not less comprehensive than the complimentary identity protection coverage that the Office provided to affected individuals before the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AD4D007300047D2828DD4D7E0371EBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is effective for the remainder of the life of the individual; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H43441CCA5524483C88646A585FE936B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes not less than $5,000,000 in identity theft insurance.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


