<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H018C307AC382490491EC951CFA34127F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2529 IH: Reducing food-based Inorganic Compounds Exposure Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2529</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish limitations on the quantity of inorganic arsenic in rice and rice products under chapter IV of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC84FB17D74A341009EC635B46ABB2D3E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3B55E345AD72481793F8E8E1D5638793" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing food-based Inorganic Compounds Exposure Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RICE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1204434A0B214548AE8A72FD65B06D23"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H98566733F6A54D9C860DF5A6AE47DD13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the World Health Organization, arsenic is a natural component of the Earth’s crust and is widely and variably distributed throughout the environment in the air, water, and land. It is also used commercially in herbicides and poultry feed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8703C14E077D4A67A70225502D3F01FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Arsenic is most toxic in its inorganic form.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE13261789E14B77B50A8661F965FA35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Inorganic arsenic is a known carcinogen and long-term oral exposure to high levels of inorganic arsenic is associated with developmental defects, cardiovascular disease, neurotoxicity, and diabetes, according to the World Health Organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BB674ED7A404CF8A331A1B4B923368B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the European Food Safety Authority, the estimated exposure of young children to inorganic arsenic is 2 to 3 times the exposure of adults to inorganic arsenic.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1DF15B96369145CBAA888663374F719D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to the European Food Safety Authority, diet is the main source of arsenic exposure for most individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EA5413AB7464B239A43D5A6B915C049"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Food and Drug Administration, due to absorption from the soil and water, arsenic is present in many foods, including grains, fruits, and vegetables.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B0645272961421C8BF6BC6F8270C3DB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Rice takes up inorganic arsenic from soil and water more readily than other grains, according to the Food and Drug Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1605791A8D045719F3FB5D355BAC32F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Rice is a staple food in the diet of many individuals in the United States and is often one of the first foods fed to infants. According to the Food and Drug Administration, inorganic arsenic has been detected in an infant’s first foods, such as infant rice cereal and brown rice syrup used in an increasing number of products including toddler formula and snack bars. Inorganic arsenic is also found in other rice products including children’s breakfast cereals and rice itself. Rice may continue to be a large part of the diet of children who have swallowing difficulties and gastrointestinal reflux, according to the American Academy of Pediatrics.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E3A7A3204484B08BAACBD3C9D97C28C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Food and Drug Administration’s analysis of approximately 1,300 samples found that the average levels of inorganic arsenic for various rice and rice products are 0.1 to 7.2 micrograms per serving.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC7454BC27054712875B4AA1AB38DECC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Environmental Protection Agency limits concentrations of arsenic in all forms in drinking water to 10 parts per billion. The Food and Drug Administration has established a limit of 10 parts per billion in bottled water, and has also proposed a limit of 10 parts per billion in apple juice. However, there are no Federal limits for arsenic in most foods, including rice for adults and children or baby foods.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0F7DB556ADCE4E6F9C0875686E6FFE80"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of limitation on inorganic arsenic in rice and rice products</header> 
<subsection id="H867581E793B44C05A97D6D159430777A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of protecting the public health, not later than the day that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and acting under the Secretary’s authority under chapter IV of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/341">21 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>), shall promulgate a final regulation establishing the minimum quantity of inorganic arsenic contained in rice or a rice product which shall cause the rice or rice product, respectively, to be deemed to be adulterated under section 402 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H34E3E9C81B5242059C0024250E59FA97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope of regulation</header><text>The minimum quantity established under subsection (a) shall apply to rice and rice products containing inorganic arsenic regardless of whether the arsenic is present as a result of a natural process, an ingredient added to a food, the use of a pesticide, or other means.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA2549F2A6EFF446E94D958BD25DDBF21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulation includes tolerances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulation under subsection (a) shall include the establishment of a tolerance under section 406 and section 408 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/346">21 U.S.C. 346</external-xref>; 346a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4DD0C0BCBE964D1EA0E93C96EDD7A730"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Minimum stringency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standard established under subsection (a) (and any subsequent revision thereto) for inorganic arsenic contained in rice or a rice product shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H14F2FE5E07754C85AB4CC0C125F4E4F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be based on the maximum achievable reduction in health risks to individuals, taking into account the cancer effects, neurodevelopmental effects, and other health effects of arsenic exposure;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C115CD3684141DB85841538C4BE0591"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be protective of the long-term health of children, taking into account—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H768001075D7E47398AB769A80DE5E9ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the differing eating patterns of children;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EEA29947A1A42F7838A62F5CCAD17C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the rate of brain development in children;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAFB4ABB3F2AF44779F74A5A1921A9D79"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any differences in the metabolization of arsenic in children, as compared to adults; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H55E3E90F9C8546F39CCD08502DA7164E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the fact that children have a longer expected life span than adults; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE47B4251A79846EEACC0A1D49E807DC9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include separate standards for rice milk and other frequently consumed rice-based foods, especially rice-based foods frequently consumed by infants and children.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEB3C0F624A4C4FB98F40A7ED321BCD38"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0A81367ED46844FFAB04C01E68E6F013"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Food</header><text>The term <term>food</term> has the meaning given such term in section 201(f) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0F60BA38B6E4460926BBF13B4B9308C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inorganic arsenic</header><text>The term <term>inorganic arsenic</term> means inorganic arsenic and its metabolites.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7993646783954E3086F27790D44F36B2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rice</header><text>The term <term>rice</term> means a food that is rice.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9ACA2A69FE644EFAB3960BB2447902A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rice product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rice product</term> means a food that contains an ingredient made from rice.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF47EC22644934BE4827E13D8B8449BE5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on inorganic arsenic in rice</header> 
<subsection id="H756742CF75C0458D82E807BFDDE88B83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to the Congress on inorganic arsenic in rice grown in the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5603D77DB9444659A50CA38877F8FECB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3EEAD53FB79D4CFEA255478B14041539"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of—</text> <subparagraph id="HDF25136183C644A888E7F2C4A06198C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agronomy and production management practices that will reduce inorganic arsenic in rice;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC03B8A1178154500B6A9BCDA2D679122"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the germplasm analysis and breeding that may reduce inorganic arsenic in rice; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F0F7E9741E24D6F9BBB2DD5DDFC75C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the analytical technology improvements needed to address the issue of inorganic arsenic in rice; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H655AA0E3F610404DA91FBF147F753667"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the current efforts of Federal agencies to reduce inorganic arsenic in the food supply;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B8D00D351B947198413F19278BFD714"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for actions by the Federal Government in order to reduce the presence of inorganic arsenic in rice grown in the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F9A61045B984669934F6AA16C060A2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for additional research on inorganic arsenic in rice, including the estimated cost for such research.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

