<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB3989F021FF14A2A94F460AFB30DF8B6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 874 IH: American Super Computing Leadership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 874</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150211">February 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Department of Energy High-End Computing Revitalization Act of 2004 to improve the
			 high-end computing research and development program of the Department of
			 Energy, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4B49421259E74A66B80C1373FA6546C1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7CDCF7FC5B344656853CC170BC17A146" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Super Computing Leadership Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA9577E07F2934E5DA0D6E7B06EF52583"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of the Department of Energy High-End Computing Revitalization Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/5541">15 U.S.C. 5541</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraphs (1) through (5) and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HE702C15E4EB14D3F87D3D4154415DC72">
 <paragraph id="H027AE613A96E4FB68462EBDCEDDDB39B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Co-design</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>co-design</term> means the joint development of application algorithms, models, and codes with computer technology architectures and operating systems to maximize effective use of high-end computing systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H298D98FBC9674A24BF6AABA7D713F566"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Energy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA318ED311D2F4A36B2AEAB769B041826"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exascale</header><text>The term <term>exascale</term> means computing system performance at or near 10 to the 18th power floating point operations per second.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97F7A1D47ACF48B982C32F0B565B13FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-end computing system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high-end computing system</term> means a computing system with performance that substantially exceeds that of systems that are commonly available for advanced scientific and engineering applications.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H378E7DA3597C4C94867A40F1454BC8B4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H53639D9946DE47218B996EFE19453EE2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Leadership system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>leadership system</quote> means a high-end computing system that is among the most advanced in the world in terms of performance in solving scientific and engineering problems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEBED3405BB847A6B31CC33C0C7B2C0D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>National laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> means any one of the seventeen laboratories owned by the Department.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD38090D06B64BA79AAB9DD3F361B589"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE010B47B5904D4D94027BA14E719C12"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Software technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>software technology</term> includes optimal algorithms, programming environments, tools, languages, and operating systems for high-end computing systems.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HE8BD31A7A2BC4EE386C93F257B846944"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Energy high-end computing research and development program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Department of Energy High-End Computing Revitalization Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/5542">15 U.S.C. 5542</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H72AFFE5AAB6F43D48E7D6DAFD986F417"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFBBDE901F8B0498CAA7CA523892DD632"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>program</quote> and inserting <quote>coordinated program across the Department</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94B43411A2704A828C1F1B74EEA16F30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H989AC15A3E2E44EEB9F3BD664CE0B01D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (2) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69895FBDB605467CBC01CFCE5E30F6D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA4533C86C6F431C92C481153579AE46" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC28A27C7E2BD4FCC848CAD46B0E0ACC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partner with universities, National Laboratories, and industry to ensure the broadest possible application of the technology developed in this program to other challenges in science, engineering, medicine, and industry.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF10A508DBE7249F9B2DB3049D303CD08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>vector</quote> and all that follows through <quote>architectures</quote> and inserting <quote>computer technologies that show promise of substantial reductions in power requirements and substantial gains in parallelism of multicore processors, concurrency, memory and storage, bandwidth, and reliability</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEBBA224CF4F4430A3E2DE1EDF2B5623"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H9671F53AC92646398ADA3BEA28144BFF" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H0228E0FF2E28436F8C0B3CC80434FDB9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exascale computing program</header> <paragraph id="H41ED4223AD4040C28FF45FFC596C184B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a coordinated research program to develop exascale computing systems to advance the missions of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H515EE71A8D0D463BBE50DA3B503C661B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Execution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, through competitive merit review, establish two or more National Laboratory-industry-university partnerships to conduct integrated research, development, and engineering of multiple exascale architectures, and—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF93C0232D15342A3A4650B5C70A60588"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct mission-related co-design activities in developing such exascale platforms;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BB36886AEEA42739A98BBB396D1CF93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop those advancements in hardware and software technology required to fully realize the potential of an exascale production system in addressing Department target applications and solving scientific problems involving predictive modeling and simulation and large-scale data analytics and management; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD137F2452EAF4E0085121583B4CB9F76"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">explore the use of exascale computing technologies to advance a broad range of science and engineering.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F92EA4797D9468CB8629B6368DC4BE5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>In carrying out this program, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H20324833020A4F929715744FAB6AD339"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide, on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, access for researchers in United States industry, institutions of higher education, National Laboratories, and other Federal agencies to these exascale systems, as appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F02740C9ABE451998DC6E3AE2B836AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct outreach programs to increase the readiness for the use of such platforms by domestic industries, including manufacturers.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H254CBDD5CCEB4EC3B876387FB7E83699"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE28FF719B67C4FC8BD24C64F60678226"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Integrated strategy and program management plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to Congress, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>American Super Computing Leadership Act</short-title>, a report outlining an integrated strategy and program management plan, including target dates for prototypical and production exascale platforms, interim milestones to reaching these targets, functional requirements, roles and responsibilities of National Laboratories and industry, acquisition strategy, and estimated resources required, to achieve this exascale system capability. The report shall include the Secretary's plan for Departmental organization to manage and execute the Exascale Computing Program, including definition of the roles and responsibilities within the Department to ensure an integrated program across the Department. The report shall also include a plan for ensuring balance and prioritizing across ASCR subprograms in a flat or slow-growth budget environment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DCC5F68E91148F7848A51ABD6174AF0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Status reports</header><text>At the time of the budget submission of the Department for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that describes the status of milestones and costs in achieving the objectives of the exascale computing program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04DFFFD657EC49FAB8FC87E9BA99D248"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exascale merit report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 18 months prior to the initiation of construction or installation of any exascale-class computing facility, the Secretary shall transmit a plan to the Congress detailing—</text>
 <clause id="HB922748515D344DC8A41326825DA163E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proposed facility's cost projections and capabilities to significantly accelerate the development of new energy technologies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H84C2C76B00504EED8DD0A31F51A35FB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>technical risks and challenges that must be overcome to achieve successful completion and operation of the facility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF61EA550809742189494EAFE69001383"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an independent assessment of the scientific and technological advances expected from such a facility relative to those expected from a comparable investment in expanded research and applications at terascale-class and petascale-class computing facilities, including an evaluation of where investments should be made in the system software and algorithms to enable these advances.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


