<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9D351E2F6DC442AC9BF8B7ADBA1DEC8A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3070 IH: EEZ Clarification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3070</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150715">July 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To clarify that for purposes of all Federal laws governing marine fisheries management, the
			 landward boundary of the exclusive economic zone between areas south of
			 Montauk, New York, and Point Judith, Rhode Island, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H58DE1A59806546BCBC159E7D347A0BF5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBAFA73E0B9B746BAB8F11FCA3D31BCDD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>EEZ Clarification Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7B617ACCC3A54CCB8733F1C693D14865" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Landward boundary of EEZ near Block Island for purposes of Federal marine fisheries management</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of all Federal laws governing marine fisheries management—</text>
 <paragraph id="H921B95F3614345E4839EB330BF392A27"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the landward boundary of the exclusive economic zone between the area south of Montauk, New York, and the area south of Point Judith, Rhode Island, shall be considered to be a continuous line running—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFA2D9EB4F9A94153BD8AC3612663E895"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from a point 3 miles south of the southernmost point of Montauk to a point 3 miles south of the southernmost point of Block Island, Rhode Island, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EC50270377B43A8A826ED742758F41E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from such point 3 miles south of the southernmost point of Block Island, Rhode Island, to a point 3 miles south of the southern most point of Point Judith; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDE8E89894A74DA2AD88EFC787CE3162"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authority to manage such fisheries in waters landward of such line is vested in States and interstate marine fisheries management commissions, as applicable, that otherwise have jurisdiction over such waters.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H603C6DDD4554414688840ED69E551364"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on impact of modifying landward boundary of EEZ for all Federal fisheries management</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall report to the Congress on the impact of section 2.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


