<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCE03B0A970E74579A2B1AF050DD7BB1C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3818 IH: Ending Special National Origin-Based Immigration Programs for Cubans Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3818</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151023">October 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To repeal the Cuban Adjustment Act, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/89/732">Public Law 89–732</external-xref>, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6ACCF1063BFB44829934F087D0CB52E8" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB2B4BDB1A06C4576ADF2D1A0D238F0BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Special National Origin-Based Immigration Programs for Cubans Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H443795FBCC824829AA6BC20A617E8EDE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="HF34A1AC6CFCA46E0B504EE32DB9A0CF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H567BA7C9DA78458499AE450AC4FCB0A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 1, 2015, President Obama announced that Cuba and the United States would reopen their embassies and restore diplomatic ties.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49BBD50145074BA38D2D2C3EAE1FE7DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Diplomatic relations between the two countries were formally reestablished July 20, 2015, when the United States and Cuba reopened their respective embassies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H621A34D0FA73454FB02AB81A9EE7C9D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The International Business Times reported on September 10, 2015, that <quote>Texas is on pace this year to set a new record for the number of Cubans trying to enter the United States through the Lone Star State, with about 60 percent more migrants from the island nation making the trip in 2015 compared to one year before.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9F7284B524D4910BABACE9174B5B3B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Obama Administration has reestablished relations with Cuba, and that, therefore, the special treatment Cuban nationals receive under the Cuban Adjustment Act, the Immigration and Nationality Act, the Cuban Family Reunification Program and the Wet Foot/Dry Foot policy are no longer applicable and fail the <quote>urgent humanitarian reasons</quote> and <quote>significant public benefit</quote> tests.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28A9C60DC60E4ABBA2109281B33391F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that Cuban nationals should be treated under the same immigration rules as nationals of other countries with which the United States has diplomatic relations and should not receive preferential treatment.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB2842042E70E427E84B0123662448CAF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of the Cuban Adjustment Act</header>
			<subsection id="H9B61905E72EC41579C88049D87B200D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeals of relevant statutes</header>
 <paragraph id="H6A05A9F206A04F77A52EAD90A5CF1BA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeal of limitation on repeal of Cuban Adjustment Act</header><text>Section 606 of title VI of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref> is repealed.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E30CFC33E4F42C4A5FE22FD6E88E4FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cuban Adjustment Act</header><text>Public Law 89–732 is repealed.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC29107B804114BFAB64E22DCF52FF1CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The repeal made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply only to any alien admitted or paroled into the United States on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3BAD82F3A03143DDB816E39446341514"><enum>4.</enum><header>Certain activities restricted</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds, resources, or fees made available to the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, or to any other official of a Federal agency, by this Act or any other Act for any fiscal year, including any deposits into the <quote>Immigration Examinations Fee Account</quote> established under section 286(m) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(m)</external-xref>), may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out (including through the issuance of any regulations) any of the policy changes set forth in the memorandum from the Director of United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement entitled <quote>Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program</quote> dated November 21, 2007 (or any substantially similar policy changes, whether set forth in memorandum, Executive order, regulation, directive, or by other action).</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


