<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BF4A911955A49808897425B387401F7" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1697 IH: Electric Charging And Refueling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1697</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend and modify the tax credit for electric vehicle recharging property.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H04ED453ED404429ABFDAF5E96DACF561" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5049CF94EB674F6C9326BD43E67751DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Electric Charging And Refueling Act</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>E–Car Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1905C21AC86F478F866526F827FE067E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension and modification of credit for electric car recharging property</header> <subsection id="H1991825D100744FCB4088E7A9D8E299F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/30C">Section 30C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC398702CD44D4D0AA3ADCA126217362B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF92277E4F5634A88B3607152C07FEF65"><enum>30C.</enum><header>Electric vehicle charging and refueling property credit</header> 
<subsection id="H161E3F56D94F48979522DBEACA34154D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Credit allowed</header><text>There shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to 50 percent of the cost of any qualified electric vehicle recharging or refueling property placed in service by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7386D53A55104F3596966AC59AD62311"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The credit allowed under subsection (a) with respect to all qualified electric vehicle recharging property placed in service by the taxpayer during the taxable year at a location shall not exceed—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8E6A18B5DAC247F9AC750F5E96A36C34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a property of a character subject to an allowance for depreciation, the greater of—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E290CEC826B4C7F896C381DCEC14127"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$100,000, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H041B838B13C843998231D8D3FC947291"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$10,000 multiplied by the number of devices placed in service at the location by the taxpayer during the taxable year, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76A7B0640FAE4D87B50EC91DF0AE05FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$2,000 in any other case.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F65737A5DA94A309E5A44E8D10F30F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H52D0BEC97AEF4DCE972F31916E30F96E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified electric vehicle recharging or refueling property</header><text>The term <term>qualified electric vehicle recharging property</term> means any property (not including a building) if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5955D1EF87C54FBA9F512D203FCCDA52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such property is—</text> <clause id="HBF41038936014FC2A7BEDA7F94B62C20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2FD1B5DBA1704B418AB336F9699E025E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>installed on property which is used as the principal residence (within the meaning of section 121) of the taxpayer,</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCA9DB0487F149AAB28BF68288C09460"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the original use of such property begins with the taxpayer,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8398A95C89CC4C2688EA27967E9526BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such property is for the recharging or refueling of motor vehicles propelled by electricity, including property providing electricity for plug-in electric drive vehicles and property providing hydrogen for fuel cell electric vehicles, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF10F33FC167C4B14AA81CF9F19C32337"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such property includes related property providing electricity for such recharging or is otherwise necessary for such recharging or refueling property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H673F4535D1334EA98A65FD0C595BD3B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Device</header><text>The term <term>device</term> means an individual item of property, whether a stand-alone item or part of property that includes multiple devices, which functions to recharge one vehicle at a time.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H57848746A24745B594A9D082D8F6B6A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application with other credits</header> <paragraph id="HCAF4A3290AB743F980CB0011705886D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business credit treated as part of general business credit</header><text>So much of the credit which would be allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined without regard to this subsection) that is attributable to property of a character subject to an allowance for depreciation shall be treated as a credit listed in section 38(b) for such taxable year (and not allowed under subsection (a)).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7C73EEFF91F4ACDBCAB06BCC54158B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personal credit</header><text>For purposes of this title, the credit allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (after the application of paragraph (1))—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2380F6C2B614075A509F0CB406FEA16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be treated as a credit allowable under subpart A for such taxable year, and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H42B809EA97554F88B6CF7F49BF513CFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not exceed the excess of—</text> <clause id="H4F40176C3D2C41488533EDB882444A10"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sum of the regular tax liability (as defined in section 26(b)) plus the tax imposed by section 55, over</text></clause>
<clause id="H677012BC8D244C07B21AB7625FA82ACB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sum of the credits allowable under subpart A (other than this section and sections 25D and 30D) and section 27 for the taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H458768A747BC4DA5A10EC2F451357717"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H72821829491241D8A85005589D6A3F05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reduction in basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subtitle, the basis of any property for which a credit is allowable under subsection (a) shall be reduced by the amount of such credit so allowed (determined without regard to subsection (d)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50C651B890EF4D2EBA0D9A95B226ACB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Property used by tax-exempt entity</header><text>In the case of any qualified electric vehicle recharging property the use of which is described in paragraph (3) or (4) of section 50(b) (including use by an Indian tribal government) and which is not subject to a lease, the person who sold such property to the person or entity using such property shall be treated as the taxpayer that placed such property in service, but only if such person clearly discloses to such person or entity in a document the amount of any credit allowable under subsection (a) with respect to such property (determined without regard to subsection (d)).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB15CC10972C4B7D84EDE746E9B8576C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Property used outside United States not qualified</header><text>No credit shall be allowable under subsection (a) with respect to any property referred to in section 50(b)(1) or with respect to the portion of the cost of any property taken into account under section 179.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C1DDDA87738437DAC9B85CEC5F26128"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Election not to take credit</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) for any property if the taxpayer elects not to have this section apply to such property.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2385E78FFE45453B98B90C3443298CAA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recapture rules</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 179A(e)(4) shall apply.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED992D67C820497BB6BF01329173F44C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Joint ownership of qualified electric vehicle recharging property</header> <subparagraph id="H1D64871A49734786A1AE6E4C4BD068D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any qualified electric vehicle recharging property shall not fail to be treated as such property solely because such property is placed in service with respect to 2 or more dwelling units.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H479DF0C2AC8346859C1535605FDBECB9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limits applied separately</header><text>In the case of any qualified electric vehicle recharging property which is placed in service with respect to 2 or more dwelling units, this section (other than this subparagraph) shall be applied separately with respect to the portion of such property attributable to each such dwelling unit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H24FB6BB651014101889D1AD8E5F277F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Clause (ii) of section 30D(c)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 25D</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 25D and 30C</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDE68AE9B226041DC8566B3B56331C49D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<paragraph id="HA113188396FA44E2B32AD1627FD56CB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to property placed in service after December 31, 2013.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91AEB55CCF6F4889BEFEFCEC89CA21E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hydrogen refueling property</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to hydrogen property placed in service after December 31, 2014.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

