<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H13A20E48ADA64467B29BF520959E428F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3286 IH: HIRE Vets Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3286</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To encourage effective, voluntary private sector investments to recruit, employ, and retain men and
			 women who have served in the United States military with annual
			 presidential awards to private sector employers recognizing such efforts,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA9DD6735B19A4A80A50098069519BAD0" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFBC84597676A4F5DAFDD5C7FAF46A2D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Honoring Investments in Recruiting and Employing American Military Veterans Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>HIRE Vets Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD279DB31818E4CD580391FD137AA5C2F"><enum>2.</enum><header>HIRE Vets Medallion program</header> <subsection id="H80A7CA5A0DE34F3A82D0EC2E6F1F4863"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program Established</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall establish, by rule, a HIRE Vets Medallion Program to solicit voluntary information from employers for purposes of recognizing, by means of an award to be designated a <quote>HIRE Vets Medallion</quote>, verified efforts by such employers—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4FE16FB6BD4A4086856950E8E66F1516"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to recruit, employ, and retain veterans; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H537A10B33E6248CD974152F6C66D06FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide community and charitable services supporting the veteran community.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B179CA6CC034A3380D779F784768F75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in the calendar year following the calendar year in which the Secretary establishes the program—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA1F24F6ED6474C82BE8DC8D58AB343C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary shall annually—</text> <subparagraph id="H716C21EFCD5C466B8A280A67F6503D69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicit and accept voluntary applications from employers in order to consider whether those employers should receive a HIRE Vets Medallion;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9B4848C9E254D7A8FAE948CFFEFB25F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review applications received in each calendar year; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF67521E6046D41B1BC9D6B28D3643158"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide to the President a list of recipients; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H027B0B8BDD794CCBBDF5CC9B5B295391"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President shall annually—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8C0C14298834446B4EEC526B31CF4A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify such recipients of their awards; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD80CBFB494424ED595F6F876A054E439"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at a time to coincide with the annual commemoration of Veterans Day—</text> <clause id="H23DBA339334847E5B765802911D8024A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>announce the names of such recipients;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H23091F8063D447EDB8B97AFEA5BBEF1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recognize such recipients through publication in the Federal Register; and</text> </clause><clause id="H72A387879DB54BF8B1C19A6E785C8E3A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>issue to each such recipient—</text>
 <subclause id="H6A4CCFAC0B564483BAA18156E6E70FD9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a HIRE Vets Medallion of the level determined under section 3; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC6E3D9B74C634468B31F92D61751C528"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certificate stating that such employer is entitled to display such HIRE Vets Medallion during the following calendar year, to be designated a <quote>HIRE Vets Medallion Certificate</quote>.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1512E9C3670D404AB499A42786BE61A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing</header>
 <paragraph id="HFA2BEC8ADBB8492FBBA64E24143458B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Solicitation period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall solicit applications not later than January 31st of each calendar year for the medallions to be awarded in November of that calendar year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE6FE9A1FC945459E082324905705C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>End of acceptance period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall stop accepting applications not earlier than April 30th of each calendar year for the medallions to be awarded in November of that calendar year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B8B1F3C369C45248371B3A2219F6323"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall finish reviewing applications not later than August 31st of each calendar year for the medallions to be awarded in November of that calendar year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAB80129DA954CAB9883066FB8450282"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recommendations to President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to the President a list of employers to receive HIRE Vets Medallions not later than September 30th of each calendar year for the medallions to be awarded in November of that calendar year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5ACAAD0C49FA40F6B3C8D357E075266B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notice to recipients</header><text>The President shall notify employers who will receive HIRE Vets Medallions not later than October 11th of each calendar year for the medallions to be awarded in November of that calendar year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC3F611B6E1E547D69E160969A3C95680"><enum>3.</enum><header>Selection of recipients</header>
			<subsection id="H7D4302CDE3324A428CDC8D5A56CDA39B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application review process</header>
 <paragraph id="HD3435FDB065442D599632A962198D532"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall review all applications received in a calendar year to determine whether an employer should receive a HIRE Vets Medallion, and, if so, of what level.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H868793CEE10C4D91B7F67C6642531585"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require that all applications provide information on the programs and other efforts of applicant employers during the calendar year prior to that in which the medallion is to be awarded, including the categories and activities governing the level of award for which the applicant is eligible under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2856712EC34D432FA0AC78E333CF6D72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>In reviewing applications, the Secretary shall verify all information provided in the applications, to the extent that such information is relevant in determining whether or not an applicant should receive a HIRE Vets Medallion or in determining the appropriate level of HIRE Vets Medallion for that employer to receive.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03152B8198B44AF1A011F1D66B595214"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards</header>
				<paragraph id="HB8B3DC37A00B4828B28EED6F2A90AA36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Large employers</header>
 <subparagraph id="H79A01CF7F5F14881A0F4A2F8B491D19F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish four levels of HIRE Vets Medallions to be awarded to employers employing 500 or more employees, to be designated the <quote>Bronze HIRE Vets Medallion</quote>, the <quote>Silver HIRE Vets Medallion</quote>, the <quote>Gold HIRE Vets Medallion</quote>, and the <quote>Platinum HIRE Vets Medallion</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5E8B43D839D4F579944BA1B10753A3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Bronze HIRE Vets Medallion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No employer shall be eligible to receive a Bronze HIRE Vets Medallion in a given calendar year unless—</text>
 <clause id="H7408D3EDDDA1406AB1CC9149C8AEDC35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such employer has hired a veteran during the previous calendar year;</text> </clause><clause id="H3F43A20CABAC485B8835FD2A444F644C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such employer provides support to each of its employees who are performing active duty service in the United States National Guard or Reserve, including by providing to each such employee a guarantee of employment following such employee’s active duty service; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H96E71D9C3E9F4CFB8945908A340BD04E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such employer provides charitable resources in support of veteran support organizations.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB445564010524C44AB9F4857F9B425DB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Silver HIRE Vets Medallion</header><text>No employer shall be eligible to receive a Silver HIRE Vets Medallion in a given calendar year unless—</text>
 <clause id="H6F443C0CB9824FBFA77FBDEBBA76A0C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such employer is eligible to receive a Bronze HIRE Vets Medallion in such year;</text> </clause><clause id="HBC2D714EF4644FA39F8FBBC4064432BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>veterans constitute not less than 5 percent of all employees hired by such employer during the prior calendar year;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE9959C7913554A8BB8E9A206E8E7B5AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such employer retains through the end of the prior calendar year not less than 75 percent of veteran employees hired during the calendar year before the prior calendar year; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6F0D4CF6FB1F4D80877F755AF8F09623"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such employer provides a targeted training program for new veteran employees.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H999A9F50E7DA482EB7F830AD06A3B001"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Gold HIRE Vets Medallion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No employer shall be eligible to receive a Gold HIRE Vets Medallion in a given calendar year unless—</text>
 <clause id="H02658DA9B3834408AAF4C39A45F332EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such employer is eligible to receive a Silver HIRE Vets Medallion in such year;</text> </clause><clause id="H89387A2E5A9749D98C5B7F60E7ED6F08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>veterans constitute not less than 7 percent of all employees hired by such employer during the prior calendar year;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5A5793D4F6E341E1B1359732B40A5C09"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such employer has established an employee veteran organization or resource group to assist new veteran employees with integration, including coaching and mentoring; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H415A93FE4BF7464686C836C728DA3F79"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such employer has established programs to enhance the leadership skills of veteran employees during their employment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H661D29D185CE47C8AB06756454A8A62D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Platinum HIRE Vets Medallion</header><text>No employer shall be eligible to receive a Platinum HIRE Vets Medallion in a given calendar year unless—</text>
 <clause id="H27C877C637B24A209BB0AC956B4F556B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such employer is eligible to receive a Gold HIRE Vets Medallion in such year;</text> </clause><clause id="H348E9E7CF2CE483A9182CD3D949879D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>veterans constitute not less than 10 percent of all employees hired by such employer during the prior calendar year;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4C4CA38A3FDA4F6F9CCFB6DF8CBB57EC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such employer retains through the end of the prior calendar year not less than 85 percent of veteran employees hired during the calendar year before the prior calendar year;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2007254F0CF64D2886FEBEEBBC36EB94"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such employer employs dedicated human resources professionals to support hiring and retention of veteran employees, including efforts focused on veteran hiring and training;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9C270B86785A4F69AD5374EAE93A669D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such employer provides each of its employees serving on active duty in the United States National Guard or Reserve with compensation sufficient, in combination with the employee’s active duty pay, to achieve a combined level of income commensurate with the employee’s salary prior to undertaking active duty; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5511F0D2C8CA42FFAEB29E1F98A9E824"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>such employer has established a tuition assistance program to support veteran employees’ attendance in postsecondary education during the term of their employment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A340B21DE044D11A52C6B1FB9C00AA6"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Exemption for smaller employers</header><text>An employer shall be deemed to meet the requirements of subparagraph (E)(iv) if such employer—</text> <clause id="H35413CFDFE444014A24D01061AA96B90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employs 5,000 or fewer employees; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5051CC29BC7445708E0F4577B29F7396"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>employs at least one human resources professional whose regular work duties include those described under subparagraph (E)(iv).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CED77B662754BF5B065923039E4B8F8"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Additional criteria</header><text>The Secretary may provide, by rule, additional criteria with which to determine qualifications for receipt of each level of HIRE Vets Medallion.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4F6F190ECE74B45837011B641587A8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Small- and medium-sized employers</header><text>The Secretary shall establish similar awards in order to recognize achievements in supporting veterans by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03D50D747DAD4ED5B8A99512FCC8A112"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employers with 50 or fewer employees; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3B3878E918A44DE99EDCA5A916200B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employers with more than 50 but fewer than 500 employees.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H404E18A6511C40C39F5E4331BB2676ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Design by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall establish the shape, form, and metallic content of each HIRE Vets Medallion.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HB04D49C6B7EE465EACD2BAB4EB78652F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Display of award</header> <subsection id="H3FD4597BD3404584A9C802281AF91B3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recipient of a HIRE Vets Medallion may—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5EC4F0D90EB94119B2058D4EA2A0B56B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publicly display such medallion through the end of the calendar year following receipt of such medallion; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE563DA979E648589DB6C21C773138F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publicly display the HIRE Vets Medallion Certificate issued in conjunction with such medallion.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B48493CC50A4937B4EC99CD7828FD15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unlawful display prohibited</header><text>It is unlawful for any employer to publicly display a HIRE Vets Medallion—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA3B5CF480FB045F2AC43F7FF3E4F4D12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if such employer did not receive such medallion through the HIRE Vets Medallion Program; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3C49F701B044A0B8C90B1BFA27DF324"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after the end of the calendar year following the calendar year in which such medallion was issued to such employer through the HIRE Vets Medallion Program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEDAA238B0C3446D1A5ED0B57F0760DEE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Application fee and funding</header>
 <subsection id="H011C551D993647AC8BEBE19B5CEF0215"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fee authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may assess a reasonable fee on employers that apply for receipt of a HIRE Vets Medallion.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3EC5F0ADC93D4F829A8C656419EDA13A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fund established</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a separate account for the deposit of fees collected under subsection (a), to be designated the <quote>HIRE Vets Medallion Award Fund</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H81AA1805320A4F4CAA1C08DC16455F87"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text>The Secretary shall deposit any fees collected pursuant to subsection (a) into the HIRE Vets Medallion Award Fund.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC6969C8DDD00435BB175C2ABA16BED7A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
				<paragraph id="H328926BEC0C04C03BC85CB9953A5E950"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sources of appropriations</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD649D840C19248B2B4D60D5B3238331E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First year</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for the first fiscal year in which applications are to be solicited under section 2(b) such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act in such fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H824CF4C117B84D76AD688D8D232A5C64"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Following years</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated from the HIRE Vets Medallion Award Fund, for each fiscal year following a fiscal year in which fees are collected under subsection (a), an amount equal to the total fees collected under subsection (a) during such prior fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H235C676F378346BCA3CB4ECCC5871133"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A8C6DEFFFE9414BA857E0518A177ADE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be used for carrying out the HIRE Vets Medallion Program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDE2DE8297C63415E82FEB764DA70BD8E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="HF7CE354375B34603AF4D46BFE70CF2F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress annual reports on—</text>
 <paragraph id="H064018B3B46742D2B4F3E3DFD4D7936B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the fees collected from applicants for HIRE Vets Medallions in the prior year and any changes in fees to be proposed in the present year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33D4D41A19704F7E8AE3E08B830834CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cost of administering the HIRE Vets Medallion Program in the prior year;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H27E77EBDBA4847FD9063621C98E5E9B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of applications for HIRE Vets Medallions received in the prior year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BE19F0FE8424E2C9FD21E32E40DAD73"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the HIRE Vets Medallions awarded in the prior year, including the name of each employer to whom a HIRE Vets Medallion was awarded and the level of medallion awarded to each such employer.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A4E7B37EF99433AA6AB7715C07BCD93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Committees</header><text>The Secretary shall provide the reports required under subsection (a) to the Chairman and Ranking Member of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7CCA30837F804359853E68D675944EF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committees on Education and the Workforce and Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F81DBDA0BAA4EA7A4B5432577ADD70C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3C8B961D3174DBC9BCF369F649BEFFF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <subsection id="HE793A9E483164BE0ABEEC54F8570793F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <quote>employer</quote> has the meaning given such term under section 4303 of title 38, United States Code, except that such term does not include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBEFCC1295D954B4FB176492FFD90738C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Government;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H637D383F61D9466AB80C3B1A11CED596"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any State, as defined in such section; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57B5E4C4BC9844C0844C0A7C031811A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any foreign state.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H841A0625807E49288641EEDC01A0E838"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Labor.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA1BECE27CCF470E935DC5178C02426B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>veteran</quote> has the meaning given such term under section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

