<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3096659C5F1445F88C74660BA4997EE0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3169 IH: Smithsonian Modernization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3169</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150722">July 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To revise the composition of the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution so that all
			 members are individuals appointed by the President from a list of nominees
			 submitted by the leadership of the Congress, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H65F40FE85BD247678BA38D070DF26A6F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H51DA64F7ADB64961B9BA20A8EB7BBE79" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Smithsonian Modernization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBB8918AB821C411B9B13A33AF925E31E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Appointment of Members of Smithsonian Board of Regents</header> <subsection id="HE835DD78EAA149C7AC9A8BDA070AA589"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number of Members; Appointment of All Members From List of Nominees</header> <paragraph id="HDA06E717C53247A2A0E17C864BA67005"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 5580(a) of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/42">20 U.S.C. 42(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>to be composed of</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>to be composed of 21 members appointed by the President from among the list of nominees submitted under subsection (b), of whom 2 shall be residents of the District of Columbia.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HACAD8F3B3F5B42D9ABA3D06119F8E530"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List of Nominees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5580 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/42">20 U.S.C. 42(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H38C5F72080C44FFCA90E22BB561F51CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H751433C8F88F4E0AAFC0D6FD09717D27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H365E514FE8EB4AE893021D29881BB706" style="traditional"> <subsection id="H7A051828C6D448B58CDFE666F3BEAD3B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Majority Leader of the Senate shall each submit to the President a list of 12 nominees for appointment as members of the Board of Regents.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11DA7E06AAB74DCCA0F9E8CE3BAAC70C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revision of quorum</header><text>Section 5582 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/44">20 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>eight shall constitute a quorum</quote> and inserting <quote>17 shall constitute a quorum</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF329AF1FF04568B8EBC61189C795B3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No effect on current citizen Regents</header><text>Nothing in the amendments made by this subsection may be construed to affect the authority of any individual who serves as a Regent of the Smithsonian Institution as of the date of the enactment of this Act pursuant to a joint resolution of the Congress to continue to serve as a Regent after that date.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FA0A44562224FC482E50061A8D2D453"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Uniform Term of Service</header><text>Section 5581 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/43">20 U.S.C. 43</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H290F1DB91EFD46FABC64EE7DE5EF8C59" style="traditional">
					<section id="HBF34FED71E0B4A7BA0788DB7ACDED66A"><enum>5581.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H99FA2AE9D1D840CFAA63BB5A59EEAF00"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), each Regent of the Smithsonian Institution shall be appointed for a term of 6 years, and may be reappointed for additional terms.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9AB0AA962E6943F88DF27D18E5689E34"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Of the Regents who are appointed after the date of the enactment of the Smithsonian Modernization Act of 2015 who were not serving as Regents prior to that date—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8799532668C04AAFB5C214687E91C286"><enum>(1)</enum><text>4 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years (as designated in the joint resolution under which they are appointed) and may be reappointed for additional terms of 6 years; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88E8D338040E4A4C9468CE5240C3E649"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">4 shall be appointed for a term of 4 years (as designated in the joint resolution under which they are appointed) and may be reappointed for additional terms of 6 years.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B7AD17F4B934FBEB1F4CED36F0C0C95"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Regent appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the Regent’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term. A Regent may serve after the expiration of that Regent’s term until a successor has taken office.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


