<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H39DF724D6E3649B1B1B636AA4036C0C5" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4305 IH: Ukrainian Warfighter Assistance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4305</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 to further enhance the
			 assistance provided by the United States to Ukraine to defend against
			 further aggression by Russia and Russian-backed separatists against
			 Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE6FFB40FD16A4F5AAA7450A7701C13E0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H26D51C40F9E84AD4AFE49E8C148490DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ukrainian Warfighter Assistance Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H03D189E975014455B0F3D781ED2019EB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF7AB89010396438B8FE4DE27FB260C7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ukraine’s border is 6,995 kilometers long, including 1,974 kilometers of controlled border with Russia, 195 kilometers of an administrative line with Crimea, and 409 kilometers of border in the east that is currently uncontrolled.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCAFCC5874554403BF2590930C52AFA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Since the beginning of the Russian-Ukrainian conflict in 2014, 64 Ukrainian border guards have been killed and another 391 have been wounded.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7410DB695254C219E46A599FA5727CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation of the Minsk Agreement will require the State Border Guard Service of Ukraine to reestablish border checkpoints in currently uncontrolled territory and to monitor the border to verify full implementation of the Agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FAB8DC01CB74D60B58755B8546AD4A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ukraine has already ordered the development of engineering and technical systems to strengthen the controlled border between Ukraine and Russia, Ukranian maritime borders, and areas adjacent to the uncontrolled territory and occupied Crimea.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25DE00C93881422CBE99B342A555FBB4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russian unmanned aerial vehicles are being used for correction of Russian-backed separatist artillery fire, and Russian-backed separatists continue to compromise Ukrainian tactical communication networks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E206462643548898A2706649A422E6F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A Ukrainian early warning network is needed to warn of any new aggression on the border.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7677EAAB7E994C4FB513D5B2E461AFEF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ukrainian anti-tank guided missiles require modernization to increase soldier survivability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96B8F16848174282A0F4C782DA7876A6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Because future military operations in eastern Ukraine will rely heavily on special operations forces, special operations training is a high priority for the armed forces of Ukraine.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H417D039016954F108743D69296F461AF"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1250 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/92">Public Law 114–92</external-xref>) rightfully called for the United States to provide to Ukraine critical training and equipment to enhance the capabilities of the military and other security forces of Ukraine to defend against further aggression from Russia and Russian-backed separatists.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA99699150BB04C01A694EE46205C94A5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The assistance provided to Ukraine under such section must be enhanced even further to adapt to the current threats facing Ukraine.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H650ABFCD2E6E4D71A33826574DF9C6E6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enhancement of Ukraine security assistance initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1250(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/92">Public Law 114–92</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3026A146C2DD4742BE413EB3220B4C58"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>and jamming counter-measures against such systems</quote> after <quote>surveillance systems</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA069A1D415314BA8B4DCE71C18A93C59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (7), (8), and (9) as paragraphs (8), (9), and (10), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08A66024B5014617B7F6730A5DCC3AEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92B407426B084743BD32800C9384E7B7" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H9A63D87C15BB4DCE99EC43244A9DCC6A"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Electro-optical/infrared sensor and multi-mode radar equipped early warning systems.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E281787946E4EB4B85FB4A6D073AF74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>(7)</quote> and inserting <quote>(8)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3BEBD353A004F28B3BDB89DDB8B296C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEF9F513B2EF4CBFBAA9EE33721FB87A" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3A503F1B31A147B7B7F2A03285041FC0"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training for the staff officers and leadership of the military and other security forces of the Government of Ukraine.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1ABB17499CE24597B49CB76A1116C440"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance to Ukraine to develop the ability to domestically produce anti-armor weapon systems.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7ABAD29CB3A846FFAAEBACD7C9E13A0D"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Equipment and technical assistance provided directly to the State Border Guard Service of Ukraine for the purpose of developing a comprehensive and routine surveillance network.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C70D6FB7F8F4123ABBC9302537F3C3F"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Construction of a special forces training center and assistance in developing a special forces training program.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H2C438CD69CF942D8881770B769DF0B26"><enum>4.</enum><header>Border guard prioritization</header>
 <subsection id="HBBFD4A5D6BCE431A968F70A1C6BA2FB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States that the Secretary of Defense, in cooperation with the Secretary of State, when providing equipment and technical assistance to the Government of Ukraine, shall give priority to assistance for purposes of protecting and monitoring the borders of Ukraine.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE192ACF4F11F4923855984987C05C523"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of report on military assistance to Ukraine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1275(c) of the Carl Levin and Howard P. “Buck” McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/291">Public Law 113–291</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 3591) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3FB3650A3ED47D285B6A1FF52292970" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H59CBC1E1E0EF4C79B0889F09256A8861"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the extent to which the Secretary of Defense has prioritized, or is prioritizing, the security assistance provided, or to be provided, to the Government of Ukraine for the purposes of protecting and monitoring the borders of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


