<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1FB54F76B90A4A4193F68CB04B55CD2D" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2436 IH: To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to appropriate age groupings to be included in research studies involving human subjects.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2436</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150519">May 19, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to appropriate age groupings to be included in research studies involving human subjects.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H90F56E6A0B32427285A174FFE205CD27" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3BCB8EB44C864F0C88E269C6BE1F9DAE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Appropriate age groupings in clinical research</header> 
<subsection id="H873F08F30DB94000A9C124F1FFCA82AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Input from experts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall convene a workshop of experts on pediatrics and experts on geriatrics to provide input on—</text> <paragraph id="H0B1500957FA8410DB12C90C9DE5FB979"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriate age groupings to be included in research studies involving human subjects; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4EAC5853F5B48AAA1D0C1129A7642DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acceptable scientific justifications for excluding participants from a range of age groups from human subjects research studies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE5158216BC3C4DA0960D3390FA59C7EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the conclusion of the workshop under subsection (a), the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall publish guidelines—</text> 
<paragraph id="H51A3B10880A44C63BD8D18DAD07052FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>addressing the consideration of age as an inclusion variable in research involving human subjects; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD99B4C5D00394298AE1FB9D46006DB64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying criteria for justifications for any age-related exclusions in such research.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43CDBDF1467E4DC2A71590C814E590A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability of findings and conclusions</header><text>The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3FEC9E43CA9B4D519CA6D7B3F3471E54"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the findings and conclusion resulting from the workshop under subsection (a) available to the public on the website of the National Institutes of Health; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8ACD2CBDCF824991891FA8DA0E161049"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less than biennially, disclose to the public on such website the number of children included in research that is conducted or supported by the National Institutes of Health, disaggregated by developmentally appropriate age group, race, and gender.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

