<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H880979CA851B4F7C96ECAFC8EBCAFEC9" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1362 IH: Medicaid Requiring Expenditures for Public Objectives to be Reflective of Total Spending Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1362</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150313">March 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to require States to submit an annual report on sources of funds used to finance the non-Federal share of expenditures under such title, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H80D58832118946E6947CF22CCE3F3E38" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7A7BF494C39F46E182BE36F63A67117B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Requiring Expenditures for Public Objectives to be Reflective of Total Spending Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Medicaid REPORTS Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HFD66BDFFB8134385B22846472D44CE2A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring States to submit an annual report of sources funds used to finance the non-Federal share of Medicaid</header> <subsection id="H6B872DFA8B294F2CA391F1A0A6EBFE8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(w)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(w)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs: </text> 
<quoted-block id="HE10EAC2D875D4C1B87A31F0652685EF3"> 
<subparagraph id="HB3ABB2CBBCE54E65BA2555545DA8804E" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to fiscal year 2016 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall require each State to submit, using formats and standards established and updated as necessary by the Secretary, a report that identifies each source of funds, each entity providing such funds, and the amount of funds from each such source, used by the State to finance the non-Federal share of expenditures under this title. Such report shall provide such information as the Secretary determines is sufficient to ensure the State’s compliance with the requirements of this title applicable to financing such non-Federal share with respect to each of the following sources of funds:</text> <clause id="H92624872D1D640B38471B8212AFE1F65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State appropriations or transfers to the State agency administering the State plan under this title, or to other State agencies or government entities that are used to finance such non-Federal share of payments under this title.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDF72909E3E7B492FA093682748DBCF25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Bona fide provider-related donations (as defined in paragraph (2)(B)) and donation revenue (as defined in paragraph (2)(C)).</text></clause> <clause id="HA7E0027544444EA7A8959E0F1960081C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Intergovernmental transfers from units of government within the State.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H78B52A766C1F4C28BD85C55FBC537250"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Certified public expenditures from units of government within the State.</text></clause> <clause id="HF34A46AD91DD4A978134D9FD787A71E0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other sources as determined necessary by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65A81A255B5F41278EC6234A7E58D86C" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary shall make the information reported under subparagraph (C) publicly available through publication on the Internet site of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HCA7293D0D6614E8289E294C0B85CD016"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(w)(6)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(w)(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, or are not reported as required under subparagraph (C)</quote> after <quote>this section</quote> .</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


