<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEBA0DE70D3214BABB203AD6C38A7B79F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2642 IH: Community Lender Regulatory Relief and Consumer Protection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2642</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150603">June 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide sensible relief to community financial institutions, to protect consumers, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H612955F4A8184AC189F7F50A376AE503" style="OLC">
		<section id="H837DF1499C2E45D884A4F62D0A96AE7D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H09060B807D994E4EB009C154D9E5841E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Lender Regulatory Relief and Consumer Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HB5D576EFC2144283A4946501C6FE4524"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="H837DF1499C2E45D884A4F62D0A96AE7D" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5008D43845F240828AEB4B704E092C4F" level="title">TITLE I—Helping community lenders</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA7A5292875EB4A688891A6FC7407987A" level="section">Sec. 101. Community bank and credit union portfolio lending.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2F665BA47D484A4BA22AC80FF702B5A3" level="section">Sec. 102. Exception to annual written privacy notice requirement under the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4D47EBA8CEB44095A96B4AE0734CF798" level="section">Sec. 103. Expansion of threshold for 18-month on-site examination cycle.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2451DBE1A414491D81A39275C5B1E73A" level="section">Sec. 104. Privately insured credit unions authorized to become members of a Federal home loan bank.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4BFE91CA60B2435DB7ACBFE1509F46AB" level="section">Sec. 105. Registration threshold for savings and loan holding companies.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H086EBA8C6D5642849EC5DD1F0318CC02" level="section">Sec. 106. Transitional license authority.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H87064F8FE1B74B3688F27404CF66ADD1" level="title">TITLE II—Protecting consumers</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEC792F966DFA4838B6E29FC6A2D56EB7" level="section">Sec. 201. Protecting servicemembers.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB6562739F3B0489686E53F5E6509DB1F" level="section">Sec. 202. Restoration of the Protecting Tenants at Foreclosure Act of 2009.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD2A74F85B2AA4B9A9B83BF8EBCD0CE3B" level="section">Sec. 203. Confidentiality of information shared between State and Federal financial services
			 regulators.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><title commented="no" id="H5008D43845F240828AEB4B704E092C4F" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Helping community lenders</header>
 <section commented="no" id="HA7A5292875EB4A688891A6FC7407987A"><enum>101.</enum><header>Community bank and credit union portfolio lending</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 129C(b)(2) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639c">15 U.S.C. 1639c(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE07AEC322FA845FE8F5C50981221F110" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H2547D37054864D78B703D2C9C522133B"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Safe Harbor</header>
 <clause id="HEAB5ABDC07874D9AB129A440976161FB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section—</text> <subclause id="HA1A28AAAB34C4B3F935DDAD6C0A38113"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the term <term>qualified mortgage</term>, as defined in subparagraph (A), includes any residential mortgage loan—</text>
 <item id="HF55674FB826B4AEF8F5D281D686ED214"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>that is originated by a covered institution and continuously retained in portfolio by the covered institution;</text>
 </item><item id="HBFD0DA5562054123A111ACDAD81BC2EB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that, except as provided in subparagraph (E), fully amortizes over a term of not longer than 30 years;</text>
 </item><item id="H380F42E568F64E8DA3FDB93CFCE8A58E"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>that complies with—</text> <subitem id="H2C801EC350F64CA89CDB57FED35F6618"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the requirements of clauses (i), (ii), (iii), (iv), (v), and (vii) of subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H723579FBCDDD40F383C27DA6023A6BB5"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>any requirements consistent with the purposes described in paragraph (3)(B)(i);</text> </subitem></item><item id="H886240E81B5647F98372D4261CC6846C"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>for which the covered institution, at or before consummation of the residential mortgage loan, takes into account and verifies the monthly debt and income of the consumer; and</text>
 </item><item id="HDCFCBBA3C7EC45B38CFAB6D0E8608588"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>that is not considered a high-cost mortgage; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H1A97DBF1AA0545D191F80C3DCA6A5938"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a residential mortgage loan that meets the requirements of subclause (I) shall be deemed to meet the requirements of subsection (a) until the residential mortgage loan no longer meets the requirements of subclause (I).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HFA726C84FB444263B35866545646CA48"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>covered institution</term> means—</text> <subclause id="HC33FFB4826284ED48C70784B489D35FF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an insured depository institution or insured credit union that—</text>
 <item id="HED08557CEFA54A5A8A8D2D6506767DC8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>at the time of origination of the residential mortgage loan, together with its affiliates, has less than $2,000,000,000 in total consolidated assets; and</text>
 </item><item id="HA43D93C50C3E4F4BB11DD05B7BF44A58"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>during the calendar year preceding the time of origination of the residential mortgage loan, originated not more than 2,000 residential mortgage loans that were—</text>
 <subitem id="H30D80319DA3A4BB5BAA394F8BB281BB9"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>sold, assigned, or otherwise transferred to another person; or</text> </subitem><subitem id="H5FB5C274886D499B876D1367ED0EF424"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>subject to, at the time of consummation, a commitment to be acquired by another person; or</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="HC89023EB9FB7438DB2D199506F2C74D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an insured depository institution or insured credit union that, at the time of origination of the residential mortgage loan—</text>
 <item id="H4638CAF207834FD69DC39BDF696E1E3D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>together with its affiliates, has more than $2,000,000,000 and less than $10,000,000,000 in total consolidated assets;</text>
 </item><item id="HA03A2F62D83F4E5C8C98BD445940EBC2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is not considered a specialty bank, such as a bank that offers only a narrow product line (including credit card or motor vehicle loans) to a regional or broader market;</text>
 </item><item id="HEF0F7C426EE044E8A4F6B50F551D5813"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>engages in the basic activities of lending and deposit taking as a significant percentage of total assets;</text>
 </item><item id="H3DC3C8E16F614A9996F24266A5752671"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>has a limited geographic scope; and</text> </item><item id="HA26D24B0E6434121B288C94DA5661AF5"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>meets any other criteria as determined by the Bureau, including restrictions on the volume of residential mortgage loans—</text>
 <subitem id="H61FDF0A4D17549ADA3FC7A6AFC0FB1D0"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>sold, assigned, or otherwise transferred to another person; or</text> </subitem><subitem id="H578D9E3B9F704465BDF754AE6FCA21E2"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>subject to, at the time of consummation, a commitment to be acquired by another person.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F665BA47D484A4BA22AC80FF702B5A3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception to annual written privacy notice requirement under the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 503 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6803">15 U.S.C. 6803</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE885E599CC941819FB2BB13495DC531" style="OLC">
					<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD201226329B14C3A9E5D97981EF5B730"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception to annual written notice requirement</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6615B4F5C1A547C1BC1C8178847D286F"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A financial institution described in paragraph (2) shall not be required to provide an annual written disclosure under this section until such time as the financial institution fails to comply with subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18B558E73BFD4BE7B67D609771BA4DCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A financial institution described in this paragraph is a financial institution that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE60CFD1A03184E0098767F974602BCD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides nonpublic personal information only in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(2) or (e) of section 502 or regulations prescribed under section 504(b);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8B672CE55424F0EB85FC06E1D0A78E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not changed its policies and practices with respect to disclosing nonpublic personal information from the policies and practices that were disclosed in the most recent disclosure sent to consumers in accordance with this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC735DA5EB1EC4AF68741A34688119CB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise provides customers access to such most recent disclosure in electronic or other form permitted by regulations prescribed under section 504.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H4D47EBA8CEB44095A96B4AE0734CF798"><enum>103.</enum><header>Expansion of threshold for 18-month on-site examination cycle</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10(d) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1820">12 U.S.C. 1820(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC09D5C8E86234E6B9BB6AC711C768497"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A), by striking <quote>$500,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,000,000,000</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F6E877A62C740EB8FD6C93B7383F391"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>$500,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,000,000,000</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H2451DBE1A414491D81A39275C5B1E73A"><enum>104.</enum><header>Privately insured credit unions authorized to become members of a Federal home loan bank</header> <subsection id="H137113266732416D95C5057F78EAFAE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4(a) of the Federal Home Loan Bank Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1424">12 U.S.C. 1424(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H59F4B296101545048EECE56669E4CEF5" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HEC88B8F13377441CB59999FABC2C9825"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Certain privately insured credit unions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB3DBD55CB86D4CD79ECBC346DEA4C5C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the requirements of subparagraph (B), a credit union that lacks insurance of its member accounts under Federal law shall be treated as an insured depository institution for purposes of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9D2DF8F1BD44E41A169ECA0CAE8D59C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification by appropriate State supervisor</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, a credit union that lacks insurance of its member accounts under Federal law and that has applied for membership in a Federal home loan bank shall be treated as an insured depository institution if the following has occurred:</text>
								<clause id="H13140A7219334A05A6DEC2CA43A76F7A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Determination by State supervisor of the credit union</header>
 <subclause id="H81B873DFD78840DEB775971DBA6D6F01"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subclause (II), the appropriate supervisor of the State in which the credit union is chartered has determined that the credit union meets all the eligibility requirements under section 201(a) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1781">12 U.S.C. 1781(a)</external-xref>) to apply for insurance of its member accounts as of the date of the application for membership.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD449CE6A46B94AAAA4831C6009A6DF58"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Certification deemed valid</header><text>In the case of any credit union to which subclause (I) applies, if the appropriate supervisor of the State in which such credit union is chartered fails to make the determination required pursuant to such subclause by the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the application is submitted to the supervisor, the credit union shall be deemed to have met the requirements of subclause (I).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H221B404EE2F44CEAA839179B1FE0FB2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination by State supervisor of the private deposit insurer</header><text>The licensing entity of the private deposit insurer that is insuring the member accounts of the credit union—</text>
 <subclause id="HDD17A32E119A4DD1B524C7FA2EB49CDA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>receives, on an annual basis, an independent actuarial opinion that the private insurer has set aside sufficient reserves for losses; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H77A388BA4A304405B25705BBE5C498E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>obtains, as frequently as appropriate, but not less frequently than every 36 months, an independent actuary’s study of the capital adequacy of the private insurer.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H1AFF9E7938174F3B87C077371E427514"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Submission of financial information</header><text>The credit union or the appropriate supervisor of the State in which such credit union is chartered makes available, and continues to make available for such time as the credit union is a member of a Federal home loan bank, to the Federal Housing Finance Agency or to the Federal home loan bank all reports, records, and other information related to any examinations or inquiries performed by the supervisor concerning the financial condition of the credit union, as soon as is practicable.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC728A73D88E4C09AF3A9C6DFE0C17BD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Security interests of federal home loan bank not avoidable</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of State law authorizing a conservator or liquidating agent of a credit union to repudiate contracts, no such provision shall apply with respect to—</text>
 <clause id="H02160B1A2FA9427DA153E8434C0170D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any extension of credit from any Federal home loan bank to any credit union that is a member of any such bank pursuant to this paragraph; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7748C086376C43EF88973A3C97DF0734"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any security interest in the assets of such a credit union securing any such extension of credit.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2CDD9D3366241188511E14E50B72B4A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Protection for certain Federal home loan bank advances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any State law to the contrary, if a Bank makes an advance under section 10 to a State-chartered credit union that is not federally insured—</text>
 <clause id="H5D1CDC63E3B44CFE9C6A6A2DAF059E2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Bank’s interest in any collateral securing the advance has the same priority and is afforded the same standing and rights that the security interest would have had if the advance had been made to a federally insured credit union; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE684ACD7AAFE454FA97ED4FA506268DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Bank has the same right to access such collateral that the Bank would have had if the advance had been made to a federally insured credit union.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6DFEE9E05934EA190B5A542D72D47AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Copies of audits of private insurers of certain depository institutions required To be provided to
 supervisory agencies</header><text>Section 43(a)(2)(A) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831t">12 U.S.C. 1831t(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC58BF91A036040CBBC0B5C903503C107"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32EF47B4B9CB4F02B96E59D579FE47BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BFBE26B80804135ABEA2369BB584253"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HF4B5FF1702794631B63476EFA3CB5E03" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H7B294D0BE18F46BBA6151DDDFF824AAB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of depository institutions described in subsection (e)(2)(A), the member accounts of which are insured by the private deposit insurer, which are members of a Federal home loan bank, to the Federal Housing Finance Agency, not later than 7 days after the audit is completed.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H057C08168FD54D9AA9CCD3CFE1E00EB8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and submit a report to Congress—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD1A74D6823584EF39C7FDFCB557AE91B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the adequacy of insurance reserves held by a private deposit insurer that insures the member accounts of an entity described in section 43(e)(2)(A) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831t">12 U.S.C. 1831t(e)(2)(A)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H846B271AC30D43F2BB629417AB2CD25A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for an entity described in paragraph (1), the member accounts of which are insured by a private deposit insurer, information on the level of compliance with Federal regulations relating to the disclosure of a lack of Federal deposit insurance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4BFE91CA60B2435DB7ACBFE1509F46AB"><enum>105.</enum><header>Registration threshold for savings and loan holding companies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE8452182D89D47188AF81309F7DCEFE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 12(g)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7BB1B3AA075B4F4E9A2F8CF25E9781CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(B), by inserting after <quote>is a bank</quote> the following: <quote>, a savings and loan holding company (as such term is defined in section 10 of the Home Owners' Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1467a">12 U.S.C. 1467a(a)</external-xref>)),</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H515248E804A64FE691163399954BDCD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting after <quote>case of a bank</quote> the following: <quote>, a savings and loan holding company (as such term is defined in section 10 of the Home Owners' Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1467a">12 U.S.C. 1467a(a)</external-xref>)),</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB5365DFE4F9474585F409A087DD55B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 15(d)(1), by striking <quote>case of bank</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>case of a bank, a savings and loan holding company (as such term is defined in section 10 of the Home Owners' Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1467a">12 U.S.C. 1467a(a)</external-xref>)),</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H086EBA8C6D5642849EC5DD1F0318CC02"><enum>106.</enum><header>Transitional license authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1504 of the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5103">12 U.S.C. 5103</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1C90AB646A6946E6966D350F7F0C1016"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting after <quote>as the case may be,</quote> the following: <quote>and except as provided in subsection (c),</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2237A08D336F4224A0FC6722D8C4F63E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD39F8B98BB314392AD024B1F54F7DCEB" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H3EDEA05BCF2C4D6D9F3CA6DD25A40C62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transitional authority</header> <paragraph id="H0D826D8354F846519953CBB3BFD42D4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered registered loan originator</term> means a registered loan originator who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFFD63930372148D0920BD1418128CADA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submits the information required under section 1505(a); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFECAD5971BE34C42AC717AEEB7D34BD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the 30-day period preceding the date of such submission, met the standard of being qualified under section 129B(b)(1)(A) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639b">15 U.S.C. 1639b(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97279D8EFC8F48618D387873F76557BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of subsections (b) through (e) of section 1505, a State may permit a covered registered loan originator to act as a loan originator, under the supervision of a non-depository firm that engages in loan origination in that State, for the 120-day period beginning on the date on which the covered registered loan originator submits the information required under section 1505(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB8B0B374D814FDBB0C4D2D5369C8CA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A covered registered loan originator may not act as a loan originator under paragraph (2) after the date on which the 120-day period described in that paragraph expires.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section></title><title id="H87064F8FE1B74B3688F27404CF66ADD1" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Protecting consumers</header>
 <section id="HEC792F966DFA4838B6E29FC6A2D56EB7"><enum>201.</enum><header>Protecting servicemembers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1002(12) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481(12)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC28964AE24A542D985E250F1D23E8854"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Q), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H850B251CCC774381A73E618720BAD602"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (R), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H505607D6163A4EE68C523179EE00850C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC89720CA371C4CC4B75D2C2B6283B0E3" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H8D488B3788664CC49497748C5A381286"><enum>(S)</enum><text>sections 101, 107 (except with respect to bailments), 108 (except with respect to insurance), 201 (except with respect to child custody proceedings), 207, 301, 302, 303, 305, and 305A of the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/511">50 U.S.C. App. 511</external-xref>, 517, 518, 521, 527, 531, 532, 533, 535, and 535a).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section id="HB6562739F3B0489686E53F5E6509DB1F"><enum>202.</enum><header>Restoration of the Protecting Tenants at Foreclosure Act of 2009</header>
 <subsection id="H53377B9417BE4A328166618E5C2559D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of sunset provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 704 of the Protecting Tenants at Foreclosure Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5201">12 U.S.C. 5201</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5220">12 U.S.C. 5220</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E95681B7B344834BEBD091AA9F20F67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 701 through 703 of such Act, the provisions of law amended or repealed by such sections, and any regulations promulgated pursuant to such sections, as were in effect on December 31, 2014, are restored and revived as if the sunset provision in section 704 had not taken effect.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD2A74F85B2AA4B9A9B83BF8EBCD0CE3B"><enum>203.</enum><header>Confidentiality of information shared between State and Federal financial services regulators</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1512(a) of the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5111">12 U.S.C. 5111(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or financial services</quote> before <quote>industry</quote>.</text>
			</section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


