<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4DD8B009A1CA416F9486AF43218C8843" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4211 IH: Credit Score Competition Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4211</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151210">December 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to establish procedures for considering certain credit scores
			 in making a determination whether to purchase a residential mortgage, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2F51FE93AE56494884BBB3F1F0A11FCC" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD0DBA8AF53AF4DCF909AC7F2EBBD1449" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Credit Score Competition Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8D8B4935FCBE4C43A41F30DF38E1B1DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit score validation; validation process</header> <subsection id="HB25840BC2B55441F9111DEC1C5F052AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of credit scores by Fannie Mae in purchasing residential mortgages</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 302 of the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1717">12 U.S.C. 1717(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF13296EB1027411AB2614E818CC2A330" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HA7CD7270A5F64E84A0507FD0DFA622FA" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H822ACE18178D4F47A2E17A5B56323378"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of credit scores</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The corporation may condition its purchase of a residential mortgage under this section on the provision of a credit score for the borrower only if—</text>
 <clause id="H0017660FA6F2430CA43039607CF2973B" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credit score is derived from any credit scoring model that has been validated and approved by the corporation under this paragraph;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H505D2BC1CB2A41C0A7508031F537077C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the corporation has established and made publicly available a description of the process the corporation will use to validate and approve credit scoring models, which process shall comply with any standards and criteria established by the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency pursuant to section 1328 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0571F520D7A74DCD93645421D96E20BC" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the corporation provides for the use of such credit score by all of its automated underwriting systems and any other procedures and systems used to purchase residential mortgages.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H501C084778244EF4BF3CFD0EC1849897" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Validation and approval process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall include an evaluation of—</text> <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE736DAFD8EA74A3E851320AC6F27F6D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the criteria used to validate and approve a credit scoring model, including measures of the integrity, reliability, and accuracy of such model, and an assurance that such model is consistent with the safe and sound operation of the corporation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H96ADBCE585E54216993E0B63DC69D380"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the data necessary for the validation of the credit scoring model.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED52C3DC31CE4F308CBB950F181BD81A" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the corporation elects to use a credit score under this paragraph, the corporation shall solicit applications from developers of credit scoring models for the validation and approval of such models under the process described in subparagraph (A)(ii).</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD46A8166522497297ED5876514A1EC9" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Timeframe for determination; notice</header>
 <clause id="HE484E2A2398A4360A5DCA819AFC43520"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The corporation shall establish a date before which the corporation shall make a determination with respect to any application submitted under subparagraph (C) and provide notice of such determination to the applicant. Such date shall not be later than 180 days after the date on which an application is submitted to the corporation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H84A4395EBA494073B86BBAD8460B90EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency may authorize up to 2 extensions of the date established under clause (i), each of which shall not exceed 30 days, upon the written request and a showing of good cause by the corporation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HED4BA380F1F14CAEA802725F83BB5E83"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Status notice</header><text>The corporation shall provide notice to an applicant regarding the status of an application submitted under subparagraph (C) not later than 60 days after the date on which the application was submitted to the corporation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H51A83A42983643FEA26E09F2F87BDF10"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Reasons for disapproval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an application is disapproved, the corporation shall provide to the applicant the reasons for the disapproval not later than 30 days after a determination is made under this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35B1C0B1883D4EB38CE5A012BB6D2A12" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Authority of Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the corporation elects to use a credit score under this paragraph, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency shall require the corporation to routinely update the validation and approval process described in subparagraph (A)(ii) as the Director, in the Director’s discretion, deems to be necessary to ensure such process remains appropriate and adequate and complies with any standards and criteria established pursuant to section 1328 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EC87EF9E022486094D532F1515D48A1" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Credit score defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>credit score</term> means a numerical value or a categorization derived from a statistical tool or modeling system used by a person who makes or arranges a loan to predict the likelihood of certain credit behaviors, including default.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H225222F1A5F649D1B4C802B68AF60A31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of credit scores by Freddie Mac in purchasing residential mortgages</header><text>Section 305 of the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1454">12 U.S.C. 1454</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EA06017E10844AEA23BDA2CFF989C66" style="OLC">
					<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H282BC4BF0C2D483BBD648B036BC99F08"><enum>(d)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H14CB68855E84487BB752D8F8D333F1FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of credit scores</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation may condition its purchase of a residential mortgage under this section on the provision of a credit score for the borrower only if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H60DFE7FC33F74A1CB27082F98A5A66EA" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credit score is derived from any credit scoring model that has been validated and approved by the Corporation under this subsection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0CAECFC234148699CEA68F7C1FD02C1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Corporation has established and made publicly available a description of the process the corporation will use to validate and approve credit scoring models that, which process shall comply with any standards and criteria established by the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency pursuant to section 1328 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23B20AF7A760495DB3F85F12BB8FDDE6" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Corporation provides for use of such credit score by all of its automated underwriting systems and any other procedures and systems used to purchase residential mortgages.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2C9E1EE37A643D7AD9B69D9776DA01A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Validation and approval process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process described in paragraph (1)(B) shall include an evaluation of—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA34C3932B7247A78B5BAD14ED5B46D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the criteria used to validate and approve a credit scoring model, including measures of the integrity, reliability, and accuracy of such model and an assurance that such model is consistent with the safe and sound operation of the Corporation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB266435E44E64D8A81C9CC7DE4FC40D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the data necessary for the validation of the credit scoring model.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD84AFA1D5EB94232AA888A7C6F760ABE" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Corporation elects to use a credit score under this subsection, the Corporation shall solicit applications from developers of credit scoring models for the validation and approval of such models under the process described in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HB0439443105E4AC9B9236E74BC69D46D" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timeframe for determination; notice</header>
 <subparagraph id="H677C0C53E7374B92A2F96F1BB7A69F4E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation shall establish a date before which the Corporation shall make a determination with respect to any application submitted under paragraph (3) and provide notice of such determination to the applicant. Such date shall not be later than 180 days after the date on which an application is submitted to the Corporation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A654AC97DB34BEFA2BF5CF559A1E196"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>The Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency may authorize up to 2 extensions of the date established under subparagraph (A), each of which shall not exceed 30 days, upon the written request and a showing of good cause by the Corporation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA11852AAD8924E9383400C2BDA50D0B6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Status notice</header><text>The Corporation shall provide notice to an applicant regarding the status of an application submitted under paragraph (3) not later than 60 days after the date on which the application was submitted to the corporation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1000C221138F48A38AEB0870B72CA54C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reasons for disapproval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an application is disapproved, the corporation shall provide to the applicant the reasons for the disapproval not later than 30 days after a determination is made under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE88B6E63AEA4263A4D3D739E4C8346E" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authority of Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Corporation elects to use a credit score under this subsection, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency shall require the Corporation to routinely update the validation and approval process described in paragraph (1)(B) as the Director, in the Director’s discretion, deems to be necessary to ensure such process remains appropriate and adequate and complies with any standards and criteria established pursuant to section 1328 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H711E2285D9B0486DA6408FD38E21A183" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Credit score defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>credit score</term> means a numerical value or a categorization derived from a statistical tool or modeling system used by a person who makes or arranges a loan to predict the likelihood of certain credit behaviors, including default.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H701D23938B9F443A9FAF04514A4FD371"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority of Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart A of part 2 of subtitle A of the (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4541">12 U.S.C. 4541 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23435021FB0643FA89EB4CB1B7381C66" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB2CAE3225D114398958FA45441461B04"><enum>1328.</enum><header>Regulations for use of credit scores</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director may, by regulation, establish standards and criteria for any process used by an enterprise to validate and approve credit scoring models pursuant to section 302(b)(7) of the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act and section 305(d) of the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H6E3033EE87E54383A5E994B619FF279A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

