<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA9D6D055D3F04C82BEE6D3F13094E57E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1692 IH: Safety, Efficiency, and Accountability in Transportation Projects Through Public Inspection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1692</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require public employees to perform the inspection of State and local surface transportation
			 projects, and related essential public functions, to ensure public safety,
			 the cost-effective use of transportation funding, and timely project
			 delivery.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H95687E1CC9774031BBF3E80C9C4BCAF3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC5213BEE53314D70A59CA087397B529A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safety, Efficiency, and Accountability in Transportation Projects Through Public Inspection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="H24873FCD29A74DAABACACCBA08C2264E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public inspection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Public employees shall carry out the construction inspection functions for all surface transportation projects receiving Federal funding.</text>
 </section><section id="H958D932C273340C0BEB113E29717A641"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HE7E8DFA853DB44848DD0AAF2456F7499"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Construction inspection functions</header><text>The term <term>construction inspection functions</term> means construction engineering, contract administration, quality control inspection, materials testing, and resident engineer and assistant resident engineer functions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H690F7C05C2B546C9B7CC21968DB209DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public employee</header><text>The term <term>public employee</term> means an employee of a Federal, State, or local government.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B9428CF6EBF4F03B28171606219332E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Surface transportation project</header><text>The term <term>surface transportation project</term> means a project receiving assistance under title 23, United States Code, a capital project (as defined in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code), and any other project related to surface transportation that the Secretary of Transportation determines appropriate.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


