<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE58113A4AC774EE98730DE27CB90887F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2053 IH: Military Reserve Survivor Benefit Equity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2053</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to eliminate the different treatment under the Survivor Benefit Plan accorded members of the reserve components who die from an injury or illness incurred or aggravated in the line of duty during inactive-duty training compared to members of the Armed Forces who die in the line of duty while on active duty.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3E5711CD36374558BE615179A49E74A8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE2F539F8A72F47C989DB5654E05C675F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Reserve Survivor Benefit Equity Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HBBC0D4C4ECB94AEE96FFFB97C16A6325"><enum>2.</enum><header>Equal benefits under Survivor Benefit Plan for survivors of reserve component members who die in the line of duty during inactive-duty training</header> <subsection id="H9F19EEBA29274781B0FB46EF687BF69F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment of inactive-Duty training in same manner as active duty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1451(c)(1)(A) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A156861698F4C5BB80D5D56B6A061C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i)—</text> <subparagraph id="H54692A4350BD44779026634D503A65BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or 1448(f)</quote> after <quote>section 1448(d)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4010755B822F408ABAF2AFB1B4B242AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or (iii)</quote> after <quote>clause (ii)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2257ABE62DFE4558BAA6C4C6FB97822A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iii)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H97CBC2A67C4349F89DB77E0C920D8F29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 1448(f) of this title</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1448(f)(1)(A) of this title by reason of the death of a member or former member not in line of duty</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECE5B02B19A94A66B7963E6F4250EACF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>active service</quote> and inserting <quote>service</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4DF1D98998E64C70BD925713FBB04112"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consistent treatment of dependent children</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 1448(f) of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H798C5F67A55A4A829C7E7DD4FBB29A6E" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H1975497510D84266BD815116A22DC0F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dependent children annuity</header> <subparagraph id="H4BCF475CD62A4C8CB6CAC49F14C3EA5E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annuity when no eligible surviving spouse</header><text>In the case of a person described in paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall pay an annuity under this subchapter to the dependent children of that person under section 1450(a)(2) of this title as applicable.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H307F254A40CA4784B12C5F394451665C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Optional annuity when there is an eligible surviving spouse</header><text>The Secretary may pay an annuity under this subchapter to the dependent children of a person described in paragraph (1) under section 1450(a)(3) of this title, if applicable, instead of paying an annuity to the surviving spouse under paragraph (1), if the Secretary concerned, in consultation with the surviving spouse, determines it appropriate to provide an annuity for the dependent children under this paragraph instead of an annuity for the surviving spouse under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H521A615AC68D44AA83283A422CC8B000"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deemed elections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1448(f) of title 10, United States Code, is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H23532ED9FEBF452CB88BC27C5726C841" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H8E97AC27CB96461F922A2E82C2FA40BE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deemed election to provide an annuity for dependent</header><text>Paragraph (6) of subsection (d) shall apply in the case of a member described in paragraph (1) who dies after November 23, 2003, when no other annuity is payable on behalf of the member under this subchapter.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H11558D2DBC01403AAF90AC75F9B81729"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of special survivor indemnity allowance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1450(m)(1)(B) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or (f)</quote> after <quote>subsection (d)</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C5A4E211E104085A79857FED7309249"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="HEFBA70A00564407E9129C4ED12C3DFE9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>No annuity benefit under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, shall accrue to any person by reason of the amendments made by this section for any period before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC8A8A4A6A7E4A98B89BE712B3A329E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elections</header><text>For any death that occurred before the date of the enactment of this Act with respect to which an annuity under such subchapter is being paid (or could be paid) to a surviving spouse, the Secretary concerned may, within six months of that date and in consultation with the surviving spouse, determine it appropriate to provide an annuity for the dependent children of the decedent under paragraph 1448(f)(2)(B) of title 10, as added by subsection (b)(1), instead of an annuity for the surviving spouse. Any such determination and resulting change in beneficiary shall be effective as of the first day of the first month following the date of the determination.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

