<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5C6EBCBEFC2D47E18B17FD1DF3254613" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3152 IH: Rural Broadband Initiative Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3152</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150722">July 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to establish an Office of Rural Broadband
			 Initiatives in the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HDC56F42C431D41A2BBC4D498C4F3B600" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB794C0187AC04B4DBD35273332C4A755" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Broadband Initiative Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H01867215FA784F9AA765771ABE96826F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4FB7DD6141B3414A8A264435829790E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Rural Electrification Act of 1936 helped bring electricity and telephone service to rural America, thus removing major barriers to the development of our rural economies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H874680C8A36642E195264843D70F1BC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A lack of affordable broadband presents a similar barrier to the development of our rural economy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B352F0090884AA797CDF8EFBB288E3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the Federal Communications Commission, 53 percent of rural Americans lack access to service delivering broadband speeds of 25 Mbps for downloads and 3 Mbps for uploads.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57422630D91E464992FD925334EF5633"><enum>(4)</enum><text>High-speed broadband access helps rural communities compete and grow in our digital economy.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HD3C8CCA2CFB04768B089622894060E57"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of the Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that necessary funds should be made available to provide universal and affordable broadband access to the United States of America with a focus on underserved rural communities.</text>
		</section><section id="HAEF8CB878E4A4E6B9ABE5BB79F6BCCB0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Office of Rural Broadband Initiatives</header>
 <subsection id="HDA84A415AF4441B49E108DD72365FE1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VI of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/950bb">7 U.S.C. 950bb et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4FDAB0B6929D44D9A58E0B332982E25B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating sections 601 through 603 as sections 603 through 605, respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F2A13DD375E441E85B6CDA46BF37E77"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting before section 603 (as so redesignated) the following new sections:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8AB156A32A44B16A99FC56AFEC08A38" style="OLC"> <section id="H057623CB66F84AE387E8BA3790670491"><enum>601.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF3F49078DA234D1C90D7E5874D742FA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Rural Broadband Initiatives established by section 602(a)(1).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D03808FCAD740DBBC2940263B96A472"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Under Secretary</term> means the Under Secretary for Rural Broadband Initiatives appointed under section 602(a)(2).</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="H3FE5F25A80AB41B085F08E385B5D461C"><enum>602.</enum><header>Office of Rural Broadband Initiatives</header>
							<subsection id="H721580ED20D64EC5AACC9FE9957352A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="HFE0BB06BDCB540AD8F2EC848DDFDD5AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Department of Agriculture an office to be known as the <term>Office of Rural Broadband Initiatives</term>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H40323C5AA53C4651BF805001182F4D37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text>The head of the Office shall be the Under Secretary for Rural Broadband Initiatives, who shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F30D2C7D1104E9EA0DDBC4F5B366296"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC85F9D7CD83B429F8369B595C07340C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report directly to the Secretary.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AA31885941A40B0940E9022AD71DBC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header>
 <paragraph id="H136C863A8D5E4C9D81B40E039C217E16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D281A4BECA24DCEAA36EACE42D61AFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of this section, administer all rural broadband-related grant and loan programs previously administered by the Administrator of the Rural Utilities Service, including—</text>
 <clause id="HAC8212266A1945968C671C340C4B20F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the rural broadband access loan and loan guarantee program established under section 603;</text> </clause><clause id="HD45D84283D414F9C97F9C4C20331A102"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Community Connect Grant Program described in subpart A of part 1739 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H678C094045EF4C478854C07EA8F9B1D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Telecommunications Infrastructure Loan program established under this Act.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7205DADEAE344317BDD26732207AF31B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Under Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD998ABB237584FE9A51A89DA98E1F866"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct extensive, nationwide outreach to rural areas;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FF7BF2CA62E40B6BBAB8079D5538461"><enum>(B)</enum><text>foster the development of a comprehensive rural broadband strategic vision;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A269C4F138D4559B588AFBBBE916B95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>plan coordination of Federal resources for State, regional, and local governments to assist citizens living and working in rural areas;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB885CC1BEC784660BAC1906BA38E31FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assess all relevant technologies (including WiFi, WIMAX, DSL, cable, satellite, fiber, and broadband over power lines), as the technologies are able to support in whole or in part rural broadband needs and requirements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E68A908082F4CC485BE09B0349FC6E3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as a single information source for all rural broadband programs and services administered by Federal agencies, and coordinate the activities undertaken under Federal rural broadband programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1A6BE0AB95242598B654CCE94E343DB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to State, regional, and local governments to develop broadband deployment strategies.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA269232F24FE44F7BC7D39D561A1B9EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comprehensive rural broadband strategy</header>
 <paragraph id="HEC30DEC41C2A4BA38DB541B33A6F6256"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the appointment of the first Under Secretary, the Under Secretary shall submit to the President and Congress a report describing comprehensive rural broadband strategy that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8AB91925DEF2446888A4DD3AD7F5E405"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommendations—</text> <clause id="H02D144B1BC3A43AC83FF266BD3E011CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to promote interagency coordination of Federal agencies in regards to policies, procedures, and targeted resources, and to improve and streamline the policies, programs, and services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1375B4A64BFD45EF8CD8AB2EA39128E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to coordinate among Federal agencies regarding existing rural broad­band or rural initiatives that could be of value to rural broadband development;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC4207842660D43F0B2DBECE58337A8BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to address both short- and long-term solutions and needs assessments for a rapid build-out of rural broadband solutions and applications for Federal, State, regional, and local government policy makers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H937267E15FDF49BE9A0278CC4B53BF73"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to identify how specific Federal agency programs and resources can best respond to rural broadband requirements and overcome obstacles that currently impede rural broadband deployment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE24EA2E6F64A40C79E2CF992C50E2E07"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to promote successful model deployments and appropriate technologies being used in rural areas so that State, regional, and local governments can benefit from the cataloging of successes of other State, regional, and local governments; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF388DD076AD94AF68A3951B9DFC2B9C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of goals and timeframes to achieve the strategic plans and visions identified in the report.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BEFFD9F446641E9AE60A63A86380ACB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Under Secretary shall update and evaluate the report described in paragraph (1) on an annual basis.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A375367C5994CE99E42144808FEB8F0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rural Broadband Advisory Panel</header>
 <paragraph id="HD22347EBBE5A48A8905A245DD43C7204"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of appointment of the first Under Secretary, the Under Secretary shall submit to Congress a plan to establish a Rural Broadband Advisory Panel (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Panel</term>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35A197313C2B438E9BF9BC147BA3BECD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Panel shall be chaired by the Under Secretary or a designee.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AA027225CBB4C83B7C3198B16FB6099"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Panel shall be composed of representatives of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA799D4C3F77A4CF4A2AA2F54EC7ABF48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State government;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H237959D9AAB548598C0B1C65C45265A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H949FDA9102174549987879C8B898D7F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>communications equipment vendors (including broadband data service providers);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7BD69775BB84694B0CF3C642107F428"><enum>(D)</enum><text>public utility services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H716403EE796C4978956C758E02917C7C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>local exchange carriers;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C441D49970B4C0CBDD0039939CFA640"><enum>(F)</enum><text>wireless carriers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H552D70D436A94A84985836AA4FEEBF19"><enum>(G)</enum><text>satellite communications services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB78F8E42EEB47F8B6C3AC7280FC3AEA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>other appropriate public or private sector entities, as determined by the Under Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4431D6772944F8A9556F9D058F50F75"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Panel shall meet not less than 4 times each year.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H474F906F4F4742A585AE6C8591FD39CB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Panel shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA5E6856A690E4626B0D302FD0AEA3B2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assist the Under Secretary in updating the annual report described in subsection (c)(2);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43C492CEE5804C20A1EF03CE904F2968"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of all Federal broadband assistance programs and policies aimed at fostering broadband access in rural and underserved areas;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E3C90EE851240538EBB2C7A13CFE629"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluate best practices employed at the State and local government level to foster broadband access in rural and underserved areas; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9C1B935B32E44C6B6AD632E886D98D6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>cooperate with the Under Secretary in addressing and evaluating issues determined by the Under Secretary to be critical to fostering broadband access and connectivity in rural and underserved areas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1348D0D60F84DA49AB58BDAD217585B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Web-Based Clearinghouse</header><text>The Under Secretary shall establish a comprehensive and interactive rural broadband Web-based clearinghouse that describes options, opportunities, resources, successful public-private partnerships, comprehensive funding sources, and technology tutorials for rural broadband, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H12E15F4C7FA54077B4C266666E18355B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>case studies;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D475F4EB8684205BB55615AF04298C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>descriptions of best practices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD078803C167D494C89973A180B905734"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assessments of various technology solutions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H60E4BCA674EB4C609BDCB7F0E7DE98E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>feasibility studies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A34B91EFDB34000B9CFC6F499181D9A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>applications, including telework, telemedicine, distance learning, training, homeland security, senior citizen connectivity and program development, and business and economic development;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F0A11C42A2A4706BA2205C15356DC57"><enum>(6)</enum><text>rural broadband options and policies analysis; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F0591BD174345968620D6BC002C2378"><enum>(7)</enum><text>support for networks among rural communities and economic development agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07A14243E83840D4B89FAF5D4D1FE2EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 603 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (as so redesignated by subsection (a)(1)) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCF0F47C868D8466B8C04A33D1DC52CAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)(B), by striking <quote>subsection (k)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (l)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC9B82BDD60C4A1DA5DB0B3388EE14DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by striking <quote>Administrator</quote> and inserting <quote>Under Secretary</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB493AE41C854A5F8610180572DCC868"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (k) and (l) as subsections (l) and (m), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A48AD11221A494A90127AA0C54D631C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (j) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D94E3ED810A46AAA447B6AB9E689CEC" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HC4C05E61E70D40B489AA1EE7BDADEE75"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Rules revision</header>
 <paragraph id="HB6706ABC25304C519E3FA962C052D226"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of appointment of the first Under Secretary, the Under Secretary shall submit to Congress a revision of the rules and qualification criteria for the loan and loan guarantee programs under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72722FDC231D4809BBBF42690BD11AA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In preparing the revision, the Under Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF349C1FBB81246D9BE703ACEBBDBEA57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>emphasize streamlining the application process and processing time;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37A95897E25248289AC7E43288F60036"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the financial requirements for applicants do not unduly disqualify applicants that have demonstrated a viable business plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F4154C1564D4B209B694997ABB4AA77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not diminish the mission of the program to deliver broadband service to underserved rural areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H337A9F7A92D04824833253714584C75B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sufficiency of resources</header> <subsection id="H79863FC50B7A4934AE6FC09AD8157E2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to Congress a report describing the resources and staff necessary to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H983F0E26E8FB4A8597CF25D4ED0C0E76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preparation of report</header><text>The Secretary shall provide the Office of Rural Broadband Initiatives the resources and staff necessary to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6BE83F73171C42E79BB6B29CDDE9D93A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller General review</header>
 <paragraph id="H2723886B1A9045DD9A82F3342853E70D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall review the report submitted under subsection (a) for validity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HACC30D663EB94CBF804C307B911E9C0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the report is submitted under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings of the review under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


