<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBEC87FE26FCE46BD8E6E4F63A2623673" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 126 IH: Students Voicing Opinions in Today’s Elections (VOTE) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 126</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Election Assistance Commission to carry out a pilot program under which the
			 Commission shall provide funds to local educational agencies for
			 initiatives to provide voter registration information to secondary school
			 students in the 12th grade.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBB94A7DF3BBE48D38428AD2408C1F5B2" style="OLC">
		<section id="H3948EFABAF5C4CDA967A63FFEA68DE9C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Students Voicing Opinions in Today’s Elections (VOTE) Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H399E0B13D94D49E7A3CD5436367F6334"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for providing voter registration information to secondary school students prior to
			 graduation</header>
			<subsection id="H6E38B3B8A5684970980A1D5CF8814B4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Election Assistance Commission (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall carry out a pilot program under which the Commission shall provide funds during fiscal year
			 2015 to eligible local educational agencies for initiatives to provide
			 information on registering to vote in elections for public office to
			 secondary school students in the 12th grade.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H5CCE4D6C21C546A7A32DD4202BA9284E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A local educational agency is eligible to receive funds under the pilot program under this Act if
			 the agency submits to the Commission, at such time and in such form as the
			 Commission may require, an application containing—</text>
				<paragraph id="HF80C0FC624824691A76BEA2558C318CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the initiatives the agency intends to carry out with the funds;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H76AE64470952401DA5FD1BC6666A3ED7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimate of the costs associated with such initiatives; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD344CF907EC14E228A3173103A29242A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such other information and assurances as the Commission may require.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7ABA412ECD75434EB6635B09BBEDCF77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation with election officials</header><text>A local educational agency receiving funds under the pilot program shall consult with the State and
			 local election officials who are responsible for administering elections
			 for public office in the area served by the agency in developing the
			 initiatives the agency will carry out with the funds.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HEEAE64485D9343CBA574B0039D06FB4D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act, the terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act
			 of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF6B56036B2AB4F76B3F1C42E01A4C652"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports</header>
			<subsection id="HD2CCB9E6BDCB44ECB26A6061C3A0FEFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports by recipients of funds</header><text>Not later than the expiration of the 90-day period which begins on the date of the receipt of the
			 funds, each local educational agency receiving funds under the pilot
			 program under this Act shall submit a report to the Commission describing
			 the initiatives carried out with the funds and analyzing their
			 effectiveness.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H41622EF8C2F54B9E8E914CD3798251B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report by Commission</header><text>Not later than the expiration of the 60-day period which begins on the date the Commission receives
			 the final report submitted by a local educational agency under subsection
			 (a), the Commission shall submit a report to Congress on the pilot program
			 under this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9F7BC6BED9334098AE6695E6DBE14A6A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


