<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H98BD50ADA9BE456EB9CD049E4D8C627D" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1066 IH: Clinical Trials Modernization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1066</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150225">February 25, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000602">Mr. Pompeo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to promote the use of adaptive trial designs, Bayesian methods, and other innovative statistical methods in clinical protocols for drugs, biological products, and devices, and with respect to the requirement to conduct postapproval studies and clinical trials, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE03338BE7B704FB39D76A39C244281EA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE68990DB11AF409AA82166D71FC9F622" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clinical Trials Modernization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3F2298BFB02545A497998A8561B411A1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clinical trial modernization</header> <subsection id="H8C955B86A6D54968819A0850471B7D41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Proposals for use of innovative statistical methods in clinical protocols for drugs, biological products, and devices</header><text>Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 506F (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/356f">21 U.S.C. 356f</external-xref>) the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H207A1239F28E48EBB8881017E78CC40D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H662B151B8F114DACB696A1BEB7385F0D"><enum>507.</enum><header>Clinical trial modernization</header> 
<subsection id="H10CF4A9FC089453F96BF775D0E5B8F4A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To promote the efficiency of the development and regulatory review and approval, licensure, or clearance of drugs, biological products, and devices and the timely availability of innovative treatments, the Secretary shall, after providing notice and an opportunity for public comment, establish and implement a framework through which—</text> <paragraph id="H34477FB4AE27404AA35E55B350730E64"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sponsors of drugs, biological products, or devices may submit to the Secretary a proposal for the incorporation of adaptive trial designs, Bayesian methods, or other alternative statistical methods into proposed clinical protocols and marketing applications for drugs, biological products, or devices; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FB02AE22E374498BF1E8C83FB5B46FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary will commit to timelines for reviewing and providing feedback on proposals so submitted.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB8CAB8E5B5C248428D6F7E44A69EB756"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance addressing use of adaptive trial designs and Bayesian methods</header> <paragraph id="H82A6EAD461074321B6B1196BB4861233"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8D707EB715C045E7B51A5436B8D386A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update and finalize the draft guidance addressing the use of adaptive trial design for drugs and biological products; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H315D9CAD23654AC8B2DBF4D0EF38C70E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue draft guidance on the use of Bayesian methods in the development and regulatory review and approval, licensure, or clearance of drugs, biological products, and devices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA71B6DC32D724B75B1A770177038C0F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The guidances under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H1E0A9CA4383143D39AAE4731D57D9A2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish or clarify standards for using adaptive trial designs and Bayesian methods in clinical trials, including clinical trials that form the primary basis for approval, clearance, or licensure of the products involved (such as trials that provide substantial evidence for the approval of drugs);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2463306A23B54774BBD5D6A335FE5D21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a mechanism for sponsors to obtain feedback from the Secretary under section 507, as added by subsection (a), on technical issues related to modeling and simulations prior to—</text> <clause id="HC550F09C481744108F553B7242EB474A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>completion of such modeling or simulations; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H130FBD1A25A14734AD957D51017E7FA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the submission of resulting information to the Secretary;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H653E2F11FC90475C8B3F71BEC4C90814"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the types of quantitative and qualitative information required for review; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F1C11844E1646AAB73034AD86902154"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the recommended analysis methodology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42A8B47D11D24C15B791FB666128C989"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to updating or developing the guidances required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult, through a public meeting to be held no later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, with stakeholders including representatives of regulated industry, academia, patient advocacy organizations, and disease research foundations. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H326896B71BD24E15897D7EB3EB28D9A2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text>The Secretary shall, after providing notice and opportunity for public comment, publish—</text> <subparagraph id="H989F8C051844455DA63AA9BAEB97413D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the final guidance required by paragraph (1)(A) not later than 6 months after the date of the public meeting required by paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0777C71A7FB4A39AA2F2C867A7C8BDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the guidance required by paragraph (1)(B) not later than 12 months after the date of the public meeting required by paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D3163B9F9744F7EB5D8FA17BC9F2A71"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Review and revision of guidance documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall review and, as appropriate, revise the guidance documents required by subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) to reflect developments in statistical methods that could be appropriate for use in clinical trials, including clinical trials that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H33B8B78A93C646AEBCB8D617ED165F23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>form the primary basis for approval, clearance, or licensure of drugs, biological products or devices; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7BB3ECF6E71491A9B2258F86EE06679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide substantial evidence for the approval of drugs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H114562EE6F96440F98A44207C2CA8950" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Evaluations of required postapproval studies and clinical trials</header> 
<subsection id="HB602F2DD023147C1925BA58AD4C9C9CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505(o)(3) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(o)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAA722D9CEB48426DB039179F4D7D4FBD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HF15D1388D14E4D669C3A71FD527B76CC"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Evaluations of required postapproval studies and clinical trials</header> <clause id="HF7B214E474AE44008396F60183CF6C77"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process under which the Secretary, on the initiative of the Secretary or at the request of a responsible person, shall periodically evaluate a postapproval study or clinical trial required to be conducted under this paragraph to determine whether—</text> 
<subclause id="HA1C05BF3D8E04129AABC7BC50576F269"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the trial or study is no longer scientifically warranted; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB99BC1736D9A45D9995329246D9ED9CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the design, or the timelines applicable to the completion of, the study or trial should be renegotiated because of changes in medical practice or the standard of care.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H347DCA9F81E442C9A8B3514338931768"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Not scientifically warranted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a determination under clause (i)(I) that a postapproval study or clinical trial required to be conducted under this paragraph is no longer scientifically warranted, the Secretary shall no longer require the responsible person to conduct the study or trial.</text></clause> <clause id="H099D7FC8A59D4A15BCB6E053E13430EF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Renegotiation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a determination under clause (i)(II) that the design, or the timelines applicable to the completion of, a postapproval study or clinical trial required to be conducted under this paragraph should be renegotiated, the Secretary shall enter into negotiations with the responsible person to make such changes as may be necessary to such design or timelines as the Secretary determines are necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F068A0372B847D1917E2CCF85F4EB60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue draft guidance on the implementation of subparagraph (G) of section 505(o)(3) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(o)(3)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a). Not later than two years after such date of enactment, the Secretary shall issue final guidance on such implementation.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

