<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB834C9B1B64A4192B2E56F024E960C83" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3843 IH: Locatable Minerals Claim Location and Maintenance Fees Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3843</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151028">October 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize for a 7-year period the collection of claim location and maintenance fees, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H54A8FBA923094121BE2C23BC98238577" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFFF3E88E93CD44E7B03030E280BF7F26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Locatable Minerals Claim Location and Maintenance Fees Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H15C214F96AAD486FAB16B159699940E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is the following:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="HFFF3E88E93CD44E7B03030E280BF7F26" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H15C214F96AAD486FAB16B159699940E9" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB867A0ADC3334228B79F13EE740208A8" level="title">Title I—Mining Claim Location and Maintenance Fees</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE48DFFFF3C3448A0BBAE2E0C5094E008" level="section">Sec. 101. Definitions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HA0532D4F0BC44D46A8AA54634F0507D8" level="section">Sec. 102. Claim location and maintenance fees.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H8402B05BEE204BDA8EE40C9E7BA3D845" level="section">Sec. 103. Mining claim validity exams and mineral reports for areas segregated or withdrawn from
			 mineral entry.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE75030A5E0EB4CCFB82401F0685C6AAD" level="section">Sec. 104. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H9C439DA52C484BABA1B62F7FFA8CD09A" level="section">Sec. 105. Mineral potential reports and mining claim validity exams.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H686A556585DA4786880AC579BE1615A2" level="section">Sec. 106. United States mineral deposit database.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HDD7DA1895DD8405FBD37D6823CA57AAE" level="title">Title II—Department of the Interior Inactive and Abandoned Noncoal Mine Lands Program</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2FA4AF9D421E40A78A4596783A24BEB0" level="section">Sec. 201. Definitions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF22A6CC1135A415690AC1B60F000FE4A" level="section">Sec. 202. Establishment of inactive and abandoned noncoal mine lands program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCFDCAEDDDC7849C7A6A9A4D11FFA2112" level="section">Sec. 203. Inactive and abandoned mine land program partners.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H8D8F587B2CC74C5D845C8501F401B757" level="section">Sec. 204. Priority sites for Good Samaritan projects on Federal lands.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2DBDAB89A7EF471BA619DD75370E6105" level="section">Sec. 205. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H59291BAEC21547CF9D3536E965090148" level="title">Title III—Good Samaritan Remediation of Abandoned Mine Lands</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HAEE25494EB174FAF9D6A8E6058C0CF2F" level="section">Sec. 301. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HAD52273D88F24EE1BB060BDC39993CEB" level="section">Sec. 302. Definitions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H5DEF6FEA150240A9A4855FD3AD82EB90" level="section">Sec. 303. Permits for remediation of inactive or abandoned mine lands by Good Samaritans.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE3AB8EB5318D48E29D3A9F1316DFD161" level="section">Sec. 304. State or tribal programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HAE197160F5DC4F76BA04E6F355E4EBB8" level="section">Sec. 305. Enforcement.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1E828E77588B4F97A8B800F75F7F646D" level="section">Sec. 306. Grants eligibility.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HAF89E590249743C99A22721142BDCBFB" level="section">Sec. 307. Construction of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H11E94FD7330A4605B6C455DA37E4507A" level="section">Sec. 308. Use of projects to meet offsite mitigation requirements.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H59C7EA7BA55642F48D4702386029FA04" level="section">Sec. 309. State and tribal reclamation plans under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act
			 of 1977.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC35D7DAE5E364AF6AE7D8962EF43F8B7" level="section">Sec. 310. Savings provisions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H032B3794E74A476DBE65E47CFA9C15C8" level="section">Sec. 311. Sunset.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
		</section><title id="HB867A0ADC3334228B79F13EE740208A8"><enum>I</enum><header>Mining Claim Location and Maintenance Fees</header>
 <section id="HE48DFFFF3C3448A0BBAE2E0C5094E008"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HE58FE3358BB047799DBA5B4A4A7FA90B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claim</header><text>The term <term>claim</term> means an unpatented lode mining claim, placer claim, mill site, or tunnel site located under the general mining laws.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB8AD6EDEE244051B6103E8F4E1A03B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Claim holder and claimant</header><text>The terms <term>claim holder</term> and <term>claimant</term> mean the owner or holder of a claim.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H165C68733B5E4362B3759FBFE0CA66FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certified mineral examiner</header><text>The term <term>Certified Mineral Examiner</term> means an employee of the Federal Government who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8D086D26865147F499AF761A8B9850C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>possesses sufficient college education to qualify as a geologist, mining engineer, or metallurgical engineer; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B6F00FFC2854F29B15E9C6BFD1C7ED1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has completed training specified by the Chief Mineral Examiner of the Bureau of Land Management, Department of the Interior.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB26DC2739724B4E8E009AD8606414C3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certified review mineral examiner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Certified Review Mineral Examiner</term> means a Certified Mineral Examiner who is determined by the Bureau of Land Management Mineral Examiner Certification Panel to possess an additional breadth of training and experience that is sufficient to review mineral potential reports and mining claim validity exam reports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7C65B08081489884C478EE55C1FE9B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal lands</header><text>The term <term>Federal lands</term> means lands and interests in lands owned by the United States that are open to mineral entry and location, or that were open to mineral entry and location at the time of entry or location.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8041D38FEA804662BD927F8CCB227CB3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>General mining laws</header><text>The term <term>general mining laws</term> means those Acts that generally comprise chapters 2, 11, 12, 12A, 15, and 16, and sections 161 and 162, of title 30, United States Code, all Acts that are amendatory of or supplementary to any of the foregoing Acts, and the judicial and administrative decisions interpreting such Acts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F784934C02544E0867FB8D4D0A308CF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Locatable minerals</header><text>The term <term>locatable minerals</term> means those minerals held by the United States and not subject to disposition under—</text> <subparagraph id="H82A65AB5D9454A239446333E32190073"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H003E53B6F68B455AA0309A451EDA32AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1001">30 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEC81E0403914E42826E543933CA72BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Materials Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/601">30 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H762AB5E1361645F8BC9A5EDC0FFA4C83"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/351">30 U.S.C. 351 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA29EA1C0FC14021962A35B7F2A6935A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Mineral activities</header><text>The term <term>mineral activities</term> means any activity on Federal lands under a claim with or without a discovery, or off of claims, for mineral prospecting, exploration, development, mining, extraction, milling, beneficiation, processing, storage of mined or processed materials, or reclamation activities for any locatable mineral and uses that are reasonably incident thereto, including the construction and use of roads, transmission lines, water wells, pipelines, utility corridors, and other means of access across Federal lands for ancillary facilities used in conjunction with such activity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61429D411CA3401780DBC1A65DD932A5"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Mineral potential report</header><text>The term <term>mineral potential report</term> means a report described in section 204(c)(2)(12) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1714">43 U.S.C. 1714(c)(2)(12)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECFF19FD1F7841A2822154AB5978128F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Mining claim validity exam</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mining claim validity exam</term> means an examination of a mining claim to determine if it establishes a valid existing right in a valuable mineral deposit (as that term is used in section 2319 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/22">30 U.S.C. 22</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5864F4B2E5AF432080C39561E18700C2"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual, partnership, association, society, joint venture, joint stock company, firm, company, limited liability company, corporation, cooperative, or other organization, and any instrumentality of State or local government, including any publicly owned utility or publicly owned corporation of State or local government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02517E3C73194894A2C114BA42C06A19"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, unless otherwise specified.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1BE160FA5404B13B63833494733DF76"><enum>(13)</enum><header>United States Mineral Deposit Database Project</header><text>The term <term>United States Mineral Deposit Database Project</term> means the interactive database of mines and mineral deposits in the United States administered by the United States Geological Survey Mineral Resources Program.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="HA0532D4F0BC44D46A8AA54634F0507D8"><enum>102.</enum><header>Claim location and maintenance fees</header>
 <subsection id="HCB3080680FB24D8F86B614F802FF66BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Location fee</header><text>For each claim located after the date of enactment of this Act, a claimant shall pay the Secretary a location fee of $37 not later than 90 days after the date of location, at the time the location notice is recorded with the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HECDF1D91FD474B9D8C4A6F4DB6A4B96A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual claim maintenance fee</header><text>Commencing the first calendar year after the date of enactment of this Act, a claimant shall pay the Secretary on or before September 1 of each year, a claim maintenance fee of $155 per 20.66-acre claim or fraction thereof to maintain the claim for the following assessment year beginning at noon on September 1. Payment of such claim maintenance fee shall be in lieu of the assessment work requirement contained in the general mining laws and the related filing requirements contained in subsections (a) and (c) of section 314 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1744">43 U.S.C. 1744</external-xref>).</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HE0A15A41AA0D4E0B85FB3532A9248890"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver for holders of 10 or fewer claims</header>
 <paragraph id="H6703286D3AD946A9AEA675FB67C9B730"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The claim maintenance fee required under this section shall be waived for a claimant who certifies in writing to the Secretary that on the date the payment was due—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H76A134FF3CBF4929BC33C884C3BCFE41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the claimant was—</text> <clause id="HB612F211E1FE401E835D4F9D4FBDA059"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the holder of not more than 10 lode claims on Federal lands; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H929967067144465BAD54678675D3DBDF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an association that held less than or equal to 320 acres; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD18D730E3E324F1A8F6FBD6165335384"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the claimant has performed assessment work sufficient to maintain the claims held by the claimant for the assessment year ending on noon of September 1 of the calendar year in which the claim maintenance fee payment was due.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13B89FD3757F478A92EC2F0DCF62B9ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Holder</header><text>As used in paragraph (1), the term <term>holder</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H939C6709FD4D4C5C8569CC816FA3F56E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the claimant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40B95AE47CDF435AADFBCA44B013E972"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the spouse and dependent children (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/152">section 152</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), of the claimant; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEAF3DDB5268456587A391D3C2A1ED93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a person affiliated with the claimant, including—</text> <clause id="HABF4D303CFEC4A449FAE32DD5908F378"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a person controlled by, controlling, or under common control with the claimant; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBC198DD548044D75A937ECDFB46AC8B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a subsidiary or parent company or corporation of the claimant.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC8FABFF5EF45FA88E6DB3612856A3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certification processing fee</header><text>The Secretary shall charge a certification processing fee of $30 for the filing of a certification under this subsection.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD7BE9441DFE4441AB99DE9B5BE1A240"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Suspension of claim maintenance and waiver of cost recovery fees</header>
 <paragraph id="H64DA35631F1B408C934D72C10A366736"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claim maintenance fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The claim maintenance fees required under this section shall be suspended for any claims of a claimant for an area that was open to mineral entry and location at the time of entry or location that has subsequently been segregated or withdrawn from mineral entry and location by order of the Secretary or a law enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act until such time as the area is reopened to mineral entry, or the claimant has submitted a notice or permit to explore or develop their claims or is actively mining.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1C4FA9C846D429B9A8A599363E53ECD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost Recovery Fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fees required by part 3000 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, and any substantially similar fee charged for a mining claim validity exam, shall be waived for any claimant with claims in an area that was open to mineral entry and location at the time of claim location that has subsequently been segregated or withdrawn from mineral entry and location by order of the Secretary or a law enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3312BC6604346EAB7201CA41D08F2F3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effects of payment</header>
 <paragraph id="H22195417704844608D7DDAF99AFEF977"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Timely payment of the location and claim maintenance fees under this section secures the rights of the holder of a mining claim against the Federal Government both prior to and after discovery of valuable mineral deposits, to use and occupy Federal lands under the provisions of the general mining laws for all mineral activities. This section shall not be construed to amend section 910 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/53">30 U.S.C. 53</external-xref>) or in any way affect the law of possession or the doctrine of pedis possessio.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CA1DD5311C740018B019B8598243411"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver of claim maintenance fee</header><text>In the case of a claim holder who qualifies for a waiver of payment of the claim maintenance fee under subsection (c), timely payment of the location fee and compliance with the assessment work required under the general mining laws (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/28-28e">30 U.S.C. 28–28e</external-xref>) secures the rights of the holder of a claim, both prior to and after discovery of valuable mineral deposits, to use and occupy Federal lands under the provisions of the general mining laws for all mineral activities.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80A4D37BA55341AFB6FA8FBCC31379B1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Forfeiture of unpatented claim for failure To pay maintenance fee</header>
 <paragraph id="H81AD9D61170E4830B40132FB86DDDEBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Failure to pay</header><text>Failure to pay a claim maintenance fee or a location fee under this section for an unpatented mining claim shall subject the claim to forfeiture by the claim holder as provided in this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD31F21E8EE146E8AC0018D064A69EA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall provide the claim holder—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC75010A3F534EF6BBF85C5007777934"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of the failure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE12BC15B92034E8796FF6973B4E308F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the opportunity to correct the failure within 45 days after the claim holder’s receipt of the notice.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CFC9792DDA248EDAA3CBE5BEF05F348"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>To correct the failure the claim holder must, within such 45-day period, pay twice the amount of claim maintenance fee that would otherwise have been required to be timely paid. The Secretary shall specify the amount that must be paid in the notice under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD207A9A9E7C4769A66AEB87E0395673"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header><text>Failure by the claim holder to make a timely and proper payment in the amount specified in the notice, within 45 days after the claim holder’s receipt of the notice, shall constitute a forfeiture of the mining claim by the claim holder by operation of law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H926B3EA067394C36BAB300A3CC6A66A2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective period of fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fees imposed under this section shall apply during the period beginning September 1, 2016, and ending August 31, 2022.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H8402B05BEE204BDA8EE40C9E7BA3D845"><enum>103.</enum><header>Mining claim validity exams and mineral reports for areas segregated or withdrawn from mineral
 entry</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">All mining claim validity exams shall be completed by Certified Mineral Examiners and reviewed by Certified Review Mineral Examiners.</text>
 </section><section id="HE75030A5E0EB4CCFB82401F0685C6AAD"><enum>104.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior to carry out mining law administration program operations $40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2026.</text>
 </section><section id="H9C439DA52C484BABA1B62F7FFA8CD09A"><enum>105.</enum><header>Mineral potential reports and mining claim validity exams</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Mineral potential reports for areas withdrawn from mineral entry, and any mining claim validity exam on claims located within those areas, must be completed or prepared by a Certified Mineral Examiner and reviewed by Certified Review Mineral Examiner.</text>
			</section><section id="H686A556585DA4786880AC579BE1615A2"><enum>106.</enum><header>United States mineral deposit database</header>
 <subsection id="HB1661816876A46ACB46D1C8BE24D25DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Geological Survey shall enter into separate memorandum of understanding to share data for the purpose of expanding and maintaining the United States Mineral Deposit Database, with each of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDDEA2F00A43C44FEA0D199BE766FE928"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Land Management;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EAB5C2262D549D698740CE354779ABC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB88FE99052DE4457A42DCEA44D51984C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Chief Forester of the Forest Service.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B27AE106B294086B04FBD7BE81E4361"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>From amounts available for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2022 for operations to administer the mining laws, the Secretary may use not more than $1,000,000 to support the United States Mineral Deposit Database of which not more than 5 percent may be used for overhead expenses.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="HDD7DA1895DD8405FBD37D6823CA57AAE"><enum>II</enum><header>Department of the Interior Inactive and Abandoned Noncoal Mine Lands Program</header>
 <section id="H2FA4AF9D421E40A78A4596783A24BEB0"><enum>201.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HAE463F417B044028A52904156B621DA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Environmental hazard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental hazard</term> means degradation of air, soil, or water resources resulting from the effects of past mining practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B8DC42224F9495680077059359596FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historic mine residue</header><text>The term <term>historic mine residue</term> means mine residue, or conditions related to an inactive or abandoned mine site that pollute the environment, resulting from prior mining activities, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H52ED53D6354A46ADA90CDB458056D830"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tailings or mine waste piles;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H64A99D298D5741DB992A68F1D07D1515"><enum>(B)</enum><text>abandoned equipment (or materials in such equipment); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HED2FF5839B2C448298AEEF0DEBFA9C2A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>acidic or otherwise polluted flows in surface or ground water.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H155C8187C66C4022A3FAD3EADD0C2BC3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inactive and abandoned noncoal mine lands</header><text>The term <term>inactive and abandoned noncoal mine lands</term> means any location of a noncoal mine, including mill sites and processing sites, that was inactive or abandoned before January 1, 1981, and that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H12A9CC0232A24EC59EAA2597AEF6E611"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contains historic mine residue;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H154A6978AFB34463B472FA2E9A77BC1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not owned by any person who caused or contributed to the historic mine residue;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6573C58BFBDB46F0988FBFAA0452F904"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was used for the production of a noncoal mineral; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H524082C728A2435D845B4D330275E492"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is no longer in operation and is not subject to a temporary shutdown, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17AFCDD3A6794C62A18E1AC2D9263FF7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Physical safety hazard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>physical safety hazard</term> means any dangerous condition or effect resulting from past mining practices, that poses a risk of death or serious injury to the public, livestock, or wildlife.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BF252EE65C04655957C41A363F98757"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9FB5A800D474ED585807BB14A9F1A51"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Water resources</header><text>The term <term>water resources</term> means any watershed, ground water, water course, or lake.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="HF22A6CC1135A415690AC1B60F000FE4A"><enum>202.</enum><header>Establishment of inactive and abandoned noncoal mine lands program</header>
 <subsection id="H6BFA74D1C8634EC1A2882A4EC4C58636"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of the Interior a program to be known as the Abandoned Noncoal Mine Lands Program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>). The Program shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2D101471D15840B7BE11AC724F7468DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of program</header><text>Under the Program, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2AD3490433704B808D64315EA8324A11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify, secure, and remediate physical safety hazards and environmental hazards associated with inactive and abandoned noncoal mine lands that are located on, or affecting, Federal public lands, including such hazards on other lands that are adjacent to such Federal lands;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H457E8D8D2F684C49B97343DF32967E6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain an inventory of the sites of such inactive and abandoned noncoal mines, affected Federal public lands, and other lands that are adjacent to such Federal public lands, including such sites that have been remediated in whole or in part, and associated water resources; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41645B70EDC74248BE0977ACF43BF49A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify the persons, if any, who are responsible for paying the costs to remediate such hazards.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC29FCD2F7FA4450CABC105152D67A359"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priorities</header><text>In securing and remediating hazards under this title, the Secretary shall give priority (in the following order of priority) to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE4B242D1F0A04A8AAC277D1F3B9EA85F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the protection of public health, safety, and general welfare from the adverse effects of inactive and abandoned noncoal mine lands; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9B5602E13E4405892169F4D81CBF9CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reclamation of land and water resources degraded by the adverse effects of such mines lands.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCFDCAEDDDC7849C7A6A9A4D11FFA2112"><enum>203.</enum><header>Inactive and abandoned mine land program partners</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, where appropriate, shall seek out Federal agencies or departments, State agencies, Indian tribes, nonprofit organizations, individuals, and corporations to participate as partners, including partners that are Good Samaritans (as that term is defined in title III), to facilitate remediation and securing of physical safety or environmental hazards under this title.</text>
			</section><section id="H8D8F587B2CC74C5D845C8501F401B757"><enum>204.</enum><header>Priority sites for Good Samaritan projects on Federal lands</header>
 <subsection id="HEFC877711EB3447A8E78E8F0B7735AA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification required</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, in consultation with other Federal land management agencies, shall identify a minimum of 20 priority sites on Federal land containing inactive or abandoned mine sites suitable for Good Samaritan projects under title III.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H80205F30450E4841A4261C62ADD7BE5A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nominations</header><text>In identifying priority sites under subsection (a), the Secretaries shall accept nominations from the public.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6660228192A5498BB145EB7832616EEF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual review</header><text>The Secretaries shall annually review the sites identified under subsection (a) and identify additional priority sites as appropriate.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2DBDAB89A7EF471BA619DD75370E6105"><enum>205.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title $17,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text>
			</section></title><title id="H59291BAEC21547CF9D3536E965090148"><enum>III</enum><header>Good Samaritan Remediation of Abandoned Mine Lands</header>
 <section id="HAEE25494EB174FAF9D6A8E6058C0CF2F"><enum>301.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote>Good Samaritan Cleanup of Abandoned Mine Lands Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAD52273D88F24EE1BB060BDC39993CEB"><enum>302.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text>
 <paragraph id="H34AF0C8830E74F9A949E12CCC44A0782"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2C7D2A079104780905F1D9B39633BC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cooperating person</header><text>The term <term>cooperating person</term> means any person (other than a Federal agency) that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF71E3466FCD24F46ADDAFE15558AD29E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a Good Samaritan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98E58FA1840546EBBDC7E96CDDF4B993"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assists another Good Samaritan in a remediation project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB081894C789A46AC9831404F6A088AD6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is identified as a cooperating person in a permit issued under this title.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC36FA26AA904C138663E5385EB2A054"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental laws</header><text>The term <term>environmental laws</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H07E3B00CD795476983847F7AADFCFF8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) and any State law implementing a permit program under section 402(b) or 404(g) of such Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA0DC9E178D745218D8DDE329F201BD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA405786C96854F6E8BD13804500B510E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal land management agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal land management agency</term> means any agency of the Federal Government authorized by statute to exercise jurisdiction, custody, or control over lands of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB1CECC00CCFF460D89EFE8F1DA0B0AD9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Good Samaritan</header><text>The term <term>Good Samaritan</term> means any person that did not participate in any way in the creation of, or activities that caused, any historic mine residue at the inactive or abandoned mine site and that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCDD3D8467095419BBA682602D095236D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has an ownership interest in the inactive or abandoned mine site, but—</text> <clause id="HCC5EE60131614791B876FE9D851F4091"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not liable or potentially liable for remediation costs related to the historic mine residue at the inactive or abandoned mine site, or affiliated with any other person potentially so liable through any contractual, corporate, or financial relationship (other than a contractual, corporate, or financial relationship that is created by the instruments by which the ownership interest in the inactive or abandoned mine site is conveyed or financed or by a contract for the sale of goods or services); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H75B10A52D05D43F2A3E2CE809D592BFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not a successor entity to a business entity that was liable or potentially liable for such remediation costs;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C0F0CAFC59E43C6A321EC48994302E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has an ownership interest in the inactive or abandoned mine site that was acquired through the inheritance of a patented mining claim; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB903961E92414DD5A22C9CF0149EB98E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has no ownership interest in the inactive or abandoned mine site and had no such an interest at any time during or since the creation of the historic mine residue at the site.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H996B1AA050754967B1E73B25A06505F5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Historic mine residue</header><text>The term <term>historic mine residue</term> means mine residue, or conditions related to an inactive or abandoned mine site that pollute the environment, resulting from prior mining activities, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H523A3C76C4CD4FE69F88B2B54786CF3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tailings or mine waste piles;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAED588D7373E446EBA38486A19D93D15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>abandoned equipment (or materials in such equipment); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB488FF2EBEAE4FAEB0596FF4F8B60EAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>acidic or otherwise polluted flows in surface or ground water.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF6FF7A0CDD6C4401858215BD760F7297"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Inactive or abandoned mine site</header><text>The term <term>inactive or abandoned mine site</term> means any mine site, including any mill or processing site, that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1662FC43FB6742B7B17BB97A441D99E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contains historic mine residue;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H016B8C017FEB47739CC7879FAD605F68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not owned by any person who caused or contributed to the historic mine residue;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B68F0F8BB0248F983B6E5C2A86259AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was used for the production of a mineral-bearing ore or coal; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H511DDEBF54404BE4B126E80F37DED26A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is no longer in operation and is not subject to a temporary shutdown, as determined by the permitting authority.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3E48BC0AE12B4678ACB58622D3716E0C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Indian country</header><text>The term <term>Indian country</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1151 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC34F47DEA2FC49F2A98CAAA6325EE0E6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian tribe</term> means an Indian tribe that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8492DB4D210B42BDA4BA95B5696C2936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is federally recognized; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC638DCA485E7475388F8D89CE2747380"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an Alaska Native Corporation as defined under section 1602 of title 43, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C878A1E27AF458E98885B91F3B2DA3C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Lead agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lead agency</term> means a State or tribal agency designated under section 304(c)(1) as the lead agency responsible for carrying out permitting responsibilities of the State or Indian tribe under this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H715DD6D578024607BA9557529BFF5433"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Offsite mitigation requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>offsite mitigation requirement</term> means a requirement imposed under another Federal law to improve, enhance, restore, or create a wetland, stream, or habitat conservation area to offset or compensate for adverse impacts to similar ecosystems resulting from the development of a natural resource or other commercial activity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCBC81BDB91043B8ACCDE9FFE077D1DE"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Permitting authority</header><text>The term <term>permitting authority</term> means the Administrator or, in the case of a State or tribal program authorized by the Administrator under section 304, the lead agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9DFF628034F407F94D05E4D41478D7F"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Remediation</header><text>The term <term>remediation</term> means activities to clean up or otherwise mitigate the impacts of historic mine residue.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF530C35D722E47D9935FF9526D2990BF"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any of the 50 States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, and any other territory or possession over which the United States has jurisdiction.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H5DEF6FEA150240A9A4855FD3AD82EB90"><enum>303.</enum><header>Permits for remediation of inactive or abandoned mine lands by Good Samaritans</header>
 <subsection id="H47F281DA5B3D4B369536B061AAC4D59A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A permitting authority may issue a permit to a Good Samaritan to carry out a project in accordance with this section.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H89947AFAF4DE4468AB093F8BB26CFAFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header>
					<paragraph id="H4937ECB533C34ED99EFE69DDEF941060"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose of project</header>
 <subparagraph id="H834412CCCC1E4D67AA93CC454EF99656"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A permitting authority may issue a permit under this section for a project to improve the environment (including water quality) by carrying out remediation at or related to an inactive or abandoned mine site.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD7E9366D5E234F49896D18DD0EE07C32"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Water quality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A permitting authority shall ensure that remediation carried out pursuant to a permit issued under this section—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HB01D1D8462844D87AB6FF8CF8880924F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assists in the attainment of applicable water quality standards to the extent reasonable and practicable under the circumstances; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H53922A8FF40147D0A122C6EA7FD75816"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not result in water quality that is worse than the baseline water condition.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H56153AE6372A4E119AC30ED65878FE99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A permitting authority may not issue a permit under this section for a project at or related to a mine site included on the National Priorities List developed by the President in accordance with section 105(a)(8)(B) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9605">42 U.S.C. 9605(a)(8)(B)</external-xref>) or a mine site at which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency or another Federal, State, or tribal agency is taking an environmental enforcement or response action, unless the permitting authority determines, after consultation with any other interested agency, that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAF5A3B355C1C4982BDB5AE1A863806D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposed project is not inconsistent, and will not interfere, with any other planned remediation at the mine site that is reasonably likely to occur; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H92BAF1D09961446781C6FFF3AD4768E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the proposed project will accelerate environmental improvements.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H230590CBD86A45B3AEF85D553B29DC30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permit applications</header> <paragraph id="H81F2B1675BA14D12B599DD1C41782BBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A permitting authority shall require an application for a permit under this section to include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD05388D818604783A0A2520F784F13A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the project site (including the boundaries of the project site and any degraded waters related to the project site);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F722ED365EB45F4B0A207AD84733F2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of—</text> <clause id="H6C7B4F767B434C52975572FEED6116C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any current owner of the property on which the project is proposed to be carried out;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE2748DEF0C564C6EA4254FF724613515"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any person with a legal right to exclude other persons from the project site or affect activities on the project site, with a description of those legal rights;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC9AED63573054C22BA01AD85B38C675C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for project sites on Federal lands, the Federal land management agency; and</text> </clause><clause id="H29224EB792124974A3224782C34E6C95"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>based on the conduct of an inquiry that is reasonable under the circumstances—</text>
 <subclause id="H9123001F5F94499EB369D6F52FFAFF82"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all persons that may be legally responsible for remediation of the project site; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H46B192F2C00F43068F46D71F4A56C909"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any relationship between those persons and the applicant;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C46D84B3E144B089316026BD8E61840"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any contractual ties or other legal relationship between the applicant and all persons with responsibility for compliance with environmental laws at the project site;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58BD7C9221AA4051B1F653181D298541"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a general description of the known and identifiable baseline conditions, including conditions existing prior to the commencement of mining activities, as of the date of submission of the application, of the environment affected by the historic mine residue to be remediated, including, if available, any sampling data or information regarding the extent of contamination;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75266EB87D6E4EE29DF24C92045C2E83"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <clause id="H975085C2FACD4B758FB9E65C3FE09C55"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the historic mine residue proposed to be remediated;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4E66D419D25349DABCCF0DD11ACCD034"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the nature and scope of the proposed remediation, including—</text> <subclause id="HB55B26DAC6694EA09006D8989F26DFD1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any proposed recycling or reprocessing of the historic mine residue, how the recycling or reprocessing relates to the remediation, and where the recycling or reprocessing will occur; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8619C8F3B25F497B8B693871AE0FFB04"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the manner in which the proposed remediation will mitigate the drainage from the inactive or abandoned mine site to improve water quality, if applicable;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H8FBC3A5ABB01444D886B5A62F809BC7F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the remediation alternatives, if any, considered in developing the proposed remediation plan for the project site;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5761CC18E9A648A58B2F17AAB60090B0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>engineering plans for the project;</text> </clause><clause id="HD961F6230CAA412E8F92245B659098CB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>how any material related to the inactive or abandoned mine site that is identified or listed as hazardous waste under the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6901">42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.</external-xref>) will be disposed of;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H856DCEE87EED407E9D370226AD583DEF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a monitoring program proposed to be carried out following completion of the remediation, if applicable, that will be implemented to evaluate the effects of the remediation on the environment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H21610EF90ABF40ACAEAC8B9B4CF1874A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the capacity (including technical and administrative) of the applicant to carry out the proposed activities and any terms of the permit for which the application is being submitted;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0109B271EB184CCEA64535556EAB3500"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a plan for any operation and maintenance related to the proposed remediation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09539D02718943F2901F138AEDD31AD3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a proposed schedule for activities to be carried out under the project, including an expected completion date for the remediation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60464724F50A4F00BA69DACB57AE19DD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a budget for the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC043B99FF144E1BB24BD5DA88AAEA73"><enum>(I)</enum><text>evidence satisfactory to the permitting authority that the applicant has sufficient financial resources to ensure that the activities proposed to be carried out by the applicant, including any operation and maintenance activities related to the remediation, will be carried out under the permit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA52FC15539354816A1760EBE5C14F9D4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>an identification of any cooperating persons and a description of activities proposed to be carried out by such persons;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B09B9ADE4EC422383A0B4723B8E7A92"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE27369C095B04E89B40292AB34A2D7AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any recognition for excellence in environmental compliance, reclamation, or remediation received by the applicant or any cooperating person identified under subparagraph (J); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB6DD6E9C9B88404F837576F99E608679"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the history of any noncompliance with environmental laws by the applicant or any cooperating person identified under subparagraph (J) during the 5-year period preceding submission of the application; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB0B3A36E70AC4B14A702491184ECF2D3"><enum>(L)</enum><text>if the applicant intends to use the project to comply with an offsite mitigation requirement, a reference to the offsite mitigation requirement and any related permit.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCC3BEAB1AFC4910A8ECC1500CC23EEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA8A4BBE5AF3B473793EEBFAB861B29F6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State, local, and tribal communities</header><text>As soon as practicable after receiving an application under this section, a permitting authority shall provide notice of the application, including a copy of the application, to—</text>
 <clause id="HE4B9A7E700E444B8958E1DDFB81D927B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each local government located within a radius of 20 miles of the project site;</text> </clause><clause id="H7FF4207356A2483A8EB7154F8F67FBB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each Federal, State, and tribal agency that the permitting authority determines may have an interest in the application; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD3E1E0FF0FA140ADA46D1B7722C961FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the project site lies in the headwater area of a major drainage basin, local governments located outside of the 20-mile radius of the project site that are downstream of the project site and may be affected by a discharge resulting from activities carried out pursuant to the project.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAF13DF5D6E9434B80D7F92D7C90FA73"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving an application under this section, a permitting authority shall provide to the public notice of the application.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCFBB6EEF925F4BD1A9E60E81A4D77F43"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigative sampling</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4EAB2200DC444E5F86B066FA76123D78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A permitting authority may, upon request, authorize a person to carry out investigative sampling, as determined appropriate by the permitting authority, prior to submitting an application for a permit under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H81CFA3FC1E254AFE9370AED9DAB67349"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of authorization</header><text>An authorization to carry out investigative sampling under this section shall, with respect to the authorized activities, have the same effect as a permit for the purposes of subsection (g).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B69AF147BFF4111BABB1B0D3E0F6CD3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public participation</header>
 <paragraph id="H205E7E35C1724801BE5BDD742A500ACD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text>Prior to issuing a permit under this section, a permitting authority shall conduct a public hearing in the vicinity of the proposed project site, and shall give public notice of the hearing not later than 30 days before the date of the hearing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H848D097200E44AB29ED7B5E29D3B8B9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Draft permit</header><text>The permitting authority shall include a draft permit in the notice of a hearing to be conducted under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56DBA5A1F8434AE089DBB7A861BB9221"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Comments</header><text>The permitting authority shall provide the applicant and the public with the opportunity to—</text> <subparagraph id="H48C60A5F3D9C470AACDCB021CDC92EFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comment on the draft permit at the public hearing; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6FEAD2759DF454E988A03020746DE3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit written comments to the permitting authority during the 30-day period following the hearing.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65F5F2FB97024AAF9DA9F1B435B532B5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Permit issuance</header> <paragraph id="HB43099323682413E96A665FCC040830A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>A permitting authority shall issue a permit or deny a permit application under this section not later than—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7D1B371293FC410985C70EBBB7C481D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after the date on which the permitting authority receives a complete application for the permit, as determined by the permitting authority; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAB170A75BE6437D9144C5907E9A76F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such later date as may be determined by the permitting authority, with the agreement of the applicant.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CF77AB9CE764B03B0393AF01535F217"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Constructive denial</header><text>If the permitting authority does not issue a permit or deny the permit application by the applicable date described in paragraph (1), the application shall be considered to be denied by the permitting authority.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H12D5B54C09EB45A6A786695AFE3FABD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency consultation</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H77CDD739E11944EAAAAF91C42A29F3C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In considering whether to issue a permit for a project to be carried out on Federal lands, a permitting authority shall consult with any applicable Federal land management agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC267687F04047A4BF00091299F74691"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Objection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A permitting authority may not issue a permit under this section if—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H3C64BFCE870C4570B0A72771823C31B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proposed project site is not a priority site designated under section 204; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB821E2264E0446B0A52CD12F0E0AD2E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the permitting authority receives an objection to the proposed permit from a Federal land management agency with jurisdiction over the project site.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86833B229B8747BF95C9E718676D85F4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Permit contents</header>
 <paragraph id="H993AC9F89E6C4A73A34FF1D54BB987F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A permitting authority shall include in a permit issued under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="HD545D22D5F81499F8C04B0D72CAF2516"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the activities authorized by the permit, including a description of any activities to be carried out by a cooperating person in accordance with paragraph (5);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F1C8C90D7504C9CB595F16755C65643"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a schedule for the activities to be carried out under the project, in accordance with paragraph (3), including an end date by which the permittee shall complete the permitted activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97F173A0025D432FA7C77EFA76C87859"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conditions requiring the permittee to—</text> <clause id="HB0C241F327A94D96AEB94520F44EAAF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>secure, for all activities authorized under the permit, all authorizations, licenses, and permits required under law;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA1307EEDE8264BBA8D5A4C935478D985"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish and maintain records, conduct monitoring (as described in paragraph (4)), and provide such other information as may be reasonably necessary to ensure the project will result in improvement to the environment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7F745548FBFB44E793151FCE13FBBCFB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>minimize any short-term adverse environmental impacts from the remediation, to the extent practicable;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F6FFA0BEEAE4E8199C161FF99DC7EB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a right of entry to the project site for the permitting authority to inspect and collect such information as is reasonably necessary to carry out this title;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC40E96F15F7844D2B3B68ED31E6F7A5D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>if the project to be carried out under the permit will be used by the permittee to comply with an offsite mitigation requirement, a reference to the offsite mitigation requirement and any related permit; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B1580BDEA0643CAA1B8E1DB30308B47"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other terms and conditions determined appropriate by the permitting authority.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFAD52729BB594F3CB38BA50753D26DD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Benchmarks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A permitting authority shall ensure that a permit issued under this section is site- and situation-specific, relying on pre-mining conditions and conditions existing as of the date of issuance of the permit to determine appropriate water quality or other environmental benchmarks to achieve in carrying out remediation under the permit.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D88B5A47EE444ED9A1F2257CF138A33"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>A permitting authority shall require activities authorized by a permit issued under this section to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D2D35CD5ABB40F3A794EF60D702FCEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>commence not later than the date that is 1 year after the date on which the permit is issued; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09DC3C5B5E914EB49D5D91FCC68C9A62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continue until completed, with temporary suspensions permitted during adverse weather or other circumstances, as approved by the permitting authority.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6BDDA374F2446738F03E0048387D06A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Monitoring</header>
 <subparagraph id="H42928860438E4B3B8075A63B7906F092"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A permitting authority shall require a permittee to take such actions as the permitting authority determines are necessary to ensure, where appropriate, baseline, remedial alternative, and postremediation monitoring of the environment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8F613A42BC84676AC6B64F6F8EF297C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>In selecting the type and frequency of monitoring requirements to be included in a permit under this paragraph, the permitting authority shall—</text>
 <clause id="HE9E1C68D58284EAB8CF0A6A2D2578667"><enum>(i)</enum><text>balance the utility of information obtained through monitoring against the cost of the monitoring, based on the circumstances relating to the project; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H75F8DDE326B54C539AD7C15D82979F29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>take into account the scope of the project.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HECA770944C5249E98CF0085DF424C2B9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cooperative activities</header><text>A permitting authority may approve in a permit the conduct of project activities by cooperating persons if, as determined by the permitting authority, the cooperative arrangement will effectively accomplish the purposes of this title.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC009CFF777144E5869A7052FB2AB428"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effect of permit</header>
 <paragraph id="H3CC1311C46D0461FA52CD22455F998EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person authorized by a permit issued under this section to carry out activities—</text> <subparagraph id="HBC8F1E50AEB64904A2E9DC9007B50255"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be deemed to be in compliance with environmental laws with respect to such activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6B7088F8BF242DB9B2CDF5F2E4A3802"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be liable under environmental laws with respect to such activities, including for any costs or damages deriving from the prior activities of others at the project site.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF2F7AFCB03E4D55A84FECBA08461DAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply if—</text> <subparagraph id="H0326B4DDB8DA4BD4B7A87E49CC0F9878"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person impedes or fails to facilitate a response action, remediation, or other natural resource restoration activity at the project site;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H483A763043014332B674CCBF5D101783"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the person exacerbates the pollution from historic mine residue as a result of gross negligence or intentional misconduct, in which case the person may be liable under environmental laws for costs or damages resulting from such gross negligence or intentional misconduct; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14EDBCA2611E4D558CDC89C5654E11B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information supplied to the permitting authority in the permit application is subsequently determined to contain a dishonest, fraudulent, or materially misleading statement or omission, in which case the permit shall be deemed to have been invalid beginning on the date the permit was issued, and shall have no force or effect.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA348EA0478E14F308B6F614B5E4B4489"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administration of permits</header>
					<paragraph id="HCD94209B95A6488CA9E38B9CFF8AE7A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Modification or termination of permits</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB302FBEF3749470FBE465A1C85D89692"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>A permitting authority may—</text> <clause id="H7C7E3FFFD278433D87B3D20EB5B72408"><enum>(i)</enum><text>extend the period during which a permit is valid under procedures established for such purpose by the permitting authority; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4EFAC03099D24ED987EE8C6FC3CDF5DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>modify or terminate a permit for cause, including misrepresentation or a violation of a permit.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9500722E5E64B86ADAA77BDEB475648"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless the permitting authority has extended the period during which a permit is valid, the authority to carry out activities under a permit issued under this section shall terminate—</text>
 <clause id="HE26CD5A445064A56ACA3CAAFB4368470"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the activities do not commence by the date that is 1 year after the date on which the permit is issued;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H988118DD1D5843F19264432247529CE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the activities are discontinued or not completed by the end date specified in the permit; or</text> </clause><clause id="HEF055BC41D644D99AE649FDA2C411D37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on any other grounds determined appropriate by the permitting authority.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CCBF28F0B6349C99CF45BF08FEC3637"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer of permits</header><text>A permit may be transferred to another person only if—</text> <subparagraph id="H5BD9E8B2F468413895278F60F94E5219"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appropriate permitting authority determines that the transferee will satisfy all of the requirements of the permit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC0292BD3B6CF491E934A997BC26A42EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the transferee is a Good Samaritan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H808ED2A77BFB4A6C937605ED38B04B35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the transferee accepts all of the requirements of the permit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4381E7650CD34AECB22456F2E9ABDB2A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the permitting authority includes in the transferred permit any additional or modified conditions determined to be appropriate by the permitting authority; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F602AFD318545B7A97425F8F1829C5B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any Federal, State, or tribal land management agency with jurisdiction over the project site is notified of the proposed transfer and does not object to the permitting authority before the date that is 30 days before the proposed transfer is to take effect.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC43197F236424F29B95036EDBB51F3C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maintenance of records</header><text>A permitting authority shall maintain all records relating to permits and the permit process under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF4069D54555B413BBA6C792B7937A8AD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Other activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A permit issued under this section may not authorize any new mining activities other than those activities directly related to carrying out remediation at or related to the inactive or abandoned mine site.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HE3AB8EB5318D48E29D3A9F1316DFD161"><enum>304.</enum><header>State or tribal programs</header>
 <subsection id="HDACDB760C3F04F91B891D32ADE5105E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or Indian tribe may issue a permit under this title if the State or Indian tribe has in effect a Good Samaritan permit program approved by the Administrator under this section.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H1FE9AE2FA61B475AB0C20C042F7DB361"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="H506E79014AC44A84B3C8B3638BC25AC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The Governor of any State or the head of an Indian tribe’s governing body may submit to the Administrator an application to carry out a Good Samaritan permit program within its jurisdiction at any time.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEFC0A7DC58254BEDB93B63480F90B3C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application under this section shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HA5D0177D8F314CB5BA9780A5E945C38F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a full and complete description of the Good Samaritan permit program it proposes to administer under State or tribal law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12627A1E9830452D8153D9D72A5E9B8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement from the State Attorney General, or, for an Indian tribe, the equivalent official authorized to represent the tribe in court pertaining to the application, that the laws of the State or Indian tribe provide sufficient legal authority to carry out the described program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF5E24E1AB6B4DC6BC365F341543E945"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after receiving an application submitted under this subsection, the Administrator shall approve the Good Samaritan permit program unless the Administrator determines that the requirements of this section are not met.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03663C4B3C484F22A0DFD696BA78795A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>To meet the requirements of this section, a State or Indian tribe shall—</text> <paragraph id="HECE85364388247ECB623256029451277"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate a lead agency that is responsible for carrying out permitting responsibilities under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H608389C968F740B3A79F9C3B5C2BA470"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have in effect laws providing sufficient legal authority to carry out a Good Samaritan permit program in accordance with this title.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H089EAFA37DEA4C22B61E1B7D2EC2BE12"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Delegation of authority</header><text>Upon approval of a State or tribal Good Samaritan permit program under this section, the Administrator shall transfer all authority to issue permits under this title for the State or relevant area of Indian country to the lead agency designated under subsection (c)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H46B04FED9BE04C4C8CAB10695A923D9D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>A State or tribal Good Samaritan permit program approved under this section shall be administered in accordance with this title, except that nothing in this title precludes a State or Indian tribe from imposing more stringent requirements on permit applicants or permittees.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HAE197160F5DC4F76BA04E6F355E4EBB8"><enum>305.</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HC4741B428027495BA853F1633ADBF067"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A permitting authority may enforce any violation of this title, with respect to which the permitting authority has jurisdiction, by—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H1AE6F2416C2C4EAAA0E22034F322691E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issuing an order to comply with the violated provision; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H81B8022549DE4F6797058A406404C625"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commencing a civil action for appropriate relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15CDE089DEBC49B58901D744163A5691"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum requirement</header><text>In the event of a permit violation, and absent extraordinary circumstances, the court shall, at a minimum, require the person to repair, to the extent practicable, the damage to any part of the environment caused by an action of the person in violation of the permit.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54A8AA7B833541CBAFDECBC132336F2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>Any person who violates this title shall be subject to a civil penalty of up to $5,000 for each day of the violation (except in cases of knowing conduct, in which case the civil penalty shall be $32,500 for each day of the violation).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H1E828E77588B4F97A8B800F75F7F646D"><enum>306.</enum><header>Grants eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A project authorized by a permit issued under this title is eligible for funding pursuant to section 319 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1329">33 U.S.C. 1329</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="HAF89E590249743C99A22721142BDCBFB"><enum>307.</enum><header>Construction of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No action of the Administrator taken pursuant to this title shall be required to comply with section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H11E94FD7330A4605B6C455DA37E4507A"><enum>308.</enum><header>Use of projects to meet offsite mitigation requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A project authorized by a permit issued under this title shall be considered to satisfy all or part of any offsite mitigation requirement of the permittee, upon approval by the authority imposing the offsite mitigation requirement.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H59C7EA7BA55642F48D4702386029FA04"><enum>309.</enum><header>State and tribal reclamation plans under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No State or Indian tribe conducting remediation of an inactive or abandoned mine site pursuant to an approved State or tribal abandoned mine reclamation plan approved under title IV of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1231">30 U.S.C. 1231 et seq.</external-xref>) shall, with respect to the remediation activities, be required to obtain a permit under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</section><section id="HC35D7DAE5E364AF6AE7D8962EF43F8B7"><enum>310.</enum><header>Savings provisions</header>
 <subsection id="H43B4F07152624F1292A50DBCC98305E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emergency authority</header><text>Nothing in this title affects the authority of a Federal, State, tribal, or local agency to carry out any emergency authority, including an emergency authority under environmental laws.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H322C41F1EB5047D785698B9EB7DE839E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Liability under other laws</header><text>Except as provided in section 303(g), nothing in this title or a permit issued under this title limits the liability of any person under any other provision of law.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H032B3794E74A476DBE65E47CFA9C15C8"><enum>311.</enum><header>Sunset</header>
 <subsection id="H1E054F5B7240482982107A8ADA164E64"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No permitting authority may issue a permit under this title after the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this title.</text>
				</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H98A68C4A6E2F44C8A71E6BF2B851C930"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study; report</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H922EAF6497854B4C91E3A2924D21E28F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not earlier than 5 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Administrator, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Interstate Mining Compact Commission, shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences, for execution by the Board on Earth Sciences and Resources, to conduct a detailed, comprehensive study of the effectiveness of the permitting activities carried out under this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6757A516311943CDAA8213E79EB01B19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 7 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Board on Earth Sciences and Resources shall submit to Congress, the appropriate Federal agencies, and the Governors of each of the States represented by the Interstate Mining Compact Commission a report containing—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB0987F87303D45DB943FFC2684FC0D83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H108D8ABB3B954170A363EBC302619346"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any recommendations regarding whether the permitting activities carried out under this title should be reauthorized and, if so, any changes that should be made to improve the effectiveness of the activities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC16D839BB3EF4503A15AF559B2BAE0E8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the funds collected as claim location fees and maintenance fees under section 102, the Secretary of the Interior shall provide to the National Academy of Sciences such funds as it requests, not to exceed $2,000,000, for the purpose of conducting the study required under this section.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


