<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBA2B300BFDA04470B860D663C07A0520" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2963 IH: Bring Jobs Home Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2963</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150708">July 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000287">Mr. Becerra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage domestic insourcing and discourage foreign
			 outsourcing.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6562E1FC9AF841F189808E1DA5502D2C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H514D413B6253488DA5481ED3C1DECFC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bring Jobs Home Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2B296278DD564FE3B8347C45245CF645"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit for insourcing expenses</header> <subsection id="HDFEFC36271454CCEBAB0CBA3F3774A5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EC174D075CE493AB11CCE77A88C2DCD" style="OLC">
					<section id="HCBAE74C8D80548A0A4F7D242A1EA684B"><enum>45S.</enum><header>Credit for insourcing expenses</header>
 <subsection id="H5DF672EC07984D6798B0E29EFC5FB7E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the insourcing expenses credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to 20 percent of the eligible insourcing expenses of the taxpayer which are taken into account in such taxable year under subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBB5150B7DA884EBDB4A68885A67F4DB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible insourcing expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HABD0372C1CA348FDBC29940E3D6CDBA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible insourcing expenses</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H74C2DEC9C45045A683D9AB45A4AB25C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eligible expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the elimination of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located outside the United States, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD272B7F7DC0E4E789E4734A8238E74D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eligible expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the establishment of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located within the United States,</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">if such establishment constitutes the relocation of business unit so eliminated. For purposes of
			 the preceding sentence, a relocation shall not be treated as failing to
			 occur merely because such elimination occurs in a different taxable year
 than such establishment.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H186C6348EEAA42B3ACA31F233862BF89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible expenses</header><text>The term <term>eligible expenses</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HCFAFD3712BDE46F4980E733FB962304F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any amount for which a deduction is allowed to the taxpayer under section 162, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8BA24E1ECA84B79B0A31C630727C994"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit and license fees, lease brokerage fees, equipment installation costs, and, to the extent provided by the Secretary, other similar expenses.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term does not include any compensation which is paid or incurred in connection with severance
			 from employment and, to the extent provided by the Secretary, any similar
 amount.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0104506305A744BBBECFC83FFBD83BE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Business unit</header><text>The term <term>business unit</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H164A5A33CFF54E8D934C1947AF742EA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any trade or business, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17ECF64897DF4C0C8DE88DB65D9431F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any line of business, or functional unit, which is part of any trade or business.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H342ABA0BC4C64A62A0504F0DAF47A98D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expanded affiliated group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>expanded affiliated group</term> means an affiliated group as defined in section 1504(a), determined without regard to section 1504(b)(3) and by substituting <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> for <quote>at least 80 percent</quote> each place it appears in section 1504(a). A partnership or any other entity (other than a corporation) shall be treated as a member of an expanded affiliated group if such entity is controlled (within the meaning of section 954(d)(3)) by members of such group (including any entity treated as a member of such group by reason of this paragraph).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA14E92995EDD45AC9A9F9AC3097A40A2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Expenses must be pursuant to insourcing plan</header><text>Amounts shall be taken into account under paragraph (1) only to the extent that such amounts are paid or incurred pursuant to a written plan to carry out the relocation described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9CDA6D26DD7420C9EAFB32677A14226"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Operating expenses not taken into account</header><text>Any amount paid or incurred in connection with the ongoing operation of a business unit shall not be treated as an amount paid or incurred in connection with the establishment or elimination of such business unit.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99AE2F3E485E435AA10A6D3A3D40EBC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increased domestic employment requirement</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section unless the number of full-time equivalent employees of the taxpayer for the taxable year for which the credit is claimed exceeds the number of full-time equivalent employees of the taxpayer for the last taxable year ending before the first taxable year in which such eligible insourcing expenses were paid or incurred. For purposes of this subsection, full-time equivalent employees has the meaning given such term under section 45R(d) (and the applicable rules of section 45R(e)), determined by only taking into account wages (as otherwise defined in section 45R(e)) paid with respect to services performed within the United States. All employers treated as a single employer under subsection (b), (c), (m), or (o) of section 414 shall be treated as a single employer for purposes of this subsection.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H2B818D827F634A9E8FC5DBAF36ED55A1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credit allowed upon completion of insourcing plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H1822B12A5579466984FC0ABE002FF2CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), eligible insourcing expenses shall be taken into account under subsection (a) in the taxable year during which the plan described in subsection (b)(5) has been completed and all eligible insourcing expenses pursuant to such plan have been paid or incurred.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HF52B64054F53499CB207913F5A39400B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election to apply employment test and claim credit in first full taxable year after completion of
 plan</header><text>If the taxpayer elects the application of this paragraph, eligible insourcing expenses shall be taken into account under subsection (a) in the first taxable year after the taxable year described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBD3751DFFDAD4A8EB18A0624C5A15F79"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Possessions treated as part of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>United States</term> shall be treated as including each possession of the United States (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H171F65D8269F4CF5A793026148A2382A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4C24488A3A854010A9275143DF866358"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To Be Part of General Business Credit</header><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H8A82F3C087424189AF93A14FED70A24A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0BA11E736E714BCDB8A7D2E2B660D432"><enum>(37)</enum><text>the insourcing expenses credit determined under section 45S(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H107D9AD73F0C4A74B04289ED2A135257"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90E58D5666204751B8DBB62CCB340F37" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H1EC174D075CE493AB11CCE77A88C2DCD" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="HCBAE74C8D80548A0A4F7D242A1EA684B" level="section">Sec. 45S. Credit for insourcing expenses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H80DC7D2B567C442BA712F4D92624D858"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3A67B16F94274C51A884ABF1388B6E31"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application to United States possessions</header>
				<paragraph id="HA81265916E7D47929045FB27AB9A338D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments to possessions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF615041AE22948E69F833EDCC99CFC14"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mirror code possessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall make periodic payments to each possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system in an amount equal to the loss to that possession by reason of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45S">section 45S</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. Such amount shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H645F90C8751747EEACE2839E23D0BBCF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other possessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall make annual payments to each possession of the United States which does not have a mirror code tax system in an amount estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the aggregate benefits that would have been provided to residents of such possession by reason of section 45S of such Code if a mirror code tax system had been in effect in such possession. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to any possession of the United States unless such possession has a plan, which has been approved by the Secretary of the Treasury, under which such possession will promptly distribute such payment to the residents of such possession.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2032A3C1B7F443291B7709C126988B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against United States income taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed against United States income taxes under section 45S of such Code to any person—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9DAB10AF80F543BEA5EC897FDFE5F974"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to whom a credit is allowed against taxes imposed by the possession by reason of such section, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF94E07380E6D4B93A3310B5F6F547A13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is eligible for a payment under a plan described in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0477C7CCE544EF4BCFA021686AD8528"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="H83D19AC48CB44937AE2125FD01CEDCDC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Possessions of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>possession of the United States</term> includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE16E634B8784CAE9608085E1A3C5A49"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mirror code tax system</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>mirror code tax system</term> means, with respect to any possession of the United States, the income tax system of such possession if the income tax liability of the residents of such possession under such system is determined by reference to the income tax laws of the United States as if such possession were the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDD331173F28460297BEF34BE9D1606E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text>For purposes of section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, the payments under this section shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from sections referred to in such section 1324(b)(2).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAF5956E3B9C0467DA5CC49419116E38C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Denial of deduction for outsourcing expenses</header>
 <subsection id="HA67B6F571C7D4915923FFEEE173D6DB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part IX of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H319550A0F56E41CA9571867BEF5B15DB" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD7CCF89A85B046A98D10C0C5EEB5FC0A"><enum>280I.</enum><header>Outsourcing expenses</header>
 <subsection id="HB78F1B9D3EBD4E32AF132CF2B7766437"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction otherwise allowable under this chapter shall be allowed for any specified outsourcing expense.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H20607A5AA2674FF2809F5D9C17BEC21F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified outsourcing expense</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H94BBBB23FDF0443C9EA959A4743A6B1C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>specified outsourcing expense</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H69B56E65733F40AAACE97EC20E6DBA73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any eligible expense paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the elimination of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located within the United States, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8EFD39366774020BF11CC34EE52EF69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any eligible expense paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the establishment of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located outside the United States,</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">if such establishment constitutes the relocation of business unit so eliminated. For purposes of
			 the preceding sentence, a relocation shall not be treated as failing to
			 occur merely because such elimination occurs in a different taxable year
			 than such establishment.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BFA13CEE5A44E24B0158F680263C3DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of certain definitions and rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9329B611854748BA996D2E87F9F597E6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the terms <term>eligible expenses</term>, <term>business unit</term>, and <term>expanded affiliated group</term> shall have the respective meanings given such terms by section 45S(b).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA61C86964D1648D285572BB43879DDF0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Operating expenses not taken into account</header><text>A rule similar to the rule of section 45S(b)(6) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3484E27C3EE34B2987664D10A41A10EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="H9F2390291E2049478C862ADFBCC04295"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application to deductions for depreciation and amortization</header><text>In the case of any portion of a specified outsourcing expense which is not deductible in the taxable year in which paid or incurred, such portion shall neither be chargeable to capital account nor amortizable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF3F25C49637C48C09256FFE47F697405"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Possessions treated as part of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>United States</term> shall be treated as including each possession of the United States (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D442741F596499CAAF2B51A643F0CCD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations which provide (or create a rebuttable presumption) that certain establishments of business units outside the United States will be treated as relocations (based on timing or such other factors as the Secretary may provide) of business units eliminated within the United States.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCF95565FE760477788F6783F4AF1538E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on subpart F income of controlled foreign corporations determined without regard to
 specified outsourcing expenses</header><text>Section 952(c) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB45382F9E3C041158807A99CDB0801FC" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB53668034DF64A75BCD32F9F888DBDE3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Earnings and profits determined without regard to specified outsourcing expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, earnings and profits of any controlled foreign corporation shall be determined without regard to any specified outsourcing expense (as defined in section 280I(b)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1CD737C565F64C4EADB3B0EB554400AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part IX of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AB6F20DDFDD43A8B0A654AA1BC32F01" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H319550A0F56E41CA9571867BEF5B15DB" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="HD7CCF89A85B046A98D10C0C5EEB5FC0A" level="section">Sec. 280I. Outsourcing expenses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H150DE62D6DF84CE58638427C38ED9DAB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


