<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H80C08FD3BBB04560ACCB9FD421A8155B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 60 IH: Cyber Defense National Guard Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 60</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="">Select Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Director of National Intelligence to conduct a study on the feasibility of
			 establishing a Cyber Defense National Guard.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H63513691759C4EBCB194B5336BCE3E7D" style="OLC">
		<section id="H96C82A6EA9A5411A85FD4495291CCF0B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cyber Defense National Guard Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H78427C28BA29478B9A99B25F1CF81356"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on establishment of Cyber Defense National Guard</header>
			<subsection id="H4365611BE02848D2A31EDC28AEE5F2BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the
			 Secretary of Homeland Security, shall conduct a study on the feasibility
			 of establishing a Cyber Defense National Guard.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB261102FBDB646E89199326226FE8EA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall include an analysis of—</text>
				<paragraph id="H174E2B579E944FF1A5319B7AC85C7C8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of creating a Cyber Defense National Guard;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H80D553A1D6D2433DAD67174131242AC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of persons who would be needed to defend the critical infrastructure of the United
			 States from a cyber attack or manmade intentional or unintentional
			 catastrophic incident;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H95737216334F4882BB56239DABC9D7A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the sources of potential members of a Cyber Defense National Guard, including industry, academic
			 institutions, research facilities, and Federal contractors;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H7EC0080A8D35449FA5C37883C10675E7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>which elements of the Federal Government would be best equipped to recruit, train, and manage a
			 Cyber Defense National Guard;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H818FFE2DBA47425884688988F00FA9A0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the criteria required for persons to serve in a Cyber Defense National Guard;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBF3921DC3AC345F6882FA3F16C915355"><enum>(6)</enum><text>if an incident disrupts communications in a region or area, what resources can be pre-positioned
			 and training instilled to assure the effectiveness and responsiveness of a
			 Cyber Defense National Guard;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9B26B2DC900E4F66AD4D515014EEEF64"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the minimum requirements for consideration for inclusion in a Cyber Defense National Guard;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HAA4F44452ED9460FABD80F48127B6C38"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the impact of the effectiveness of a Cyber Defense National Guard of the possibility that the
			 population of potential recruits may be dominated by men and women without
			 military, intelligence, law enforcement, or government work experience;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3E212799F50247949480EB91C0312671"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the recruitment and vetting costs for a Cyber Defense National Guard;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H454E10C934244A19AA81C93BBBE3B15B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the frequency of cyber defense and unit cohesion training;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H16EC15C81BD0469CBECE8A9C7F4F84BD"><enum>(11)</enum><text>how well military discipline is able to be adapted for use for creating command and control systems
			 and protocols for a Cyber Defense National Guard;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HF4A85D2E1A3145288FA1EC5A0AD1DC64"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the logistics of allowing governors to use the Cyber Defense National Guard in States during times
			 of cyber emergency;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBCED43C2FF1E4FC0911F6F67C5A3EA42"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the advantages and disadvantages of creating a Cyber Defense National Guard on the cyber security
			 of the United States; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H6AFFA6CC7E9D457C834870B3E9516B25"><enum>(14)</enum><text>whether a force trained to defend the networks of the United States in the event of a major attack
			 or natural or manmade disaster will benefit overall efforts to defend the
			 interests of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59A56591AA5C4BBC85442313310CB93F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header>
				<paragraph id="HB1E5C364811D419587EBEFE88A45AC7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 240 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National
			 Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the
			 Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the Committee on Armed
			 Services, the Committee on Homeland Security, the Permanent Select
			 Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House
			 of Representatives and the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on
			 Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Select Committee on
			 Intelligence, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report
			 containing the results of the study required under subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H5BFD3DC4C3B449D09DF65C0E9AC2786E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a
			 classified annex.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


