<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4D5C7EBE121B4D3698698D7FC2528E1A" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1865 IH: Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1865</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To designate certain Federal lands in California as wilderness, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB39E7565DFFF4D13B75F378D8A219A87" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC1CEB1FCF8BB42CAB9B5A966538724DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HD5575C9AE8EC40ED8D4696309FE01E61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H450B4D2CF1584CEC8F426041EE12F433"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="HC1CEB1FCF8BB42CAB9B5A966538724DE" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H05D3C34243F44EEB8AF02FF7B36BDE2A" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4813F77CFEC543A5AC7E4FD62016880C" level="section">Sec. 3. Designation of wilderness.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB25668B8CE9041469DCCF187C073B02A" level="section">Sec. 4. Designation of the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H19BE5A9EF4DE425E9927F7BB7AC5BBA6" level="section">Sec. 5. Administration of wilderness.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA3D05504B4EC4F239E372C8D978E0071" level="section">Sec. 6. Designation of wild and scenic rivers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDF4E752692BD45F0AA7D5962625C3441" level="section">Sec. 7. Designation of the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3F0A691F26DE4056A97139984763793A" level="section">Sec. 8. Designation of scenic areas.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA7F242DF53C742568FBAD379514839E0" level="section">Sec. 9. Condor National Recreation Trail.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB88D9C0164B14FB2A0219B918F37E253" level="section">Sec. 10. Forest Service study.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC1E3045DED914BD4B6C9C412F32B567D" level="section">Sec. 11. Nonmotorized recreation opportunities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H6D817A9D885D457B992DAF3F3C241FC8" level="section">Sec. 12. Use by members of Native American tribes.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H05D3C34243F44EEB8AF02FF7B36BDE2A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H37B994D45091428B9D2F01A7295817BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scenic areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>scenic areas</term> means the Condor Ridge Scenic Area and Black Mountain Scenic Area designated by this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E156309CB65444B9218A42E6D34EBFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HBE88F2BCDB5F48DCA4B47573C7C7F4AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to lands managed by the Bureau of Land Management, the Secretary of the Interior; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H901500E1E8D8438C82522C1E31C1A3D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to lands managed by the Forest Service, the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBBB00D7E1754F5F87C8E5A01DA7E9D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H4813F77CFEC543A5AC7E4FD62016880C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of wilderness</header> 
<subsection id="HD06F1A452E6249BD8B4D53833CD90BB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the following areas in the State are designated as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text> <paragraph id="H4E8DBB3C0D6742238799940953CA8D14"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 35,619 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Caliente Mountain Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be known as the <quote>Caliente Mountain Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F9B23E57DDF4A3AA31F4C5707279582"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 13,332 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Soda Lake Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be known as the <quote>Soda Lake Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09031BCDC333458D80F1DAB7C6922049"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 12,585 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Temblor Range Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be known as the <quote>Temblor Range Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6695334CFDA94282975811143AB001C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 23,524 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Chumash Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Chumash Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BD8512465BD4DE6B194B6B0B301EC2B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 54,609 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Dick Smith Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Dick Smith Wilderness as designated by the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24ACA9CB6EF449D1A40B9F301C5E1CBC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 7,315 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Garcia Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Garcia Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H929A5588A9E94DBBBE5F520A0878C685"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 8,081 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Machesna Mountain Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Machesna Mountain Wilderness as designated by the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BCBD760C5AF4A84A00F9293D1C262A1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 29,677 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Matilija Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Matilija Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5276C69BED04837A99C84CF79459B34"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 24,131 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>San Rafael Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the San Rafael Wilderness as designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/271">Public Law 90–271</external-xref> (82 Stat. 51), the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note), and the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52EDBCF41ACB4E11AA41800F8ADCE7C8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 3,153 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Santa Lucia Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Santa Lucia Wilderness as designated by the Endangered American Wilderness Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/237">Public Law 95–237</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6B40C311C7C4A80BD53738F4664D33D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 14,795 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Sespe Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Sespe Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7BB954F2218419A9C9618BFBADE2F64"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 18,176 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Diablo Caliente Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated ____, which shall be known as the <quote>Diablo Caliente Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0B23EC09C87846E98380AE419784CCFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header> <paragraph id="HE5A6719034654576BFEDE41A655640D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file maps and legal descriptions of the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by subsection (a) with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB7EF7DD2CA8B40909F2D6B890D6DA358"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8688373010C34390AC215BC1FD544DD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1F6EA80AD7F4740B585F3C03021B91A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DF1B67F73E44F96AC7E9BDA608A688B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB25668B8CE9041469DCCF187C073B02A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness</header> 
<subsection id="HAE535B3E638F441EADDD787532B8B8AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 2,174 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness Area</quote> and dated _____ , is designated as the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness Area.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H21C3BCB3BBFA43DC8EFDE4E4BD84DF9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header> <paragraph id="H57FA1FD7165E484B93C861A4DC88920A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and a legal description of the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness Area (referred to in this section as the <quote>potential wilderness area</quote>) with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9F0166C9B7E84B82B0D91BBCE9D9552A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCF57C5E5BA74AAC808EAFE24841CC8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H418877BE2D434F94B1DF20479E2A180D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2EDC345F6C3427EADC58844D9F4D02F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9ACEBAAFE350442BA92DDD3C5740CAE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d) and subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall manage the potential wilderness area in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9A58B608B8904E84B3F71CB4F4CE4C81"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Trail use, construction, reconstruction, and realignment</header> <paragraph id="HAC16CCACC3C14150AC404CD02B060309"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary is authorized to reconstruct, realign, or reroute the Pine Mountain Trail.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0DCD519CE66469180AC6570E4B011AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out the reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0CEC785EC4474829A78CBFA8049FED14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comply with all existing laws (including regulations); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7153B76BC6BE4F69B62D216320FFF53B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, use the minimum tool or administrative practice necessary to accomplish the reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting with the least amount of adverse impact on wilderness character and resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A47374F71AF44F3B220EE694238AED4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles and machinery</header><text>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary may use motorized vehicles and machinery to carry out the trail reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting authorized by this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DDF55E7A3F64B098B9405AD8E727DB5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Motorized and mechanized vehicles</header><text>The Secretary may permit the use of motorized and mechanized vehicles on the existing Pine Mountain Trail in accordance with existing law (including regulations) and this section until such date as the potential wilderness area is designated wilderness in accordance with subsection (h).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFFBE426E730D4C618A3BF3A7F2A48025"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in the potential wilderness area is withdrawn from all forms of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF9A6CF46E0A74D4AA3F5B7BAAF940DF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7AEAC5236A6A4854B97D970B1FBAC94C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24A36529DA8948C48D591758276176D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1949F3D8C3DB424DA3C8F60B73E1F2FE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with State, tribal, and local governmental entities and private entities to complete the trail reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting authorized by subsection (d).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0AF925FAB8C84FC3B2F03158CC2D91E1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The Secretary shall modify the boundary of the potential wilderness area to exclude any area within 150 feet of the centerline of the new location of any trail that has been reconstructed, realigned, or rerouted under subsection (d).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H50A5245218034EB88C75DB54CB0B3110"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Wilderness designation</header> <paragraph id="H2CF6B31323114D7B9B2689A118F45BB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The potential wilderness area, as modified under subsection (g), shall be designated as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System on the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice that the trail reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting authorized by subsection (d) has been completed or 20 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, whichever comes sooner.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E8EFA228BAD417D9610E7625C691E02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header><text>Upon designation as wilderness under this section, the potential wilderness area shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HFBFD130BFFD448C7BC8FF267FD262579"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporated into the Machesna Mountain Wilderness Area, as designated by the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note) and expanded by section 3; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56E6EE43BB0B4C0E9DEC6BD8A0EED12F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administered in accordance with section 5 and the Wilderness Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H19BE5A9EF4DE425E9927F7BB7AC5BBA6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header> <subsection id="H7CD5CB0A57E74F42ABBD73D0A870D9B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 3 shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this Act and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), except that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H880273BCAB1B4B8D928DACCE2E3CD125"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2F572991AD34641BAA6DD0A154544DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be considered a reference to the Secretary that has jurisdiction over the land.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD572B0DC158B4CF3862C06DE56223AC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fire management and related activities</header> 
<paragraph id="H7EEF37EF7EDB4A408202F82636DE66F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take such measures in a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 3 as are necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>) and House Report 98–40 of the 98th Congress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5601718116FE4D22A1832E0EFADBDD81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding priorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act limits funding for fire and fuels management in the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H604FEC692CFF4F3198EB148FA53ED284"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revision and development of local fire management plans</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the local fire management plans that apply to the land designated as a wilderness area or wilderness addition by section 3.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8960EBD5DFBE45C8B8B6D6903A8B63F5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with paragraph (1) and other applicable Federal law, to ensure a timely and efficient response to fire emergencies in the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 3, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H951F63794F094C53A9E6F93B19033E05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, establish agency approval procedures (including appropriate delegations of authority to the Forest Supervisor, District Manager, or other agency officials) for responding to fire emergencies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H567996CA5535401FB73A8A0487CC6751"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into agreements with appropriate State or local firefighting agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDBEF9083F23749EC9CD25CD9ED05A267"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 3, if established before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue, subject to such reasonable regulations as the Secretary considers necessary in accordance with—</text> <paragraph id="H66AE21FAA6D54DB38F98E69E90E5923D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4C98284A83A49E6AD4326FA55097F0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in Appendix A of House Report 101–405, accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress for lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B587BFF4EF148F3B24A9C6A16C1AC60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in House Report 96–617, accompanying H.R. 5487 of the 96th Congress for lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D3E442569A34F2CA12204453996FA1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>all other laws governing livestock grazing on Federal public lands.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5CA1DD8E45CB4AD68A4966D26032DFD7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header> <paragraph id="H080070D0585A46668ABB6D241744E653"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife on public land in the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E10DF4198774F7B9CDD72750E3BED5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management activities</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes and principles of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary may conduct any management activities that are necessary to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and habitats in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 3, if the management activities are—</text> <subparagraph id="H452AAB83B80D44E7A5EE0D4CDD059EBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistent with relevant wilderness management plans; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFF9865484FB445AA83C4E31AA988347"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducted in accordance with appropriate policies, such as the policies established in Appendix B of House Report 101–405.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDE474AEC20F44B493FC3E8AD2BAD6E6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Wildlife water development projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Management activities to maintain water sources for wildlife may be carried out within wilderness areas designated by this Act and may include the use of motorized vehicles by the appropriate agencies and their designees if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4F8EE7C370114F6F925F05676A7ACE03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the water sources will, as determined by the Secretary, enhance wilderness values by promoting healthy and viable wildlife populations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F272607484B4DAFA0F73EC90A12CB41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the visual impacts of the water sources on the wilderness areas can reasonably be minimized.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H958DC005A9034FEE9B0C007A26335E5F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header> 
<paragraph id="HBB2B8C5B89A7411EAC55B8DB0B416C82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress does not intend for designation of wilderness by this Act to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around each wilderness area or wilderness addition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9CE2297D5B648258F7036DBDE4FD0BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities or uses up to boundaries</header><text>The fact that nonwilderness activities or uses can be seen or heard from within a wilderness area shall not, of itself, preclude the activities or uses up to the boundary of the wilderness area.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D92ADEF07CC4DB290B85F9F6F51B454"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Military activities</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes—</text> <paragraph id="H94ABCEA8D955434298A1571957129F43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft over the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 3;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B87974BE9A446428E5CA97968F6A94B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the designation of new units of special airspace over the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 3; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9038D977EA9B4BF5881F16844A7D8CC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or establishment of military flight training routes over wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H358FE9F1D2C54686A161B9AF8C1B469C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Horses</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes horseback riding in, or the entry of recreational or commercial saddle or pack stock into, a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 3—</text> <paragraph id="H3785C69D355345B6B0052B2CEBBCE7E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with section 4(d)(5) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(5)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC344C3DB193E446EB79793648A57F634"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to any terms and conditions determined to be necessary by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDCF6DD756A1B40DB837410BE728653D7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 3 are withdrawn from—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9984F75C61D14E9696BACE3A9D68E39C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A6870918F314720B920D81B42489480"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87BA8CE729034D6B9EA0FA504506B499"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3968764B581C4F31A50AEF29055BE83D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land within the boundary of a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 3 that is acquired by the United States shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA8AB0319073044CA9C59D2E10EC3BF99"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the wilderness area in which the land is located; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27D4C7B9AE8B4A9EBFC440E18D41D398"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with this section, the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), and any other applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF744063BAB34B8BB43417120F43B7E7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Climatological data collection</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may authorize the installation and maintenance of hydrologic, meteorologic, or climatological collection devices in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 3 if the Secretary determines that the facilities and access to the facilities are essential to flood warning, flood control, or water reservoir operation activities.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA3D05504B4EC4F239E372C8D978E0071"><enum>6.</enum><header>Designation of wild and scenic rivers</header> <subsection id="H49CD9B0088BA4114A131B22E129F11F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Indian Creek, Mono Creek, and Matilija Creek, California</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1AC57426E9A9445583FAA74EE160793F" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H5F52CAEE04194C48B03BC37EEE0CAD2F"><enum>(__)</enum><header>Indian Creek, California</header><text>The following segments of Indian Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> <subparagraph id="H5DC0E52DED2D4F44A4A6E50A0A2C98B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 9.5-mile segment of Indian Creek from its source in section 19, T7N, R26W to the Dick Smith Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAB21A9831FA417DA97E34E789CFCA28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 1-mile segment of Indian Creek from the Dick Smith Wilderness boundary to 0.25 miles downstream of Road 6N24, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C1C33D8ECE042E2920AC1F4F4A36A1E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 3.9-mile segment of Indian Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Road 6N24 to the southern boundary of section 32, T6N, R26W, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF30C43C14D274ADC82FE1E66A28B136C"><enum>(__)</enum><header>Mono Creek, California</header><text>The following segments of Mono Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> <subparagraph id="H4ACA2F6D09A94F7BB94C5580F93D5129"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 4.2-mile segment of Mono Creek from its source in section 1, T7N, R26W, to 0.25 miles upstream of Don Victor Fire Road in section 28, T7N, R25W, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F315B140FDB48EC94848A8E172AE30C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 2.1-mile segment of Mono Creek from 0.25 miles upstream of the Don Victor Fire Road in section 28, T7N, R25W to 0.25 miles downstream of Don Victor Fire Road in section 34, T7N, R25W, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FB714388FAF4EC49719F5A76BAF9EE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 14.7-mile segment of Mono Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Don Victor Fire Road in section 34, T7N, R25W to the Ogilvy Ranch private property boundary in section 22, R26W, T6N, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H70673351087F4A16910F511693A1F74F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 3.5-mile segment of Mono Creek from the Ogilvy Ranch private property boundary to the southern boundary of section 33, T6N, R26N, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B2EA04B19CD4156A02347795E916E1E"><enum>(__)</enum><header>Matilija Creek, California</header><text>The following segments of Matilija Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD546B2252B59436CAB7EC29A1B206141"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 7.2-mile segment of the Matilija Creek from its source in section 25, T6N, R25W to the private property boundary in section 9, T5N, R24W, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF60217B0CD54F269F40BC42364DE480"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 7.25-mile segment of the Upper North Fork Matilija Creek from its source in section 36, T6N, R24W to the Matilija Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C7FECB3AC6E4EA99DED400816C7BEF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sespe Creek, California</header><text>Section 3(a)(142) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)(142)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H94797EFF4672465183D1B400C7ACD479" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H93FF7D4220A247A59F86F805250F4D0D"><enum>(142)</enum><header>Sespe Creek, California</header><text>The following segments of Sespe Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD18E8D8502B44164B308556DE6BEF7B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 2.7-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the private property boundary in section 10, T6N, R24W, to the Hartman Ranch private property boundary in section 14, T6N, R24W, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE53DE2C3E6D54F5E911CB740FA564468"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 15-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the Hartman Ranch private property boundary in section 14, T6N, R24W, to the western boundary of section 6, T5N, R22W, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B7F10E2A47545F2AA93510B05F9CE2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 6.1-miles segment of Sespe Creek from the western boundary of section 6, T5N, R22W, to the confluence with Trout Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2492831CC0194C02BDD2C45E7FD7A3D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 28.6-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the confluence with Trout Creek to the southern boundary of section 35, T5N, R20W, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27E1546E2A5A4967B21DE44984C7A862"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sisquoc River, California</header><text>Section 3(a)(143) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)(143)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HB053AB588A3F4A61BD79B32B35A7A7B0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC5D5273E5E914FE4A1CFF248BCED4990"><enum>(143)</enum><header>Sisquoc River, California</header><text>The following segments of the Sisquoc River and its tributaries in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H127239EA6AF74D2DABD80EBDB9BB9EBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 33-mile segment of the main stem of the Sisquoc River extending from its origin downstream to the Los Padres Forest boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H66FA92A039944C4EBA8CE5BFF5C7BBB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 4.2-mile segment of the South Fork Sisquoc River from its source northeast of San Rafael Mountain in section 2, T7N, R28W to its confluence with the Sisquoc River, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3A78D87B7517491BBECC9A4369A9E98E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 10.4-mile segment of Manzana Creek from its source west of San Rafael Peak in section 4, T&amp;N, R28W to the San Rafael Wilderness boundary upstream of Nira Campground, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60EDCA3835C046EAA5DB8F684D7308C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 0.6-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the San Rafael Wilderness boundary upstream of the Nira Campground to the San Rafael Wilderness boundary downstream of the confluence of Davy Brown Creek, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H67B42106CD704F3AAF113CD229ECCE24"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 5.8-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the San Rafael Wilderness boundary downstream of the confluence of Davy Brown Creek to the private property boundary in section 1, T8N, R30W, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43EC8B0414354E378C20EADB46AA061D"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 3.8-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the private property boundary in section 1, T8N, R30W, to the confluence of the Sisquoc River, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H022176113B034F19A34FBE4E24E137D2"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 3.4-mile segment of Davy Brown Creek from its source west of Ranger Peak in section 32, T8N, R29W to 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Munch Canyon, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7A4156EA4CA43C69897B8919A2D6519"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The 1.4-mile segment of Davy Brown Creek from 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Munch Canyon to its confluence with Manzana Creek, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1A84AB7850B74E7ABD3CD571F14E2469"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 2-mile segment of Munch Canyon from its source north of Ranger Peak in section 33, T8N, R29W to 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Sunset Valley Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC20BB29F516B4AD98B08F5ACC02E40A0"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The 0.5-mile segment of Munch Canyon from 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Sunset Valley Creek to its confluence with Davy Brown Creek, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5360D0E32DFD44F39A48B36750D80288"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The 2.6-mile segment of Fish Creek from 500 feet downstream of Sunset Valley Road to its confluence with Manzana Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H992A85211A144C239FDDAFDCB46607D4"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 1.5-mile segment of East Fork Fish Creek from its source in section 26, T8N, R29W to its confluence with Fish Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E9E2C32937F4C06BC0661594FD955BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Piru creek, California</header><text>Section 3(a)(199) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)(199)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H9638378FEC0949ADBBDEBB01F8EA392A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE0877D789EFF41C2B7B1B7D6B27D4484"><enum>(199)</enum><header>Piru creek, California</header><text>The following segments of Piru Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC9B8790DEAAE48DC9BC4028FA7A0206D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 9.1-mile segment of Piru Creek from its source in section 3, T6N, R22W, to the private property boundary in section 4, T6N, R21W, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE90AEF2BD4B403B9342E10B8CAC9CD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 17.2-mile segment of Piru Creek from the private property boundary in section 4, T6N, R21W, to 0.25 miles downstream of the Gold Hill Road, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H216DAB6669784871838C7DB7980B32C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 4.1-mile segment of Piru Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Gold Hill Road to the confluence with Trail Canyon, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72EF82B0846449A9BE936F8FC60BC641"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 7.25-mile segment of Piru Creek from the confluence with Trail Canyon to the confluence with Buck Creek, as a scenic river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC33E14134A6B4EA69C64DED9D21C7E52"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The 3-mile segment of Piru Creek from 0.5 miles downstream of Pyramid Dam at the first bridge crossing to the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9AE471EC152944A1A1061E9AA47B96E4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The 13-mile segment of Piru Creek from the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness to the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E86D89FAFDF48F880B1D0F0C852B293"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The 2.2-mile segment of Piru Creek from the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness to the upper limit of Piru Reservoir, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H9B80CEC1611940FDBF7476CB9C7FDCF3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>The designation of Piru Creek under subsection (a) shall not affect valid rights in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE866A37A1B2948C594CFBC7547754318"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Motorized use of trails</header><text>Nothing in this section shall affect the motorized use of trails designated by the Forest Service for motorized use that are located adjacent to and crossing upper Piru Creek.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HDF4E752692BD45F0AA7D5962625C3441"><enum>7.</enum><header>Designation of the Fox Mountain potential wilderness</header> <subsection id="H8C8FE78C27464A18BB8C72A7DB6579BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 41,617 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness Area</quote> and dated __, is designated as the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness Area.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H536E0060A46D4737AD3F5F0CD0403B8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header> 
<paragraph id="H24D71A4CC06C46D092B6036E59C444FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall file a map and a legal description of the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness Area (referred to in this section as the <quote>potential wilderness area</quote>) with—</text> <subparagraph id="H95CFE05D8200492C8BA01E5B748F319C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8EB33499D8EE410A8564C766E00269C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59C0DF4604104FB48AFF73FE93D7E664"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary of Agriculture may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E4BAA578E8444798EE3C6DB2BC00F1A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H49ADD62962A442EB8EEBEF0C7A84777C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d) and subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall manage the potential wilderness area in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBDABE367C71946D482883D38675EED5C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Trail use construction, reconstruction, and realignment</header> 
<paragraph id="HDA5EDCDD94754BA3A6A4718F9FA8B878"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to—</text> <subparagraph id="H820A39672ADA4E66B49F3FCCF4C55713"><enum>(A)</enum><text>construct a new trail for use by hikers, equestrians, and mechanized vehicles that connects the Aliso Park Campground to the Bull Ridge Trail; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6BE9FFC9716244B68C6143D6F8B6BF07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reconstruct or realign the—</text> <clause id="H2831D216EC884D76B5BE999AB07057C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Bull Ridge Trail; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1E28134DF9BE48029A87E217D696901F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Rocky Ridge Trail.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4E720AF523C4924B12C0F2AF197BDC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out the construction, reconstruction, or alignment under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H98C147402E964870B725E7AE899F70F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comply with all existing laws (including regulations); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16763875735F4905A4C7221B3A6FC0AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, use the minimum tool or administrative practice necessary to accomplish the construction, reconstruction, or alignment with the least amount of adverse impact on wilderness character and resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E3FFB4F312447F6A86E74486216B362"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles and machinery</header><text>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary may use motorized vehicles and machinery to carry out the trail construction, reconstruction, or realignment authorized by this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35B0814869FE40718482E0D9B8678590"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mechanized vehicles</header><text>The Secretary may permit the use of mechanized vehicles on the existing Bull Ridge Trail and Rocky Ridge Trail in accordance with existing law (including regulations) and this section until such date as the potential wilderness area is designated wilderness in accordance with subsection (h).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB2BD9F0A195244C2A7E5E74447ADFAAF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in the potential wilderness area is withdrawn from all forms of—</text> <paragraph id="H23CC3E155FE74459AFEC5C98C9100C14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9167181467FD40F9B9CFC016F876624F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D5076A0ABC5495299053FA5D8AE2C77"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H87F4E5A313A94B8AAC6868D719D588E3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with State, tribal, and local governmental entities and private entities to complete the trail construction, reconstruction, and realignment authorized by subsection (d).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5311077903D9468CBFECDD97534B3D1C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The Secretary shall modify the boundary of the potential wilderness area to exclude any area within 50 feet of the centerline of the new location of any trail that has been constructed, reconstructed, or realigned under subsection (d).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8A16DDBEC69436297451F5DCD99AB0B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Wilderness designation</header> 
<paragraph id="H0CDAE7BF00EB4E60BC5EF6AA7E831922"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The potential wilderness area, as modified under subsection (g), shall be designated as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System on the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice that the trail construction, reconstruction, or alignment authorized by subsection (d) has been completed or 20 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, whichever comes sooner.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E3234E0191841AEB8B43DBB718F5264"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header><text>Upon designation as wilderness under this section, the potential wilderness area shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCF95F8C0BF054E278A81A178383629E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporated into the San Rafael Wilderness, as designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/271">Public Law 90–271</external-xref> (82 Stat. 51), the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note), and the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242), and section 3; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H950E85262E9D4357AE37FEFB921A9606"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administered in accordance with section 5 and the Wilderness Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3F0A691F26DE4056A97139984763793A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Designation of scenic areas</header> 
<subsection id="HB13528950E7547BEA3B12883378402AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, there are established the following scenic areas:</text> <paragraph id="H63488FFB938F4D8887935A234B22F9C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Condor Ridge Scenic Area</header><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 18,666 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Condor Ridge Scenic Area—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be managed as the Condor Ridge Scenic Area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDEED5A09FD94420B4017CD0B238ED01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Black Mountain Scenic Area</header><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 15,846 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Black Mountain Scenic Area—Proposed</quote> and dated ___, which shall be managed as the Black Mountain Scenic Area.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5D232D12D6E14D61AF29BC34196BA9B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header> <paragraph id="H6FE2DC6C76F74BBE8F15150D4254450C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall file a map and a legal description of the Condor Ridge Scenic Area and Black Mountain Scenic Area with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HADBCF7997C77499DA0227FCC6BA09719"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DD337FB665A4DA1939467E6E8A1447C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA220D463B32E4C43BE9DFD3A72D50120"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary of Agriculture may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53840662201144DEBB99FC3B745711DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A56534DC9C3449BB84DFF312FA5BF21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the scenic areas is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the scenic areas.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H36B79726453A462A8731941288D42294"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management</header> <paragraph id="HE348E5B81DA44AFBB57C87259D1E29A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the scenic areas—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2C209096A6E547D2A52F166ADBA8CC06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the scenic areas; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8330595BE62C43B5B43B3A650F1D46A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> 
<clause id="HF1BC57A19E9B41F69CB52DB6A39D5273"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section;</text></clause> <clause id="H7E563A70E6B44F9AB65AFD3E9180A75D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) for lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE64041BADDF4726A0AC51ED49CC3482"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any laws (including regulations) relating to the National Forest System, for lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBFE7F62D810846A5A2DA79F32673B812"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other applicable law (including regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE5D3E57F67D417082744DF098959ED6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow such uses of the scenic areas that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBD9A53AA90354F7897AE4CAC89341588"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in the scenic areas is withdrawn from all forms of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB2F9D8B221CD46B3BD7E9255904ABAEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11CF1BC00A0348FCB2D952A7F8589A0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H784EB84E08A741E8A55E3A70869A59C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDA642D636C554DAEB8D38D59FB3AC9B5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header><text>The following shall be prohibited on the Federal land within the scenic areas:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0A11171925D84883A10DF3FB78F50D08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Permanent roads.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H695D6A97495D42DE97DEC11C4DE29FCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Permanent structures.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0328CCCEAADA42E89196426FFBE0A532"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Timber harvesting.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCB9A58623EA447E9AF28C8C5F163704"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Transmission lines.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H531366E7BF974525BBDF00107643BB5A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Except as necessary to meet the minimum requirements for the administration of the scenic areas and to protect public health and safety—</text> <subparagraph id="H19F1EE0C0E4541D8800023BF9EDE599B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of motorized vehicles; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34947AB590A948ACBEA0C8546A81FEE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the establishment of temporary roads.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8C7A0697AAF48E38D946166F0EBCA4E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Commercial enterprises, except as necessary for realizing the purposes of the scenic areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H60C2F40C997848B498A784B68FD8E5FA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Wildfire, insect, and disease management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with this section, the Secretary may take any measures in the scenic areas that the Secretary determines to be necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases, including, as the Secretary determines appropriate, the coordination of those activities with the State or a local agency.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA7F242DF53C742568FBAD379514839E0"><enum>9.</enum><header>Condor National Recreation Trail</header> <subsection id="H656AA0D5F3A642EEA51B6691FCEB6BF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Condor National Recreation Trail is to provide a continual hiking trail corridor spanning the entire length of the Los Padres National Forest along the coastal mountains of Central California. The trail is named after the California Condor, a critically endangered bird species which lives along the extent of the Condor Trail within the National Forest. The trail will traverse a diversity of geography and communities through the southern and northern sections of the Los Padres National Forest.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H19F235737F6444159423DB6640BC7965"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(a) the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H872B5889847940BC9F1F60B8714DACEA"> <paragraph id="H27E7ED5AD75A4303B373D1FFBCAD7591"><enum>(31)</enum><header>Condor National Recreation Trail</header> <subparagraph id="HE67AF59BCB0E4BC68F12A2237230B242"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Condor National Recreation Trail, extending approximately ___ miles from Lake Piru to the Botchers Gap Campground in Monterey County corridor, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Condor National Recreation Trail—Proposed</quote> and dated ____.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD6ED14AB64B477D8EDC81A9E58230E1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Condor National Recreation Trail (referred to in this section as the <quote>trail</quote>) shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with—</text> <clause id="H5CD5D30B7843413CA056A0ED258F5234"><enum>(i)</enum><text>other Federal, State, tribal, regional, and local agencies;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H75AE247517014B778015EB33530B51BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>private landowners; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4D3424ED734841CE9F12E094B3DE9D7C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other interested organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0AE78AE91E644798A5F3276D2063D5E1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Continual route</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In building new connectors, and realigning the existing trail, the Secretary shall provide for a continual route through the southern and northern Los Padres National Forest, promote recreational, wilderness and cultural values, enhance connectivity with the overall National Forest trail system, emphasize safe and continuous public access, dispersal from high-use areas, and suitable water sources, and, to the extent practicable, provide all-year use.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79A7F3305D8E4E3783B13E38BC36589A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Private property rights</header> <clause id="HD3A1E3401D7449BDBDE0985F02CE7211"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No portions of the trail may be located on non-Federal land without the written consent of the landowner.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H28A753A292B34207A0EDA60865B6D4E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Secretary shall not acquire for the trail any land or interest in land outside the exterior boundary of any federally managed area without the consent of the owner of land or interest in land.</text></clause> <clause id="H42EC2B4130C44D0BB390ECD5F0FDFF93"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> 
<subclause id="HC1ED8388C41F40AAA8965799757CFBF8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>requires any private property owner to allow public access (including Federal, State, or local government access) to private property; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H85E8ACCB10BF4C228CD4EE13E6B4B235"><enum>(II)</enum><text>modifies any provision of Federal, State, or local law with respect to public access to or use of private land.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC43F2377984C432DB077EDCC35E8FF08"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The map referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7272E7DAD6EB4682A71BDAF352B14714"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Study</header> <clause id="H27D087923F874DB09D685C3EC0B3039B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a study that describes the feasibility of, and alternatives for, connecting the northern and southern portions of the Los Padres National Forest using a trail corridor across the applicable portions of the Northern and Southern Santa Lucia Mountains of the Southern California Coastal Range.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H242055A6A4E04646B699154EA2DE39D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>In completing the study required by clause (i), the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with—</text> <subclause id="HACB18B2227DF4F879C01DBFAAC653400"><enum>(I)</enum><text>appropriate Federal, State, tribal, regional, and local agencies;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7E14955333E94083B5BD741385989E4B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>private landowners;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5ED7598489124B77BC53522482196B04"><enum>(III)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3E5567CD90C14784AB4002233D0F8E13"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>members of the public.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H936C51425AED464BA1C69580A35B26DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with State, tribal, and local government entitles and private entities to complete needed trail construction, reconstruction, and realignment projects authorized by this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="HB88D9C0164B14FB2A0219B918F37E253"><enum>10.</enum><header>Forest Service study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Forest Service shall study the feasibility of opening a new trail, for vehicles measuring 50 inches or less, connecting Forest Service Highway 95 to the existing off-highway vehicle trail system in the Ballinger Canyon off-highway vehicle area.</text></section> <section id="HC1E3045DED914BD4B6C9C412F32B567D"><enum>11.</enum><header>Nonmotorized recreation opportunities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with interested parties, shall conduct a study to improve nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities (including mountain bicycling) on land not designated as wilderness within the Santa Barbara, Ojai, and Mt. Pinos ranger districts.</text></section> 
<section id="H6D817A9D885D457B992DAF3F3C241FC8"><enum>12.</enum><header>Use by members of Native American tribes</header> 
<subsection id="H3C5E313BFD4A4535B11B1F3DEADE8612"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that Indian tribes have access, in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), to the wilderness areas, scenic areas, and potential wilderness areas designated by this Act for traditional cultural and religious purposes.” .</text></subsection> <subsection id="H37290384A417403199031ACB46385FDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary closures</header> <paragraph id="H3BB22CA93A1D4DA3AF340765F8B921A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary, on request of an Indian tribe, may temporarily close to the general public 1 or more specific portions of a wilderness area, scenic area, and potential wilderness area designated by this Act to protect the privacy of the members of the Indian tribe in the conduct of traditional cultural and religious activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF57CFF1E81C3405D8D2512574F266B5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any closure under paragraph (1) shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C2833A1F4294605BEB92D1C597752BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made in such a manner as to affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum period of time necessary for the activity to be carried out; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5034DC0A1B5641308C4956956203C561"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be consistent with the purpose and intent of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>), commonly referred to as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act, and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

