<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDB1AFBB4462D405DB2D884BB14419A47" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1424 IH: Infection Reduction Labeling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1424</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to allow the marketing,
			 distribution, or sale of solid antimicrobial copper alloys with certain
			 claims, to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to exclude
			 certain solid antimicrobial copper alloys from regulation as drugs or
			 devices, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8F847A7FBDE74FECA4F257BC54FDE4DE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H554B288316674057A3F500AEAA6BCD9F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Infection Reduction Labeling Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFFB1AF3CC0EB424F8A813B5519C56040"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of solid antimicrobial copper alloys under Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136a">7 U.S.C. 136a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2426A1C6D5D24B13827387BE8ED016C1" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H65A4AE638E19484DA11CDF9A1DB845C2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Claims made for solid antimicrobial copper alloys</header>
 <paragraph id="HCFB3D80323594EFAB668D884C5B1C59B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain claims authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, solid antimicrobial copper alloys, and products made from such alloys, may be marketed, distributed, or sold with labeling making claims regarding the microbial reduction or infection control efficacy of the alloys if the claims are consistent with the results of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H81AED228F80F41FE9DDF569C0C756D39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>federally funded clinical trials finding greater than 25 percent reductions in infection rate or 50 percent reductions in microbial burden; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC568E34B37234E249DF2CA3045B8FF4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>federally funded clinical trials finding statistically significant reductions in infection rate or microbial burden.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFABE998E1CE4A50814B07C22A3C1AC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission or review of efficacy data waived</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The registration of solid antimicrobial copper alloys under this section shall not require submission or review of efficacy data related to claims consistent with the results of the clinical trials described in paragraph (1).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H6B0337E655E64154AC87929883F12776"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consistency of claims with agency-registered product label</header>
 <subparagraph id="H637FDD880A594C65B0CC009C99637A77"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Claims described in paragraph (1) shall be consistent with the product label registered under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67C37F1F3FEF4255BD6CAC0716C10AC4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Process for modification of labeling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In lieu of the notification process under subsection (c)(9), registration of a solid antimicrobial copper alloy may be modified to ensure the consistency of claims described in paragraph (1) with the product labeling pursuant to the following process:</text>
 <clause id="H1DC5CE6E015746CD97444F8CAFA53EED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The registrant shall submit a notification identifying the proposed claims that are consistent with the results of the clinical trials described in paragraph (1), and include a copy of the proposed amended product label.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H43E2A979F28F42C48D71CB318FAF9313"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Within 30 days after receipt of such a notification, the Administrator shall—</text> <subclause id="HC7F88FDB5F30442A82B984EF9457A093"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the registrant in writing if the Administrator objects to any of the proposed claims as not consistent with the results of the clinical trials described in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFDD7B4E852514F4C9E908D133656E6AD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>state the reasons why.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HBF23E902F4564F6CA39484E9E2DD48E4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A registrant may file a response to any such objection not later than 30 days after the registrant’s receipt of the objection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8011711160734DE2B1541F4434DC729F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>After receipt and consideration of any such response, the Administrator shall issue a decision within 30 days.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD55CEA00200F49D497196DD5FAF47BDC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A decision under clause (iv) shall be considered to be a final agency action.</text> </clause><clause id="H0598608286634E1987A0C5D98E838BD0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A registrant may distribute or sell a solid antimicrobial copper alloy product with the claims described in paragraph (1) after 60 days of submission of the notification described in this subparagraph, unless the Administrator issues an objection as described in this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEABD2CAB1ED54B1FAE489AA5482187C4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>solid antimicrobial copper alloy</term> means a solid copper alloy that—</text> <subparagraph id="H43DA6B558F5D4CBBBB6871EB500F4841"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is registered under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD25A599806F845739E5C1444102B5138"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is listed under Environmental Protection Agency registration number 82012–1, 82012–2, 82012–3, 82012–4, 82012–5, or 82012–6, or is otherwise identified by a Unified Numbering System code in an Environmental Protection Agency registration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E1DB7577EBB43AE8967C0DA8BCDED69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has a copper content of not less than 60 weight percent; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21A02E6180764E35A5DBD62A9AB33620"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has a content of not more than 0.1 weight percent of each of the following: lead, chromium, and arsenic.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H131A7823FB084DA4898125AF95BD60EE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Treatment of solid antimicrobial copper alloys under Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter E of chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 569C of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-8c">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–8c</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A448FE33C5A41E181E7C8B4B9F9C683" style="OLC">
				<section id="HE2845FBD57D94DDF825D59CEC1141096"><enum>569D.</enum><header>Solid antimicrobial copper alloys</header>
 <subsection id="H843D22971BD04B31B4A2AD8B7A65094D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusion from treatment as drug or device</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A product that is made from solid antimicrobial copper alloy and has labeling making a claim regarding the microbial reduction or infection control efficacy of the alloy, consistent with the results of federally funded clinical trials, shall not, by virtue of such claim—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3FCBDA4913724105B362490CEDCDA31D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be treated as a drug or device, or as a combination thereof, for purposes of this Act; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE81306336BE44B069F99CEACDED394E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>otherwise be subject to regulation by the Food and Drug Administration.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE48DC1B35F934ED7804464382D4DE561"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>solid antimicrobial copper alloy</term> means a solid copper alloy that—</text> <paragraph id="H11F2F18FD6184594A840E9653C65728B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is listed under Environmental Protection Agency registration number 82012–1, 82012–2, 82012–3, 82012–4, 82012–5, or 82012–6, or is otherwise identified by a Unified Numbering System code in an Environmental Protection Agency registration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A2EE253FA9F4630810E4FA5A1C93DB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has a copper content of not less than 60 weight percent; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4B44F03048485EAF430CCC81B7B899"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has a content of not more than 0.1 weight percent of each of the following: lead, chromium, and arsenic.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


