<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3E2A906F38BB476282ACA97DA720B4C2" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1741 IH: Truth in Healthcare Marketing Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1741</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150413">April 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To ensure that patients receive accurate health care information by prohibiting misleading and
			 deceptive advertising or representation in the provision of health care
			 services, and to require the identification of the license of health care
			 professionals, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H893B65546C924DA49EA73CA6B0309F4A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6EE9767DCCA54131874DFBA2452FE8F4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Truth in Healthcare Marketing Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H568B753E9BC0455891A5B6BA9BDC44B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H49BE078A9DB44091AE274581821195C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">many types of health care professionals including physicians, technicians, nurses, physician assistants, and other allied practitioners are engaged in providing services in health care settings, and all of these individuals play an important and distinct role in the health care delivery system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CDAF96DC6D54869A95D1981ABEEE225"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the exchange of information between patients and their health care professionals is critical to helping patients understand their health care choices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59E1580A1EB54A0680BD4FAADFC6C2AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consumers are often unaware of the differences in, and seek more information about, the qualifications, training, and education of their health care professionals;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CFFBC4277D44CA2A35E04C59B2BAA5D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evidence exists of patient confusion resulting from ambiguous health care nomenclature and related advertisements and marketing products; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H444EBC65719E4AE394EF781CFDFB4AA2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>nationwide surveys conducted in 2008 and 2010 revealed the depth of confusion regarding the education, skills, and training of health care professionals and indicated strong support for increasing clarity in the advertising and marketing claims of health care professionals.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H681211664CC24AB18765BD7876D20953"><enum>3.</enum><header>Health care service professional unfair and deceptive acts and practices</header>
 <subsection id="H6F5055A333BC470CABF406519C502A31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conduct prohibited</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to make any deceptive or misleading statement, or engage in any deceptive or misleading act, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H43C4EDC68E624FF99E75478CA6F3AAAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">misrepresents whether such person holds a State health care license; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H23494ED27E13454AAB38896CFF47FD98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>misrepresents such person’s education, training, degree, license, or clinical expertise.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE456C469F42B456AA493980FC29FA0E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To identify license in advertising</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is advertising health care services provided by such person, shall disclose in such advertisement the applicable license under which such person is authorized to provide such services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4DA72996E49F422F990D4BB3699FF2F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) or (b) shall be treated as an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>). The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H132A64F0FEDE4EE394CCB6165836EBAB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nonpreemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section does not preempt any State or local law relating to the subject matter of this section so long as such law does not prevent the implementation of this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H78F1608036DA4ED7A39A4E04DF4F6666"><enum>4.</enum><header>Truth in advertising study</header>
 <subsection id="H4855A21A7C664835AE88C32D42D4B3FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission shall conduct a study of health care professionals subject to the requirement of section 3(a) to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0B05791ECE2A424793AD199F73C75ACF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify specific acts and practices constituting a violation of such section;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAD5016EB1AB461CB42F595CA539B588"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the frequency of such acts and practices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5ECA2120B304C19997472D03C149F60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify instances of harm or injury resulting from such acts and practices;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8643734EC6549F8BB9B6B7E4AA1FCEF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>determine the extent to which such persons comply with State laws or regulations that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0A01A5449E254B3EB1F7DEF21D4EA576"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require oral or written disclosure, to the patient or in an advertisement, of the type of license such person holds; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7823841AD00E4CA59D6030484F3F3E54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>set forth requirements for advertisements for health care services with regard to disclosure of the type of license under which such person is authorized to provide such services; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8262BCF355EA4FE58D06C726C1BB782B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify instances where any State public policy has permitted acts and practices which violate section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECB9A15DC687402FB195299A18B1DEED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall report its findings to Congress not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2BE25F50E8E945FDB6B2DD4A0920BCB7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed or have the effect of changing State scope of practice for any health care professional.</text>
 </section><section id="H734B01F4FA3442F5AA1A54C5F0C8CB9D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purpose of carrying out this Act, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Trade Commission such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


