<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6A7604A5FF6C4EE2BBE8A985657D37BA" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3114 IH: To provide funds to the Army Corps of Engineers to hire veterans and members of the Armed Forces to assist the Corps with curation and historic preservation activities, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3114</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150720">July 20, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide funds to the Army Corps of Engineers to hire veterans and members of the Armed Forces to
			 assist the Corps with curation and historic preservation activities, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6517382AD2FE44A0AB129F79FAD6BFEB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H25E89C462F5C49808A5D21BBD14343E6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HDECE0D0C25D54D179D52006BD0159E56"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corps of Engineers and other Federal agencies are required to preserve and catalogue artifacts and other items of national historical significance that are uncovered during the course of their work (notably under part 79 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D297F6A7EB043C0BACAEE941A6E2CDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Uncatalogued artifacts within the care of Federal agencies are stored in hundreds of repositories and museums across the Nation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4357338C74224888A09DD86F04CCDA99"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In October 2009, the Corps of Engineers, Center of Expertise for the Curation and Management of Archaeological Collections, initiated the Veterans’ Curation Program to employ and train Iraq and Afghanistan veterans in archaeological processing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD1B8963CB4C48B9B3651BAF5EFF630C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Veterans’ Curation Program employs veterans and members of the Armed Forces in the sorting, cleaning, and cataloguing of artifacts managed by the Corps of Engineers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82CBBF87003E45C3BB5E21828FE6B220"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Employees of the Veterans’ Curation Program gain valuable work skills, including computer database management, records management, photographic and scanning techniques, computer software proficiency, vocabulary and writing skills, and interpersonal communication skills, as well as knowledge and training in archaeology and history.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBECE6219B49490E8051628A5890AEC5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since 2009, a total of 241 veterans have participated in the Veterans’ Curation Program, including the current class of 38 participants. Of the 203 graduates of the program, 87 percent have received permanent employment in a field related to training received under the program or chosen to continue their education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB654620C45244DC6BE120F64BB8FFCEA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Experience in archaeological curation gained through the Veterans’ Curation Program is valuable training and experience for the museum, forensics, administrative, records management, and other fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5541242F1B074D0897E521F3E331589C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Veterans’ Curation Program participants may assist the Corps of Engineers in developing a more efficient and comprehensive collections management program and also may provide the workforce to meet the records management needs at other agencies and departments, including the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HC0425EBE24514AE395D87B063706FE36"><enum>2.</enum><header>Training and employment for veterans and members of Armed Forces in curation and historic
			 preservation</header>
 <subsection id="H2E981FD3CA3D4EE08CB0DC08614F04B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training and employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall carry out a Veterans’ Curation Program to hire veterans and members of the Armed Forces to assist the Secretary in carrying out curation and historic preservation activities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF00CA8A17CFD4A25928E860921ACDEC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text> <paragraph id="HAC06F222743E4C2096B09FDB124085F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$5,000,000 for fiscal year 2016;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9485D6784A5D4C7EA03D26E6EAA3BE11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$6,000,000 for fiscal year 2017;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H80084D8296B54675A1899D45EB04A648"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$7,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H707460EE31D24A418F9D6EA3D6F9F270"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$8,000,000 for fiscal year 2019; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D7230923E494399BF9986D9094E1B31"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$9,000,000 for fiscal year 2020.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


