<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H52CAED8953074E25B1D27A90594AA305" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2337 IH: To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize priority review for breakthrough devices.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2337</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150514">May 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize priority review for breakthrough devices.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H636C8C31A52041B6A7B3AB32264799E0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2646E54D16DE47A48092EEC654DC2AA6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Priority review for breakthrough devices</header> 
<subsection id="H537162E7C293460EAB570CBF49A87D14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H668A751143804BEBBA0ECEB842DBAC9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 515(d)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H331FF214ECE644DAA6AA1D7C45BD8B7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECB8301D65A5471D8E8C9496480C6530"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (5); and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H830384AE93A4448CB555450CFA380094"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 515A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360e-1">21 U.S.C. 360e–1</external-xref>) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H4A459E745B3F43CEABF7D3F0D4C15807" style="OLC"> <section id="H723966B8CA00494AB29C042A53AA81F0"><enum>515B.</enum><header>Priority review for breakthrough devices</header> <subsection id="H61932DE263F9480FB7CEC04331A924D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to provide for more effective treatment or diagnosis of life-threatening or irreversibly debilitating human diseases or conditions, the Secretary shall establish<italic></italic> a program to provide priority review for devices—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3BAC374B3B8F4A9AA27F3915889DA4D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>representing breakthrough technologies;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6288646D9774F7F91922609821D42B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for which no approved alternatives exist;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5536DB1697074162BBAC07FAAA5A24A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offering significant advantages over existing approved or cleared alternatives, including the potential to, compared to existing approved or cleared alternatives, reduce or eliminate the need for hospitalization, improve patient quality of life, facilitate patients’ ability to manage their own care (such as through self-directed personal assistance), or establish long-term clinical efficiencies; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9864EBA80C94BF2BBE31FDFBA9F4985"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the availability of which is in the best interest of patients.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA6A810C426B4464984F952611773CD13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Request for designation</header><text>A sponsor of a device may request that the Secretary designate the device for priority review under this section. Any such request for designation may be made at any time prior to the submission of an application under section 515(c), a petition for classification under section 513(f)(2), or a notification under section 510(k).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H0B9721A31E86452B8BF31A8B6F8D5694"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation process</header> <paragraph id="HB8D25542D9AE48A48BAE54B820575AF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 calendar days after the receipt of a request under subsection (b), the Secretary shall determine whether the device that is the subject of the request meets the criteria described in subsection (a). If the Secretary determines that the device meets the criteria, the Secretary shall designate the device for priority review.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD38723E4E18B484093D8CA9D2BD9FE27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Review of a request under subsection (b) shall be undertaken by a team that is composed of experienced staff and managers of the Food and Drug Administration and is chaired by a senior manager. <italic></italic></text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE4DB7738FE74F988AE8236E809C0077"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designation determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination approving or denying a request under subsection (b) shall be considered a significant decision under section 517A and the Secretary shall provide a written, substantive summary of the basis for the determination in accordance with section 517A(a).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H908A9655F4B140CBB0F0902D61907AFA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reconsideration</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6B3C2B50C04D43F39922FFE7CCCF4F2C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Request for reconsideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person whose request under subsection (b) is denied may, within 30 days of the denial, request reconsideration of the denial in accordance with section 517A(b)—</text> <clause id="H75878B69297340A691585B8A8526B6BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based upon the submission of documents by such person; or</text> </clause>
<clause id="H23316B98A4D648A69D682849BFA9CEF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based upon such documents and a meeting or teleconference.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H793D79420F5845A0AF0D4C5F1BF822E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Response</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reconsideration of a designation determination under this paragraph shall be conducted in accordance with section 517A(b).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD5B1C7DB213D4D08872979D4F12755D3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary approves a priority review designation for a device under this section, the Secretary may not withdraw the designation based on the fact that the criteria specified in subsection (a) are no longer met because of the subsequent clearance or approval of another device that was designated under—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF34F901A4F548F1925A90AB62C4DD23"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">this section; or</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A7AABDA5C4748CAB3E1C420DDF6B57E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 515(d)(5) (as in effect immediately prior to the enactment of the 21st Century Cures Act).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H511FDD0ADBC7425298327B8BE28BC2D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority review</header> <paragraph id="HAA4C4BCCBA584FF191F92C846F062BB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of expediting the development and review of devices designated under subsection (c), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAC5A6B3568544CA2AD8BAFF40FB28255"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assign a team of staff, including a team leader with appropriate subject matter expertise and experience, for each device for which a request is submitted under subsection (b);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB22002766FA41F6BBF34E47CA23EFDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide for oversight of the team by senior agency personnel to facilitate the efficient development of the device and the efficient review of any submission described in subsection (b) for the device;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBA1710110E224B7C8EA54AB084C2E9F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>adopt an efficient process for timely dispute resolution;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08039EA20C43460D85AC03BA373E3731"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide for interactive communication with the sponsor of the device during the review process;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H96D5D4E7518D49AFBE3349E28F3F2F5E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>expedite the Secretary’s review of manufacturing and quality systems compliance, as applicable;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE44AA203355048289592E0CDDE6EC41E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclose to the sponsor in advance the topics of any consultation concerning the sponsor’s device that the Secretary intends to undertake with external experts or an advisory committee and provide the sponsor an opportunity to recommend such external experts;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H551C96F94DD045658C29EB55A240FFA2"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for applications submitted under section 515(c), provide for advisory committee input, as the Secretary determines appropriate (including in response to the request of the sponsor); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3228FD16A414EF48C4B528A9E07DA0D"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assign staff to be available within a reasonable time to address questions by institutional review committees concerning the conditions and clinical testing requirements applicable to the investigational use of the device pursuant to an exemption under section 520(g).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD122641C9FC4D96844FA5F505593E48"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the actions described in paragraph (1), for purposes of expediting the development and review of devices designated under subsection (c), the Secretary, in collaboration with the device sponsor, may, as appropriate—</text> <subparagraph id="H22D49283CD18469FA9FEA43110D13A00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with the sponsor regarding early agreement on a data development plan;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H044BCACC06864422BFE00AA9F2D9E472"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take steps to ensure that the design of clinical trials is as efficient as practicable, such as through adoption of shorter or smaller clinical trials, application of surrogate end­points, and use of adaptive trial designs and Bayesian statistics, to the extent scientifically appropriate;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4BC8BCC7BCE43E3998781E49254EE2E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitate, to the extent scientifically appropriate, expedited and efficient development and review of the device through utilization of timely postmarket data collection, with regard to applications for approval under section 515(c); and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H76D805CD9B64454FB6239F95AFD78100"><enum>(D)</enum><text>agree to clinical protocols that the Secretary will consider binding on the Secretary and the sponsor, subject to—</text> <clause id="H5FB59531E4754BA5A3223E907BDD7411"><enum>(i)</enum><text>changes agreed to by the sponsor and the Secretary;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H1A6EE8A25CF440F487E1B8A7F3C0F009"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>changes that the Secretary determines are required to prevent an unreasonable risk to the public health; or</text> </clause> <clause id="H54056BD5841E43AD9676218D89EC3862"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the identification of a substantial scientific issue determined by the Secretary to be essential to the safety or effectiveness of the device involved.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H837BB48A8FD747EA9CA121F662C87BC0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority review guidance</header> 
<paragraph id="H84EDE6AA5E4F4EC3B40B1ADF7ABDD64A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The Secretary shall issue guidance on the implementation of this section. Such guidance shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H687EC336939D406298DCB33099E77E49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The process for a person to seek a priority review designation.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H32111F79272B4FAAA9EEAAFA85C533A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A template for requests under subsection (b).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6317BF52CAED44329AF9FBAE344E1888"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The criteria the Secretary will use in evaluating a request for priority review.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7642C41C81B44F65B12343216A5C2199"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The standards the Secretary will use in assigning a team of staff, including team leaders, to review devices designated for priority review, including any training required for such personnel on effective and efficient review.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEA42FCF388047868D404BB04BABE662"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text>Prior to finalizing the guidance under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall propose such guidance for public comment.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2AAE4B82DC2D4630B0FEAAAD04EECC6E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Construction</header> 
<paragraph id="HFDBD5FFB6BEB46818C2FB3C2F24C4B90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>This section is intended to encourage the Secretary and provide the Secretary sufficient authorities to apply efficient and flexible approaches to expedite the development of, and prioritize the agency’s review of, devices that represent breakthrough technologies.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EE9F2762EFD4A7F9E1BF42B059B871D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><italic></italic>Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter the criteria and standards for evaluating an application pursuant to section 515(c), a report and request for classification under section 513(f)(2), or a report under section 510(k), including the recognition of valid scientific evidence as described in section 513(a)(3)(B), and consideration of the least burdensome means of evaluating device effectiveness or demonstrating substantial equivalence between devices with differing technological characteristics, as applicable. Nothing in this section alters the authority of the Secretary to act on an application pursuant to section 515(d) before completion of an establishment inspection, as the Secretary deems appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H545500F2D7514BC7ACCCE6691D4CB244"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment related to designation determinations</header><text>Section 517A(a)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360g-1">21 U.S.C. 360g–1(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>a request for designation under section 515B,</quote> after <quote>an application under section 515,</quote>.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

