<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H610189273CEA492DA833A5C6F46BF677" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3350 RH: Know the CBRN Terrorism Threats to Transportation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 225</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3350</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 114–296]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>October 20, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To require a terrorism threat assessment regarding the transportation of chemical, biological,
			 nuclear, and radiological materials through United States land borders and
			 within the United States, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HDB5E80F3F9ED4631960C7D30BFDE7005" style="OLC">
 <section id="H909789E7CDD44623B4057EF2DC9859A7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Know the CBRN Terrorism Threats to Transportation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB4604D34605646BF8452892B8F9308E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Terrorism threat assessment</header> <subsection id="H957380F828F24ECBA9416F886C8E1BF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Under Secretary of Intelligence and Analysis, shall conduct a terrorism threat assessment of the transportation of chemical, biological, nuclear, and radiological materials through United States land borders and within the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7A49A3BA92DB4AE8BF8D731A581721BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the terrorism threat assessment required under subsection (a), the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis shall consult with the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, to ensure that such terrorism threat assessment is informed by current information about homeland security threats.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7CA6F75717FB4F67B042509364100E36"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Upon completion of the terrorism threat assessment required under subsection (a), the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis shall disseminate such terrorism threat assessment to Federal partners, including the Department of Transportation and the Department of Energy, and State and local partners, including the National Network of Fusion Centers.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>October 20, 2015</action-date>
		<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


