<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCA3972FE213E4803A0F0C7121F008BD6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2962 IH: America’s College Promise Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2962</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150708">July 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000030">Ms. Loretta Sanchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000473">Mr. Takai</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide greater access to higher education for America’s students.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H991585723BB646C88A6A25B4AD728A0C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9E195F942FDB4590BA451C74F632B903" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>America’s College Promise Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF09475474A6A4306B39F34DD8816F6EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to help all individuals of the United States earn the education and skills the individuals need—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA03DFA91175245C480611F8DE3C31EDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by making 2 years of community college free, through a new partnership with States and Indian tribes to help the States and Indian tribes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2089F880EDC4481BBB250DFD4D8AC49B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>waive resident community college tuition and fees for eligible students;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08484B09D1824D579A38BE8C8DEC261F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain State and Indian tribe support for higher education; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FC2800F939D4B01B70E036EC0EB1F0B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote key reforms to improve student outcomes; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H569155EB8C1F4BE59182C79C9B48E87B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>through a new partnership with minority-serving institutions to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H95611F13C7BB4441BBF4250C2EAB1D8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage eligible students to enroll and successfully complete a baccalaureate degree at participating institutions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC24638E4C614276A88434B22D2C9621"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote key reforms to improve student outcomes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><title id="HA4DCB2D2241042508B6A85AFFB876F70"><enum>I</enum><header>STATE AND INDIAN TRIBE GRANTS FOR COMMUNITY COLLEGES</header> <section id="HAB0BAFBAFD2D44CA87AAC44F4283ABDE"><enum>101.</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">From amounts appropriated under section 107(a) for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall award grants to eligible States and Indian tribes to pay the Federal share of expenditures needed to carry out the activities and services described in section 105.</text>
			</section><section id="H2E74A89938DE43548D332E2A31AAEC5A"><enum>102.</enum><header>Federal share; non-Federal share</header>
				<subsection id="HCE7FCCED1B7E4EC0B7697D8966C1EE41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal share</header>
 <paragraph id="H005AFB518D834A619F94191A792226F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Formula</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Federal share of a grant under this title shall be based on a formula, determined by the Secretary, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0ADB65F34301426EA62C01C9192784CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accounts for the State or Indian tribe’s share of eligible students; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA67B715AF0E4B5AABE22351428C6DA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides, for each eligible student in the State or Indian tribe, a per-student amount that is—</text>
 <clause id="HAC29DBA565934F0ABB2E7F8E3EB3B458"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 300 percent of the per-student amount of the State or Indian tribe share, determined under subsection (b), subject to clause (ii); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD0709498BEAD41ADB5572DEFA55D24E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not greater than 75 percent of—</text> <subclause id="HC7539653F7FC471C806084DF97053D44"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for the 2016–2017 award year, the average resident community college tuition and fees per student in all States for the most recent year for which data are available; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD8C62E9FDCB04004997012FF4C928B93"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for each subsequent award year, the average resident community college tuition and fees per student in all States calculated under this subclause for the preceding year, increased by the lesser of—</text>
 <item id="H8AC62E694E254B4B8A1236FD1C6EEEBD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the percentage by which the average resident community college tuition and fees per student in all States for the most recent year for which data are available increased as compared to such average for the preceding year; or</text>
 </item><item id="H6D4C48BB60F8417EB37959EAE7863663"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>3 percent.</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD54F2E0B4BBB4280A88B7B3631D4617D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for certain indian tribes</header><text>In any case in which not less than 75 percent of the students at the community colleges operated or controlled by an Indian tribe are low-income students, the amount of the Federal share for such Indian tribe shall be not less than 95 percent of the total amount needed to waive tuition and fees for all eligible students enrolled in such community colleges.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E3AB2D57E304CDEBF4FAD617773B2E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State or tribal share</header>
					<paragraph id="H11B4CE6E40DD4A47A3888D7D38A7002C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Formula</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF7767D4B618A4679A74D957040ECC106"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The State or tribal share of a grant under this title for each fiscal year shall be the amount needed to pay 25 percent of the average community college resident tuition and fees per student in all States in the 2016–2017 award year for all eligible students in the State or Indian tribe, respectively, for such fiscal year, except as provided in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CBE799EC9EB4CB2A13E8BDA0F0021F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for certain indian tribes</header><text>In a case in which not less than 5 percent of the students at the community colleges operated or controlled by an Indian tribe are low-income students, the amount of such Indian tribe’s tribal share shall not exceed 5 percent of the total amount needed to waive tuition and fees for all eligible students enrolled in such community colleges.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13E2D46F5F5148978D3BC082C0C56B0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Need-based aid</header><text>A State or Indian tribe may include any need-based financial aid provided through State or tribal funds to eligible students as part of the State or tribal share.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B4421953F00450FBC50B478591ED067"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No in-kind contributions</header><text>A State or Indian tribe shall not include in-kind contributions for purposes of the State or tribal share described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2BE61DE8C0E242B988E922551FD17DE8"><enum>103.</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this title, a State or Indian tribe shall agree to waive community college resident tuition and fees for all eligible students for each year of the grant.</text>
			</section><section id="H424573730A1241B1840E374BB9A34B82"><enum>104.</enum><header>Applications</header>
 <subsection id="H018BB03014F84DDC91F2A45D5E93C5EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>For each fiscal year for which a State or Indian tribe desires a grant under this title, an application shall be submitted to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Such application shall be submitted by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1FCC1673EB7E43CCA8A1AE97EF5075EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a State, the Governor, the State agency with jurisdiction over higher education, or another agency designated by the Governor to administer the program under this title; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H891ABB8D5B684ED2A75E46A9286D344E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an Indian tribe, the governing body of such tribe.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06951EAF206F4E4D83F107907378EB49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each State or Indian tribe application shall include, at a minimum—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD830535865A8447B80354A105B781862"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an estimate of the number of eligible students in the State or Indian tribe and the cost of waiving community college resident tuition and fees for all eligible students for each fiscal year covered by the grant, with annual increases of an amount that shall not exceed 3 percent of the prior year’s average resident community college tuition and fees;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B07BA376579476588EF693159EB4E9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assurance that all community colleges in the State or under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe, respectively, will waive resident tuition and fees for eligible students in programs that are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H25876C3A35EB4F02A343FA02D1EFF05E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>academic programs with credits that can fully transfer via articulation agreement toward a baccalaureate degree or post­bac­ca­lau­reate degree at any public institution of higher education in the State; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF5B37CF23B74F4CBFFA0BEA28770218"><enum>(B)</enum><text>occupational skills training programs that lead to a recognized postsecondary credential that is in an in-demand industry sector or occupation in the State;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FED428101DF401F825A91761BC61B42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the promising and evidence-based institutional reforms and innovative practices to improve student outcomes, including completion or transfer rates, that have been or will be adopted by the participating community colleges, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H17871A62954F468AB6BD361B2220CEEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing comprehensive academic and student support services, including mentoring and advising, especially for low-income, first-generation, adult, and other underrepresented students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69AC9742882A4F0AA27D19ACCD155235"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing accelerated learning opportunities, such as dual or concurrent enrollment programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49BDE50A632849B084BFA72E6EA221E7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advancing competency-based education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09C02518C2AE43CE9D623DD5C54FE1D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthening remedial education, especially for low-income, first-generation, adult and other underrepresented students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H464C5F3715AF4F81B63F1C120701AE9E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implementing course redesigns of high-enrollment courses to improve student outcomes and reduce cost; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87051905C52F41FFB125464AB35305F7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>utilizing career pathways or degree pathways;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H380CC1D696214BFAA1FFB29BD06690EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of how the State or Indian tribe will promote alignment between its public secondary school and postsecondary education systems, including between 2-year and 4-year public institutions of higher education and with minority-serving institutions described in section 371 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q</external-xref>), to expand awareness of and access to postsecondary education, reduce the need for remediation and repeated coursework, and improve student outcomes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8705AD8B410E427B8B18442461FC5EAD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of how the State or Indian tribe will ensure that programs leading to a recognized postsecondary credential meet the quality criteria established by the State under section 123(a) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3153">29 U.S.C. 3153(a)</external-xref>) or other quality criteria determined appropriate by the State or Indian tribe;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1AB5F2C65EF411A925381BD659F06FC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an assurance that all participating community colleges in the State or under the authority of the Indian tribe have entered into program participation agreements under section 487 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H998093F7B2F74E4692B22E450B118386"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an assurance that, for each year of the grant, the State or Indian tribe will notify each eligible student of the student’s remaining eligibility for assistance under this title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8B2504C162A4C489352AA527F1995FB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of how the State or Indian tribe will promote the improved performance of public institutions of higher education through funding reform, including through the use of a performance-based model that allocates a portion of the State or Indian tribe’s public higher education expenditures based on the performance of those institutions on State-specified metrics, including successful student outcomes, while ensuring that existing funding gaps for underresourced institutions are not exacerbated.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCD1B9B36B1E84F92B1CF8008088C6841"><enum>105.</enum><header>Allowable uses of funds</header>
 <subsection id="H5C687DC69E1A40DE8C504A466A7C8B25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or Indian tribe shall use a grant under this title only to provide funds to participating community colleges to waive resident tuition and fees for eligible students who are enrolled in—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE2C35E39FEFE4089AAF4E502E0669AE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>academic programs with credits that can fully transfer via articulation agreement toward a baccalaureate degree or postbaccalaureate degree at any public institution of higher education in the State; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D368437BF0244518289E67DFE0B5E02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>occupational skills training programs that lead to a recognized postsecondary credential that is in an in-demand industry sector or occupation in the State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA053B45183D426794B9A0517C66B937"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional uses</header><text>If a State or Indian tribe demonstrates to the Secretary that it has grant funds remaining after meeting the demand for activities described in subsection (a), the State or Indian tribe may use those funds to carry out one or more of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC5AD4B4B61724729A997CB904B7D203F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Expanding the waiver of resident tuition and fees at community college to students who are returning students or otherwise not enrolling in postsecondary education for the first time, and who meet the student eligibility requirements of clauses (i) through (v) of section 106(4)(A).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72D856E78AA04078A2EB71831B075294"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Expanding the scope and capacity of high-quality academic and occupational skills training programs at community colleges.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9B763BB2C284D63B95A112E7075204F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improving postsecondary education readiness in the State or Indian tribe, through outreach and early intervention.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB3D604E45394956941854B168FC133F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Expanding access to dual or concurrent enrollment programs.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC12D3D5658940DDBFF54089B7E26F61"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Improving affordability at 4-year public institutions of higher education.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89564EDA56E3454E83DDFA96323EC684"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds for administrative purposes</header><text>A State or Indian tribe that receives a grant under this title may not use any funds provided under this title for administrative purposes relating to the grant under this title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0FDFFE1953724F6791C8E774AEAD179D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintenance of effort</header><text>A State or Indian tribe receiving a grant under this title is entitled to receive its full allotment of funds under this title for a fiscal year only if, for each year of the grant, the State or Indian tribe provides financial support for public higher education at a level equal to or exceeding the average amount provided per full-time equivalent student for public institutions of higher education for the 3 consecutive preceding State or Indian tribe fiscal years. In making the calculation under this subsection, the State or Indian tribe shall exclude capital expenses and research and development costs and include need-based financial aid for students who attend public institutions of higher education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D49FCA59E2247739DA38A2B54BF0860"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Indian tribe receiving a grant under this title shall submit an annual report to the Secretary describing the uses of grant funds under this title, the progress made in fulfilling the requirements of the grant, and rates of graduation, transfer and attainment of recognized postsecondary credentials at participating community colleges, and including any other information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1BD15DEDAEEA4B26B566E22931A58BEF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting by secretary</header><text>The Secretary annually shall—</text> <paragraph id="H47E099A9EE23411ABBA48A070BAA1141"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compile and analyze the information described in subsection (e); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80DD6AC076E042388D09BA086435C107"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepare and submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives containing the analysis described in paragraph (1) and an identification of State and Indian tribe best practices for achieving the purpose of this title.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD27BAB2D6F0F4DE687CD3B5A1801B249"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to eligible States and Indian tribes concerning best practices regarding the promising and evidence-based institutional reforms and innovative practices to improve student outcomes as described in section 104(b)(3) and shall disseminate such best practices among the States and Indian tribes.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HB9150E5AF2064FB89F48498199332746"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Continuation of funding</header>
 <paragraph id="HD10E1CAFB20F4F3CABB40DD89FBD46AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or Indian tribe receiving a grant under this title for a fiscal year may continue to receive funding under this title for future fiscal years conditioned on the availability of budget authority and on meeting the requirements of the grant, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H828B1211976E49B2BFBCADA5C2E22A0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discontinuation</header><text>The Secretary may discontinue funding of the Federal share of a grant under this title if the State or Indian tribe has violated the terms of the grant or is not making adequate progress in implementing the reforms described in the application submitted under section 104.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA3E603AA08D54ECF984322A9E3511849"><enum>106.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="H384463907A8649A4B53F912A507493A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Career pathway</header><text>The term <term>career pathway</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96736B17774146DCB623EAE9D86FB3D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community college</header><text>The term <term>community college</term> means a public institution of higher education at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree, including 2-year tribally controlled colleges under section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>) and public 2-year State institutions of higher education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9A047045A0648EE8D69B14901919AD2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Dual or concurrent enrollment program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>dual or concurrent enrollment program</term> means an academic program through which a secondary school student is able simultaneously to earn credit toward a secondary school diploma and a postsecondary degree or other recognized postsecondary credential, including early college high school programs.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H856DCA90BE2E4E54BF38879ED4CF8D4F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible student</header>
 <subparagraph id="H024E7238F4B048C3A7C70FCB9C3CA126"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>The term <term>eligible student</term> means a student who—</text> <clause id="H2F8A760F4B7944ACAFD5EAF9C1C64705"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC1E1F5988E8348C1A2FE35F05AFBEACC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>enrolls in a community college for the first time, regardless of age, after the date of enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0DCDF62C789D44F2BC01C845F1F44557" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is enrolled in a community college, for the first time, as of the date of enactment of this Act;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HF003AA92823C42969EA2016093FFE971"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>attends the community college on not less than a half-time basis;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFEB6ED204F5B43679F2C2C2B7719454C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is maintaining satisfactory progress, as defined in section 484(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1091">20 U.S.C. 1091(c)</external-xref>), in the student’s course of study;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0CF631EA7E434B028A1FDD10167C13DF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>qualifies for resident tuition, as determined by the State or Indian tribe; and</text> </clause><clause id="HC766C4AF174A4DB299659E90D8F7026B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is enrolled in an eligible program described in section 104(b)(2).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4C0553F26564AF980A6FFDE2704C4F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An otherwise eligible student shall lose eligibility 3 calendar years after first receiving benefits under this title.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD9547BD2CC542CD9739C536A95ABD2A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>In-demand industry sector or occupation</header><text>The term <term>in-demand industry sector or occupation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1346ABD58C5949D78A7629E1EABFB01F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/479a">25 U.S.C. 479a</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C18F6F79C414877876A9A489F975337"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H523C54AAE7034010B808D0AD02470A87"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Recognized postsecondary credential</header><text>The term <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term> has the meaning as described in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6C85A74D6824B2DA3512EAACE79FAB3"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H698719B970B34FA68BADE753FB29AF80"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H68643D0590464222909FB87FAE6CB634"><enum>107.</enum><header>Appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="H541C579B693D4BFE83C5E4334A18800E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization and appropriations</header><text>For the purpose of making grants under this title, there are authorized to be appropriated, and there are appropriated—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1379AB08DE1F4EB6A2D0EDC2569E5761"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,365,000,000 for fiscal year 2016;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7BB0F783C794FD4A8BD726D35A81B78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$3,020,000,000 for fiscal year 2017;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB4C11BDA06A4D55B70929B786E1CADC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$3,854,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD174DBC671CE471D8D5893D01801418D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$5,395,000,000 for fiscal year 2019;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE2ABBE0D886480D89CD563C670A96A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$7,061,000,000 for fiscal year 2020;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F1BE88E2A2A46409DB30E27895F8FE1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$8,085,000,000 for fiscal year 2021;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H815B63F69BEF431AAA66BB3A9EF19AC1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$10,182,000,000 for fiscal year 2022;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C73B5C64A02413E915B48013B31F2C7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>$13,019,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF62475B98D974192A5FD9B3BD40BFBAC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>$13,583,000,000 for fiscal year 2024; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H950A02A311414898B91DE878242A51A9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>$14,171,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3733268E79DD44ECACDEEBA0E4A9C576"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Funds appropriated under subsection (a) shall remain available to the Secretary until expended.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H59868C21377C4A4DBAB9F86639C8A122"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Insufficient funds</header><text>If the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year is not sufficient to award each participating State and Indian tribe a grant under this title that is equal to the minimum amount of the Federal share described in section 102(a), the Secretary may ratably reduce the amount of each such grant or take other actions necessary to ensure an equitable distribution of such amount.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H25B75A372534439185CB04EFF5C5F7E5"><enum>II</enum><header>GRANTS TO HISTORICALLY BLACK COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES, HISPANIC-SERVING INSTITUTIONS, ASIAN
			 AMERICAN AND NATIVE AMERICAN PACIFIC ISLANDER-SERVING INSTITUTIONS, TRIBAL
			 COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES, ALASKA NATIVE-SERVING INSTITUTIONS, NATIVE
			 HAWAIIAN-SERVING INSTITUTIONS, PREDOMINANTLY BLACK INSTITUTIONS, AND
			 NATIVE AMERICAN-SERVING NONTRIBAL INSTITUTIONS</header>
			<section id="H9F85DE99E9404A4D89A0C98A86AFEE82"><enum>201.</enum><header>Pathways to student success for historically black colleges and universities</header>
 <subsection id="H58FE364C431642598CE952793287F46B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under section 204(a) for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall award grants to participating 4-year historically black colleges or universities that meet the requirements of subsection (b) to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1690D30C657246A1A5E0A8E0F50E7CCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourage students to enroll as first-time students and successfully complete a bachelor’s degree at participating institutions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6D93A4FFEF74A4681AA0676C29FE461"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide incentives to community college students to transfer to participating institutions through strong transfer pathways to complete a bachelor’s degree program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DA46D9D8B694D18A5DE0B7EF87B0DAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support participating institutions to better serve new and existing students by engaging in reforms and innovations designed to improve completion rates and other student outcomes.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA29E8E4A49B44CCF840D303BE1DE3CB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under the program under this section, an institution shall be a historically black college or university that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD9A6CC19F135455880DDA1CDB73F2E70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a student body of which not less than 35 percent are low-income students;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD50D0CB034EE45AAB4FC6E1F9BF57BFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commits to maintaining or adopting and implementing promising and evidence-based institutional reforms and innovative practices to improve the completion rates and other student outcomes, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F62E1B1AA45487DB9F8A60537901EE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing comprehensive academic and student support services, including mentoring and advising;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00916D9A56124D6997882D179B8AEE64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing accelerated learning opportunities and degree pathways, such as dual enrollment and pathways to graduate and professional degree programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE6B5767F9324F6CB7E9AEDAF7B9BAB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advancing distance and competency-based education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H181B4A62A2F84F6B8CED4528873EC5AC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>partnering with employers, industry, not-for-profit associations, and other groups to provide opportunities to advance learning outside the classroom, including work-based learning opportunities such as internships or apprenticeships or programs designed to improve inter-cultural development and personal growth, such as foreign exchange and study abroad programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H848EEFDFD2F845F289DDE32582B0EA3D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reforming remedial education, especially for low-income students, first generation college students, adult students, and other underrepresented students; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F714A53BF0047F998D21D4575852DE1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>implementing course redesigns of high-enrollment courses to improve student outcomes and reduce cost;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9CACA21199B434EAFD15400B09A7518"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sets performance goals for improving student outcomes for the duration of the grant; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H31D342F4354549698522EB44580BE8D5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if receiving a grant for transfer students, has articulation agreements with community colleges at the national, State, or local level to ensure that community college credits can fully transfer to the participating institution.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99B778693AA94A6985ABD1626BC7330E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amount</header>
 <paragraph id="H2B604B31E1FF47D28A24A33F981D532D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial amount</header><text>For the first year that an eligible institution participates in the grant program under this section and subject to paragraph (3), such eligible institution shall receive a grant in an amount based on the product of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4879F2D42F244A808E4619AA5A699B67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the actual cost of tuition and fees at the eligible institution in such year (referred to in this section as the per-student rebate); multiplied by</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B0664DD597E43879A3EF00E5717C3FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of eligible students enrolled in the eligible institution for the preceding year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9074FF8FE830486783BAA4CE9DBD3198"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent increases</header><text>For each succeeding year after the first year of the grant program under this section, each participating eligible institution shall receive a grant in the amount determined under paragraph (1) for such year, except that in no case shall the amount of the per-student rebate for an eligible institution increase by more than 3 percent as compared to the amount of such rebate for the preceding year.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H9BB62008FAF64AEBBEEB5DA85FBC10ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H34FDCDC0308C4BBD91E53A97F4CD6048"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Maximum per-student rebate</header><text>No eligible institution participating in the grant program under this section shall receive a per-student rebate amount for any year that is greater than the national average of annual tuition and fees at public 4-year institutions of higher education for such year, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92C4BB28C126407EABB08CDEDD6AE122"><enum>(B)</enum><header>First year tuition and fees</header><text>During the first year of participation in the grant program under this section, no eligible institution may increase tuition and fees at a rate greater than any annual increase at the eligible institution in the previous 5 years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DE86CD2BC75440697F1A7E14EDB5282"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible institution that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H15487DDCB2814CFBB238489931358FC3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds awarded under this section to a participating eligible institution shall be used to waive or significantly reduce tuition and fees for eligible students in an amount of not more than up to the annual per-student rebate amount for each student, for not more than the first 60 credits an eligible student enrolls in the participating eligible institution.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HE0AFF1BD3E6D457B997AD77883FBAFA2"><enum>202.</enum><header>Pathways to student success for Hispanic-serving institutions, Asian American and Native American
			 Pacific Islander-serving institutions, tribal colleges and universities,
			 Alaska Native-serving institutions, Native Hawaiian-serving institutions,
			 predominantly Black institutions, and Native American-serving nontribal
			 institutions</header>
 <subsection id="HA204B116D27D43D688EBB42C0AB669D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under section 204(a) for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall award grants to participating 4-year minority-serving institutions to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H207885F4188D4824BE3C6DC25A0EDEE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourage students to enroll as first-time students and successfully complete a bachelor’s degree at participating institutions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD782D3A3CC734467A7C26385875D606A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide incentives to community college students to transfer to participating institutions through strong transfer pathways to complete a bachelor’s degree program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8296BC45E5EB4FBA90B2B1E4C695FE74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support participating institutions to better serve new and existing students by engaging in reforms and innovations designed to improve completion rates and other student outcomes.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D1A14428F794B19AE4A6DF1558FE2E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Institutional eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to participate and receive a grant under this section, an institution shall be a minority-serving institution that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC787849435AC43ACA4D5FBE2B30B0C1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a student body of which not less than 35 percent are low-income students;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A58A91021984BD58D4DDE07FD87598F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commits to maintaining or adopting and implementing promising and evidence-based institutional reforms and innovative practices to improve the completion rates and other student outcomes, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC14EA6214AE043D1A346D193890F26CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing comprehensive academic and student support services, including mentoring and advising;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD396D0CFC0A4CDE8CDDA24F004F977A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing accelerated learning opportunities and degree pathways, such as dual enrollment and pathways to graduate and professional degree programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8267C3CF2D8C419B923147A2041B71F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advancing distance and competency-based education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AA367A5168947B690E878AB739E9B1F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>partnering with employers, industry, not-for-profit associations, and other groups to provide opportunities to advance learning outside the classroom, including work-based learning opportunities such as internships or apprenticeships or programs designed to improve inter-cultural development and personal growth, such as foreign exchange and study abroad programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AC1F0A2D75F4E5DBB62F23EA4B35808"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reforming remedial education, especially for low-income students, first generation college students, adult students, and other underrepresented students; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBF349DD0A99417389A4FA9443A37AE7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>implementing course redesigns of high-enrollment courses to improve student outcomes and reduce cost;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3A527B0236D4A7EB1FAE6C694CC0044"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sets performance goals for improving student outcomes for the duration of the grant; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H337E02959A7E479283643E646CCDEA3B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if receiving a grant for transfer students, has articulation agreements with community colleges at the national, State, or local levels to ensure that community college credits can fully transfer to the participating institution.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1981853A9D941F3A9E537DF3DE2884C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amount</header>
 <paragraph id="HDBEA40B96A334CB8BFED2F87A49C61A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial amount</header><text>For the first year that an eligible institution participates in the grant program under this section and subject to paragraph (3), such participating eligible institution shall receive a grant in an amount based on the product of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H50FC67CE7A08484DAC0AED327FE28902"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the actual cost of tuition and fees at the eligible institution in such year (referred to in this section as the per-student rebate); multiplied by</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B7BBD18D4224560986DBF8EBA852413"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of eligible students enrolled in the eligible institution for the preceding year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H470B027E73644E76AD073730A0F4A68C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent increases</header><text>For each succeeding year after the first year of the grant program under this section, each participating eligible institution shall receive a grant in the amount determined under paragraph (1) for such year, except that in no case shall the amount of the per-student rebate increase by more than 3 percent as compared to the amount of such rebate for the preceding year.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H465180F0F5D94A3FADDFE3E047B135B3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H85B9176774124398904ACDD6C0B0D5BA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Maximum per-student rebate</header><text>No eligible institution participating in the grant program under this section shall receive a per-student rebate amount for a grant year greater than the national average of public four-year institutional tuition and fees, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F0298D90BBE4C2B9DFC42C8491806A7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>First year tuition and fees</header><text>During the first year of participation in the grant program under this section, no eligible institution may increase tuition and fees at a rate greater than any annual increase made by the institution in the previous 5 years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99FDE7A7AB93425C809A63D79A019AE1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible institution shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such a manner, and containing such information as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC37C81B7D6CF405598383F6372306E69"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds awarded under this section to a participating eligible institution shall be used to waive or significantly reduce tuition and fees for eligible students in an amount of not more than up to the annual per-student rebate amount for each student, for not more than the first 60 credits an eligible student enrolls in the participating eligible institution.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA651B533E7894B5AA484ABC8FCAB31FB"><enum>203.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HE42E5DB707B749EFA14D377C6093CB9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible student</header> <subparagraph id="H918D95CF8902427ABEA19BE98652D6B0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>The term <term>eligible student</term> means a student, regardless of age, who—</text>
						<clause id="H5C8FBE02044E435EAFAD5111C5BDC0CE"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF40B1760B6F74AA697CF7B41A09D84F1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>enrolls in a historically black college or university, or minority-serving institution, for the first time; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H72B2C9B5877543A89124E3D8E92D1529" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transfers from a community college into a historically black college or university, or minority-serving institution, for the first time;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HB41E610C5E914EDD8DEF08224777BDB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>attends the historically black college or university, or minority serving institution, on at least a half-time basis;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H37693A9C26774214B97FD11645BB2500"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>maintains satisfactory academic progress; and</text> </clause><clause id="H42120A8B9865429396F09E18CDB57686"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is a low-income student.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7799E2CE3FEB4447B71C3807D71E65E5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <clause id="HC88B2E616A574E0C9440CC28C0E8C546"><enum>(i)</enum><header>First 3 years</header><text>An otherwise eligible student shall lose eligibility 3 calendar years after first receiving benefits under this title.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H593F585BBA83434085A7A824B8B2D61C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule for certain students</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A)(i), an otherwise eligible student whose parent or guardian was denied a Federal Direct PLUS loan under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) after November 2011 and before March 29, 2015, and who subsequently withdrew from a historically black college or university, or minority-serving institution, and has not yet completed a program of study at such historically black college or university or minority-serving institution, shall be eligible to participate under section 201 or 202 in order to complete such program of study, subject to all other requirements of section 201 or 202 (as the case may be).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C09A5A402D643CCAE2AEE3C3B6C1245"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historically black college or university</header><text>The term <term>historically black college or university</term> means a part B institution described in section 322(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061(2)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B5EDC2E109E449488B44B780128259E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Low-income student</header><text>The term <term>low-income student</term> has the meaning given such term by the Secretary, except that such term shall not exclude any student eligible for a Federal Pell Grant under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF859A7C06CC54D5498DD973BB9F9B7B7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text>The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means any public or not-for-profit institution of higher education—</text> <subparagraph id="H3682AC97AD7E43ABA2EC936277EEC70D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>described in paragraphs (2) through (7) of section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A29A191A52F4E57AC974783E93DD591"><enum>(B)</enum><text>designated as a minority-serving institution by the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HC082F8A495E14E5F992415BA27C1D6B7"><enum>204.</enum><header>Appropriations</header> <subsection id="H9183444175BD4FEAABB1AAD02FC3502B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization and appropriations for HBCU and MSI grants</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out sections 201 and 202, there are authorized to be appropriated, and there are appropriated—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4F6D88E18903406AAB6ADD11C8923E46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$55,000,000 for fiscal year 2016;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H530B5B4D390C4FE88B3A20D1BE2A30CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$180,000,000 for fiscal year 2017;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E5794F3EA344C9CBFD0FC872795B6BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$1,072,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD67214BB6094E1EAB48A071DAFFFBD6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$1,115,000,000 for fiscal year 2019;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5A20243DCB94128A87505F440306A0A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$1,160,000,000 for fiscal year 2020;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H369913B56D2344DB9ADF7A4598ABBA44"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$1,206,000,000 for fiscal year 2021;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EAE186E3AD54611ADD5101C8631733B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$1,225,000,000 for fiscal year 2022;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C54BB001385413C91C54EE9EBDCF8BB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>$1,306,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58EF4FF5C9844B268F70EE677E04E443"><enum>(9)</enum><text>$1,359,000,000 for fiscal year 2024; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HACA2FFD66FAD4195A9C6DF0B75B6E405"><enum>(10)</enum><text>$1,414,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6038D8401C442FD9AE3D2CA15B08A08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Funds appropriated under subsection (a) are to remain available to the Secretary until expended.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H866A3C97F71B45D4B47191BD894905D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Insufficient funds</header><text>If the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year is not sufficient to award each participating institution in the grant programs under sections 201 and 202 a grant under this part equal to 100 percent of the grant amount determined under section 201(c), the Secretary may ratably reduce the amount of each such grant or take other actions necessary to ensure an equitable distribution of such amount.</text>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


