<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFC56F76D0C274B8C85830159782ABDC3" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3720 IH: Water Advanced Technologies for Efficient Resource Use Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3720</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To encourage water efficiency.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H22C7492F8E084D11A44309DB27E0AF3D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H87E418B3B5BD41CDBEF5E1FAAA742958" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Advanced Technologies for Efficient Resource Use Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4654AC437B7345999B2FA14B7777131D"><enum>2.</enum><header>WaterSense</header> <subsection id="H13D74C4652F44BC587FB023EFC30C446"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Environmental Protection Agency a WaterSense program to identify and promote water efficient products, buildings and landscapes, and services in order—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDAA0BD2667A34E24A398151B86AB9CEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to reduce water use;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA150FE6C37D426A9679468B1E98CC7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to reduce the strain on water, wastewater, and stormwater infrastructure;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F785B85FB9F45539810DCA1EFD94E59"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to conserve energy used to pump, heat, transport, and treat water; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H02C7991301094FCEA2CA307205D2A05E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to preserve water resources for future generations,</text>
				</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">through voluntary labeling of, or other forms of communications about, products, buildings and
			 landscapes, and services that meet the highest water efficiency and
 performance standards.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HA0D844B253444C42814AF73803ED8573"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H64E52DA391144ADBB55FEA4CD85522FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote WaterSense labeled products, buildings and landscapes, and services in the market place as the preferred technologies and services for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAE813DCAA0A64E7A8D9732E67B4FEF26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing water use; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55745E243B2548AFA910F7EB9F627A8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring product and service performance;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD92C15A2DB9840B0B10E2B8D61BA8984"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work to enhance public awareness of the WaterSense label through public outreach, education, water recycling and reuse technology research and development, and other means;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC1831AF50934369A4E489DBAC88DF33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish and maintain performance standards so that products, buildings and landscapes, and services labeled with the WaterSense label perform as well or better than their less efficient counterparts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA12B5D51C53447FCB216C0A5E58FD2F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>publicize the importance of proper installation of WaterSense plumbing products by a WaterSense-certified or, if WaterSense certification guidelines do not exist, licensed plumber or mechanical contractor, and the installation, maintenance, and audit of WaterSense irrigation systems by a WaterSense-certified irrigation professional to ensure optimal performance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FFDC0BDA86C413F87C912DE169EEF4A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>preserve the integrity of the WaterSense label;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7A51259194A4ECEB583CF4306BC1907"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regularly review and, when appropriate, update WaterSense criteria for categories of products, buildings and landscapes, and services, at least once every four years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B901BFFD4E3477392671722D9404991"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, regularly collect and make available to the public summary data on the production and relative market shares of WaterSense labeled products, buildings and landscapes, and services, at least annually;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D1A816B2ECB4ACBB4CD4E4CE0328E23"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the maximum extent practicable, regularly estimate and make available to the public the water and energy savings attributable to the use of WaterSense labeled products, buildings and landscapes, and services, at least annually;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C8CFA11ED7A48E3A1BF1382147E9ACB"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit comments from interested parties and the public prior to establishing or revising a WaterSense category, specification, installation criterion, or other criterion (or prior to effective dates for any such category, specification, installation criterion, or other criterion);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60FD947150E94826897CC94E81A42CAF"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide reasonable notice to interested parties and the public of any changes (including effective dates), on the adoption of a new or revised category, specification, installation criterion, or other criterion, along with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAB483E7E6A6B4047AA92341BAD6B3CD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an explanation of changes; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H276EF629E7B541EB9EE00F9180DAF03A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as appropriate, responses to comments submitted by interested parties;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACE22B6B32414694A8410AE660B951CA"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide appropriate lead time (as determined by the Administrator) prior to the applicable effective date for a new or significant revision to a category, specification, installation criterion, or other criterion, taking into account the timing requirements of the manufacturing, marketing, training, and distribution process for the specific product, building and landscape, or service category addressed; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6F1E184376144EB8B125B7C1680A2A0"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and, where appropriate, implement other voluntary approaches, such as labeling waterless devices that perform the same function as a water consuming product or encouraging reuse, reclamation, and recycling technologies, in commercial, institutional, residential, municipal, and industrial sectors to improve water efficiency or lower water use while meeting the performance standards established under paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD032EEFB8D20436095CFB8D71C2B16DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $7,500,000 for fiscal year 2016, $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2017, $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2018, and $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2019 and each year thereafter, adjusted for inflation, to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HDF189259DD4748ACA44F516445F9DF84"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal procurement of water efficient products</header>
 <subsection id="H0380E299A8854B7F9B68E05582DD791E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HEB9B14652D6A40C4865473823A988E9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 7902(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3F21F3FC122433BB07E651F81E2D3B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Watersense product or service</header><text>The term <term>WaterSense product or service</term> means a product or service that is rated for water efficiency under the WaterSense program.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA188BE04CCCD43D98D2D2CDE5D608EFF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Watersense program</header><text>The term <term>WaterSense program</term> means the program established by section 2 of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H370E8B2040CC43EB8182D806CC824B16"><enum>(4)</enum><header>FEMP designated product</header><text>The term <term>FEMP designated product</term> means a product that is designated under the Federal Energy Management Program of the Department of Energy as being among the highest 25 percent of equivalent products for efficiency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87A5A93D527449B7B1CC9EA2CBDFFD96"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Product and service</header><text>The terms <term>product</term> and <term>service</term> do not include any water consuming product or service designed or procured for combat or combat-related missions. The terms also exclude products or services already covered by the Federal procurement regulations established under section 553 of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8259b">42 U.S.C. 8259b</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6779122866374E3896D817E809AC3BB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procurement of water efficient products</header>
 <paragraph id="HE6B9DDFFF1A94D90885839C2313F7A4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>To meet the requirements of an agency for a water consuming product or service, the head of the agency shall, except as provided in paragraph (2), procure—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H153A68800BA4488F9CD40B910910CE73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a WaterSense product or service; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70556E43275A4DAEBFDADA65B0B3A367"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a FEMP designated product.</text>
					</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">A WaterSense plumbing product should preferably, when possible, be installed by a
			 WaterSense-certified or, if WaterSense certification guidelines do not
			 exist, licensed plumber or mechanical contractor, and a WaterSense
			 irrigation system should preferably, when possible, be installed,
			 maintained, and audited by a WaterSense-certified irrigation professional
 to ensure optimal performance.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78B715DBF2AE4E329E801EFE12CAF349"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The head of an agency is not required to procure a WaterSense product or service or FEMP designated product under paragraph (1) if the head of the agency finds in writing that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H69648DC182BE41D9A470F6A2C804C0CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a WaterSense product or service or FEMP designated product is not cost-effective over the life of the product, taking current and future energy, water, and wastewater cost savings into account; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9F4E6C5422746AFB5546897E2C35C38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no WaterSense product or service or FEMP designated product is reasonably available that meets the functional requirements of the agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0DE1BEC7490467F8484B652F100D628"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procurement planning</header><text>The head of an agency shall incorporate into the specifications for all procurements involving water consuming products and systems, including guide specifications, project specifications, and construction, renovation, and services contracts that include provision of water consuming products and systems, and into the factors for the evaluation of offers received for the procurement, criteria used for rating WaterSense products and services and FEMP designated products. The head of an agency shall consider, to the maximum extent practicable, additional measures for reducing agency water consumption, including water reuse, reclamation, and recycling technologies, leak detection and repair, and use of waterless products that perform similar functions to existing water-consuming products.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09B687D5CB644E099461CF1B99223033"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Listing of water efficient products in federal catalogs</header><text>WaterSense products and services and FEMP designated products shall be clearly identified and prominently displayed in any inventory or listing of products by the General Services Administration or the Defense Logistics Agency. The General Services Administration and the Defense Logistics Agency shall supply only WaterSense products or FEMP designated products for all product categories covered by the WaterSense program or the Federal Energy Management Program, except in cases where the agency ordering a product specifies in writing that no WaterSense product or FEMP designated product is available to meet the buyer’s functional requirements, or that no WaterSense product or FEMP designated product is cost-effective for the intended application over the life of the product, taking energy, water, and wastewater cost savings into account.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5A571E9F60CF4127B4CC9C36F9A60BDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall issue regulations to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H11C342DF3C9C46509EDA0BB91FF9F342"><enum>4.</enum><header>Early Adopter Water Efficient Products Incentive Programs</header>
 <subsection id="HF43AA3E60E8D4FECAA0A6C60FD6373F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6A5FFD6AFC0045D0BC3E80C6C35602D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H096CC7905E764B008CAC4BB46FCCA56E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State government, local or county government, tribal government, wastewater or sewage utility, municipal water authority, energy utility, water utility, or nonprofit organization that meets the requirements of subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6989CC0444064FBCA77A96D5258F30B3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incentive program</header><text>The term <term>incentive program</term> means a program for administering financial incentives for consumer purchase and installation of residential water efficient products and services as described in subsection (b)(1).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9D4FCA631E3D433FB0949206AE7D61DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Residential water efficient product or service</header>
 <subparagraph id="H78728118286E47F0B1F165FF2919D3FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>residential water efficient product or service</term> means a product or service for a single-family or multifamily residence or its landscape that is rated for water efficiency and performance—</text>
 <clause id="H00CFC29D9A3C458981C832E27BBE5997"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by the WaterSense program; or</text> </clause><clause id="H22D43BE2CC2644EA9E50BA2142D9052D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by an incentive program and approved by the Administrator.</text>
						</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Categories of water efficient products and services may include faucets, irrigation technologies
			 and services, point-of-use water treatment devices, reuse, reclamation,
 and recycling technologies, toilets, and showerheads.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D04DC2F3695454A8A75514639A0393B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Third-party certification</header><text>A product shall not be treated as a residential water efficient product until after the product—</text> <clause id="H0CCDFB8632DC413E96227C368F24472F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is tested by an accredited third-party certifying body or laboratory in accordance with the WaterSense program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F0BBB6A64E4443F9CD0C7C4461414D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is certified by such body or laboratory as meeting the performance and efficiency requirements of such program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H12C410F89026451595B135EA6BF5AB53"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is authorized by such program to use its label.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4605100CC4D4F41A70DFAAFEA7F51AF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H622CF697BB55499CB583A34BC7FAB620"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Watersense program</header><text>The term <term>WaterSense program</term> means the program established by section 2 of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3B3195C42B74FF98C7B2D736D43DC7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>An entity shall be eligible to receive an allocation under subsection (c) if the entity—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDFB36ED57C964D38BC9B8A4B79835FC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishes (or has established) an incentive program to provide rebates, vouchers, other financial incentives, or direct installs to consumers for the purchase and installation of residential water efficient products or services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F883A9D25B347538B0535F093E6FB5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits an application for the allocation at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Administrator may require; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8139622350F4268B2BA4110BE0A5A69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides assurances satisfactory to the Administrator that the entity will use the allocation to supplement, but not supplant, funds made available to carry out the incentive program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H191BF8EBA1FA479A957F548FFD738FC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of allocations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year, the Administrator shall determine the amount to allocate to each eligible entity to carry out subsection (d) taking into consideration—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9630C9456F9C42BA833C3577216445FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the population served by the eligible entity in the most recent calendar year for which data are available;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA38A5514DD4043A0B619A74791A4C171"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the targeted population of the eligible entity's incentive program, such as general households, low-income households, or first-time homeowners, and the probable effectiveness of the incentive program for that population;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A9F1A787EF94848A6AA5C90864F2A65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for existing programs, the effectiveness of the incentive program in encouraging the adoption of water efficient products and services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2177CB15CAB24A16B0CD2A21B3E2F518"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any prior year's allocation to the eligible entity that remains unused.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE25DD2DAB14440384C5C1380401BC84"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of allocated funds</header><text>Funds allocated to an entity under subsection (c) may be used to pay up to 50 percent of the cost of establishing and carrying out an incentive program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA3FC234A91844EE7A40492877B2D5D8C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fixture recycling</header><text>Entities are encouraged to promote or implement fixture recycling programs to manage the disposal of older fixtures replaced due to the incentive program under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7324924B7D854583B46E9AD10FB54F3C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Issuance of rebates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Financial incentives may be provided to consumers that meet the requirements of the incentive program. The entity may issue all financial incentives directly to consumers or, with approval of the Administrator, delegate some or all financial incentive administration to other organizations including, but not limited to, local governments, municipal water authorities, and water utilities. The amount of a financial incentive shall be determined by the entity, taking into consideration—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5E15D20E220D4DAFA7FA26077DFD2E60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount of the allocation to the entity under subsection (c);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFE320C5E61B4BCB8484B3664CBD49F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of any Federal, State, or other organization's tax or financial incentive available for the purchase of the residential water efficient product or service;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D5CB8FC5075443B828026EF6C594B80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the amount necessary to change consumer behavior to purchase water efficient products and services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E1949A0190346BBA68C98D87FF1C498"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the consumer expenditures for onsite preparation, assembly, and original installation of the product.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9DF9374D36048CBBA9C59AC523A7873"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2016, $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2017, $150,000,000 for fiscal year 2018, $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2019, and $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2020.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H89E59F46DBAB4B6E80DB981C569753BF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Early adopter water efficient products incentive programs</header>
 <subsection id="H731164C172B34700B144CE8CB96AD2F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part III of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting before section 140 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A3E1293E0BA445984F2AE695E8AD41C" style="OLC">
					<section id="H3B7ABDC63EB94D768130D20A4DE17CD3"><enum>139F.</enum><header>Early adopter water efficient products incentive programs</header>
 <subsection id="H02D5A6DEFB82495D90ECE9E94B66820D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an individual, gross income does not include any amount received under an incentive program under section 4 of the Water Advanced Technologies for Efficient Resource Use Act of 2015.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0A01244E278A46FFAB4194DA3878B36E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, no deduction or credit shall be allowed for, or by reason of, any expenditure to the extent of the amount excluded under subsection (a) for any amount which was provided with respect to such expenditure. The adjusted basis of any property shall be reduced by the amount excluded under subsection (a) which was provided with respect to such property.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBA5C27154654460E9F06D644F375AB26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part III of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting before the item relating to section 140 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBBAD3CD0C9EC465E9C33D7A7356F28BE" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 139F. Early adopter water efficient products incentive programs.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H881B4882330440C0BFA30970D9C1D91F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


