<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H25B6B28BC6454C3BADB0FED6559EAD70" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3715 IH: Final Farewell Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3715</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to permit
			 interments, funerals, memorial services, and ceremonies of deceased
			 veterans at national cemeteries and State cemeteries receiving grants from
			 the Department of Veterans Affairs during certain weekends if requested
			 for religious reasons.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HDF51A78BAB3744F48371AD84190AA636" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE4883A3B05F04CC5BD824F77BF1E5CF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Final Farewell Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6C34E20B7B3B42ECBFC5FBA989170D4C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of interments, funerals, memorial services, and ceremonies at national cemeteries and State cemeteries receiving grants during weekends when requested for religious or cultural reasons</header> <subsection id="H253014E691C0475DAB74612B37DD0E2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National cemeteries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2404 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9CCAEFE7F5B4263A8E4E8C03C710BC5" style="USC">
 <subsection id="H41A20E058B0F4CF492BA1BE7F75290F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall permit the interment or funeral, memorial service, or ceremony of a deceased veteran at a national cemetery during weekends, other than Federal holiday weekends, upon a request of the next-of-kin of the veteran made for religious or cultural reasons, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1244A43ECF8B4C6CA8E6DA762FBA3DF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State cemeteries</header><text>Section 2408(c) of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8090F78C6A2342C3B384E5886FED5FA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA201B3B036D64C44B399E4062D4D828E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph (2):</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AE32CA9AB714466AF381964F95DCCEB" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H3A2FA1CB427948C59E3808D9C33ECDCA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the conditions specified in subsection (b) and paragraph (1), any grant to a State under this section to assist such State in establishing a veterans’ cemetery shall be made on the condition that such cemetery shall permit the interment or funeral, memorial service, or ceremony of a deceased veteran at the cemetery during weekends, other than Federal holiday weekends, upon a request of the next-of-kin of the veteran made for religious or cultural reasons, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B5AC83B8D324111ADC5E68958CF010C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to deaths occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H47FE425783C54A4997DE864296F1E6E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of a request for an application for burial or interment in a national cemetery, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide notice to the individual submitting the request of the opportunity to request the interment or funeral, memorial service, or ceremony of a deceased veteran at a national cemetery during weekends, other than Federal holiday weekends, for religious or cultural reasons, as authorized by subsection (i) of section 2404 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


