<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1A2D99B5E955495E815AAD75031E626A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3680 IH: Co-Prescribing to Reduce Overdoses Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3680</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151001">October 1, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a grant program for
			 co-prescribing opioid overdose reversal drugs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H36D9ACF9E9DC4C0BAC8499B5ED7012B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H36B6EAADBF1841E4B99914F16355D107" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Co-Prescribing to Reduce Overdoses Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCE1E50CFCCC0449BB143A145AF9A4E93"><enum>2.</enum><header>Co-prescribing opioid overdose reversal drugs grant program</header> <subsection id="H7216C375371049F3875955B0E5E16B7B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="HEEBCEF656FB848BEA79ED47EE31B9A64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish, in accordance with this section, a four-year co-prescribing opioid overdose reversal drugs grant program (in this Act referred to as the <quote>grant program</quote>) under which the Secretary shall provide not more than a total of 12 grants to eligible entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADF08B6D215749C98384C548CAC97139"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum grant amount</header><text>A grant made under this section may not be for more than $200,000 per grant year.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AE8CCA6C2AB4EA3864191EB2D1B9554"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means a federally qualified health center (as defined in section 1861(aa) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)</external-xref>), an opioid treatment program under part 8 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, or section 303(g) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(g)</external-xref>), or any other entity that the Secretary deems appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC43960DBF5E9425C9019D1057777433C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Co-prescribing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section and section 3, the term <term>co-prescribing</term> means, with respect to an opioid overdose reversal drug, the practice of prescribing such drug in conjunction with an opioid prescription for patients at an elevated risk of overdose, or in conjunction with an opioid agonist approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) for the treatment of opioid abuse disorders, or in other circumstances in which a provider identifies a patient at an elevated risk for an intentional or unintentional drug overdose from heroin or prescription opioid therapies. For purposes of the previous sentence, a patient may be at an elevated risk of overdose if the patient meets the criteria under the existing co-prescribing guidelines that the Secretary deems appropriate, such as the criteria provided in the Opioid Overdose Toolkit published by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD79CC09490349A0947067972D574ED4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in such form and manner as specified by the Secretary, an application that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE45B3606003D428F86E0A95A43701EBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which the area to which the entity will furnish services through use of the grant is experiencing significant morbidity and mortality caused by opioid abuse;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFFB1502794242698DA872FB08DEA425"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the criteria that will be used to identify eligible patients to participate in such program; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5233A44DA8947EEAE628ECEA02EEACD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how such program will work to try to identify State, local, or private funding to continue the program after expiration of the grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B51ED9160E348548CB358179C881D3B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may use the grant for any of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1D4D7A9A139840FE9D62B557678CD7D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To establish a program for co-prescribing opioid overdose reversal drugs, such as naloxone.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H21CB8186BF9A4E5F8327412994CBA020"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To train and provide resources for health care providers and pharmacists on the co-prescribing of opioid overdose reversal drugs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7B90EDD3D34AF485C823E8B36DDF53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To establish mechanisms and processes for tracking patients participating in the program described in paragraph (1) and the health outcomes of such patients.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H095ADD964D2B4257AF0A5D49FD581943"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To purchase opioid overdose reversal drugs for distribution under the program described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD24609165C744A4BAF976D18F6977BA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To offset the co-pays and other cost sharing associated with opioid overdose reversal drugs to ensure that cost is not a limiting factor for eligible patients.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF7F0C2A31AD4D33B2133E472E74C86D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To conduct community outreach, in conjunction with community-based organizations, designed to raise awareness of co-prescribing practices, and the availability of opioid overdose reversal drugs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB020B499AED46F5AB7883CCFD39B4D7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To establish protocols to connect patients who have experienced a drug overdose with appropriate treatment, including medication assisted treatment and appropriate counseling and behavioral therapies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B62022EA49E4E8E8EA13BE9C23BAC23"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluations by recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receipt of a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall, for each year for which the grant is received, submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services information on appropriate outcome measures specified by the Secretary to assess the outcomes of the program funded by the grant, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE2D76F637C7B40EFA44C38B6F9D3D76B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of prescribers trained;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6145E74BAEB4C2EA0E64026E72AD023"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of prescribers who have co-prescribed an opioid overdose reversal drugs to at least one patient;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B408736AEB74692A7F0CFB6E9EE5C6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total number of prescriptions written for opioid overdose reversal drugs;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE57F248CC54A28BCBCEECF25878A85"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the percentage of patients at elevated risk who received a prescription for an opioid overdose reversal drug;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H742A9B64C8A949FBB34BAA28F3B9BB16"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of patients reporting use of an opioid overdose reversal drug; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB4F3C5E88E4296A3A3FCB65ECA7C29"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other outcome measures that the Secretary deems appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4E3B5B1FB974E489887C0C16DE3B24C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports by Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each year of the grant program under this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the appropriate Committees of the House of Representatives and of the Senate a report aggregating the information received from the grant recipients for such year under subsection (d) and evaluating the outcomes achieved by the programs funded by grants made under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA3248B3A8D84469A9837B0056551433C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Opioid overdose reversal co-prescribing guidelines</header>
 <subsection id="H233A56AC600B4A9D82DE9F3D5D2B424C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a grant program under which the Secretary shall award grants to eligible State entities to develop opioid overdose reversal co-prescribing guidelines.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC8485D63CA86479183C6BFA4C3B3B2DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible State entities</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), eligible State entities are State departments of health in conjunction with State medical boards; city, county, and local health departments; and community stakeholder groups involved in reducing opioid overdose deaths.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H1353B2D3887349DC861A5D1D2B8FF374"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="H73F61981D260403D9F5A353FD6A55711"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant made under this section may not be for more than $200,000 per grant.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4830A44EA8F47EC9F16BE832A0C9FE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible State entities which propose to base their guidelines on existing guidelines on co-prescribing to speed enactment, including guidelines of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H304B3B06D76C4851ADFBCB9CFEAD56D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EFB6ECD262D4A0AA2882959FB4D8423"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nationwide medical societies, such as the American Society of Addiction Medicine or American Medical Association; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B1E796313504B0D8487D05B28714F8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA045FB7CC265497591F6A934A215A429"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


