<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H00C41FDD070044B2A7FB760BEE053A5B" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3322 IH: To establish a Residence Star program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3322</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a Residence Star program, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6F4FC264A7FA450C93FCBAC64062441F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5A3A0A37A7FF4F53A055428F12CAC1D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Residence Star program</header> 
<subsection id="H8D03D06877474CF795C62B2838BB4637"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title IV of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8E831F01B71244D18358B7533916B7CC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H284B20AB9C41451080BE738CB33A14DA"><enum>414.</enum><header>Residence Star program</header> <subsection id="H47B09FB80E044AF0AEC06483C0AD8A79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFA81DDA7CA67451E844384A25098288D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>High-performance energy efficiency measure</header><text>The term <term>high-performance energy efficiency measure</term> has the meaning given that term in section 424.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4ED7349502F4B9D89AD965F1E866588"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Residence Star program</header><text>The term <term>Residence Star program</term> means the voluntary program established under subsection (b). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8150426CD11042DE915508FC04C39878" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Separate residential spaces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>separate residential spaces</term> means areas within a residential building that are leased or otherwise occupied by a tenant or other occupant for a period of time pursuant to the terms of a written agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HED3308811617482C87298694D10A6F4D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Residence Star</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish a voluntary program within the Energy Star program established by section 324A of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6294a">42 U.S.C. 6294a</external-xref>), which may be known as Residence Star, to promote energy efficiency in separate residential spaces.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC992D33F092E4AC4B5645374EB821C2F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recognition of separate residential spaces</header> 
<paragraph id="H46A14D648F37420FB85E08E6CC111A7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Occupancy-based recognition</header><text>In establishing the Residence Star program, the Administrator shall, following public notice and an opportunity for comment—</text> <subparagraph id="H50417A306DE647149572787A257CA8CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a manner similar to the Energy Star rating system for commercial buildings, develop policies and procedures to recognize separate residential spaces with respect to which the owner of the separate residential space voluntarily achieves high levels of energy efficiency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H863743AD03F74A769D154DFF548C631A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish building occupancy categories eligible for Residence Star recognition; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE50F508C6BDB41BAA78901AAE6098097"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider other forms of recognition for separate residential spaces with respect to which the owner of the separate residential space lowers energy consumption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F3683D14E8E4ED1BF22666621700640"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Design- and construction-based recognition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the Residence Star program, the Administrator, following public notice and an opportunity for comment, shall develop policies and procedures to recognize separate residential spaces with respect to which the owner of the separate residential space uses high-performance energy efficiency measures in design and construction.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C6F456F7DAB4F6C8BBD3F46FB62CE07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Audits required</header> <subparagraph id="H3B25DE66CA2D4FE1AAB93EFBBFBA4B5C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the Residence Star program, the Administrator shall require that in order for a separate residential space to be eligible to receive recognition under this subsection, the owner of the separate residential space shall submit the separate residential space to an audit by a third party to certify that the requirements of the program are met with respect to the separate residential space.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H350F7950ACBB483388362EE1D8C361C7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maintenance audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the Residence Star program, the Administrator shall require that in order for a separate residential space to be eligible to maintain recognition under this subsection, the owner of the separate residential space shall, not later than 7 years after the date on which the initial audit is conducted under subparagraph (A), and every 7 years thereafter, submit the separate residential space to an audit by a third party to certify that the requirements of the program continue to be met with respect to the separate residential space.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB11F3B051FE47839114E725AE647B05"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Administrator shall require that an audit conducted under this paragraph shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H4C4D12939EA04F73936027B82F99DEC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of the energy efficiency of the separate residential space; </text></clause> <clause id="HA3063883CE5B4A1BB5CC4A0CBFB2D0DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an estimate of the monetary and energy savings the tenant or other occupant of the separate residential space can expect annually as a result of such energy efficiency, as determined based on standards of measurement established by the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H76EF50A03BA943B6A68C1DEA81A56049"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other requirements determined appropriate by the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, following public notice and an opportunity for comment.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D5096D62CA34D458A088F0742A9B678"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Use of estimates</header> <clause id="H1EC3049D7ABD4D3EA03361F48A39B5A3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Use by owners</header><text>The owner of a separate residential space that is recognized under the Residence Star program may, with respect to such separate residential space, display, publish, or otherwise use for purposes of advertising the estimate of the monetary and energy savings included in the most recent audit of the separate residential space conducted under this paragraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAB22B17E80C34086A622D6E5FA36BB4F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Use by third parties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Third parties, including realtors and property managers, may display, publish, or otherwise use for purposes of advertising the estimate of the monetary and energy savings included in the most recent audit of a separate residential space conducted under this paragraph on behalf of an owner permitted to do so under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H812AFA77D4B64EF8999CA6894F778B6C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Criteria for third party auditors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the Residence Star program, the Administrator, following public notice and an opportunity for comment, shall develop criteria for third parties to be eligible to conduct audits under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H39AFE9A0A1624995B9998AC67C68D171"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Branding</header> 
<paragraph id="HDC658CCE16B4404C9B52ECBC078253DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Creation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall create a logo and branding for the Residence Star program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55B52150334E4C17B13573DFF9BE0A3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permitted use</header> <subparagraph id="H05B1ACF2E6734BA0ACDDA9E2C49312B6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use by owners</header><text>The owner of a separate residential space that is recognized under the Residence Star program may, with respect to such separate residential space, display, publish, or otherwise use for purposes of advertising the logo and branding created under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAA5DD7A9C5BE4884824BEBFDC001E295" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use by third parties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Third parties, including realtors and property managers, may display, publish, or otherwise use for purposes of advertising the logo and branding created under paragraph (1) on behalf of an owner permitted to do so under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D7751FA22814A3FA0DFBFCBE26B0C74"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An owner of a separate residential space that is not recognized under the Residence Star program may not, with respect to such separate residential space, display, publish, or otherwise use for purposes of advertising the logo and branding created under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7FFD70E0844451F8E28EF998DD084D1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication of list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall publish and maintain, on an Internet website, a list of separate residential spaces that are recognized under the Residence Star program. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H0FCE1321AA4547E091A40B7C47C2D7DA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preservation of integrity</header><text>The Administrator and the Secretary shall preserve the integrity of the Residence Star brand.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E4B5AEDDF3D449F8826144AC26516FA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Residence Star program is established, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the program.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H67FA837943B34E6297CA115181FE078F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical Amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 413 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB17A0A5AD3BA4E5FB53145E5670859E1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 414. Residence Star program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


