<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB5DD2FACB3A94EE4BB52766F64D9E68E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3642 IH: To provide for increased flexibility in the extension of the Social Security program to Guam.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3642</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150929">September 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for increased flexibility in the extension of the Social Security program to Guam.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9D9A16CF3DB44F90BB94AB3E27A83883" style="OLC">
 <section id="H035894C1CCC24AD8A57E29E174FAE5B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Increased flexibility in the extension of the Social Security program to Guam</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103(v)(1) of the Social Security Amendments of 1960 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/86/778">Public Law 86–778</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB7743254287C480D8777A93401DCD2C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The amendments made by subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) The amendments made by subsection (a)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37FFC53FD8F0414F8EAF410D49C044D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BEF0566ECB043F98EBAFF2CF52468F9" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC3046C2E2AEF47D6A75FC5127CF23DE1" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the legislation enacted by the Government of Guam described in the fifth sentence of subparagraph (A) includes a provision expressing the desire of the Government of Guam that the insurance system established by title II of the Social Security Act would extend only to such officers and employees of such Government and such political subdivisions and instrumentalities initially employed (as determined by the Government of Guam at the time of, and included as a provision in, the certification described in such sentence) by such Government and such political subdivisions and instrumentalities after the calendar quarter in which the Secretary of the Treasury receives such certification, the amendments made by subsections (c), (n), (q), and (r) shall apply to only such individuals.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


