<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1E6E7773302243C7A197ACA3127B97D5" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3376 IH: To authorize States to carry out bridge construction, maintenance, repair, and replacement projects using previously allocated surface transportation funds that are identified as being excess or inactive, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3376</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize States to carry out bridge construction, maintenance, repair, and replacement projects
			 using previously allocated surface transportation funds that are
			 identified as being excess or inactive, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8B031CD2D14043A6BA0B1D9F80F5663F" style="OLC">
		<section id="H16B6DCE9624549C4B5A8ABB81C0B49CD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header>
 <subsection id="H3070B7E7CA8F41E888FDAC4B3A091980"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H72AF28646355414D867D47872DA19509"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Highway Administration estimates that there are 604,485 bridges on the Nation’s public road network, of which 116,669 are on the National Highway System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EAD80493DE84E53A4C8279019FF3994"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The average age of the Nation’s bridges is 39 years old and more than two-thirds of the Nation’s bridges are more than 26 years old.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1A060BA2ECC4BC4965CB22B9E7D9FD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>One in 9 bridges is classified as structurally deficient and requires significant maintenance, repair, or replacement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2DB68976DF84A308BF05B7D41218E1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Fourteen percent of the Nation’s bridges are functionally obsolete and do not meet current design standards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96B10302E9AC4FCE813A090EA5A03426"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Highway Administration estimates that to eliminate the Nation’s deficient bridge backlog by 2030, $20.2 billion of investment would be required annually through Federal, State, and local levels of government, although current annual bridge investment is approximately $17.1 billion.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CFE82DD49814026AB794C9CE41BBB62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H76A54F19D34844B5BC0E8DEE8FB4D07F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible funds</header> <subparagraph id="HA2F8082D4DFD40ADAE1676D600F793A2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>eligible funds</quote> means funds—</text>
 <clause id="H88FB20496138422086228F5EF8B6694D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>authorized or designated in—</text> <subclause id="H1EE17CE60A004A7CB8FAB65F7FD98225"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Public Law 109–59 or a prior surface transportation authorization Act; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H65DE04CE57FF496797EA82659F20455A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an appropriations Act, or a report accompanying an appropriations Act, for allocation to a specific surface transportation project or activity; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H9E1586FB10D346CAA227A20498710F5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identified, not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, by the State in which the project or activity is authorized to be carried out as being excess funds or inactive funds.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6837F23FD3D647F7AFA7AF0B0F01694E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <quote>eligible funds</quote> includes funds described in subparagraph (A) that were allocated and designated for a demonstration project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6782076109534968B1C8BDD17EAA65FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excess funds</header><text>The term <quote>excess funds</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFFE23F9996114AB4A5E1570FD36E9825"><enum>(A)</enum><text>funds obligated for a specific surface transportation project or activity that remain available for the project or activity after the project or activity has been completed or canceled; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H128C0FF6616247098A4AB0A7284C4025"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an unobligated balance of funds allocated for a specific surface transportation project or activity that the State in which the project or activity is authorized to be carried out certifies is no longer needed for the project or activity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04195E33836F4AF8A3F692E16D5C0E80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inactive funds</header><text>The term <quote>inactive funds</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H55AAE1C2910E420C96A6886F0CC251C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an unobligated balance of Federal funds for an eligible surface transportation project or activity against which no more than 10 percent of the Federal funds originally designated for the project or activity have been obligated; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF953FB09EF124D938BAE39DD0F0FC025"><enum>(B)</enum><text>funds that are available to carry out a surface transportation project or activity in a State, but, as certified by the State, are unlikely to be advanced for the project or activity during the 1-year period beginning on the date of certification.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F6E46FF2C064F4D8662436DAEF862E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of funds for bridge projects</header><text>Eligible funds shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H30107CCDE3AA4164ACA157ED7D5CA6BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>made available in accordance with this section to the State that originally received the funds; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48F22802A9544E88A9A60A1E90E7650E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>available for obligation for any eligible project under section 133(b)(2) or 133(b)(3) of title 23, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E08A52E444C47ECB9938547F297CA5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority To obligate</header><text>Notwithstanding the original source or period of availability of eligible funds, the Secretary of Transportation may, on the request by a State—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF101FD9F0EE3434499F5DBF2B1600825"><enum>(1)</enum><text>obligate the funds for any eligible project under section 133(b)(2) or 133(b)(3) of title 23, United States Code; or</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H8733EED94A6448D69ECF5293A54FCF45"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H97B053B29DBE4B23859FD5EFC48C7743"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deobligate the funds; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD7AB7EDC8F84BF3B4E9B0B98A16E4CD" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reobligate the funds for any project eligible under such sections.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC705459B8E804205993FA66AE307551F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Period of availability; title 23 requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H62EB04834CB9444DB1518B135AC273ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the original source or period of availability of eligible funds obligated (or deobligated and reobligated) under subsection (d), the eligible funds—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H83F172839FDD445A8E25269F12AAB653"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall remain available for obligation for a period of 3 fiscal years after the fiscal year in which this Act is enacted; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF4A6E71C9B94D758C5ECC689F27D633"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided in this subsection, shall be subject to the requirements of title 23, United States Code, that apply to section 133 of that title, including provisions relating to Federal share.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB211DACD51B41BEA6FA2A61799E1E40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No allocation based on population</header><text>Section 133(d) of title 23, United States Code, shall not apply to eligible funds under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD83B7448DAA64020A87EB0F34E4164E3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report describing any action taken by the Secretary under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


