<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23522EAE1B0F49F6932A3402E4EB1988" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3792 IH: Young Adults Driving Safety Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3792</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151021">October 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To assist young adults with obtaining or regaining driver’s licenses, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5DD86F3B6FD1437892EFBBFB0056965F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBC47A055FA484D8CBAE886E7550B85B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Young Adults Driving Safety Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCFECBC20613A40D5B768BBFA0815F511"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to assist young adults with obtaining driver’s licenses</header> <subsection id="HE98B8F6CC8D142678676E741D2BCA2CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header> <paragraph id="H0455CBF1CFF3446DAEE7F148BD24FA17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, may award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to develop model programs to assist young adults with obtaining or regaining driver’s licenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H371D570F0D8E469384230C8063BAD864"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum grant award</header><text>A grant awarded under this section may not exceed $100,000.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B251B4BB0574F35B5298C83DD943B02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may use the grant funds to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H96F086EBD4A84079AA81777999573D1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a comprehensive assessment of the driver’s licensing status of young adults in the neighborhoods in which the majority of the youth to be served by the program reside or attend school;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34D6B7309BD84615BC64273607ED94F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and implement strategies to address licensing deficits and barriers young adults and disconnected youth face in obtaining a driver’s license;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H419075794C5448218F352CA6C18B9218"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">study the impact of State and local driver’s license suspensions and revocation policies, including the implementation of such policies by municipal courts, on young adults in the areas where the youth who will be served by the program reside or attend school;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2C010B07C5C459383CC241252A56A4B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify potential sources of funding for high school driver’s education programs for each high school in a school district;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0ECB3DB7A8ED48F6BDED553B6DFDA8EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop innovative and cost-effective strategies for preparing young adults for legal driving;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H069D6D03E04440BC912472FDBC75A9FF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of the funded grant activities in achieving the program goals; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EDE3964F4E045C7B366C06ED4C9A992"><enum>(7)</enum><text>conduct any other activities considered appropriate by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8605B67C71F64008853D2C1204BCE964"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Such application shall describe the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H92BA62EB71174B76A423E1927D763F31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>How the eligible entity proposes to use the grant funds to create a program to assist young adults with obtaining or regaining driver’s licenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H19700D2B4D1D4D81A1E4F417BE420F63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>How the eligible entity intends to collaborate with education institutions and organizations with job training programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1F890C5786945EBAD605C56B933E76F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>How the proposed program is expected to create opportunities for the employment and job training of young adults who participate in the proposed program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H600CEF6A045E41A1B32F8ED332866795"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the eligible entity intends to target youth in areas experiencing high levels of unemployment among young adults.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F996E32F5124932B8256EDBD17AB9B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>How the proposed program is expected to assist low-income young adults and disconnected youth with school and employment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H73DDF27B1ADC4B809F2087D33D02484B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The eligible entity’s history of working with young adults.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF1C0DCF678624891A799222A5D9C3072"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The eligible entity’s history of assisting individuals in regaining a driver’s license, especially in cases in which the driver’s license was suspended or revoked for non-safety related reasons.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11ABDDDE0C8E43A2979D96A32E9DAC6D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities proposing programs to assist low-income young adults with obtaining or regaining driver’s licenses.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D6F0119BC7346849E3D7728E2966696"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF531E536955547F19C6E45C4BA23BF00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disconnected youth</header><text>The term <term>disconnected youth</term> means low-income young adults who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HADB5445E15A24023B72C667C6C55BA93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are homeless;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA366AC0091AD4A3A8C8197CE8C69E85F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are in foster care;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8A27EF0D4C8416484343423955322B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have come into contact, or are at risk of coming into contact, with the juvenile justice or criminal justice system;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H519E0F7ABD1F464FB3A3EF86AE5EE28E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are not employed and not enrolled in school; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB45CE58DED28470A82AB111AF699033C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>are at risk of dropping out of an education institution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD542C40B5D17431EB039975F25AAF027"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a non-profit organization, tribal government, education institution, or any other organization considered appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H683D4F4D15FB43C9AA2A003F7467EEFE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Education institution</header><text>The term <term>education institution</term> means an institution of higher education or a high-need local education agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FE0182CAC4D4E339E88863672F8897D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-need local education agency</header><text>The term <term>high-need local education agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2102(3)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6602">20 U.S.C. 6602</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB35BFD06F8E14115AC5F6522EF89CC18"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9C488B439784B4B8D39E230A3B8619E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Low-income</header><text>The term <term>low-income</term>, with respect to a young adult, means a household income at or below 185 percent of the poverty line.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF77C4AECFB64FED82CBBAF15F034C3C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means any organization that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF8A73BA2D449A8B36257AC1B95ADCF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Poverty line</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>poverty line</term> means the poverty line (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget and revised annually in accordance with section 673 of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/97/35">Public Law 97–35</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902</external-xref>)) applicable to a family of the size involved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72A15E3364AB4DBEB4B925B4F37E6417"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE99E31B3419340A3812A6DD88FD09A43"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Young adult</header><text>The term <term>young adult</term> means an individual who is at least 16 years old and less than 25 years old.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H646DBB5E7710416FAFFED39A20B6E167"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 each year for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2019.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H7EF206BFCA9A43788277464D75762956"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority to use State Highway safety funds for teen driving education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402(m)(2)(A) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8E5A93C2FCD446C9AEB5B511725104BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BE79A8A6D474CB4AE13FDD0F04F471B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB713FD7A59E5494D84F27DE397DF2342" style="USC"> <clause id="H175DEC042D2047C497984FF6CD4F8E7B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support teen driving education and driving skills improvement; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


