<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD7CF24A3CA54DBC8B49381A68929F27" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 858 IH: To establish a comprehensive literacy program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 858</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a comprehensive literacy program, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H02C0DD11CF404B75952FE15694E4ED58" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEC6850A858B741B781864B5A4AA588E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HD3DA78844EFD4B40BC1435E22FCA22C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as—</text> <paragraph id="HBDCD1A997A7D42DCAB2C94093585B917"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <quote>Literacy Education for All, Results for the Nation Act</quote>; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05E1DF0752694138A9DB581E5C5B09C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <quote>LEARN Act</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB6297AE170E74091A78487682788079B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HEC6850A858B741B781864B5A4AA588E5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H82AF8740258B45BCABE6F44C8680DE8F" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7E6BE5A6171F4B6B86AE0F3FCB2198DD" level="section">Sec. 3. Purposes.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HADC9B2BC0E5B438DBFD1DF37ED3A28AD" level="section">Sec. 4. Programs authorized.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H714AB7A15A164BF3A4A56998594D6830" level="section">Sec. 5. State planning grants.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5FEF4DDDE51B416B8C7EBCE0CAF8F886" level="section">Sec. 6. State implementation grants.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF12BB49DC3BA4881B8348115581597CF" level="section">Sec. 7. Subgrants to eligible entities in support of literacy for children from birth through kindergarten entry.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H40BC3F74942D4EFB9E09F226307FDAE4" level="section">Sec. 8. Subgrants to eligible entities in support of literacy for students in kindergarten through grade 12.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8BC6939616BF4CFFB992A2969EBE8661" level="section">Sec. 9. Additional State activities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0F7CE02AFC484EAD8F0ACF379545BE7C" level="section">Sec. 10. National evaluation, information dissemination, and technical assistance.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H144C3C2C39774E54B63C828B5970A0E1" level="section">Sec. 11. Consequences of insufficient progress, reporting requirements, and conflicts of interest.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H115511EF1F5E47AFB7F32E9EDE54D566" level="section">Sec. 12. Rules of construction.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H80E4FC8BB3354527AA391AC151E9229F" level="section">Sec. 13. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC7630AC6C74141BC89ADF90418DC3EAF" level="section">Sec. 14. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H82AF8740258B45BCABE6F44C8680DE8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that in order for a comprehensive and effective literacy program to address the needs of children it is critical to address the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC27E578372E5440E9B4570EE66C9DB2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Literacy development is an ongoing process that requires a sustained engagement and investment beginning in early childhood and continuing through secondary school.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAED97E074CD94458B6B6360E46A6AA03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Developing literacy skills begins at birth as infants and toddlers associate sounds, gestures, and marks on paper with consequences and meaning. Many teachers and staff in early learning programs are not provided with high-quality professional development in how to support children’s language and literacy development. Such high-quality professional learning and preparation, that is job-embedded and ongoing, promotes strong early language and literacy for all children’s readiness for school.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7789ECBE90764CDCB88350E74764DCF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research shows that writing leads to improved reading achievement, reading leads to better writing performance, and combined instruction leads to improvements in both areas. Students in kindergarten through grade 12 need to be engaged in combined reading and writing experiences that lead to a higher level of thinking than when either process is taught alone.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE89CBBFD8A4D4C749949FAD9081960A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Teachers and early childhood educators need professional development to improve the reading and writing abilities of children who are at risk for developmental delays or are reading and writing several years below grade level. Middle school and secondary school teachers in core academic subjects must have the tools and skills to teach reading and writing for subject area understanding and to differentiate and provide instruction for students with varying literacy skills.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD62DE9A3850A40DA8970FDFA7285BA67"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Approximately 65 percent of 4th graders and 8th graders read below the proficient level on the 2013 National Assessment of Educational Progress.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96853512BCA84324812107B56918C660"><enum>(6)</enum><text>One in four students enter 9th grade reading below grade level and struggle to graduate because their literacy achievement is alarmingly low. Many of the more than 700,000 students who leave U.S. high schools each year without a diploma have low literacy skills. For those students who earn a diploma, an increasing number must take remedial coursework upon entering college, without promising results: students who enroll in a remedial reading course are less likely to eventually earn a degree or certificate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE58660BD07454A1E842F6A032BD27115"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Fewer than 2 in 10 high school students who graduated in 2014 met all 4 ACT College Readiness Benchmarks (English, Mathematics, Reading, and Science), the minimum level of achievement that ACT indicates is necessary if students are to experience success in first-year college courses.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B869FAE3C5940AAA3FCC0F71E9D9A39"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Roughly 40 percent of secondary school graduates lack the literacy skills employers seek. The 25 fastest growing professions have higher than average literacy demands while the fastest declining professions have lower than average literacy demands.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83662E72CFCC4C88AA51FE808E8C2843"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The intellectual and linguistic skills necessary for reading and writing must be developed through explicit, intentional, and systematic language activities, to which many low-income and minority students do not have access.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5544F6A0D5FB43D19C483FD4E1C0C199"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Meaningful engagement of families in their children’s early learning supports school readiness and later academic success. Parental literacy habits are positively associated with parental reading beliefs, parent-child literacy and language activities in the home, children’s print knowledge, and interest in reading and writing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EA9E00C979A405893D52D379EB063EE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Research shows that low expectations for the reading and writing achievement of students in schools results in curricula that do not challenge students or adequately support literacy education, while high academic expectations and quality instruction and supports can boost student learning and achievement.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7E6BE5A6171F4B6B86AE0F3FCB2198DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="H6F050B70AA304E079B1486C0265CED87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve reading, writing, and academic achievement for children and students by providing Federal support to State educational agencies, in collaboration with State agencies that oversee child care programs, to develop, coordinate, and implement comprehensive State literacy plans that ensure high-quality instruction and effective practices in early language and literacy in early learning programs (serving children from birth through kindergarten entry) and in reading and writing in kindergarten through grade 12; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9ED3B11E56A348A789ACB6AE22111CAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist State educational agencies and State agencies that oversee child care and other early childhood programs in achieving the purposes described in paragraph (1) by—</text> <subparagraph id="H67401221A305490E894937647347923E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting the development and implementation of early learning through grade 12 literacy programs that are based on scientifically valid research, to ensure that every student can read and write at grade level or above;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08D187C93D194A18AAF6692640A4FB58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing children attending early learning programs that serve children from birth through kindergarten entry, including programs, such as child care, Early Head Start, Head Start, State-funded preschool, public library programs, and other early childhood education settings, with high-quality, language-rich, literature-rich, informational text-rich, culturally relevant, developmentally appropriate environments, so that such children develop the fundamental knowledge and skills necessary for literacy engagement, development, and achievement in kindergarten and beyond;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H264ACF2FDD0B49C3AAF3B63AFB7DC88A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>educating parents in the ways they can support their child’s communication and literacy development;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H44E81E9E43D24D1D84C48B595AC56024"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supporting efforts to link and align standards and evidence-based teaching practices and instruction in early learning programs serving children from birth through kindergarten entry;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3350D538C05745B69F88B213431154A1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>supporting high-quality, effective educational and development environments for children and students from birth through grade 12 to develop oral language, reading comprehension, and writing abilities through evidence-based instruction and practices;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4DC7DA037A3440C88234738A6E0139C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>improving student achievement by establishing literacy initiatives that provide explicit and systematic instruction in oral language, reading, and writing development across the curriculum;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B7C3B72D2B14EBBAA4C5C01514AC802"><enum>(G)</enum><text>identifying and supporting students who are reading and writing below grade level by providing evidence-based intensive interventions, including extended learning time, to help such students acquire the language and literacy skills they need to graduate from secondary school;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC20C1F04A29E42AEAF093D919AD9DFA0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>providing assistance to eligible entities in order to provide educators with high-quality professional development in the essential components of early literacy instruction and the essential components of reading and writing instruction;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09A8E6548B494E048FECC5A1A7C6E841"><enum>(I)</enum><text>supporting State educational agencies and local educational agencies in using age- and developmentally appropriate instructional materials and strategies, including those consistent with universal design for learning, that assist teachers as they work with students to develop reading and writing competencies appropriate to the student’s grade and skill levels;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H151F672F280147B29A031E3129890B6D"><enum>(J)</enum><text>supporting State educational agencies and eligible entities in improving reading, writing, and academic achievement for children and students, especially those that are low-income, limited English proficient, migratory, Indian or Alaskan Native, neglected or delinquent, homeless, in the custody of the child welfare system, those that have disabilities, or those who have dropped out of school; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CD826BF9B53486C85D04865CEA53868"><enum>(K)</enum><text>strengthening coordination among schools, early learning programs, early literacy programs, family literacy programs, juvenile justice programs, public libraries, and outside-of-school programs that provide children and youth with strategies, curricula, interventions, and assessments designed to advance early and continuing language and literacy development in ways appropriate for each context.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HADC9B2BC0E5B438DBFD1DF37ED3A28AD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Programs authorized</header> 
<subsection id="H7AC46D5A82BF415ABB55ADD4F1278AC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary is authorized—</text> <paragraph id="HA27878E8D7BB4A2E9CBBA1F0C8FA183F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to award State planning grants in accordance with subsection (b) and section 5; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H12E61FB08D43478CADD2CF810F626C0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to award State implementation grants in accordance with subsection (b) and section 6 to enable—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE16C095241C478E99612291F204F682"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State agency that oversees child care programs, in consultation with the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care described in section 642B of the Head Start Act and other early childhood agencies, to award subgrants to eligible entities in accordance with section 7;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD13CF3ED17C481CBEE8AD1C5CD2052F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State educational agency to award subgrants to eligible entities in accordance with section 8; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1772B4B617844064969A6727D0605125"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State educational agency to carry out the additional State activities described in section 9.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE35CEB8320EF428E9EF30CC66A9EC57B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards to state educational agencies</header> 
<paragraph id="HBC6E8B618762463FA00DD7308EB806E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Discretionary grants</header> 
<subparagraph id="HED8C4734BE344F6D9C0A244FBA26E237"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the amount appropriated under section 14 for a fiscal year is less than $500,000,000 the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H1BD53F6555D3428BAC9D0D5BEA33726B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reserve not more than 5 percent of such amount for the national evaluation, dissemination of information, and technical assistance under section 10;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H304AE06AE1FE4CDF8BD79F4B258091E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reserve not more than 5 percent of such amount to make awards, on a competitive basis, under section 5; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBE7589C3F03B4FB09B274B9F56A3B605"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>use the amount not reserved under clauses (i) and (ii) to make awards, on a competitive basis and based on the quality of the applications submitted, to State educational agencies that have applications approved under section 6 to enable the agencies to carry out sections 7 through 9.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H24091B9C4A984EF6A26FE00E1C00AD93"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text>The Secretary shall allocate the funds described in subparagraph (A)(iii) among approved applicants on the basis of the relative number or percentage of children counted under section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>) in a State served by an approved applicant compared to the number or percentage of such children in all States served by approved applicants, except that awards under this paragraph shall be of sufficient size and scope to be effective.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FDD70776FB742EA9F60DDE832A40544"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formula grants</header> <subparagraph id="H4D9A409580D245288F5B6CB1E36CC61E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the amount appropriated under section 14 for a fiscal year is equal to or exceeds $500,000,000 the Secretary shall—</text> 
<clause id="H779235265A184B83B5AA144EEBDAB4D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reserve not more than 5 percent of such amount for the national evaluation, dissemination of information, and technical assistance under section 10;</text></clause> <clause id="H52F12FFCF3F5448CB674A1A5CD0E6036"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reserve not more than 5 percent of such amount to make awards, on a competitive basis, under section 5;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H895563C6685F4CD692E6052FD65F31F6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reserve a total of 1 percent of such amount for—</text> <subclause id="H8F992F69A1294211AE31884CED32FA89"><enum>(I)</enum><text>allotments for the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, to be distributed among such outlying areas on the basis of their relative need, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with the purposes of this Act; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3CBF9BDBF4E54CA0BE6FCE253B3F72ED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior for programs under sections 5 through 9 in schools operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Education; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H8015BDC9344E44BE80B6B895373AC326"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>use the amount not reserved under clauses (i) through (iii) to make awards, from allotments under subparagraph (B), to State educational agencies serving States, excluding States described in clause (iii)(I), that have applications approved under section 6 to enable the agencies to carry out sections 7 through 9.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H753CFC99ACAF47CE93D7DFBAE5900D19"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State allotment formula</header><text>From the funds described in subparagraph (A)(iv), the Secretary shall make an award to each approved applicant under section 6 on the basis of the relative number of children counted under section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>) in the State served by the applicant compared to the number of such children in all States served by approved applicants.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F5B20508593475498677B914592CD21"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Proportional division</header><text>In each fiscal year, the amount reserved under subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be divided between the uses described in subclauses (I) and (II) of such subparagraph in the same proportion as the amount reserved under section 1121(a) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6331">20 U.S.C. 6331(a)</external-xref>) is divided between the uses described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of such section 1121(a) for such fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H974A788CB9EB46019BF59C42D4D1BB4D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header> 
<subparagraph id="HCD9ED79D5E3A4E6B91D336718B963572"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As applicable, a State educational agency that receives a discretionary grant or allotment under this subsection shall engage in timely and meaningful consultation with representatives of Indian tribes located in the State in order to improve the coordination of activities designed to develop effective approaches to achieve the purposes of the Act consistent with the cultural, language, and educational needs of Indian students.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE99D5724330E40D5A50F157F7CDBCBCC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Of the funds reserved under paragraph (2)(A)(iii)(II), the Secretary of the Interior shall consult with tribes and school boards connected with bureau-funded schools to ensure allocation of funds to the extent possible in accordance with subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of section 6(a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBB2F11AB1FBF43FFBF4B5D6A0D1A3E4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Peer review</header> 
<paragraph id="HBC08E68A1DF04ADCBDD149E8ED2094A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall convene a peer review panel to evaluate and make recommendations to the Secretary regarding each application for a grant under section 5 or 6 using the evaluation criteria described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32722BE96D234314B68399BE4B56E325"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of evaluation criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall report to the Congress the peer review process and evaluation criteria that will be used to evaluate grant applications under sections 5 and 6 and shall make a copy of the peer review panel’s comments available to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5D2272F73510476AB8F22B8FB5051EAF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Grant funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, or local funds that would, in the absence of such grant funds, be made available for literacy instruction and support of children and students participating in programs assisted under this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H714AB7A15A164BF3A4A56998594D6830"><enum>5.</enum><header>State planning grants</header> <subsection id="HC4E68A1AFCC14016B7A515DD5944883B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Planning grants authorized</header> <paragraph id="H44A23F52B0B24A7D9EC9FF21AD014AB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may award planning grants to State educational agencies to enable the State educational agencies to develop or improve a comprehensive plan, in consultation with the State agencies that oversee child care and other early childhood programs, the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care, and the State Head Start Collaboration Office, to carry out activities that improve literacy for children and students from birth through grade 12.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8A2FD16E7194962B28BF2281D2D3406"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A planning grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of not more than 1 year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7D09BB3E1E04CC59FFDA3C82E0EB58E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonrenewability</header><text>The Secretary shall not award a State educational agency more than 1 planning grant under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3A6792A21014D18846F6E9E9697B39B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relation to implementation grants</header><text>A State educational agency may not receive a planning grant under this section at the same time it is receiving an implementation grant under section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8C1D8B4A716E49BEAB14CBCA6FC15856"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Each State educational agency desiring a planning grant under this section shall submit, jointly with the State agencies that oversee child care and other early childhood programs and the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care, an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEE476CC5D8B4CCF90A859953FC5EF84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Existing state literacy plan</header><text>An existing Federally funded comprehensive State literacy plan may be improved using a grant under this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5FEF4DDDE51B416B8C7EBCE0CAF8F886"><enum>6.</enum><header>State implementation grants</header> <subsection id="HA17925B5504B47C69F7B62CB5381497A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation grants authorized</header> <paragraph id="H3B84893AAD364A2FB753CC8BC38C34DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award implementation grants to State educational agencies—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H91B6A7035BFB419198487539D7F4DF87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to implement, in collaboration with the State agencies that oversee child care and other early childhood programs, the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care, and the State Head Start Collaboration Office—</text> <clause id="H224EA42263F641EC964D8B48F065F0A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the comprehensive State literacy plan developed under section 5, if the State educational agency received a grant under such section; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H836912172A164D35895A4795E3CAFCC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another comprehensive State literacy plan for serving children from birth through grade 12;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADFBF80080A742DDA44DE33C93CB9F33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide funds made available under paragraph (2)(A) to the State agency that oversees child care programs to award subgrants under section 7;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF2040D85D82240C6835EFC3791EFA4FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to award subgrants under section 8; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F9C0463365043C7BBFF5279AD06660A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to carry out additional State activities under section 9.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDCFDFDB87898429D894261DA02BDF316"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>State educational agency shall use implementation grant funds received under this section as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="HB287BC7BB6CC45C087506A23DC5B0FE4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Learners from birth through kindergarten entry</header><text>Not less than 15 percent of such grant funds shall be used in accordance with section 7.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF07BDB7A45B141D2BC6948D797527EBF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Students in kindergarten through grade 5</header><text>Not less than 40 percent of such grant funds shall be used in accordance with section 8, to be allocated equitably among grades kindergarten through grade 5, unless the State educational agency determines than an exception is necessary based on a capacity survey described in section 8(c)(1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF93CB66D7954A2690C8865180AB79A4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Students in grades 6 through 12</header><text>Not less than 40 percent of such grant funds shall be used in accordance with section 8, to be allocated equitably among grades 6 through 12, unless the State educational agency determines that an exception is necessary based on a capacity survey described in section 8(c)(1).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H312EEC04BBFF4E698CDE0C633A374064"><enum>(D)</enum><header>State activities</header><text>Not more than 5 percent of such grant funds shall be used for the State activities described in section 9.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA775865AC306459B883E879F2F1425CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration of grants</header><text>An implementation grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of not less than 3 years and not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06A276EAA4384D198C6F7984AFFB9306"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Renewals</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0157CC4C40954E08A86BBE8F28EF7E2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Implementation grants under this section may be renewed.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9926B33E39074EE2926377C3B3889BAE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>In order to be eligible to have an implementation grant renewed under this paragraph, the State educational agency, in collaboration with the State agencies that oversee child care and other early childhood programs and the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care, shall demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that—</text> 
<clause id="HA341411C02284539A4395350532CE232"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the State educational agency has complied with the terms of the grant, including using the funds to—</text> <subclause id="HE4E7C2A7F9664B39AF5AFBD84B3611C4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>increase access to high-quality professional development;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2CB1A359796044A9BFACBA585D47B777"><enum>(II)</enum><text>use developmentally appropriate curricula and teaching materials; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD854D9B98A124FCABCBFFB080597B415"><enum>(III)</enum><text>use developmentally appropriate classroom-based instructional assessments and developmentally appropriate screening and diagnostic assessments; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H4A248CC3F3064E8898729A671F594DAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to students in kindergarten through grade 12, during the period of the grant there has been significant progress in student achievement, as measured by appropriate assessments, including meeting the measurable annual objectives established pursuant to section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(v)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H95A41C607AE64D5993B4659709CEB465"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State Applications</header> <paragraph id="HF3DEC982A0F64C0886E2347B71FFE22A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State educational agency that desires to receive an implementation grant under this section shall, in collaboration with the State agencies that oversee child care and other early childhood programs and the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care, submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64A360C0E7E7437CA56D7AF0BE930525"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application described in paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3576BA0055AB4C879BCE1BD2F7EA4B78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State literacy team and plan</header><text>A description of how the State educational agency has formed a State literacy leadership team and developed a comprehensive State literacy plan, as described in section 5.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7860B3F6AAC9405996E950482D0B5083"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><text>An assurance that the State has a process to safeguard against conflicts of interest consistent with section 11(c) for individuals providing technical assistance on behalf of the State educational agency or the State agencies that oversee child care and other early childhood programs or serving on the State literacy leadership team.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H849DD58CC68C48FF8DC0D958974249E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>An implementation plan that includes a description of how the State educational agency and the State agency that oversees child care programs will—</text> 
<clause id="HCD04FC51602648A196FCCB3AF044D74B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assist eligible entities with—</text> <subclause id="HBCBFEA4497264816B426FFD459ADA402"><enum>(I)</enum><text>selecting and using screening assessments and diagnostic assessments;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0E91046EA65741EAA246352502EEA203"><enum>(II)</enum><text>providing classroom-based instruction that is supported by one-to-one and small group instruction;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD70BDFB4A2174010B95F7D32B74C50ED"><enum>(III)</enum><text>using curricular materials and instructional tools, which may include technology, to improve instruction and literacy achievement;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H753103636DB94925862B29F53AB70A82"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>using the principles of universal design for learning in all phases of instructional practice, including professional development, curriculum development and selection of instructional materials, and classroom instruction;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA780C869BD9D40D88C09C0259E539E39"><enum>(V)</enum><text>providing high-quality professional development as part of such eligible entities’ literacy initiatives to improve the literacy development and learning of children and students served under the implementation grant; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2C2BB901E0DC4ED0B29E9454E7192AC8"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>providing diverse learners, including English language learners, with culturally, linguistically, and developmentally appropriate curricula, instructional materials, interactive technologies, and valid and reliable assessments that support such learners in meeting State academic and content standards;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB2ADD9AB5A844B4EB40B2F84E555E313"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that eligible entities in the State have leveraged and are effectively leveraging the resources to implement high-quality literacy instruction, and have the capacity to implement high-quality literacy initiatives effectively;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H808499E1DD9F4903BB539207564BADDD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensure that professional development activities are based on—</text> <subclause id="H876703E1101840268975EC1EECEBFCDA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the essential components of early literacy instruction and the essential components of reading and writing instruction, as appropriate; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9F730C1B95F9497FAE1B90B441AFAAC7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>evidence-based English language acquisition and adult learning research, as appropriate;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H0F268E69DFED41A5ABEADAD8AEC279A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordinate and align, as appropriate, the activities assisted under this section and sections 7 and 8 with other State and local programs that—</text> 
<subclause id="HB9537C63072B4EFDA3B78CAD7811359E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>serve children and students, and their families; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2C353CBA64344F2C871BC2F73CD71589"><enum>(II)</enum><text>promote literacy instruction and learning;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H3822F98DF55F4329AA675C774BFFE945"><enum>(v)</enum><text>ensure that funds provided under this section are awarded in a manner that will provide services to all age and grade levels consistent with section 6(a)(2);</text></clause> <clause id="HEF3A809487F94B6A9A7631B2759E8F34"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>award subgrants to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out the activities described in sections 7 and 8, including to—</text> 
<subclause id="HA113DD2DC6A540209E753C6815B783F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>eligible entities that serve rural areas; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFE833E01D3C949BB840D9C88BC9B14CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>eligible entities that serve urban areas; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HB5D7411233444174937CF585A8661A73"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>assist the eligible entities in the State in—</text> <subclause id="H40839B952B5D4E44BAE551349AB7CA47"><enum>(I)</enum><text>providing strategic and intensive literacy instruction for students reading and writing below grade level, including through the use of multitiered systems of supports;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5CB04226CEB044F59ED6E54D9B1B6DC2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>providing high-quality professional development in literacy instruction to teachers, including—</text> <item id="HE8B35EA5D4A94332BD68A5CC8C9D8579"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>special education teachers or teachers of students who are English language learners; and</text></item> 
<item id="H8CB9A68E68E24217BA4BA09B6DF4ABD5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>teachers of core academic subjects;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H609C96B313714FEF87ED187DB79CB088"><enum>(III)</enum><text>addressing the literacy needs of children and students with disabilities and English language learners served by the eligible entity; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE1F894954E4B4BAD954DD03C168720F9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>providing training to parents so that the parents can participate in the literacy related activities described under sections 7 and 8 to assist in the language and literacy development of their children.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2E25E600B7842D8898C802497848590"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Key data metrics</header><text>A description of the key data metrics that will be collected and reported annually under section 11(b)(1)(E).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66AB374932E14439A7869AF11EBE5850"><enum>(E)</enum><header>National evaluation</header><text>An assurance that the State educational agency, the State agency that awards subgrants under section 7, and any eligible entity receiving a subgrant under section 7 or 8, will, if requested, participate in the national evaluation under section 10.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC20EFA520F934814ADDCD4F13F556BDF"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>An assurance that the State educational agency and the State agency that oversees child care programs, as appropriate, shall prioritize awarding subgrants—</text> 
<clause id="H653C3DD6507948DA8B61D170307F98E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under section 7, based on the percentage of low-income children proposed to be served by the applicant; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC2B1D86B085442DAA2C1A3E05061792C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under section 8, based on the number or percentage of children counted under section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>) proposed to be served by the applicant.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF12BB49DC3BA4881B8348115581597CF"><enum>7.</enum><header>Subgrants to eligible entities in support of literacy for children from birth through kindergarten entry</header> 
<subsection id="H9B00436E85864821AFEAAC8813AB77CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text>A State educational agency shall provide the funds provided under section 4(a)(2)(A) to the State agency that oversees child care programs, who shall award subgrants, on a competitive basis, in consultation with the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care and other State early childhood agencies, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3D2DB013B2994656BF554D0FCE5D87D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sufficient size and scope</header><text>Each subgrant awarded under this section shall be of sufficient size and scope to allow the eligible entity to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0C0079E42BA4296AB5AFED82F84238C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Local Applications</header><text>An eligible entity that desires to receive a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the State agency that oversees child care programs, at such time, in such manner, and including such information as such agency may require. Such application shall include a description of—</text> <paragraph id="H2F00B552EC374EC08B6763D677D25A09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a needs assessment, including an analysis of data on child literacy as applicable;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1379F7DC3804BE49A16E531BACD0029"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an implementation plan that utilizes the needs assessment described in paragraph 1 that identifies a baseline level of literacy and early literacy skills, as well as benchmarks for making improvements and monitoring progress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC64E07478B4E4A5FB53AF02A3E6289A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the programs assisted under the subgrant, including demographic and socioeconomic information on the children from birth through kindergarten entry enrolled in the programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD40C17D5FF4847329A6BB1DD9EF8952E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a budget for the eligible entity that projects the cost of developing and implementing literacy initiatives to carry out the activities described in subsection (e);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBE786CE4C0841F0B84E6E8FE36C91EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>how the subgrant funds will be used to enhance the language and literacy aspects of school readiness of children from birth through kindergarten entry in early childhood education programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7B2CABB08214D1DBA76DF2695436878"><enum>(6)</enum><text>how the subgrant funds will be used to prepare and provide ongoing assistance to staff in the programs, through professional development focused on the essential components of early literacy instruction, including onsite intensive mentoring by early childhood literacy coaches to provide high-quality literacy activities based on scientifically valid research on child development and learning for children from birth through kindergarten entry;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5FD524227E7C449C93C63B3F48CE605B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>how the subgrant funds will be used to provide services, incorporate activities, and select and use literacy instructional materials that are based on scientifically valid research on child development and early learning;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F7689EC4FB24F6993A5AC606FB5D808"><enum>(8)</enum><text>how the subgrant funds will be used to provide—</text> <subparagraph id="HA21B1702D38F43B68E533E34EEA49821"><enum>(A)</enum><text>screening assessments or other appropriate measures—</text> 
<clause id="H137AD05700234E17B2621646021BDCAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to effectively identify children from birth through kindergarten entry who may be at risk for delayed development or later academic difficulties; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF12B62C487A7486EB8E2618C95DFA8D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to determine whether such children are developing the fundamental knowledge necessary for literacy, engagement, development, and achievement in kindergarten and beyond; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAB5EACD9FE946E185A345A79D024DAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>diagnostic assessments, as appropriate, to determine the need for additional services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59B70B51BF2547EBB6EBF2A561115E7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>classroom-based instructional assessments; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4654694B1B3349B083A44AF890D68FCA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other appropriate assessments of developmental progress;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E72B5FF742E4C0980E7E1500D692462"><enum>(9)</enum><text>how the subgrant funds will be used to help instructional staff in the programs assisted under the subgrant to more effectively meet the diverse developmental and linguistic needs of children from birth through kindergarten entry in the community, including the needs of English language learners and children with disabilities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6528A1C6DCF14FDCA182EA69A0F7E370"><enum>(10)</enum><text>how the subgrant funds will be used to ensure that parents receive instruction—</text> <subparagraph id="H596F7168C7C3416EB052112AF910F264"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on their children’s early literacy development; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4DA97D153A04C949B736CEE55FB304E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on how parents can support children’s literacy development at home;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AAB0A37144C42D2904917432438597B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>how the subgrant funds will be used to help children, particularly children experiencing difficulty with spoken and written language, to make the transition from early education to formal classroom instruction;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAA19B5E565540888C4659F4157C831D"><enum>(12)</enum><text>how the activities assisted under the subgrant will be coordinated with literacy instruction at the kindergarten through grade 3 levels;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47C853EB8B874547A25B898BE2D1ABD7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>how the eligible entity will—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0288E7D97BC646F6A0696CD7F7E9E5B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the success of the activities supported under the subgrant in enhancing the early language and literacy development of children served under such subgrant; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H863D86F35E14439D8F46DE27040545D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate data for program improvement; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFF691383EA44B83B4D43F04B0FF9FDC"><enum>(14)</enum><text>such other information as the State agency that oversees child care programs may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0823D5560B164156952F2C14EEC25A81"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval of local Applications</header><text>The State agency that oversees child care programs shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H85C70718EB8445F98168CD5DCB0B24F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>award subgrants to eligible entities in accordance with this section based on the quality of applications submitted; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CEE02B2BCFB41B6B77AAFA7C6A04E32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritize awarding subgrants based on the criteria described in section 6(b)(2)(F).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA8BFB4761A004FE68A5E8F54D5D97B30"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Local uses of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H42D88B15C21A463BA7755862D733BFD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required uses</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section shall use the subgrant funds to carry out the following activities to support the development of early language and literacy in children from birth through kindergarten entry:</text> <subparagraph id="H9B0BB2B5E6BA45A68A618FA355352D36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Enhance and improve early learning programs to ensure that children in such programs are provided with high-quality, developmentally appropriate oral language, literature- and print-rich environments.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3A9F8847B010424A83F0ACDD0F1C644E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provide high-quality professional development on how children develop language and literacy skills (including children with disabilities and English language learners), and the selection and integration of developmentally, linguistically, and culturally appropriate literacy instructional strategies, activities, and materials, which may include the use of an early literacy coach for the staff of the eligible entity, in such entity’s curriculum and activities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE55A75CDB0CC40F797C6C7F6A573F25E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Acquire, provide training for, and implement, as appropriate—</text> 
<clause id="H0758B173E5D34515A9412D5C4364684B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>screening assessments or other appropriate measures to determine whether children from birth through kindergarten entry are developing appropriate early language and literacy skills;</text></clause> <clause id="H4D9FEB25B2634D62B684B1812CFE8BA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>diagnostic assessments, as appropriate, to determine the need for additional services; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H656F1C164ACC4B1E85E6BA96EFA96B47"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>classroom-based instructional assessments.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB827D705F93A4545A867DDFC8D2192C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Acquire, as appropriate, and integrate evidence-based instructional materials, activities, tools, and measures into the early learning programs offered by the eligible entity to improve development of children’s early language and literacy skills.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD6882D5FEA84F43840407BF128DEB1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowable uses</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section may use the subgrant funds to carry out either or both of the following activities to support the development of early language and literacy in children from birth through kindergarten entry:</text> <subparagraph id="H087D16D7F8D143769DDDB378EB1DC449"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Selecting, developing, and implementing a multitier system of supports.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAED31838F876469FBB0620645E7FEA94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Providing activities that encourage family literacy experiences and practices and educate parents of children enrolled in a program receiving funds under this section on the development of their children’s early literacy skills.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H18345BD07B7D41D181A11DA6F0CE5E6E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The use of assessment items and data on any assessment authorized under this section to provide rewards or sanctions for individual children, early learning providers, program directors, or principals is prohibited.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H40BC3F74942D4EFB9E09F226307FDAE4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Subgrants to eligible entities in support of literacy for students in kindergarten through grade 12</header> 
<subsection id="HA5D7EE7D1CED4326A63A7439B3632D30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text>A State educational agency shall use the implementation grant funds provided under section 4(a)(2)(B) to award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H76AD24B2DFF84EE78BA341CD00EBE5DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sufficient size and scope</header><text>Each subgrant awarded under this section shall be of sufficient size and scope to allow the eligible entity to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H71E16250A88A44C9AFB81DB8F10F9ECB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Local Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring to receive a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may require. Such application shall include, the following information:</text> <paragraph id="H156B28ADC21F4CD5A789B7924FD628A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Capacity survey</header><text>Results of the eligible entity’s capacity survey that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1BFD8CC26BE542709036F9E2BA687134"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify—</text> <clause id="HE95AFC5DD5514ADBA8ADAA1552314053"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the strengths and weaknesses of such entity related to literacy;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H97F3A05154F648F08AD15B6435016359"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how subgrant funds will be used to inform and improve literacy instruction within such entity; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCC8E4D5B8F674A6AB3828C08566D0BB2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the demographic and socioeconomic information on the students enrolled in such entity; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H856F41B969E54209947A98EAA868370C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include an analysis, disaggregated by the subgroups described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v)(II) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(v)(II)</external-xref>) and by grade level, of—</text> <clause id="H2CD2589D165C40EF9BEDEBB61135B4CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State scores on the reading or language arts assessments conducted under section 1111(b)(3) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(3)</external-xref>);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H74494EADAF7D4657B76EEEFDC0B31B2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>National Assessment of Educational Progress reading scores, as appropriate;</text></clause> <clause id="HE2CC2C45AC324AC19D7ACEE17135858B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the percentage of students in need of reading and writing remediation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5D0C5D6507494E61AE410F56FE5D2F30"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>core course passing and failure rates for secondary school students;</text></clause> <clause id="H54B1322FC60846D481BCA39788117C47"><enum>(v)</enum><text>credit accumulation for secondary school students; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEFCEA7F716AC45DEB44BAD56149E91FF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>graduation rates.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B6D2C86669D41B0B98BD0FD0AC5A611"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Professional development</header><text>How each participating school, eligible entity, or a provider of high-quality professional development will provide ongoing high-quality professional development in language development, English language acquisition (as appropriate), and literacy instruction to all teachers, principals, and other school leaders served by the school.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H787626F74B7741C5A5A645A4D62DE871"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interventions</header><text>How each participating school will identify students in need of interventions and provide appropriate scientifically valid instructional interventions or other services which may include one-on-one instruction and extended learning time for struggling students.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E7C7CEB04BE4B8A86D7D2D81F33A8D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Budget</header><text>A budget for each participating school that projects the cost of developing and implementing literacy initiatives to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD38B91EF37E4CDEB274489DF3BB959F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Integration</header><text>An explanation of how each participating school will integrate literacy instruction into core academic subjects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E4A69DC22D84828BE069AA3D50DEB3B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>A description of how each participating school will coordinate literacy instruction with early education, after-school programs, and other programs serving students in the school, such as library programs, as appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD0366DDCED84EC48A702780E812619F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Assessments</header><text>A description of the screening, diagnostic, formative, and summative assessments that will be used in an assessment system to improve literacy instruction and track student literacy progress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA74612B62AB849EF843862363A5A2195"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Families and caregivers</header><text>A description of how the families and caregivers will be involved in supporting their children’s literacy instruction and assessment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9150DCB31E44DE7AE9506170CB063DB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Initiatives</header><text>A description of the literacy and other academic initiatives, if any, in place and how these initiatives will be coordinated and integrated with activities supported under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9ED1E548B9D4DAAA401D1E075F97FF7"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Participation in evaluation</header><text>An assurance that the eligible entity will, if requested, participate in the national evaluation described in section 10.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9196DC15D8854F3396C41CFC1E1CA34A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval of local Applications</header><text>The State educational agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="HCF8C80A0ADCA4A118472E4B3B59D5459"><enum>(1)</enum><text>award subgrants to eligible entities in accordance with this section based on the quality of applications submitted; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB1F185D2DA549FB92AD2319CE19CD3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritize awarding subgrants to eligible entities based on the criteria described in section 6(b)(2)(F).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0F15ED42CED94E84B0C8F3307BED536F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Local uses of funds for kindergarten through grade 12</header> <paragraph id="H99C360B7AB9A44EC8D5911CA88A40A8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required uses</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section shall use the subgrant funds to carry out the following activities for students in kindergarten through grade 12:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H23397AE4A3DA438293FC0EE3BD37C6B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Develop and implement a literacy initiative that—</text> <clause id="H9761B4928D8F44788D2DBAC7E56790D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes all of the essential components of reading and writing instruction;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H93C9D70ACFBA4EB99FD0F6870AC29F65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supports activities that are provided primarily during the regular school day but which may be augmented by instruction during nonschool hours or periods when school is not in session (such as before and after school or during summer recess);</text></clause> <clause id="H8EE0C000E4324FBA93EBFB082F1B5C5D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>integrates literacy instruction into core academic subjects and, to the extent practicable, other subjects taught in a school, such as career and technical education; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5B47320B9E7B4C82B411B589175C292C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>addresses the literacy needs of English language learners and students with disabilities.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H137382AF6D064F4E89CDF9C840F94E69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Form school literacy leadership teams to help implement, assess, and identify changes to the literacy initiative.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16EBB6DB4A894989A5C1A10618C0A264"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Provide high-quality, developmentally appropriate oral language, including listening and speaking, literature, and print-rich classroom environments.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE91D912B8304A06923C4BE4AFB3C48C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Provide high-quality professional development for instructional staff, including literacy coaches and teachers of students with disabilities and English language learners.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB53B9332D77645B0AD57DE93537AAFBA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Select and administer screening and diagnostic assessments and support teachers’ use of formative assessments and assessment data to plan instruction.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C219AF1D71A4FD08AD3D46160B5A807"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Select and implement a multitier system of supports that includes intensive, supplemental interventions for students.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4290323D2943443AA7D320F65CC9D595"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Provide training to principals and other school and district personnel in implementing the literacy initiative, particularly in the areas of—</text> <clause id="HA26F443F29834D989F1FA6209E733976"><enum>(i)</enum><text>utilizing data;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2987BB65734944CDBA01B3115A0488B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assessing the quality of literacy instruction across content areas; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD3D472DC69894026BA1F8A97AA46B064"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing time and support for teachers to plan literacy instruction.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B4E62F8797C4B18A2CB6722BAA2F479"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Provide family literacy services for students and their parents, including training to enable families and caregivers to support the literacy initiative.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DA9F14A4A1040C18F547A92E4D50B13"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Promote writing experiences and implement programs that instruct and engage students in practicing writing for multiple audiences and purposes appropriate to the interests and capacities of students.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H373C919AF72046488B3170307B5EE69F"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Annually collect, analyze, and report data to the State educational agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA95AA987874B4E7C9BF6BC2E14790E3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowable uses</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section may use the subgrant funds to carry out the following activities for students in kindergarten through grade 12:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC1D373A3F7FA4F7DB5FDDDFF143949F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Acquire and utilize developmentally appropriate instructional materials based on scientifically valid research, including materials that utilize technology.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3078F36C42E3411A8E3FBC1211D7A476"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Hire and train literacy coaches.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB18B9A98B1B4182920434C6756ECE57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Promote reading, library, and writing programs that provide access to engaging reading material in school and at home.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H219EE5B97C934380ADDEDC5C0D7F44C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Connect out-of-school learning opportunities to in-school learning, including the alignment of after-school activities with in-school curricula, in order to improve the literacy achievement of students.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB447543EB581423BAD9C8967BE35F7A1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Form an acting partnership with 1 or more public or private nonprofit organizations that have a demonstrated record of effectiveness in improving literacy development or providing professional development aligned with the activities described in this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEC6FE0C1A464F90B0EFDC9FE007E6E4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Providing time for teachers and school librarians to meet to plan literacy instruction, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82957A84EFE3449496E5D36773354F55"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation to certain schools</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a subgrant under this section shall, in distributing subgrant funds under this subsection, provide the subgrant funds only to schools, including public charter schools, that—</text> <paragraph id="HFB581CA1A2E24B229B8571A8B876BA3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are among the schools served by the eligible entity with the highest numbers or percentages of students in grades kindergarten through 12 reading and writing below grade level, based on the most current State data as available; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9391A2C75004A9590E567BC2938958C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have the highest numbers or percentages of children counted under section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8BC6939616BF4CFFB992A2969EBE8661"><enum>9.</enum><header>Additional State activities</header> <subsection id="H9E6C6DE7D5FB4748ACB1AB8010A5AB70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required activities</header><text>A State educational agency, in consultation with the State agency that oversees child care programs, shall use funds made available under section 4(a)(2)(C) and described in section 6(a)(1)(D) to carry out each of the following activities:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCE8E8B8047AC4E96AFDABDB2352F8CEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance or engaging qualified providers to provide such assistance, to assist eligible entities to design and implement literacy initiatives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E5371F0A5954A9DA037F5BDB7E7DE11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identifying and supporting high-quality professional development in literacy instruction for eligible entities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2ED0483519954F13AE9E381B43C83730"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Coordinating activities under this Act with reading, writing, and other literacy resources and programs across the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60A9B35059DD4D9E867C45E1E091B10E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Disseminating information, including making publicly available on the Web sites of the State educational agency and the State agency that oversees child care programs, on promising practices to improve children’s early literacy and language development and student literacy achievement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61CD9F6584184D3D8C6D9AA387E17FFD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Reviewing and developing recommendations in collaboration with teachers, early childhood providers, statewide educational and professional organizations representing teachers, and statewide and educational and professional organizations representing institutions of higher education, to strengthen State licensure and certification standards for literacy instruction in early education through grade 12.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E82F3A93D0C479C95B8F20AEA3ABBD9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Coordinating with institutions of higher education in the State to strengthen and enhance pre-service course work for students preparing to teach literacy to children and students from birth through grade 12.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BEB3FD3C1214D7AA3F01C73D6357BE6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Administration and reporting.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB05C7993BD4B46789732101921739D14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permissive activities</header><text>A State educational agency, in collaboration with the State agency that oversees child care programs, may use funds made available under section 4(a)(2)(C) and described in section 6(a)(1)(D) to carry out one or more of the following activities:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5955F18D56D64C11BA124282613137C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Training personnel of eligible entities to use data systems to track student literacy achievement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE05217EF3CFC49CCA83BCC837747190D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Developing and providing training to literacy coaches, including literacy coaches with expertise in early literacy development, language development, and adolescent literacy.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0F7CE02AFC484EAD8F0ACF379545BE7C"><enum>10.</enum><header>National evaluation, information dissemination, and technical assistance</header> 
<subsection id="H2736A0328EA945FEA8097D46B88189BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National evaluation</header> 
<paragraph id="H32DFF20217BF4C4D8751487D9D3603A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From funds reserved under paragraph (1)(A)(i) or (2)(A)(i) of section 4(b), the Secretary shall perform a 5-year national evaluation of the grant and subgrant programs assisted under this Act by entering into one or more contracts or cooperative agreements with independent organizations. Such evaluation shall include scientifically valid research that applies rigorous and systematic procedures to obtain information relevant to the implementation and effect of the programs assisted under this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BDA98DAB793499D976B03CDB68FD01C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of evaluation</header><text>The evaluation described in this subsection shall include an analysis of each of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6211B397D7254212A56D4DA35E9667FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Impact</header><text>The impact of literacy initiatives supported under this Act on improving early literacy skills and student academic outcomes, including student literacy development in reading and writing, student literacy development in other academic content areas, grade promotion, and graduation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC99BAD97AB9149558D0825FB9D0E9620"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Implementation of core features</header><text>The fidelity of implementation of core program features, such as coherence of program across grades, quality of technical assistance, State and school district leadership, professional development for teachers and administrators, use of quality materials and pedagogy, and use of assessment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78A64832797A4F23A6DAA82DF386D21E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other inquiries</header><text>Other inquiries as designated by the Secretary, such as—</text> <clause id="H6C7D8D60F5FA46C1BE6033D769D670B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the types of literacy initiatives that have demonstrated the greatest impact on student achievement;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HECD2CE9994B646819FC6F38C035D2B7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how State standards, local educational agency and school curricula, assessments, and interventions combine to improve literacy;</text></clause> <clause id="H81D2A92891F74688874BF228F8D30305"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how screening, diagnostic, and formative assessments of reading and writing assist teachers in identifying students’ reading and writing needs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC99B5A01069B4BECAF28D2C021888207"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how job-embedded, ongoing, high-quality professional development improves teacher practice and increases literacy skills of children and students;</text></clause> <clause id="H288BAB4B73394546A767A98D4EFBCFF2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the types of literacy activities that improve the early reading, writing, and language skills of children from birth through kindergarten entry;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFE9399E60C3849EB80730C82F77643C0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>how early learning providers are being prepared with scientifically valid research on early childhood literacy and literacy development;</text></clause> <clause id="H1128B456E46549F8BA27AB83889BC8F2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>how early literacy instructional materials and activities based on scientifically valid research are being integrated into preschools, child care programs and programs carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>), and family literacy programs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB525CCB2D1E34D98A92676525BF27C86"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the impact of adolescent literacy initiatives on student motivation, engagement, and participation in adolescent literacy activities;</text></clause> <clause id="HE71C1F7405A14B51A5AFF33B99FD9961"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the impact of literacy initiatives on diverse learners, including English language learners;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H60B930FA3F70480D90D9DF45005E8FDC"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the relationship between students’ literacy achievement and secondary school graduation rates; and</text></clause> <clause id="H496CAC10AD7841DCB08FA6A538EA3C9A"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>effective strategies to integrate school and public library programs to improve literacy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4DF834BAD3E44A5A912B7887839517F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1CA5726DC991423689647C152DD9E0FA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress an interim report on the national evaluation conducted under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACA62B24A0554933881A8AEDC2E1FA1D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a final report containing the results of the national evaluation conducted under this subsection to—</text> 
<clause id="H3495B6EBFC1047ECBA7462B32B26919B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State educational agencies and eligible entities on a periodic basis for use in program improvement; and</text></clause> <clause id="H01F238C1075B46CF8362A52F4AD790E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Congress.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD375D4CF8E79472D9312BC2B1AD00B8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information dissemination and technical assistance</header> 
<paragraph id="H493DEEE8AC1B4A169DDA8EBC37FB70A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts reserved under paragraph (1)(A)(i) or (2)(A)(i) of section 4(b), the Secretary shall, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Director of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, regional educational laboratories established under section 174 of the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9564">20 U.S.C. 9564</external-xref>), and the comprehensive centers established under section 203 of the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9602">20 U.S.C. 9602</external-xref>), distribute information and provide technical assistance on literacy instruction, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H017DAF3B327B4871A63A144EDE55BD7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on literacy instruction and the impact of the instruction on—</text> 
<clause id="HC152337F68194B0380A4FED6D664A4BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>student achievement, motivation, and engagement for literacy; and</text></clause> <clause id="H27121908744145FB8C479FEEA8E4279D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>student graduation with a secondary school diploma;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H921C271F688B41EFBE14530917292E73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on elements of job-embedded, ongoing, high-quality professional development that improves literacy achievement in children and students in early education through grade 12; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H013BF459AF99491FB9983F838BE1F8E7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on schools, eligible entities, and States that have successfully improved literacy achievement in early education through grade 12.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9B50568A92D4338894D01CE679B4612"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dissemination and coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall disseminate and make publicly available the information described in paragraph (1) to—</text> <subparagraph id="HB94BFF13C82C4EE7AEAB37AD7276F786"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recipients of Federal financial assistance under this Act, part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>), the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>), the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9201">20 U.S.C. 9201 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C77A2DC2F774C73918105E4C51DF480"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each school operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAABD5C9C44542F5A58C1AA3611B9615"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of networks</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, use information and dissemination networks developed and maintained through other public and private entities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H144C3C2C39774E54B63C828B5970A0E1"><enum>11.</enum><header>Consequences of insufficient progress, reporting requirements, and conflicts of interest</header> 
<subsection id="H2E22810195B24567B6F9A0E7A2D089D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consequences of insufficient progress</header> 
<paragraph id="H3B6F728AAA75461CAD8B2B7D68DE9566"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consequences for grant recipients</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a State educational agency receiving an award under section 4(b) or an eligible entity receiving a subgrant under section 7 or 8 is not making significant progress in meeting the purposes of this Act after the submission of a report described in subsection (b), then the Secretary may withhold, in whole or in part, further payments under this Act in accordance with section 455 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1234d">20 U.S.C. 1234d</external-xref>) or take such other action authorized by law as the Secretary determines necessary, including providing technical assistance upon request of the State educational agency, or eligible entity, respectively.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F0D611CF6E044C19823948DC16651C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consequences for subgrant recipients</header><text>A State educational agency or State agency that oversees child care programs, as appropriate, receiving an award under section 4(b) may refuse to award subgrant funds to an eligible entity under section 7 or 8 if such State agency finds that the eligible entity is not making significant progress in meeting the purposes of this Act, after—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF3CA4050A3804058A62EA07815196A97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to the eligible entity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2895BEB17C845FE9C3DF106A54D5459"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affording the eligible entity notice and an opportunity for a hearing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCBC99638231A4412870EFE847333962B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="H401D9719F05B4CDC9D9EB27FB83AC789"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State educational agency reports</header><text>Each State educational agency receiving an award under section 6 shall report annually to the Secretary regarding the State educational agency’s progress and the progress of the State agency that oversees child care programs in addressing the purposes of this Act. Such report shall include, at a minimum, a description of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0FD0DBD3C9F419C82E73B052E67AEBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the professional development activities provided under the award, including types of activities and entities involved in providing professional development to early childhood providers, classroom teachers, and other instructional staff;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H434806E0AC0444B5BE20D164C7D963DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>instruction, strategies, activities, curricula, materials, and assessments used in the programs funded under the award;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA654A4AA8CFA427CB6DA1855E2688074"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the types of programs and program settings for children younger than kindergarten entry funded under the award and the ages, grade levels, and demographic information of children served by the programs funded under the award, except that individually identifiable information shall not be included;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1428CB5D2D324366AD05AEE84514ACC1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the experience and qualifications of the instructional staff who provide literacy instruction under the programs funded under the award, including the experience and qualifications of those staff working with children with disabilities, English language learners, and children younger than kindergarten entry;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H242DD9053EBE41B9832AC1E50266D0DF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>key data metrics used for literacy initiatives;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B9C29765CD645AB8FBED474137CE413"><enum>(F)</enum><text>student performance on relevant program metrics, as identified in the State education agency’s implementation plan under section 6(b)(2)(C), such as—</text> <clause id="HC51C58587D594C21A776EC0BF14C366B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of students reading and writing on grade level by the end of the third grade, disaggregated by the subgroups described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v)(II) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(v)(II)</external-xref>); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2F507E12483B4A19AC4CEE2C697956F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the instruction and activities delivered to at-risk students served under the award; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6417A4B0F1A042E2B84BB8D2F3C056AC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the outcomes of programs and activities provided under the award.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H905F3F167A6F45359FF1704646E466C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity reports</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a subgrant under section 7 or 8 shall report annually to the State educational agency or the State agency that oversees child care programs, as appropriate, regarding the eligible entity’s progress in addressing the purposes of this Act. Such report shall include, at a minimum, a description of—</text> <subparagraph id="H5FEE12FF052A4039B25C0891455D5AF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the subgrant funds were used;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB57828E844674E25AFE75A57FBF691E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the degree of appropriate developmental progress or literacy achievement growth of students, including children who are English language learners and children with disabilities, assisted under the subgrant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H732C3229874449C084AFBAB82042AA8C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the professional development of activities provided under the award, including types of activities and entities involved in providing professional development to early childhood providers, classroom teachers, and other instructional staff;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00A5781E3FA146F48CDE4F508B666D11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>instruction, strategies, activities, curricula, materials, and assessments used in the programs funded under the award;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83A9540849B64FB5832B45E6052C75FC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the types of programs funded under the award and the ages, grade levels, and demographic information of children served by the programs funded under the award, except that individually identifiable information shall not be included;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08D90622F4D140078904E3F2A058A4D0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the experience and qualifications of the instructional staff who provide literacy instruction under the programs funded under the award, including the experience and qualifications of those staff working with children with disabilities and with English language learners;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE27C9EB2A1D45188796283E86985C51"><enum>(G)</enum><text>key data metrics used for literacy initiatives;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DD04C8E3CFE4434A0376266268B9D5F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>student performance on relevant program metrics, as identified in the State education agency’s implementation plan under section 6(b)(2)(C), such as—</text> <clause id="H7BB8AACF81CC40C2B27B38D863AB41E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of students reading and writing on grade level by the end of the third grade, disaggregated by the subgroups described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v)(II) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(v)(II)</external-xref>); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H53D7096C44AF4C0A8E16BA505BAFD243"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the instruction and activities delivered to at-risk students served under the award;</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1207F3F7864C4857AEEBE3A0DC314314"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the outcomes of programs and activities provided under the award; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD21513EE3FD54672BA482EB24B18B2A3"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the results of an external evaluation, if the Secretary determines applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H61F2463AD2FE46288EE3D379E9BC667A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header> <paragraph id="H24F4EDF4729D4A16B9AEDC84216F8D86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall create and implement procedures—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1795620F8DD64E55B6A32D3AC99C67B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to assess whether a covered individual or entity has a potential conflict of interest; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACFAB1AC2CC44C209FD5D38CE25ED421"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to require the disclosure and mitigation of any such conflict of interest to ensure the integrity of the related program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29F54AF31FB348DCA826C73854843DBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation by the comptroller general</header> 
<subparagraph id="H303D08924CF34AC4B3AE8B11FFD2C8CD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the creation of the procedures described in paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate on the adequacy of such procedures to identify, disclose, and manage conflicts of interest.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28FC215F46E140F586BD75B1F21D8B7A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Beginning not less than 6 months after the report described in subparagraph (A) is filed, the Comptroller General shall evaluate the Department’s implementation of the procedures described in paragraph (1) and report to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate every 6 months to ensure that the Department has adequately implemented such procedures. The Comptroller General shall include in the reports any recommendations for modifications to such procedures that the Comptroller General determines are appropriate to properly identify, disclose, and manage conflicts of interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4B84B892AAE4963928364BCEA7B692D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HE9C1B45D4726429C96FD967618B9084B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered individual or entity</quote> means—</text> 
<clause id="H5C01FAB5B2174FAA949DC8D48C0C3CCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an officer or professional employee of the Department of Education;</text></clause> <clause id="H091D86D9944E4D6FA54FFC647519A89E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a contractor or subcontractor of the Department, or an individual hired by the contracted entity;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H04DA042A10574DA7A074A2C533BBEDEC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a member of a peer review panel described in section 4(c); or</text></clause> <clause id="HC04CC8490D7449E0A34825F80E407D85"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a consultant or advisor to the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8384CC78B6014BD8A4E09CD644D23190"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>conflict of interest</quote> means a financial interest or other self-interest that a reasonable person would expect to lead to an undue bias, or the appearance of such bias, towards a particular product or service purchased with, guaranteed or insured by, or under consideration for purchase with, or to be guaranteed or insured by, funds administered by the Department of Education or a contracted entity of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H115511EF1F5E47AFB7F32E9EDE54D566"><enum>12.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> <subsection id="HFE5A03C28C7F4E2F8A6F4B37F05FE037"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Student eligibility</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit students eligible for assistance under title I or III of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>, 6801 et seq.) or students eligible for assistance under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>) from receiving literacy instruction and intervention under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H07824D961C8B46F283C1792412847068"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Idea evaluation</header><text>The assessments required under this Act shall not be construed to constitute an evaluation required under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H80E4FC8BB3354527AA391AC151E9229F"><enum>13.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H644A2A95E20A4D859D0C7A89ABCB5B16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the terms used in this Act have the meanings given such terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H907DDA7CEA2C4F0B85D1312D07C7C2D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H2AC505270C2C4AC5BB9E0717BC8BB4A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child with a disability</header><text>The term <term>child with a disability</term> has the same meaning given the term in section 602(3) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401(3)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC94932BA28904B98A56BE42FC594611C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Classroom-based instructional assessment</header><text>The term <term>classroom-based instructional assessment</term> means an assessment for children in third grade or younger that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC7161110F2494413811164C49C407A05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is valid and reliable for the age and population of children served in the program, and is used to evaluate children’s developmental progress and learning, including systematic observations by teachers of children performing tasks, including academic and literary tasks, that are part of their daily classroom experience; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59CC0E29CA574B23BD62639935F23FCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is used to improve classroom instruction.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5828A34D9B049A686EA1F3D9570B9B1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Diagnostic assessment</header><text>The term <term>diagnostic assessment</term> means an assessment that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF6CD9229C9E24B73A1B4BCEECADE6506"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is developmentally, linguistically, and culturally appropriate;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7830FF372E74FA695668055A98B8F2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is valid, reliable, and based on scientifically valid research on language, literacy, and English language acquisition;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0C93263DAEF440496EB5C6B4F1FE8E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is used for the purposes of—</text> <clause id="H77D90CAE85754715B55192A3D3093821"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifying a student’s specific areas of strengths and weaknesses in oral language and literacy;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H984195556D0A4A6F862FE1CBC4B349E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determining any difficulties that the student may have in language and literacy and the potential cause of such difficulties; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HCE241687072549A28423B4DE3CAEF9E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>helping to determine possible literacy intervention strategies and related special needs of the student; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C18A5D5C46D4DCB9A9EEB1CF9483754"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of young children, is conducted after a screening assessment that identifies potential risks for delayed development or later academic difficulties.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19C838FACAF949D8AD1AA7B4C5EBEC13"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4D0A49A7C5F14CB49D915A6CDF68956E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>when used with respect to children from birth through kindergarten entry—</text> <clause id="HAE1668BCD55146078677DD8DB5E32BF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one or more local educational agencies providing early learning programs, or one or more public or private early learning programs, serving children from birth through kindergarten entry, such as a Head Start agency, an Early Head Start program, a child care program, a State-funded pre-kindergarten program, a public library program, or a family literacy program that has a demonstrated record of providing effective literacy instruction for the age group such agency or program is proposing to serve under section 7; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H5EAB96D7CC214BD2904DC25724DAF93B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one or more local educational agencies providing early learning programs, or one or more public or private early learning programs, serving children from birth through kindergarten entry, such as a Head Start agency, an Early Head Start program, a child care program, a State-funded pre-kindergarten program, a public library program, or a family literacy program in partnership with one or more public or private nonprofit organizations or agencies that have a demonstrated record of effectiveness—</text> <subclause id="HFFC8E206A9634D89A58AA81A1DF1981F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in improving the early literacy development of children from birth through kindergarten entry; and</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HDAA56F36F4694013B1B1B4386397D05A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in providing professional development aligned with the activities described in section 7(e)(1); and</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5C2FDA4C1E94A6F92DD4B7DDD604C93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>when used with respect to students in kindergarten through grade 12, a local educational agency or consortium of local educational agencies that—</text> 
<clause id="H4AB1B5DA6920489B9050D38D69377439"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is among the local educational agencies in the State with the highest numbers or percentages of students reading and writing below grade level, based on the most current State data, where available; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H899E3136909A47A5B2C8111E5836C4AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has the highest numbers or percentages of children who are counted under section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>), in comparison to other local educational agencies in the State.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FA330EE655E4D8DAAC1A78DE5187B9A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>English language acquisition</header> 
<subparagraph id="H13B4013831834986BD3FA64D5AABC5D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>English language acquisition</term> means the process by which a non-native English speaker acquires proficiency in speaking, listening, reading, and writing the English language.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF39418E8B48A4277B31C1C38FBBBA482"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion for english language learners in school</header><text>For an English language learner in school, such term includes not only the social language proficiency needed to participate in the school environment, but also the academic language proficiency needed to acquire literacy and academic content and demonstrate the student’s learning.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54F9FAAB51BC4BD0A44D25C80280F7FF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>English language learner</header><text>The term <term>English language learner</term> means an individual who is limited English proficient, as defined in section 9101(25) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801(25)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H248F5E94260F4B1C82AD480D787ECFDD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Essential components of early literacy instruction</header><text>The term <term>essential components of early literacy instruction</term> means providing, for children prior to the age of kindergarten entry, interactive experiences in a print- and literacy-rich environment that promote the development of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5F90B2C6BCE34E23B37B21990A15CF7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oral language, including vocabulary, grammar, and syntax;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73AE0A34FE7B4DD9928E16E1D1A29EC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>motivational aspects of early literacy, including enjoyment of reading and books;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1B6977D17314603A17BCF8FFBD167C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>book-reading behaviors, including book handling and orientation;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68D54545423B424F8C045526DB89C7D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recognition and understanding of pictures and story concepts;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23C07CDCF721478EB4272FB0E4ABE556"><enum>(E)</enum><text>concepts about print;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H245436EAC7874CDCB179253DFE6BD90B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>alphabet knowledge;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DF232592ECC4A7C931186617C954651"><enum>(G)</enum><text>phonological awareness, including the awareness of rhymes, sounds, and syllables;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H368A4616E09545D6BA7B69327406153D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>emergent writing skills, including use of writing materials; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19250C950089438597C7A77D4A834B5B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>integration of print concepts into play.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89559736F7124E22827958F29D05DFF6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Essential components of reading and writing instruction</header><text>The term <term>essential components of reading and writing instruction</term> means, for students in kindergarten through grade 12, developmentally appropriate, explicit, and systematic instruction that provides students the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7E5A21960E92414AB1238892EEE519FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to students in kindergarten through grade 12—</text> <clause id="H109CF66C99BE4B6C87E9858DCFB6D186"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high-quality professional development for teachers, instructional staff, and principals;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H33A46E57AEC84AA8B88DF2592E986B53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>diverse texts at the appropriate reading and interest level of students;</text> </clause> <clause id="H1942F162FB994B05B9B0B6D1893741B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>differentiated instructional approaches;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HB9A596DDB8F044B5BA565B9DCCA06332"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>instruction and supports to increase students’ motivation to read, including self-directed learning;</text> </clause> <clause id="H446273F2D315411F86487B4E436B95DF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>as appropriate, systematic and intensive one-to-one and small group instruction, including extended time for intense intervention for students reading significantly below grade level, which can be provided both inside and outside the classroom as well as during and outside regular school hours;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H5B039E32CED645FCBA0887815CB7CC82"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>opportunities to write individually and collaboratively;</text> </clause> <clause id="H4B69674A3B484CE1BE10FF304EB3572A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>instruction in uses of print materials, multimedia, and technological resources for research and for generating and presenting content and ideas; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HC037B83567704813B26170ADDA206B59"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>use of screening, diagnostic, formative, and summative assessments.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H941FC31639C44F53B95032575F4750BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to students in grades kindergarten through grade 3—</text> 
<clause id="HCB8B4973CFB14E0285A0E813A3BEDB61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>strategic and explicit instruction using phonological awareness, phonic decoding, vocabulary, language structure, reading fluency and reading comprehension;</text> </clause> <clause id="H1F5E7E4C5A4C4D20A0AE992F0B60F334"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use of oral modeling techniques to build language skills; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H7292BD4489FF45F6AD784511FDF22797"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordinated involvement of families, caregivers, school leaders, and instructional staff.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE98BA5D31FB941B7A0F5505D52EE0EB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to students in grades 4 through 12—</text> 
<clause id="HD7D54B062B4E446A9CB59DEBF7450C70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>direct and explicit comprehension instruction;</text> </clause> <clause id="H16359C5C08944AEEA3B8DE350CE547B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>direct and explicit instruction that builds academic vocabulary;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H7A129FA43C24420CB15E81F60B465F36"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>multiple opportunities to write with clear purposes and critical reasoning appropriate to the topic and purpose and with specific instruction and feedback from teachers;</text> </clause> <clause id="HC41900A7EE6F4925B13D9CF1A0E2B59A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>text-based collaborative learning; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H61C71B4592E448A984EFC041B2CCF8D6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>coordinated involvement of school leaders and instructional staff that are interdisciplinary and interdepartmental and that analyze student work over time and plan literacy instruction.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC42BBC1F64B047D9B361C6BD624157BD"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Family literacy services</header><text>The term <term>family literacy services</term> means services provided to participants on a voluntary basis that are of sufficient intensity in terms of hours, and of sufficient duration, to make sustainable changes in a family, and that integrate all of the following activities:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H18862B2B76BC4930A5093C6BD7D69C79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Interactive literacy activities between parents and their children.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A2A1495A67E416DA662D37E691CF017"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Training for parents regarding how to be the primary teacher for their children and full partners in the education of their children.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E5E9AA7D4AE4583AB72E53B77C195AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Parent literacy training that leads to economic self-sufficiency.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9609E07350954D5F8E4FEE75EE2D37C8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An age-appropriate education to prepare children for success in school and life experiences.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46481B06FAE8480A98F05AF278DE997E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Formative assessment</header><text>The term <term>formative assessment</term> means assessment questions, tools, and processes that are—</text> <subparagraph id="H6720FD286EC045A1A9A316052B5D5D24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developmentally, linguistically, and culturally appropriate;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F094997B6744F4DB9B04D0C2B8070A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>embedded in instruction; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B979E750B0B4A86AED4EB86AFDBD9CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>used by teachers and students to provide timely feedback for purposes of adjusting instruction to improve learning.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H440D1A10773446B6B8E27916132D577B"><enum>(11)</enum><header>High-quality professional development</header><text>The term <term>high-quality professional development</term> means professional development that—</text> <subparagraph id="H347F946135A44F778D4DFE58CE28BBDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is job-embedded, ongoing, and based on scientifically valid research;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE9123F93DD14C7D96A131AC83CE070C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is sustained, intensive, and classroom focused, if such workshop or conference is part of a professional development plan for the attendee;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADE7494387C244168BA3D83D59C021DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is designed to increase the knowledge and expertise of instructional staff in implementing the essential components of early literacy instruction and the essential components of reading and writing instruction, as appropriate;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E42075020B44255AA3E231336BA580B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>includes and supports teachers and early learning providers in administering age- and developmentally appropriate assessments; and analyzing the results of these student assessments when implementing the essential components of early literacy instruction and the essential components of reading and writing instruction for the purposes of planning, monitoring, adapting, and improving classroom instruction or teaching strategies to improve student learning, as appropriate;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H321F40979C624C869AA1F646A292F7F4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>for kindergarten through 12th grade, supports the integration of literacy instruction in core academic subjects and, to the extent practicable, other subjects taught at school, such as career and technical education;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65E1ADF6979F4878BC6BD19F0A9DA828"><enum>(F)</enum><text>includes information on one-to-one, small group, and classroom-based instructional materials and approaches based on scientifically valid research on literacy;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1BC640203F9740A4AFE1FC7092A68874"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provides ongoing instructional literacy coaching—</text> 
<clause id="H96D2593907A54B92BF3B42DD28977BB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to ensure high-quality implementation of effective practices of literacy instruction that is content centered, integrated across the curricula, collaborative, and school, setting, and classroom embedded; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H44FB2DB9FD2049638E68C9CBAF58EA63"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that uses student data to improve instruction;</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H01AAEC9E6B6C4A18B68312E03E3D0128"><enum>(H)</enum><text>includes and supports teachers in setting high reading and writing achievement goals for all students and provides the teachers with the instructional tools and skills, including strategies consistent with the principles of universal design for learning, to help students reach such goals; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H478E27685FBB47C289EDB7D1DC323E6F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is differentiated for educators working with children from birth through kindergarten entry, students in kindergarten through grade 5, and students in grades 6 through 12, and, as appropriate, by student grade or student need.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H440A7FED1B8944789FBFCF7AC67A4A80"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Instructional staff</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA178835E626D4EBF99D9E8E12AEEA825"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>instructional staff</term> means individuals who have responsibility for teaching students to read and write, or in the case of children from birth to kindergarten entry, teaching early literacy skills and language development.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9821FFE532244FFA35D0C830DEC2CC0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Such term includes principals, teachers, early learning providers, supervisors of instruction, pupil services personnel, librarians, library school media specialists, teachers of academic subjects other than reading or writing, other school leaders, literacy coaches, and other individuals who have responsibility for assisting children to learn to read and write.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B38256E25DA4F0BB371EA61725C4968"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Literacy coach</header><text>The term <term>literacy coach</term> means a professional—</text> <subparagraph id="HC3033F2771ED4A34969D19417E5458C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who—</text> 
<clause id="H0305AB3BF7704A1BA034EE3874CEEC78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has previous teaching experience and—</text> <subclause id="HE05F014EB12544F9A5C791E739D7A723"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for the purpose of literacy coaches working with early learning programs, has expertise in early childhood development and early literacy; and</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HF28E913119284E61B2F86E97F4824BBC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for the purpose of literacy coaches working with kindergarten through grade 12—</text> <item id="H971FFA0A96AC409A876DA48827DCEDFE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a master’s degree with a concentration in reading and writing education; or</text> </item> 
<item id="H8D833E81546848C486C1621BB1B520B0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>has demonstrated proficiency in teaching reading or writing in a core academic subject; and</text> </item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HABE5D7A00FFF45EF8CC59C90802E2C37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is able to demonstrate the ability to help early learning providers or teachers—</text> 
<subclause id="H5BFE45E88147499EB535BE1DEAD673E3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>use evidence-based research on how children and students become successful readers, writers, and communicators;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HA38E5A63463949E3A821151638638229"><enum>(II)</enum><text>use multiple forms of assessment to guide instructional decisionmaking;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H63B71D2A5D8A4C29A2AD6FA6C204632D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for the purpose of literacy coaches working with—</text> <item id="HF31158A4C01A4213A5845D94392A1B9D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>early learning programs, support and coordinate the language and literacy curricula and activities with the overall early childhood education program; and</text> </item> 
<item id="H07602168B4F64321AA5378607A010749"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>teachers in kindergarten through grade 12, improve student writing and reading in and across content areas such as mathematics, science, social studies, and language arts;</text> </item></subclause> <subclause id="HA58E3F3549114163A6CFEAC953F4F947"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>develop and implement differentiated instruction and teaching approaches to serve the needs of diverse learners, including English language learners and children with disabilities;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H6B8D6D4DA0A045FE996BF2A943B190E5"><enum>(V)</enum><text>use the principles of universal design for learning in instructional strategies and in selecting materials and tools to serve the diverse needs of all learners, including English language learners and children with disabilities;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HADE0055E7A97433CB450C129D367870E"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>employ best practices in engaging instructional staff to change school cultures to better encourage and support literacy development and achievement;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HF64E54FFE55B4B15B45756A8F5B808DF"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>use data to improve instruction; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H5D43EBA902DC49A6AF40851E77909319"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>for the purpose of literacy coaches working with—</text> 
<item id="HBF2F12829E824AA488C1A8A11F53F3B2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>early learning programs, set developmentally appropriate early literacy goals and select and acquire instructional tools and skills to help children reach such goals; and</text> </item> <item id="H182C345E43EE4598BF0AC686729B58B2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>kindergarten through grade 12, set high reading and writing achievement goals for all students and select and acquire instructional tools and skills to help students reach such goals; and</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H933B4798D3DD4F7090E9AB761D9381CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whose role with early learning providers, teachers and school personnel is—</text> <clause id="H4EC993EB0555443B9EC6E8E4ADE6CB08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to provide high-quality professional development opportunities in literacy and language development for early learning providers, teachers and school personnel, including in the case of early learning providers, helping staff in planning and implementation of ongoing professional development;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HB090CB6B03564FE8A6015601AC1D4F7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to work cooperatively and collaboratively with principals, teachers, early learning providers and other professionals in planning programs to help, as appropriate—</text> <subclause id="H1AE4564D39584E4793E659CB0968D804"><enum>(I)</enum><text>early learning providers identify children’s early literacy needs so that such providers can meet the early literacy needs of children at risk for delayed development and later academic difficulties; and</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H592BC6F9B8434E9897E4EBB98ED71CD6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>teachers identify student literacy needs and teach literacy across the content areas so that the teachers can meet the needs of students reading and writing below grade level; and</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="HBCA6B68410EF4480B1901F30C91B8F12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to work cooperatively and collaboratively with other professionals in planning programs to help early learning providers and teachers teach literacy across content areas so that the early learning providers and teachers can meet the needs of diverse learners, including children with disabilities, English language learners, and students who are reading at grade level.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H364E3751ABBD4E06AFC8F98954644F0D"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H35B627CE0B9C4EC0B11A75C64DAED8A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given to that term in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC99D3D3CD43442CDA3B1EA789D1F014B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any public charter school that constitutes a local educational agency under State law.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95311FEB9B87439EAABE4EC2323BD675"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Multitier system of supports</header><text>The term <term>multitier system of supports</term> means a comprehensive system of differentiated supports that includes evidence-based instruction, universal screening, progress monitoring, formative assessment, and evidence-based interventions matched to student needs, and educational decisionmaking using student outcome data.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA738B564A33A4F5EBCBB1052A2301BD0"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Reading</header><text>The term <term>reading</term> means a complex system of deriving meaning from print that requires all of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB44458CFE78F4BB49DDE990456F91B6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The skills and knowledge to understand how phonemes, or speech sounds, are connected to print.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB28B2BE57E76467D8140A650D33C9EB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The ability to decode unfamiliar words.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06AF11457C254BDEA35C9E6BEA2EBC0C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The ability to read fluently.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E9102DE8BA948ED91040979F9740B32"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Sufficient background information and vocabulary to foster reading comprehension.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DD8C82007124F9CBEEB16CFE3058F32"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The development of appropriate active strategies to construct meaning from print.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4ABB35D2F0E6493D99649DE60579DE0C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The development and maintenance of a motivation to read.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB72E7A6048E549E08E72E57073E433C4"><enum>(17)</enum><header>School leader</header><text>The term <term>school leader</term> means an individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE47425156E454A9482B3E441B1E29ECD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an employee or officer of a school; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC60100A9CE6E4C7A964D6854C10B7F30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is responsible for—</text> 
<clause id="HB9C2A2650C154226845D92EEAD0D488A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the school’s performance; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H06FDB5B86E4E4BEE8F4755776827EB1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the daily instructional and managerial operations of the school.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1B6FF10843C4554915F23E8CBE0B71B"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Scientifically valid research</header><text>The term <term>scientifically valid research</term> has the meaning given the term in section 200 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1021">20 U.S.C. 1021</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE96577F8CE77456C96F549ED0D1DF1F6"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Screening assessment</header><text>The term <term>screening assessment</term> means an assessment that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE5D34C7F59EE4A14A25C1D3B74C121B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is developmentally, linguistically, and culturally appropriate;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBDAE05B0C0A245B8B4324B7645634585"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is valid, reliable, and based on scientifically valid research on literacy and English language acquisition; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75A672B515FA4A6E926CD942A557FAE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a procedure designed as a first step in identifying children who may be at high risk for delayed development or later academic difficulties and in need of further diagnosis of the children’s need for special services or additional literacy instruction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6D548EFD7FC45218A2BAB8531010CAA"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Specialized instructional support personnel</header><text>The term <quote>Specialized Instructional Support Personnel (SISP)</quote>means school counselors, school social workers, school psychologists, and other qualified professional personnel involved in providing assessment, diagnosis, counseling, educational, therapeutic, and other necessary services (including related services as that term is defined in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act) as part of a comprehensive program to meet student needs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6644A4BDB5A84F419B8DA546C22B60DA"><enum>(21)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H28349F232D3D4F4D934EFFEF8F5A8651"><enum>(22)</enum><header>State literacy leadership team</header> <subparagraph id="H69D3D9308F344576A263683C7407C9A2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header> <clause id="HEA90A1CDCC2E4FC8A1DDC85259E55498"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Appointment; responsibility; composition</header><text>The term <term>State literacy leadership team</term> means a team that—</text> 
<subclause id="H980A3FAAB2FF484F85124A9C61E7A5DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is appointed and coordinated by the State educational agency, except that individuals described in subclauses (I)(aa), (I)(hh), and (II)(gg) of clause (ii) shall be appointed by the State agency that oversees child care programs; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H36CEA5EC39C1471EA4EAAA868EE7D6A0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is composed of not less than 13 individuals and includes the individuals described in clause (ii).</text> </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H9E73F59DDA6942D6B0B9976E71CFA31C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Individuals included</header><text>A State literacy team—</text> <subclause id="H9D9545F06CE34B8DBBA4E8D24F663093"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall include—</text> 
<item id="H52E58AC1B437477ABF73882C8FEE8046"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an individual who has literacy expertise with respect to children from birth through kindergarten entry;</text> </item> <item id="H168C50E2BC8146E69248D96FE6DC9D87"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>an individual who has literacy expertise with respect to students in kindergarten through grade 5;</text> </item> 
<item id="H096895098D784E95B369A5EBC8A8B5B4"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>an individual who has literacy expertise with respect to students in grades 6 through 12;</text> </item> <item id="H9E9DFF88513C47AB97E94708B6E8ACAA"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>a school principal;</text> </item> 
<item id="HF9D979CD2FC74E76A0BDD9EE071DCFE9"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>a special education teacher with literacy expertise;</text> </item> <item id="HA71D1D96D1C347D8A017B4B8FD14B46C"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>a representative from the family literacy community;</text> </item> 
<item id="H4D28097348194DF995359089EF72BEC5"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>a teacher or administrator with expertise in teaching English language learners;</text> </item> <item id="HE8CAABFAE2A7468DB94B14F4E084C0B6"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>a representative from the State’s agency that oversees child care programs;</text> </item> 
<item id="H78784DE3E50B4324AAD94FF9AA3230AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a representative from the State educational agency who oversees literacy initiatives; and</text> </item> <item id="HE556C8AF32764768B62BF349CB48C458"><enum>(jj)</enum><text>a representative from higher education who is actively involved in research, development, and teacher preparation in literacy instruction and intervention based on scientifically valid research; and</text> </item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC169B366C7354A03BE967C51C7B39CD2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may include—</text> <item id="HB9C45D081C8B4A39A350B0E48DBB0028"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a literacy specialist serving in a school district within the State;</text> </item> 
<item id="H39F9BFE1271D40C1AFD16247D860326A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a literacy coach;</text> </item> <item id="H0FCFCA08C0694EFEAF1E980CDA6292BD"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a library media specialist;</text> </item> 
<item id="H944BD2ED9F594DC7A0FB3672F9E574B5"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>specialized instructional support personnel;</text> </item> <item id="HF819D7A341C449EA8290D6495AB0D053"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>a teacher of a core academic subject;</text> </item> 
<item id="H4132D535C12240C1B125E1DABCA99FE9"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>a special education administrator;</text> </item> <item id="H1C459271EA0341199A609EF64AD2FEC1"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>an early learning provider;</text> </item> 
<item id="HE167C2D447384145866F8CCF4392951E"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>a college or university professor;</text> </item> <item id="H02653841B3734E15BB99D1CA8A30E95A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a parent;</text> </item> 
<item id="HB49AD05A78704E9A9E798383F0EFA4A3"><enum>(jj)</enum><text>a business leader;</text> </item> <item id="HE5FB48348BD54E94A9CF5B42B3C3274D"><enum>(kk)</enum><text>a representative from the Governor’s office;</text> </item> 
<item id="HFB55685809A149C7AB9E493BCA4091F5"><enum>(ll)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a representative from the State board of education;</text> </item> <item id="H6D6AC7B7D20F474694B668354D271D29"><enum>(mm)</enum><text>a representative from the State legislature;</text> </item> 
<item id="HA0F39A87B42E424E9119524D8356891A"><enum>(nn)</enum><text>a nonprofit and community-based organization providing literacy instruction and support; and</text> </item> <item id="HC12732EEC83648338AC9502D347DDCE1"><enum>(oo)</enum><text>a representative from a school district superintendent's office.</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB66D1D27B39A421C96C27DB3C8232257"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of a preexisting partnership</header><text>If, before the date of the enactment of this Act, a State educational agency established a consortium, partnership, or any other similar body that was considered a literacy partnership for purposes of subpart 1 or 2 of part B of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6361">20 U.S.C. 6361 et seq.</external-xref>, 6371 et seq.) and that includes the individuals required under subparagraph (A)(ii)(I), such consortium, partnership, or body may be considered a State literacy leadership team for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FCDD12DA7F04157AEC2FB39B5F78852"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Student with a disability</header><text>The term <term>student with a disability</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>child with a disability</quote> in section 602(3) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401(3)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4CD18763A6E4A0EAC29580EB3470672"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Summative assessment</header><text>The term <term>summative assessment</term> means an assessment that—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E8B4100EC6E41DBB9748612E2629D48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is developmentally, linguistically, and culturally appropriate;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17CE26E9A96E465DA556DEFA28BBFC3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is valid, reliable, and based on scientifically valid research on literacy and English language acquisition; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6AC4FB94966C47299F364BB4B72CE52F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>measures how young children have progressed over time relative to developmental norms and what students have learned over time.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE951DEC024244046B705878ED51D5E98"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Universal design for learning</header><text>The term <term>universal design for learning</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H747717E715274689BB74CA1C7312E2BF"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Writing</header><text>The term <term>writing</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFD423E45830945CC97724FA86E3AA71B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ability to compose meaning and print to communicate ideas, including the use of vocabulary, tone, and genre to fit purpose, audience and occasion;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19F6476467C141A0B33A8B6424A2B65B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of conventions such as spelling and punctuation; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F1A948C310844968FB290F18BF56893"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ability to revise in order to improve clarity of ideas, coherence, logical development, and precision of language use.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC7630AC6C74141BC89ADF90418DC3EAF"><enum>14.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAD898976843A417DAD3D4B610E9F51AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$500,000,000 for fiscal year 2016;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H848EFB0B2EE24686B7E952F1EADC5A00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$525,000,000 for fiscal year 2017;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE49D540E84C34E53831C40FA12C769E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$550,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45B7F2559CED4A9E99B9716DE9B5107D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$575,000,000 for fiscal year 2019; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC625C84871324043A6C052F615BFA3B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$600,000,000 for fiscal year 2020.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

