<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H313259B5C06D4C1883CC7DB41E49AB76" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 494 IH: Competitive Health Insurance Reform Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 494</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000456">Mr. Fleming</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To restore the application of the Federal antitrust laws to the business of health insurance to protect competition and consumers.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5ADC9FA2E75B4D8DA638ABD2EDE0F56C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF952D9E6F91B40F3AFFDA1520C9E6C0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Competitive Health Insurance Reform Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H041ECF72EA85422DB99BA20DD5E1DCE2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBC954B9A52A64D82A637E762D7CDDF20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Open, free, and fair competition has made the United States the strongest economy in the world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9BE3F6AB3F24064B62DE5B409DA30E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As a general proposition, Government should ensure that no industry obtains an unfair competitive advantage and that the playing field is equal. The Congress should not play favorites with certain industries or special interest groups by exempting one group from the general application of the law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A96DC2E10A74C9CB05AD0C4D8C8A574"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There is no factual basis supporting any further exemption of the health insurance industry from Federal antitrust and unfair competition laws.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD04035EB4684DCCA388119AAF3DCCCB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement of these laws is most appropriately done through the U.S. Department of Justice, and in the case of aggrieved individuals through private actions as set forth in the existing statutes.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H6E5625C901E14C638EFF34A126638A1E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to ensure that health insurance issuers are subject to the same antitrust and unfair trade practices laws that all businesses have had to comply with and to more effectively ensure that these issuers would be subject to Federal laws against price fixing, bid rigging, or market allocations to the detriment of competition and consumers. This Act remedies a special exemption provided by Congress in 1945 to respond to the United States Supreme Court decision entitled United States v. South-Eastern Underwriters Association, wherein the Court correctly held that the Federal Government could regulate insurance companies under the authority of the commerce clause in the Constitution. This Act would also retain enforcement of these laws with State and Federal law enforcement agencies and allow private causes of action by aggrieved consumers harmed by unfair trade practices.</text></section> <section id="H6708F8DC6F0B40E2A13EF426A8192624"><enum>4.</enum><header>Restoring the application of antitrust laws to health sector insurers</header> <subsection id="H8707294311604EF9A5974CFC68DA70CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to McCarran-Ferguson Act</header><text>Section 3 of the Act of March 9, 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1013">15 U.S.C. 1013</external-xref>), commonly known as the McCarran-Ferguson Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H0D7D039D95714EDA831A5B0B0DFF0D25" style="OLC"> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D6E236B7A3C47D2A2681DA447525855"><enum>(c)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAA52EB1E05FF4630B51F90B333DA6190"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nothing contained in this Act shall modify, impair, or supersede the operation of any of the antitrust laws with respect to the business of health insurance (including the business of dental insurance). For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <term>antitrust laws</term> has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act, except that such term includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96ABDC12CCE54AFB9B4A6D00603DB852" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>business of health insurance (including the business of dental insurance)</quote> does not include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H12F06DB4284846C6B56AB81299E0D8BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the business of life insurance (including annuities); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3838105D3AD24C8D874D2CA31EDDB6DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the business of property or casualty insurance, including but not limited to, any insurance or benefits defined as ‘excepted benefits’ under paragraph (1), subparagraphs (B) or (C) of paragraph (2), or paragraph (3) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9832">section 9832(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9832">26 U.S.C. 9832(c)</external-xref>) whether offered separately or in combination with insurance or benefits described in paragraph (2)(A) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCBC4C0F4D8E249B3BCA28063DFBCF0C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Related Provision</header><text>For purposes of section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent such section applies to unfair methods of competition, section 3(c) of the McCarran-Ferguson Act shall apply with respect to the business of health insurance without regard to whether such business is carried on for profit, notwithstanding the definition of <quote>Corporation</quote> contained in section 4 of the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

