<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB9ADF5AF716D4E0EB4E6243633CDECBA" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2338 IH: To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for the development and use of patient experience data to enhance the structured risk-benefit assessment framework, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2338</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150514">May 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for the development and use of patient experience data to enhance the structured risk-benefit assessment framework, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6E927E8FDFD64FC19F4815F8615C35C8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9E1ED69BC01E43A9971CD06D4EC8F53E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Development and use of patient experience data to enhance structured risk-Benefit assessment framework</header> 
<subsection id="H37DC4EF87E7F495B8013F5B9F1F0FCAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBD6DB206017D4CB88A74FDEA11908AD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>The Secretary shall implement</quote> and all that follows through <quote>premarket approval of a drug.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H860A5FBB744746219788E71BE8C92A0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8948574816F4471BA2100918A162FDA4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H3DF13495F4594B7CBC2EAF2E6C957307"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Structured risk-Benefit assessment framework</header> <paragraph id="H381025D3D8BB499C8DF37C1670AC265B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement a structured risk-benefit assessment framework in the new drug approval process—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H50D0E0F5A89C4B02A6ED41BB8B272318"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to facilitate the balanced consideration of benefits and risks; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2FA0C788FFE446092B2AB0BC92D3FE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop and implement a consistent and systematic approach to the discussion of, regulatory decisionmaking with respect to, and the communication of, the benefits and risks of new drugs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AEA4EA5BFC84F3BB4EE718723585261"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall alter the criteria for evaluating an application for premarket approval of a drug.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H39B6925A807F4FB09754BEC31EC4C63E"><enum>(y)</enum><header>Development and use of patient experience data To enhance structured risk-Benefit assessment framework</header> <paragraph id="H48EA35BFF77E44B099B0DD80D23FEC23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish and implement processes under which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2C54838CBF5C4936887748A2B70E0CFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity seeking to develop patient experience data may submit to the Secretary—</text> <clause id="H678B1D14D77246E09CD1E4E058F2ECD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>initial research concepts for feedback from the Secretary; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC5F085D5533042F0BE3283F14A01CB57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to patient experience data collected by the entity, draft guidance documents, completed data, and summaries and analyses of such data;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FF4288C4A804C8593B52DCEA7590262"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary may request such an entity to submit such documents, data, and summaries and analyses; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0FA599CEC99438C81B741CB8289D369"><enum>(C)</enum><text>patient experience data may be developed and used to enhance the structured risk-benefit assessment framework under subsection (x).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8CDE1E5A7224CC683B1F786BD98B3F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Patient experience data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>patient experience data</term> means data collected by patients, parents, caregivers, patient advocacy organizations, disease research foundations, medical researchers, research sponsors or other parties determined appropriate by the Secretary that is intended to facilitate or enhance the Secretary’s risk-benefit assessments, including information about the impact of a disease or a therapy on patients’ lives.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD63BB9E773C3430B8AFBA49C7F95CF60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header> 
<paragraph id="HD97E192AB171437794A283430434A853"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall publish guidance on the implementation of subsection (y) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a). Such guidance shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H8E651E5B6C37412B82B7BDBF4B2DB76E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to draft guidance documents, data, or summaries and analyses submitted to the Secretary under paragraph (1)(A) of such subsection, guidance—</text> 
<clause id="HD2A6586EACF1417EAEE087936736AB2C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifying the timelines for the review of such documents, data, or summaries and analyses by the Secretary; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8C865E8A04F34761995804950CA6657A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on how the Secretary will use such documents, data, or summaries and analyses to update any guidance documents published under this subsection or publish new guidance;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F7E789BE8B94D6E8759AA79E785D4ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the collection and analysis of patient experience data (as defined in paragraph (2) of such subsection (y)), guidance on—</text> <clause id="HA71F2911BDFD4815A468A2013B2176F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methodological considerations for the collection of patient experience data, which may include structured approaches to gathering information on—</text> 
<subclause id="H19905F3C384D45E9935AF4285EB5B93A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the experience of a patient living with a particular disease;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H474F2779AEBC49F79C3025BDC64084F5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the burden of living with or managing the disease;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H80A0E484B6D246AC89E2A12BC10BFA18"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the impact of the disease on daily life and long-term functioning; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCE13C1E5F26A46EFAC6D32ABCB589FC1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the effect of current therapeutic options on different aspects of the disease; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFA75C61B22E24E0AAA5749CA9790E249"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the establishment and maintenance of registries designed to increase understanding of the natural history of a disease;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87DC10463DF54A84BF1E12344AACB074"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methodological approaches that may be used to assess patients’ beliefs with respect to the benefits and risks in the management of the patient’s disease; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H90E5983749D74630812DD643D15C3B92"><enum>(D)</enum><text>methodologies, standards, and potential experimental designs for patient-reported outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BCEA2EA9F7548CD8A007EB143DB2BCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue draft guidance on the implementation of subsection (y) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a). The Secretary shall issue final guidance on the implementation of such subsection not later than one year after the date on which the comment period for the draft guidance closes. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF92274D7BE214F119EA83B745C587AE3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Workshops</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3293E0E2139144CFB2765EC23DE6F78B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and once every 6 months during the following 12-month period, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall convene a workshop to obtain input regarding methodologies for developing the guidance under paragraph (1), including the collection of patient experience data. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE60FBAA6CCDA4E54932208DC61C4D51C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Attendees</header><text>A workshop convened under this paragraph shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H86ACC6EFBE524C378D5E419A7258668F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>patients;</text></clause> <clause id="H50773DA4F12B42AB8AAA71706657950D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives from patient advocacy organizations, biopharmaceutical companies, and disease research foundations;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB0E99603FB6341F6BB4AA4A89D00E212"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>representatives of the reviewing divisions of the Food and Drug Administration; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0B3F01252DDC40018177D27D17AD19AD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>methodological experts with significant expertise in patient experience data.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30203BE8CC2B40B9A9519DA994DB10A8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the draft guidance is published under this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall convene a public meeting to solicit input on the guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

