<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5E5F83DED20C44CB898EEAC15F77EFF3" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 340 IH: REDUCE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 340</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150114">January 14, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for a limitation on the number of civilian employees at the Department of Defense, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HAC9A9C569A534E2FB7F718C1267DCBD6" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8306B1B829441F18324676EB99F9963" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rebalance for an Effective Defense Uniformed and Civilian Employees Act</short-title></quote> or <quote>REDUCE Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H24FA8E8F7C0A44D7A5A7B3DFE2E4F781" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on number of employees in the Department of Defense</header> <subsection id="HF3921AD521C24F76A068926C9F289663"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on FTEs</header> <paragraph id="HF52AD7AA44034263B1DA73EF781DBDC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 129 of title 10, United States Code, and consistent with the requirements of subsection (d), in each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, the number of full-time equivalent civilian positions in the Department of Defense may not be greater than 85 percent of the number of such positions at the Department as of September 30, 2016, as determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1081A3B465846DAAF38B899577DDE5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>SES</header><text>Of the positions permitted pursuant to paragraph (1) for fiscal years 2022 through 2026 at the Department of Defense, not more than 1,000 may be career appointee (as defined in section 3132(a)(4) of title 5, United States Code) positions within the Senior Executive Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83512480933F4CEEBEF4BF35943915E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Voluntary reductions</header><text>To achieve the reductions in personnel required by subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may exercise the authority provided for—</text>
 <paragraph id="H161271FB1D274D51B63CF4A1F0C789F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">voluntary separation incentive payments (subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA56943D975B34938938E8D8932365B41"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">voluntary early retirement payments (sections 8336(d)(2)(D) and 8414(b)(1)(B) of such title).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45E2D857665B4312BD72861F722F1FD1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Involuntary reductions</header> <paragraph id="HC37030ECE6814809A59BC8AA246E5A75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on October 1, 2016, if voluntary reductions are inadequate to achieve the limitations provided in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall separate employees using involuntary measures, including reductions in force.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DD11E3E1C5F412D85950102A3B04DB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>RIF application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule, or regulation, when applying retention factors with respect to any employee during any reduction in force under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall assign greater weight to the performance factor over the other factors if such employee has a summary rating level of <quote>fully successful</quote> or better.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A6F452DE22941B0AF6F9A52DE9C661F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Adjustment of limit</header>
 <paragraph id="HAA1A53B80F6E443BB931FA082E73DB52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>As soon as practicable after the start of each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, the Secretary of Defense shall determine the difference (if any), expressed as a percentage, between the permanent active duty end strength minimum levels in effect under section 691(b) of title 10, United States Code, for the current fiscal year and the preceding fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H087F83E2023A4DD98E18808DF7D2510B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text>On the date that the determination is made under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall adjust the limitations provided under subsection (a) with respect to the number of total full-time equivalent positions and Senior Executive Service positions by a percentage equal to the percentage determined under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H198565BB18A64C05B9C10B9E3863B64F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Achievement of adjustment</header><text>After any adjustment under paragraph (2), in order to achieve the adjusted limitation for the applicable fiscal year, the Secretary (as the case may be)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H268E7E879B5D44FF952FC97D43E9C996"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may hire individuals to occupy full-time equivalent positions; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AC4537C3DE2498398526B99B7017583"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall separate employees occupying such positions using the involuntary procedures provided under subsection (c).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46FEA3A95FC04BBD9599073A722E9B2B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No adjustment may be made under this subsection that would result in the number of full-time equivalent positions and Senior Executive Service positions to be greater than the limitations on the number of such positions provided under subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H690E62AA07A3446AB2D65D2E7DCCD874"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H83D8AE09391F4A1A86869EBDFDCD8CC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary of Defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense—</text> <subparagraph id="H0920A7360D6D448484C5B889FDFC6A2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include a report in the Secretary’s annual budget request for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2026 on the progress and impact of the requirements of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4649ACA5AC147758A6543582715EC71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may, in addition to the report required under subparagraph (A), report to Congress on the impact of such requirements at any time throughout any of such fiscal years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1D21C22977B45138D57BF9FC242D883"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of General Services shall submit to Congress a report examining the progress and impact of the requirements of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


