<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1A11B95994304C0E8530C533FFCC0C1D" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3842 IH: Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3842</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151028">October 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve homeland security, including domestic preparedness and response to terrorism, by
			 reforming Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers to provide training to
			 first responders, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H40BB890D55D24E288EC296D9AAEAB467" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6700EB9A47F8491F89612B6BF0D9D2E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6BC9DBA6D2FC4081972711ACC3CEBD8B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers</header> <subsection id="H83BED40E05FA45DB9A0EC16E9B84CC68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Section 884 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/464">6 U.S.C. 464</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HAA9E8EE136F24A18B182774544624847" style="OLC">
					<section id="HE443E09A92FC449CBBFF1EF1E1719CA3"><enum>884.</enum><header>Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers</header>
 <subsection id="H0A28F0958A19468D929D3D9E2F085818"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain in the Department the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers (FLETC), headed by a Director, who shall report to the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1B2296AB126E49A3B3127A4E220396E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Position</header><text>The Director shall occupy a career-reserved position within the Senior Executive Service.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HAAFF6EDFA4114477857AF60AA973FA41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions of the director</header><text>The Director shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDA149D3473D4497091F359AC833B233B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop training goals and establish strategic and tactical organizational program plan and priorities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F20C0DA91FF4B879E14E7B68EBE97E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide direction and management for FLETC’s training facilities, programs, and support activities while ensuring that organizational program goals and priorities are executed in an effective and efficient manner;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF89AA2BC4174549BE87EF53C6ECBEA9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop homeland security and law enforcement training curricula, including curricula related to domestic preparedness and response to threats or acts of terrorism, for Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, international, and private sector law enforcement and security agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5481648A56CA4D1AAD35B928DE6B3847"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor progress toward strategic and tactical FLETC plans regarding training curricula, including curricula related to domestic preparedness and response to threats or acts of terrorism, and facilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4122C5A807A54C9F9169AE91F5EE9C90"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the timely dissemination of homeland security information as necessary to Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, and international law enforcement and security agencies and the private sector to achieve the training goals for such entities, in accordance with paragraph (1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0ABFDE570B4407E910F5ADF61666EF3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>coordinate and share information with the heads of relevant components and offices on digital learning and training resources, as appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AB00253994742EDB0EC387B9768F8EA"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the Secretary on matters relating to executive level policy and program administration of Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, international, and private sector law enforcement and security training activities, including training activities related to domestic preparedness and response to threats or acts of terrorism; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8A33CB861314A00B4C9DC374B22AE2B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>carry out such other functions as the Secretary determines are appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C227DB885F546F58B1320B5141FF50F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training responsibilities</header> <paragraph id="HC567EDFBABF64D1692F64DD62219F916"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director is authorized to provide training to employees of Federal agencies who are engaged, directly or indirectly, in homeland security operations or Federal law enforcement activities, including such operations or activities related to domestic preparedness and response to threats or acts of terrorism. In carrying out such training, the Director shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3BA984C12B424361BC0C2295B395A26A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate best practices of law enforcement training methods and curriculum content to maintain state-of-the-art expertise in adult learning methodology;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE785297BA1A34CBF80FC5016C2C79EBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide expertise and technical assistance, including on domestic preparedness and response to threats or acts of terrorism, to Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, international and private sector law enforcement and security agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4E74361131642799F7AF87C281A9616"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintain a performance evaluation process for students.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF904788DAB984277A34D818C44498822"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relationship with law enforcement agencies</header><text>The Director shall consult with relevant law enforcement and security agencies in the development and delivery of FLETC’s training programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2945E5DAD7BC437CAD2E47FE06C9C720"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training delivery locations</header><text>The training required under paragraph (1) may be conducted at FLETC facilities, at appropriate off-site locations, or by distributed learning.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H586E3FDAC07D4333875AD910C7BD8490"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Strategic partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may execute strategic partnerships with State and local law enforcement to provide such law enforcement with specific training, including maritime law enforcement training.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE762E594D3F4A8BBBD615BBDADE0918"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Detail of instructors to FLETC</header><text>Partner organizations that wish to participate in FLETC training programs shall assign non-reimbursable detailed instructors to FLETC for designated time periods to support all training programs at FLETC, as appropriate. The Director shall determine the number of detailed instructors that is proportional to the number of training hours requested by each partner organization scheduled by FLETC for each fiscal year. If a partner organization is unable to provide a proportional number of detailed instructors, such partner organization shall reimburse FLETC for the salary equivalent for such detailed instructors, as appropriate.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H588A52806DC54A46AF027B9F8ACEB37E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Partner organization expenses requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5CAECD0D6D1A438D8491965EA42173E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Partner organizations shall be responsible for the following expenses:</text> <clause id="HF81ED5722BF649C8B43E958D666BAB2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Salaries, travel expenses, lodging expenses, and miscellaneous per diem allowances of their personnel attending training courses at FLETC.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD3E071F33893432EBA3D2DFF9CEA8383"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Salaries and travel expenses of instructors and support personnel involved in conducting advanced training at FLETC for partner organization personnel and the cost of expendable supplies and special equipment for such training, unless such supplies and equipment are common to FLETC-conducted training and have been included in FLETC’s budget for the applicable fiscal year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1B34F9FD61B4993BFC562AB7BCC6FCE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess basic and advanced Federal training</header><text>All hours of advanced training and hours of basic training provided in excess of the training for which appropriations were made available shall be paid by the partner organizations and provided to FLETC on a reimbursable basis in accordance with section 4104 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5234D854D4C4E2ABA9460689C2B6263"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Provision of non-Federal training</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6B315AC18FD14A1899AF35B7B9E74E2F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director is authorized to charge and retain fees that would pay for its actual costs of the training for the following:</text>
 <clause id="H17F9F9E0769743329E5C2FAC3623BC02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement personnel.</text> </clause><clause id="H0A802DE400DC4858998FBBED84F7DB7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Foreign law enforcement officials, including provision of such training at the International Law Enforcement Academies wherever established.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2BB38705C2A9461AB38E7B0BB0C74E69"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Private sector security officers, participants in the Federal Flight Deck Officer program under section 44921 of title 49, United States Code, and other appropriate private sector individuals.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F49142C20714D4B91439E408869238C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Director may waive the requirement for reimbursement of any cost under this section and shall maintain records regarding the reasons for any requirements so waived.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9DEF05AB43884E36943B0DDC3E7687E8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>The Director is authorized to reimburse travel or other expenses for non-Federal personnel who attend activities related to training sponsored by FLETC, at travel and per diem rates established by the General Services Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32BE173BC54F47B9B12D790FC3C8ADF5"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Student support</header><text>In furtherance of its training mission, the Director is authorized to provide the following support to students:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6DA153C2B238492FA00BF2C2865F7825"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Athletic and related activities.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87E054269B664F9EBA679672BF887151"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Short-term medical services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E0E3E592A13448DBACC82AFD6C90E7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Chaplain services.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22D4BDE3F5C94261A4883B8F0FA287A8"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Authority to hire Federal annuitants</header> <subparagraph id="HD809F3A1EB94423F89840308969C03D1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director is authorized to appoint and maintain, as necessary, Federal annuitants who have expert knowledge and experience to meet the training responsibilities under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FA43659EB47450BA13C24BAE52FAA1D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No reduction in retirement pay</header><text>A Federal annuitant employed pursuant to this paragraph shall not be subject to any reduction in pay for annuity allocable to the period of actual employment under the provisions of section 8344 or 8468 of title 5, United States Code, or similar provision of any other retirement system for employees.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC2A1C894E664A758BB7D3B48E93CBE8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Re-employed annuitants</header><text>A Federal annuitant employed pursuant to this paragraph shall not be considered an employee for purposes of subchapter III of chapter 83 or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/84">chapter 84</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, or such other retirement system (referred to in subparagraph (B)) as may apply.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A2DE15224D4480980DD6C037789E2CA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Counting</header><text>Federal annuitants shall be counted on a full time equivalent basis.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47A2919A441347CA93BC57DF656F9ED5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No appointment under this paragraph may be made which would result in the displacement of any employee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H438AC8F2201547719DF5924AB0EB3443"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Travel for intermittent employees</header><text>The Director is authorized to reimburse intermittent Federal employees traveling from outside a commuting distance (to be predetermined by the Director) for travel expenses and to compensate such employees for time spent traveling from their homes to work sites.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B4757018A2949DB803627E4BD7F1CB0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>On-FLETC housing</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, individuals attending training at any FLETC facility shall, to the extent practicable and in accordance with FLETC policy, reside in on-FLETC or FLETC-provided housing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H04A16814AE9F4AA890B4BDD98190AC76"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional fiscal authorities</header><text>In order to further the goals and objectives of FLETC, the Director is authorized to—</text> <paragraph id="H82DFD340D9EC4DAA9049DD5DB3484E06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expend funds for public awareness and to enhance community support of law enforcement training, including the advertisement of available law enforcement training programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD683139F47FF4308960399AE72848051"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accept and use gifts of property, both real and personal, and to accept gifts of services, for purposes that promote the functions of the Director pursuant to subsection (c) and the training responsibilities of the Director under subsection (d);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD80C56DC177D479186F33522962F88BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>accept reimbursement from other Federal agencies for the construction or renovation of training and support facilities and the use of equipment and technology on government-owned property;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FA7BED76C304984BBB083C14A1BF4A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>obligate funds in anticipation of reimbursements from agencies receiving training at FLETC, except that total obligations at the end of a fiscal year may not exceed total budgetary resources available at the end of such fiscal year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CA09989A9C744B89FAE26E29D988BED"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with the purchasing authority provided under section 505 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/90">Public Law 108–90</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/453a">6 U.S.C. 453a</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H05ACC339BF944DC2812E507771CD9A8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase employee and student uniforms; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB26E525C9074B67B6E15E710C8B1456"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purchase and lease passenger motor vehicles, including vehicles for police-type use; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF65C1715F2B48CA8EA9A6716AFA24CD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide room and board for student interns.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DDDBA382D3D4D3AA54642D333CF2BD3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H44E8CB9294514E3ABDC9960C267070C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basic training</header><text>The term <term>basic training</term> means the entry-level training required to instill in new Federal law enforcement personnel fundamental knowledge of criminal laws, law enforcement and investigative techniques, laws and rules of evidence, rules of criminal procedure, constitutional rights, search and seizure, and related issues.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78A5AFB296004CD5BB0741A1CF954608"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Detailed instructors</header><text>The term <term>detailed instructors</term> means personnel who are assigned to the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers for a period of time to serve as instructors for the purpose of conducting basic and advanced training.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE464D427076A44CC9C174F1C04998A49"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H66E5354DB80044EA84D23A333C993377"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Distributed learning</header><text>The term <term>distributed learning</term> means education in which students take academic courses by accessing information and communicating with the instructor, from various locations, on an individual basis, over a computer network or via other technologies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10AAF8D8DCAA4283AFDA018E8D740F07"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D43032EE6404E7DA2631170D620E062"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H08944A7B7D2842A3B8AB3EE60D115968"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an Executive Department as defined in section 101 of title 5, United States Code;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4B1A5338D774527BEA5B7022A7EC884"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an independent establishment as defined in section 104 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB95CA765954813AFB5E45C62D465B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Government corporation as defined in section 9101 of title 31, United States Code;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2041B48A74F849B29FCE0EB138EBACFD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Government Publishing Office;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H777489C5F3914C028ADC9F63B21A67F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the United States Capitol Police;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73C09FE8DB35411BA3BCBF5CC4D16CC7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the United States Supreme Court Police; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75887925D9B3403691B23CF8AAEE416E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Government agencies with law enforcement related duties.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97ADEE7BA678425C884C2A6CD0C9581E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Law enforcement personnel</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement personnel</term> means an individual, including criminal investigators (commonly known as <quote>agents</quote>) and uniformed police (commonly known as <quote>officers</quote>), who has statutory authority to search, seize, make arrests, or to carry firearms.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD94882D1442443A190DFE3C82DE5607D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Local</header><text>The term <term>local</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H47CC5CFE832A452EAD133E9F8D9E6F92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of or pertaining to any county, parish, municipality, city, town, township, rural community, unincorporated town or village, local public authority, educational institution, special district, intrastate district, council of governments (regardless of whether the council of governments is incorporated as a nonprofit corporation under State law), regional or interstate government entity, any agency or instrumentality of a local government, or any other political subdivision of a State; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA30EF583DC124087A2CDCB5AC2CEC613"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian tribe or authorized tribal organization, or in Alaska a Native village or Alaska Regional Native Corporation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AEB70A9709B4F7385ECDBB6A213B89B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Partner organization</header><text>The term <term>partner organization</term> means any Federal agency participating in FLETC’s training programs under a formal memorandum of understanding.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F8E5DC9341847BDB3B5F72888797B14"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any possession of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF16055D3A054F79BEAE1C045A1D17E4"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Student intern</header><text>The term <quote>student intern</quote> means any eligible baccalaureate or graduate degree student participating in FLETC’s College Intern Program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05BA46E115534EDD96FA7C906C3F0F64"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition on new funding</header><text>No funds are authorized to carry out this section. This section shall be carried out using amounts otherwise appropriated or made available for such purpose.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4DF04360D21146B29F7C8206CC125D88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by amending the item relating to section 884 to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7185AD292D6F489597F57EACDADD1B37" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 884. Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


