<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF884E95214434EE398C7A5E56E2C41F7" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2316 IH: Self-Sufficient Community Lands Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2316</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150514">May 14, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To generate dependable economic activity for counties and local governments containing National
			 Forest System land by establishing a demonstration program for local,
			 sustainable forest management, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H56C991E743344F8597E8613F22F8C353" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3C71C3542D01423C8C9646AE7CCF008E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Self-Sufficient Community Lands Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC0446F9A588840F59E540CAFAB112212"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose and definitions</header> <subsection id="HCA5A331B1535434E8F668F1361CC7BCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to generate dependable economic activity for counties and local governments by establishing a demonstration program for local, sustainable forest management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4B1CB1B4ACCC43C69969ADA212DBCA98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H91BBE74097474CFAA32CDD357D1F8873"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><text>The term <quote>Advisory Committee</quote> means the Advisory Committee appointed by the Governor of a State for the community forest demonstration area established for the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA37AF6CDAEF4CBFA77664259FF60AB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community forest demonstration area</header><text>The term <quote>community forest demonstration area</quote> means a community forest demonstration area established for a State under section 3.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BA099DD8B95490FBFDA9B817796927F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National forest system</header><text>The term <quote>National Forest System</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>), except that the term does not include the National Grasslands and land utilization projects designated as National Grasslands administered pursuant to the Act of July 22, 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1010">7 U.S.C. 1010–1012</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BDB2042DA1F4A1DBC8F8A56CAD1A95D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Agriculture or the designee of the Secretary of Agriculture.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8EEBB30A0F6E46E1BC128ED3378D8168"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2180E2008547453094F79FBEB0FED4C7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of community forest demonstration areas</header>
 <subsection id="H79517382FE254020863DE400C9EAC10B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment required; time for establishment</header><text>Subject to subsection (c) and not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a community forest demonstration area at the request of the Advisory Committee appointed to manage community forest demonstration area land in that State.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7F15C5D5A3284DBF9FA900CB1661D95B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered land</header>
 <paragraph id="HF6B895D9753841629FC20FDC16418441"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inclusion of national forest system land</header><text>The community forest demonstration areas of a State shall consist of the National Forest System land in the State identified for inclusion by the Advisory Committee of that State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52902EF458A942969C5DEA46F279E07C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion of certain land</header><text>A community forest demonstration area shall not include National Forest System land—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA0428F41F554E4F88F64598CAD2D273"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10F029CBFF79498A83BF51952FE1AF1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on which the removal of vegetation is specifically prohibited by Federal statute;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCC8B96E0EAA49078A35F7A48F495A3D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>National Monuments; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAD6F11AD1F84ED0AE10E0679F6B679C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>over which administration jurisdiction was first assumed by the Forest Service under title III.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1CB1FBDECBB489AB9E49BD2B66745EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conditions on establishment</header> <paragraph id="H44A8DD2885304D74858BE26512CD8EDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acreage requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community forest demonstration area must include at least 200,000 acres of National Forest System land. If the unit of the National Forest System in which a community forest demonstration area is being established contains more than 5,000,000 acres, the community forest demonstration area may include 900,000 or more acres of National Forest System land.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4BF3A7F8A0549ADB35092635C2E8812"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management law or best management practices requirement</header><text>A community forest demonstration area may be established in a State only if the State—</text> <subparagraph id="HF431108403264CD492F25F701995AF6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a forest practices law applicable to State or privately owned forest land in the State; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B2F25D6CB08463DB0DDD27D774B31C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has established silvicultural best management practices or other regulations for forest management practices related to clean water, soil quality, wildlife or forest health.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C821072341B4662B3CAE11989E2C427"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revenue sharing requirement</header><text>As a condition of the inclusion in a community forest demonstration area of National Forest System land located in a particular county in a State, the county must enter into an agreement with the Governor of the State that requires that, in utilizing revenues received by the county under section 7(b), the county shall continue to meet any obligations under applicable State law as provided under title I of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7111">16 U.S.C. 7111 et seq.</external-xref>) or as provided in the sixth paragraph under the heading <quote>FOREST SERVICE</quote> in the Act of May 23, 1908 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/500">16 U.S.C. 500</external-xref>), and section 13 of the Act of March 1, 1911 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/500">16 U.S.C. 500</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCE0DF858EAC4745B69923ACB0C0B828"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment under certain other laws</header><text>National Forest System land included in a community forest demonstration area shall not be considered Federal land for purposes of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9D2BE95E8F194F3990AD4EBD342BEAAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>making payments to counties under the sixth paragraph under the heading <quote>FOREST SERVICE</quote> in the Act of May 23, 1908 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/500">16 U.S.C. 500</external-xref>), and section 13 of the Act of March 1, 1911 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/500">16 U.S.C. 500</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F6F88B4A26941AF8C279F2292EC8682"><enum>(2)</enum><text>title I.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F39CD6C61B146C78B2D4F1BBE216066"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Acreage limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than a total of 4,000,000 acres of National Forest System land may be established as community forest demonstration areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA5D783FE1EE4C8A91DFA956563A1A3C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recognition of valid and existing rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit or restrict—</text> <paragraph id="H53810F30A31146099F1A2B719EE62F7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>access to National Forest System land included in a community forest demonstration area for hunting, fishing, and other related purposes; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76F79A74DC604E05B225E934A23F24E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>valid and existing rights regarding such National Forest System land, including rights of any federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAE8352DCD19141B79544EAA8527BE821"><enum>4.</enum><header>Advisory committee</header>
 <subsection id="H8C2D7DA9ADDD4F57908C62A295751A73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>A community forest demonstration area for a State shall be managed by an Advisory Committee appointed by the Governor of the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6496E56D41704779AF958BA4931C80E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Advisory Committee for a community forest demonstration area in a State shall include, but is not limited to, the following members:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB72686A3878E4A819D8CF3591291CF8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>One member who holds county or local elected office, appointed from each county or local governmental unit in the State containing community forest demonstration area land.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A9C7D5AC45B44A98DBF2512FF52E748"><enum>(2)</enum><text>One member who represents the commercial timber, wood products, or milling industry.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2FCC69D0878472F8E3D265ADA37FF5E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>One member who represents persons holding Federal grazing or other land use permits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A5EE28597944A88810569A458C5EF2C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>One member who represents recreational users of National Forest System land.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H859EE5AEF7FF4C3982F6221AD55331E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms</header> <paragraph id="HA6B8F3CCD8F745F5854472FBC250FB1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except in the case of certain initial appointments required by paragraph (2), members of an Advisory Committee shall serve for a term of three years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA7FFDD35F0F4583BFAAEF31FBF7B1B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial appointments</header><text>In making initial appointments to an Advisory Committee, the Governor making the appointments shall stagger terms so that at least one-third of the members will be replaced every three years.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7622A421D18F4203AAD1797F2167A463"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of a Advisory Committee shall serve without pay, but may be reimbursed from the funds made available for the management of a community forest demonstration area for the actual and necessary travel and subsistence expenses incurred by members in the performance of their duties.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H49E7ADA6630049DA8B0060AB24E3A8E3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Management of community forest demonstration areas</header>
			<subsection id="H749D5C656001448CB0F32886F57A90B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assumption of management</header>
 <paragraph id="HBCD40A883F31433C8E75A6D3179E8753"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Confirmation</header><text>The Advisory Committee appointed for a community forest demonstration area shall assume all management authority with regard to the community forest demonstration area as soon as the Secretary confirms that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H902690018DBF4E449B05FD467AA20AE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Forest System land to be included in the community forest demonstration area meets the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of section 3;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DAAF41286A640B1B73EEBB18B71EBC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Advisory Committee has been duly appointed under section 4 and is able to conduct business; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4449291C7634153B9F6FC88F650700B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provision has been made for essential management services for the community forest demonstration area.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBEC64FEC80B488583EB78B5C7A6273F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope and time for confirmation</header><text>The determination of the Secretary under paragraph (1) is limited to confirming whether the conditions specified in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such paragraph have been satisfied. The Secretary shall make the determination not later than 60 days after the date of the appointment of the Advisory Committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A38AF11E00A4E77A3C52E3554901240"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of failure to confirm</header><text>If the Secretary determines that either or both conditions specified in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) are not satisfied for confirmation of an Advisory Committee, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA9AF07214881499A82DF317F10A4F8A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promptly notify the Governor of the affected State and the Advisory Committee of the reasons preventing confirmation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF8A90646ACD4BB5BBD0E7BD1E99918D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make a new determination under paragraph (2) within 60 days after receiving a new request from the Advisory Committee that addresses the reasons that previously prevented confirmation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC762CDD54BD45B781365DF1B4BA5703"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management responsibilities</header><text>Upon assumption of management of a community forest demonstration area, the Advisory Committee for the community forest demonstration area shall manage the land and resources of the community forest demonstration area and the occupancy and use thereof in conformity with this Act, and to the extent not in conflict with this Act, the laws and regulations applicable to management of State or privately owned forest lands in the State in which the community forest demonstration area is located.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H64C9F9FAA301488F8FF3952B68C4205E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability of other federal laws</header>
 <paragraph id="H5CC883ACA3384360BEF843283A88EAA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The administration and management of a community forest demonstration area, including implementing actions, shall not be considered Federal action and shall be subject to the following only to the extent that such laws apply to the State or private administration and management of forest lands in the State in which the community forest demonstration area is located:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5666A89345A3495B8CDCA3880B366684"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251</external-xref> note).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA199A239060942309BD1431C92DEBF3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41C1DF13A5DF4CB48BCE4D48AD34C8CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD09B5FAFCFF44E30AF08A60405F5CF40"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Federal laws and regulations governing procurement by Federal agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE2CF82FD50D437B909C31BFF42D79CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), other Federal laws.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EE2F4DCA49B4B7FAB090EAAFA3C8AD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the assumption by an Advisory Committee of management of a community forest demonstration area, the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>) shall continue to apply to the National Forest System land included in the community forest demonstration area.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE6DE5BEF7D1407EB0E4F90D1F74BDBD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header>
 <paragraph id="H521A41C8E3F7478896C177A28A6E42A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>With indian tribes</header><text>The Advisory Committee for a community forest demonstration area shall cooperate and consult with Indian tribes on management policies and practices for the community forest demonstration area that may affect the Indian tribes. The Advisory Committee shall take into consideration the use of lands within the community forest demonstration area for religious and cultural uses by Native Americans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00EBF6F76D0049BC860D1EF4264A5361"><enum>(2)</enum><header>With collaborative groups</header><text>The Advisory Committee for a community forest demonstration area shall consult with any applicable forest collaborative group.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF5E1872F91B48AB83298AEF3D6C6C81"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recreation</header><text>Nothing in this section shall affect public use and recreation within a community forest demonstration area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE897590CE6C1489E8DFF0D071EE36248"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Fire management</header><text>The Secretary shall provide fire presuppression, suppression, and rehabilitation services on and with respect to a community forest demonstration area to the same extent generally authorized in other units of the National Forest System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBC2A9364717B41D3815D2B3D289E8322"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibition on export</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on the sale of timber or other forest products from a community forest demonstration area, unprocessed timber harvested from a community forest demonstration area may not be exported in accordance with subpart F of part 223 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H32D3DD6E6C1148599C3D1EA6D4FADBB7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Distribution of funds from community forest demonstration area</header>
 <subsection id="H58F62F4F2E624D6DAAFDB9AEE07794CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Retention of Funds for Management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee appointed for a community forest demonstration area may retain such sums as the Advisory Committee considers to be necessary from amounts generated from that community forest demonstration area to fund the management, administration, restoration, operation and maintenance, improvement, repair, and related expenses incurred with respect to the community forest demonstration area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H220341E090784294A25245004E88567B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funds to Counties or Local Governmental Units</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (a) and section 8, the Advisory Committee for a community forest demonstration area in a State shall distribute funds generated from that community forest demonstration area to each county or local governmental unit in the State in an amount proportional to the funds received by the county or local governmental unit under title I of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7111">16 U.S.C. 7111 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H04F97101FF444064BA07598FCBA4EABD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Initial funding authority</header>
 <subsection id="HB1D675E8CD7243AA9D3F7652C43CA714"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding source</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Counties may use such sum as the counties consider to be necessary from the amounts made available to the counties under title I of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/7111">16 U.S.C. 7111 et seq.</external-xref>) to provide initial funding for the management of community forest demonstration areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1DE83CDCF1954A49A032C2CE59CEC501"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No restriction on use of non-Federal funds</header><text>Nothing in this Act restricts the Advisory Committee of a community forest demonstration area from seeking non-Federal loans or other non-Federal funds for management of the community forest demonstration area.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD419E379445645CCBD203403E70751B8"><enum>8.</enum><header>Payments to United States Treasury</header>
 <subsection id="H78660CF58EA944C995C540A63BC8198E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payment requirement</header><text>As soon as practicable after the end of the fiscal year in which a community forest demonstration area is established and as soon as practicable after the end of each subsequent fiscal year, the Advisory Committee for a community forest demonstration area shall make a payment to the United States Treasury.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83ACC5FFEEDD4932B02B312B795640C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment amount</header><text>The payment for a fiscal year under subsection (a) with respect to a community forest demonstration area shall be equal to 75 percent of the quotient obtained by dividing—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC99E0435EFF74EC194B07D7014C16DEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number obtained by multiplying the number of acres of land in the community forest demonstration area by the average annual receipts generated over the preceding 10-fiscal year period from the unit or units of the National Forest System containing that community forest demonstration area; by</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA17D1FC059374672A6337EDDEC926013"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total acres of National Forest System land in that unit or units of the National Forest System.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF28B00458D314F82AC9244931D7DD976"><enum>9.</enum><header>Termination of community forest demonstration area</header> <subsection id="HC66DDF25EE1E4BE5B0BB703C88ED358D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination authority</header><text>Subject to approval by the Governor of the State, the Advisory Committee for a community forest demonstration area may terminate the community forest demonstration area by a unanimous vote.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H186B0428CCB8452A928247A00BAA6EE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of termination</header><text>Upon termination of a community forest demonstration area, the Secretary shall immediately resume management of the National Forest System land that had been included in the community forest demonstration area, and the Advisory Committee shall be dissolved.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8A213153BA0247E8A573BAC63B856E37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of undistributed funds</header><text>Any revenues from the terminated area that remain undistributed under section 6 more than 30 days after the date of termination shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury for use by the Forest Service in such amounts as may be provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


