<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB6A4B44D60DA4C77A42ECE314DB48EF7" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2281 IH: States’ Education Reclamation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2281</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for the elimination of the Department of Education, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB69FFA4DBE1D4862A03397CF8C4D78DD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC07723152A014D939FA4564C5EF6A71C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>States’ Education Reclamation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H5BBAE8695AF14FE1B686FB559461B73E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H38AD60AA27334CEC8F8034AF5C98E3C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Principles of federalism embodied in the Constitution of the United States entrust authority over issues of educational policy to the States and the people and a Federal Department of Education is inconsistent with such principles.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF0B6CE31E0C43F39854EC25788A6FD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Tradition and experience dictate that the governance and management of schools in the United States are best performed by parents, teachers, and communities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H664444A95088416BA2C4753BCEEC8398"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The education of the Nation’s students is suffering under a managerial government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9BAD9A25DBD4F528AFB030A743AD484"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Education has weakened the ability of parents to make essential decisions about their children’s education and has undermined the capacity of communities to govern their schools.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44BA3B2E9DA3423E97417FC68D831E27"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In the 34 years of its existence, the Department of Education has grown from a budget of $14 billion to almost $65.7 billion in annual discretionary appropriations administering around 100 programs. Meanwhile, education performance for 17-year-olds has stagnated since 1971.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BDD077D92894404B4F87035E2723C48"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Education has fostered over-regulation, standardization, bureaucratization, and litigation in United States education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6775AEDA2119462FB3246286E52E1FC7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of Education expends large amounts of money on its own maintenance and overhead. While the average national salary for public school teachers is $56,103 the average salary for a Department of Education employee is $108,571.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88624E8B8A41411FB2E061DB7B9798E7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In certain States, the average State salary for a public school teacher is less than the national average. In North Carolina, the average salary for a public school teacher is $45,737.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA14CA1C25CB44E9B7969D0C42DA7B9E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Recent tests reflect poor results in mathematics, science, and reading for American students compared with students from other nations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88FC46F51B33473B86050BC18333EF79"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Only through initiatives led by parents and local communities with the power to act can the United States elevate educational performance toward an acceptable level.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DC3DB71B0834762BF01B224230F5ED4"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The current system of top-down education uniformity is detrimental to local businesses and communities, the economic needs of the States, and the Nation’s ability to compete globally for jobs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88A33E34B80B475081B42B8A98CFDF86"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Department of Education has been hostile to many promising reforms, including reforms that would empower parents, teachers, and local communities. The United States, once a laboratory of innovation through the experiments of the States, is moving toward education standardization that does not consider the individual educational needs of our diverse population of students.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBD898F59189B4B279A74351B5E4ECB98"><enum>3.</enum><header>Abolition of department of education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Department of Education is abolished, and, with the exception of the programs transferred under section 7, any program for which the Secretary of Education or the Department of Education has administrative responsibility as provided by law or by delegation of authority pursuant to law is repealed, including each program under the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFE0102B62AB6401B85F465E09A1F26C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD459E44A848E41728D09796E26ADCDF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H16B621AC4FE744E5A772AD8990ACA354"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants to states for elementary and secondary and for postsecondary education programs</header> <subsection id="H8A42B3584C7A4A7780456321B151BD0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the requirements of this Act, each State is entitled to receive from the Secretary of the Treasury, by not later than July 1 of the preceding fiscal year—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9A825DC5F7774104A314A67E830A0F64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a grant for fiscal year 2016 and each succeeding fiscal year through fiscal year 2024, that is equal to the amount of funds appropriated for the State for Federal elementary school and secondary school programs for fiscal year 2012 (except for the funds appropriated for fiscal year 2012 for such programs for such State that are being transferred under section 7); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF208427CC0C4E5AB6572B802ADC7A3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a grant for fiscal year 2016 and each succeeding fiscal year through fiscal year 2024, that is equal to the amount of funds appropriated for the State for Federal postsecondary education programs for fiscal year 2012 (except for the funds appropriated for fiscal year 2012 for such programs for such State that are being transferred under section 7).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA25ACA17E71941328C57AE5CBFF98B95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>Out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated for fiscal years 2016 through 2024, such sums as are necessary for grants under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE8D1A27235F94F94A354F096736A4F6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements relating to intergovernmental financing</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall make the transfer of funds under grants under subsection (a) directly to each State in accordance with the requirements of section 6503 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H40781ABFF7064023B53D452F9FDCF37E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expenditure of funds</header><text>Amounts received by a State under this section for any fiscal year shall be expended by the State in such fiscal year or in the succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H33877CC59B7C4517B410FEC8A034BFC1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds made available to a State—</text> 
<paragraph id="H19EAA236C11E4A05BB7FF3131668795E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under subsection (a)(1), shall be used by the State for any elementary or secondary education purpose permitted by State law, including increases in teacher salaries; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H742F59A3ECE34FBB99D5AC76233B611E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under subsection (a)(2), shall be used by the State for any postsecondary education purpose permitted by State law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0430B07F5F344A696E1D3A39F176D67"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>A grant received under subsection (a) shall only be used to supplement the amount of funds that would, in the absence of such grant, be made available from non-Federal sources for elementary school and secondary school programs or postsecondary education programs, and not to supplant those funds.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H81F7A7CDDD4147BB938DE26A569E99DF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administrative and fiscal accountability</header> <subsection id="H4F88D1FFEE9C4D98AAAA72275874DACE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Audits</header> <paragraph id="H2642E02CF5984B59861C7306B074BD19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contract with approved auditing entity</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2015, and annually thereafter, a State shall contract with an approved auditing entity (as defined under paragraph (3)(B)) for purposes of conducting an audit under paragraph (2) (with respect to the fiscal year ending September 30 of such year).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0919503DE43C4B91BCF27F308D1D21FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audit requirement</header><text>Under a contract under paragraph (1), an approved auditing entity shall conduct an audit of the expenditures or transfers made by a State from amounts received under a grant under section 4, with respect to the fiscal year which such audit covers, to determine the extent to which such expenditures and transfers were expended in accordance with section 4.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BEF968CA9E54F8990B8506F28A33705"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entity conducting audit</header> <subparagraph id="H7C26A631EA6048E29D925F3827396D2F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to a State, the audit under paragraph (2) shall be conducted by an approved auditing entity in accordance with generally accepted auditing principles.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9EEFCB87CF3949DFAEE7E22ED521294B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approved auditing entity</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>approved auditing entity</quote> means, with respect to a State, an entity that is—</text> <clause id="HE4F8A145011D4DF1BBA16ACB55D2709F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approved by the Secretary of the Treasury;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H22B3F2B3D5094B0E8F325A1F61516087"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>approved by the chief executive officer of the State; and</text></clause> <clause id="H020B8AE5B2754334B5D54C052ACD844B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>independent of any Federal, State, or local agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC82A4315500498FB8545F05D524DE72"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission of audit</header><text>Not later than April 30, 2016, and annually thereafter, a State shall submit the results of the audit under paragraph (2) (with respect to the fiscal year ending on September 30 of such year) to the State legislature and to the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8BD18403696A4B70ABB04A9C6F7D5361"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reimbursement and penalty</header><text>If, through an audit conducted under subsection (a), an approved auditing entity finds that a State violated the requirements of subsection (d) or (e) of section 4, the State shall pay to the Treasury of the United States 100 percent of the amount of State funds that were used in violation of section 4 as a penalty. Insofar as a State fails to pay any such penalty, the Secretary of the Treasury shall offset the amount not so paid against the amount of any grant otherwise payable to the State under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC4BFA5FF8BF7400E857C4639DFC67F6C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reporting requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HC102953D4A144216B387D69FC28FF92E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 31, 2016, and annually thereafter, each State shall submit to the Secretary of the Treasury and the State legislature a report on the activities carried out by the State during the most recently completed fiscal year with funds received by the State under a grant under section 4 for such fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC62E8C408EC344558FA2AEA02D3E2312"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>A report under paragraph (1) shall, with respect to a fiscal year—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H903545F47E6048C99D81CB4BB5FB2ADD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contain the results of the audit conducted by an approved auditing entity for a State for such fiscal year, in accordance with the requirements of subsection (a) of this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1457D2C7894F45FAB52D10CBBF8FA66B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specify the amount of the grant made to the State under section 4; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3DBFBD918D54D1F8F31219D52BA78F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be in such form and contain such other information as the State determines is necessary to provide—</text> <clause id="HBFE7131016E3432BA7DB150126141CDB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an accurate description of the activities conducted by the State for the purpose described under section 4; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4FF39185B8F54AD48A3EC1C085997B22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a complete record of the purposes for which amounts were expended in accordance with this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64AB52FC2B2741C193C29F7F41BD90DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>A State shall make copies of the reports required under this section available on a public website and shall make copies available in other formats upon request.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC2F443371E154C56AA1670E0D4168F7C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Failure to Comply with requirements</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall not make any payment to a State under a grant authorized by section 4—</text> <paragraph id="H963C1BDF8533406AA8E256E80B1B02AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if an audit for a State is not submitted as required under subsection (a) during the period between the date such audit is due and the date on which such audit is submitted;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF293292AD59E4CDEB1EBC908C8396885"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a State fails to submit a report as required under subsection (c) during the period between the date such report is due and the date on which such report is submitted; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H092412E9FBDC431EA53E4C2DE5CF6452"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if a State violates a requirement of section 4 during the period beginning on the date the Secretary becomes aware of such violation and the date on which such violation is corrected by the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H255D8D4269984BB2B2DA122B8DF44B13"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative supervision and oversight</header> 
<paragraph id="H496F0F77C6F2430AAB8BB2E05CD5DC13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limited role for Secretary of the Treasury</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the Secretary of the Treasury under this Act is limited to—</text> <subparagraph id="H94FD2BDF88E34F81A14B4EAAC1E6127E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promulgating regulations, issuing rules, or publishing guidance documents to the extent necessary for purposes of implementing subsection (a)(3)(B), subsection (b), and subsection (d);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AE94D19CFA041CCB1146D66CBD6FDF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>making payments to the States under grants under section 4;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H964C05A219F9476F961CFDCB2A323F50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>approving entities under subsection (a)(3)(B) for purposes of the audits required under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FA469935865403DB3EF54F45A056F6E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>withholding payment to a State of a grant under subsection (d) or offsetting a payment of such a grant to a State under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10261E3683394F029A363004D67CE96A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>exercising the authority relating to nondiscrimination that is specified in section 6(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2809BE53245C49D6982B53A2BCB106FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limited role for Attorney general</header><text>The authority of the Attorney General to supervise the amounts received by a State under section 4 is limited to the authority under section 6(b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H782AABA5B15945FD903F35BF8F51CA7A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reservation of state powers</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the power of a State, including the power of a State to pursue civil and criminal penalties under State law against any individual or entity that misuses, or engages in fraud or abuse related to, the funds provided to a State under section 4.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF855722221FC4709A8E6CEF52945F10F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination provisions</header> 
<subsection id="H7FC76B673D8449C8BD2C6955CB6CF9E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No discrimination against individuals</header><text>No individual shall be excluded from participation in, denied the benefits of, or subjected to discrimination under, any program or activity funded in whole or in part with amounts paid to a State under section 4 on the basis of such individual’s—</text> <paragraph id="H2AB2137EF58E4028A1591CEBB620F20C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disability under section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BB776AFC74F46F5ACF2570CB87B5A4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sex under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H783B0B7F175F40F9A745483BBA0A8C56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>race, color, or national origin under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5A3103297A2846AD9D13CC13FAAC9429"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance</header> 
<paragraph id="H8D170D613B024F58A9D764DD51D80912"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that a State or an entity that has received funds from amounts paid to a State under a grant under section 4 has failed to comply with a provision of law referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the chief executive officer of the State of such failure to comply and shall request that such chief executive officer secure such compliance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED330B3A7F294BA0B344EC5C7115176D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>If, not later than 60 days after receiving notification under paragraph (1), the chief executive officer of a State fails or refuses to secure compliance with the provision of law referred to in such notification, the Attorney General may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H543F8A9C400842CAA8CECB16F4685C1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>institute an appropriate civil action; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B867871DED844E4B43C3EB6B222231D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exercise the powers and functions provided under section 505 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794a">29 U.S.C. 794a</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), or title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) (as applicable).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7208766C80CE45E2927E1949132358C9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Transfer of certain department of education programs</header> 
<subsection id="H376440D0251E461FBB0601FA5A85E88D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of certain programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H35B86638232D4C9F91C633C95B57CD6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each job training program under the jurisdiction of the Department of Education, including the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Department of Labor;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52272FE5A39646A6BC41B097DA53C613"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each special education grant program under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1460">20 U.S.C. 1460 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C513A40A00B44A2A505CCFADAA7FD86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>each Indian education program under the jurisdiction of the Department of Education shall be transferred to the Department of the Interior;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BC74FD9D3B6485592BE240A9DF16157"><enum>(4)</enum><text>each Impact Aid program under title VIII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7701">20 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be transferred to the Department of Defense;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF14C438F578D45DB805669FE95A186BE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Federal Pell Grant program under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>), shall be transferred to the Department of the Treasury;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0126C71DBA48448EAC636A85CF73B439"><enum>(6)</enum><text>each Federal student loan program under the jurisdiction of the Department of Education shall be transferred to the Department of the Treasury;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACA1354CE82F40319C7508EF44477A9E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>each program under the jurisdiction of the Institute of Education Sciences shall be transferred to the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1DD7B99FF49D4A32A6E9D35703472B57"><enum>(8)</enum><text>each program under the jurisdiction of the D.C. Opportunity Scholarship Program shall be transferred to the Department of Health and Human Services. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H76397414FC9749418F6974A059D052DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on transfer of certain programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The transfer of programs pursuant to subsection (a) is limited to only the transfer of administrative responsibility as provided by law or the delegation of authority pursuant to law and does not extend to the transfer of personnel employed by the Department of Education to carry out such programs. </text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H49F5CD3760BD45E79D258FC1F4CFFF9D"><enum>8.</enum><header>Gao report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate report, which shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HCCDBB297498B4C3DAC33FB23A1C995E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review and evaluation as to the feasibility of enhancing the ability of States and local communities to fund education by reducing the Federal tax burden and commensurately eliminating Federal Government involvement in providing grants for education programs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13550D7404E94C9C90A59EDF0CB0773E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of the feasibility of the successor Federal agencies for maintaining the programs to be transferred under section 7.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6400ECA4F5754456B6F82A046631D938"><enum>9.</enum><header>Plan for closure of the Department of Education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 365 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the Congress a plan to implement closure of the Department of Education in accordance with this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="H7FE38D5E3A714615AA9D1D19DE2927F4"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H2B67AF97640A4C6BADD04E6602DBA5E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elementary school; secondary school</header><text>The terms <quote>elementary school</quote> and <quote>secondary school</quote> have the meanings given the terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9101">20 U.S.C. 9101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA869415D9BCC460FAA518CF32E5238A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCED0E64C098146BAA1913D5A31F1AE94"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


