<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEF13673573AE49F0A0FF5D04B3FA4245" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2172 IH: To establish a pilot toll credit market place program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2172</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a pilot toll credit market place program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7D28C9EF238A45ECA21F2A329ED10BAC" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9FADDB05E5E6484A82AFD36A3FF79D21" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Toll credit marketplace pilot program</header>
 <subsection id="H598A2F3241064ACDAB0115BF538C9A27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish and implement a pilot program to develop a toll credit marketplace for States to buy and sell toll credits.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD18168CA23924E21A1C7101EC9EEE2D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the pilot program are—</text> <paragraph id="H0722E4C157134628AC262DE1CA2169A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to identify whether a monetary value can be assigned to toll credits;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA28E0F801044DDD8EBC64285F9EECCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify the discounted rate of toll credits for cash;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF560DC9A66FB46B2A75A1CE1C523EFF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to determine if the purchase of toll credits by States provides the purchasing State budget flexibility to deal with funding issues, including off-system needs, transit systems with high operating costs, or cash flow issues; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A4ADE35441F4C1D9119BD6A96817283"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to test the feasibility of expanding the toll credit market to allow all States to participate on a permanent basis.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H376B549A0C0A44418A4D715911903A7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration of pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program under this Act, the Secretary, working through the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, shall determine how a toll credit marketplace will work and—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB5FAD80931B645FD8AA27F73A5831E4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish an online platform that allows participating States to offer and bid on toll credit purchases;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BB30C6322E54B8CAD062EB6C63A80CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, provide notice to States that the Federal Highway Administration requests participants for the toll credit marketplace;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H865F3048F7734724BBC829F20BE2846F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>allow States that maintain a toll credit balance accumulated before the enactment of this Act and States that do not maintain infrastructure for the collection of toll credits or have not accumulated a toll credit balance to participate in the pilot program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27B73B91E726469B82CB7B6BB4205F5F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>not allow a State to purchase or sell toll credits in an amount that is less than 5 percent of the toll credit’s value if applied as a non-Federal share requirement under section 120(i)(1) of title 23, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7EA9C91F8B84E4DBB648C2BEC3BFBC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HD6296BF1F957496F8B7A9CE744271A29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after notice of the pilot program is provided to the States under subsection (c)(2), the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate on the progress of the toll credit marketplace.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6BA795C672845F0A652981A090AC989"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after a purchase or sale in the toll credit marketplace, a State selling toll credits shall provide the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration with information on the transaction, the amount of cash received and the value of toll credits sold, on the intended use of the cash, and an update on the State’s remaining toll credit balance. A State purchasing toll credits shall provide the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration with information on the value of toll credits purchased, the anticipated use of the toll credits, and plans for maintaining maintenance of effort for spending on Federal-aid highways projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E7E79F279A543D0BFE87BF538C9C468"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year and after notice is given under subsection (c)(2) and each year thereafter that the pilot program is in effect, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and make such report publicly available on its website that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDFE064836AEC410584192A39446AB586"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines whether a toll credit marketplace is viable;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D592B43D2D946B4AFD5CDAF0DFC6D1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describes of the buying and selling activities of the toll credit marketplace;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4431D959C32843FFA4ECAA65E2B14761"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determines of the monetary value of toll credits;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83DFD4D458F54C1CB642D211CA9A5AEF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines whether the pilot program could be expanded to more States and or all States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76FC93EA5F5C40B9BE1A7C5C9E8D0363"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides updated information on the toll credit balance accumulated by each State.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H002E31E2FA46498A8512C3997618153C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="HCF54FDD0C76947618FBF59764CC68179"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7A06A6EE607453E9B70CBCDB4C11402"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Toll credit</header><text>The term <term>toll credit</term> means the credit that can be used for non-Federal share under section 120(i) of title 23, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97B59E21266D4B9CA7FC3D4D9FD41EA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Toll credit marketplace</header><text>The term <term>toll credit marketplace</term> means a market where toll credits can be purchased and sold by States participating in the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DBA9EB586F47C2A679884DA35FF139"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States, including the Virgin Islands.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92723DB3FB004CE6A69A3D780E268438"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Maintenance of effort</header><text>A State participating in the toll credit marketplace shall continue to be subject to requirements of section 120(i)(2) of title 23, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H70E2DD1DE7D947DFBA0A1BFD17338A76"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of funds received for the sale</header>
 <paragraph id="H867D907C247C48EEAB68AC910FAD2F36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>A State receiving funds in exchange for a toll credit shall be required to certify that the proceeds will be used for highway, transit, and other related projects and must receive approval from the Federal Highway Administration before expending such funds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0DF65E7D7A4412799BA4C307C82B493"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the receipt of a certification under paragraph (1), the Federal Highway Administration shall send a notice of decision approving or rejecting the State’s submission. A notice of disapproval shall be accompanied by an explanation of the grounds for disapproval and provide recommendations for resubmitting a certification that will be approved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABB6192601874C2F93D99F30DE27019B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text>Not later than 30 days after a State receives a notice of decision to reject its submission, such State may appeal the decision to the Secretary of Transportation who, not later than 60 days after receipt, shall review and adjudicate such appeal.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88F0AF906FAB4071810C6AA6C5BD29B6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Metropolitan planning organization and local government toll credit allocation</header>
 <paragraph id="H50ECE79E96224EB28C1F7E983DA4B0C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purchase of toll credits</header><text>Upon request of an interested metropolitan planning organization or local government, a State may purchase toll credits on behalf of a metropolitan planning organization or local government upon request and timely payment of the amount of such credits by such organization or government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECEB672B96034E659A86062D590F133E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation of toll credits</header><text>A State purchasing toll credits without prior requests from a metropolitan planning organization or local government may allocate those toll credits for use by a metropolitan planning organization or local government upon approval by the board of leadership of such metropolitan planning organization or local government.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AD03C424D714396A3F696D56896FD37"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation on use of Federal funds for the purchase of toll credits</header>
 <paragraph id="H674F4CD5054B456AAC946403A5951464"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation on Federal funds</header><text>A State, metropolitan planning organization, or local government may not use Federal funds to purchase toll credits on the toll credit marketplace.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A11A76E215C4462808B4E030622E3A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of toll credits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any recipient of Federal funding under Title 23 or Title 49 that purchases toll credits under this Act may not use such toll credits for more than 10 percent of its annual apportionment in any fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H038D6575B5F14C068CB4839D51677732"><enum>2.</enum><header>Toll credit eligibility as collateral under the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing
 Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 822(f) of title 45, United States Code, is amended by adding after section 822(f)(2)(A) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H765CC1B087CE4111BBF7C2780AA620DD" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H3A1CF09AB2814D468293C7327A944D04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collateral that is eligible for use in an application includes credits earned under section 120(i) of title 23, United States Code.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


