<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6BB6E359409A46AAB38D3293C5AD2219" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3301 IH: To prohibit Federal funding of Planned Parenthood Federation of America.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3301</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit Federal funding of Planned Parenthood Federation of America.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H85C109EF7C954DFFAF2B4AE933192C91" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFC6E0D0E16FA44FAA7A192619E0EDADF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H70E54091860343E3A71D7BB7FD9A6F3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State and county health departments, community health centers, hospitals, physicians offices, and other entities currently provide, and will continue to provide, health services to women. Such health services include relevant diagnostic laboratory and radiology services, well-child care, prenatal and postpartum care, immunization, family planning services including contraception, sexually transmitted disease testing, cervical and breast cancer screenings, and referrals.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HACAF028B69C143238879CF18B073493A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Many such entities provide services to all persons, regardless of the person’s ability to pay, and provide services in medically underserved areas and to medically underserved populations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3ACCC9BC628B4FBB8D66B1C31D8278F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All funds no longer available to Planned Parenthood will continue to be made available to other eligible entities to provide women’s health care services.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H7A9ECF12EBD148E1BE8C4C6633513C5D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition</header>
<subsection id="HE79B703A16F747F08D631C18B451E7EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds may be made available to Planned Parenthood Federation of America, or to any of its affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, or clinics.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H35B136B66131410B85C11CB1B2400CFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text>
<paragraph id="HF414499B4BAB42A5B021003135C49DB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affect any limitation contained in an appropriations Act relating to abortion; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E392C6D35854D538ACB9F13B6B6B79D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce overall Federal funding available in support of women’s health.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


