<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5A64530A00A24E57B012856CD9C22359" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3509 IH: EV–COMUTE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3509</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150915">September 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000810">Mr. Woodall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize any office of the Federal Government which owns or operates a parking area for the use
			 of its employees to install, construct, operate, and maintain a battery
			 recharging station in the area, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3948E36A1B314CC49CF6326FBC074FF5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE09F35058A3C424B93721CD54AC086BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Electric Vehicle Charging Offers Modern Utility Terminals for Employees Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>EV–COMUTE Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBFCDDE494E424A4F9D6EA9BAEF1594C2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Operation of battery recharging stations in parking areas used by Federal employees</header> <subsection id="H72213C92EBCC44F89D67CF9F6FB06071"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header> <paragraph id="H9BD5DCC73AB24BC18CE95521FE767026"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of any office of the Federal Government which owns or operates a parking area for the use of its employees (either directly or indirectly through a contractor) may install, construct, operate, and maintain on a reimbursable basis a battery recharging station in such area for the use of privately owned vehicles of employees of the office and others who are authorized to park in such area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B0A7B873F2948EA82B3FCA8E21F98CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of vendors</header><text>The head of an office may carry out paragraph (1) through a contract with a vendor, under such terms and conditions (including terms relating to the allocation between the office and the vendor of the costs of carrying out the contract) as the head of the office and the vendor may agree to.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AFE4570D19A4236AF8F0E3F475339DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Imposition of Fees To Cover Costs</header>
 <paragraph id="HFF1B31DAB30645A18AC9AE5B7C3CD1D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an office of the Federal Government which operates and maintains a battery recharging station under this Act shall charge fees to the individuals who use the station in such amount as is necessary to ensure that office recovers all of the costs it incurs in installing, constructing, operating, and maintaining the station.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3585C288EAA845D88DD917A688463794"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposit and availability of fees</header><text>Any fees collected by the head of an office under this subsection shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HA284D7C3D8734F57ABDA3BD5D735B215"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deposited monthly in the Treasury to the credit of the appropriations account for salaries and expenses of the office; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B24D24BE3EC4CE19C012D2BBE5DBFAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>available for obligation without further appropriation during—</text> <clause id="HE7943EE1F8A241A093E54E5DE2468D09"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the fiscal year collected; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0D5B489225EA47BFADDB33BB3840A379"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fiscal year following the fiscal year collected.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07661B97269F4B8EA17B6EA68276EBFF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No Effect on Existing Programs for House and Senate</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to affect the installation, construction, operation, or maintenance of battery recharging stations by the Architect of the Capitol—</text>
 <paragraph id="H103931E2A85648E59FA9BA7A0CE9560E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/170">Public Law 112–170</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2171">2 U.S.C. 2171</external-xref>), relating to employees of the House of Representatives and individuals authorized to park in any parking area under the jurisdiction of the House of Representatives on the Capitol Grounds; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5824D7CD2924962A30EBEE8063A5197"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/167">Public Law 112–167</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2170">2 U.S.C. 2170</external-xref>), relating to employees of the Senate and individuals authorized to park in any parking area under the jurisdiction of the Senate on the Capitol Grounds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0D10117ADA3441968145A33291F730C1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2016 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

