<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7E3FE9967B94D429F793A2C5C55330E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1390 IH: Small Business Joint Venturing Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1390</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150317">March 17, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Small Business Act to modify the requirements for joint venture offers for bundled or consolidated contracts, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7F84FFA604954A899FA7CD603288D173" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6D49BAFCBDB64A72ABD4DA38A31AA514" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Joint Venturing Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3C00C1AD719E4A09B953A0A48304C21B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Joint venture offers for bundled or consolidated contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(e)(4) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(e)(4)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE6C2ADE7A9614D20B684F357A78E440C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HCFABFEEF328A4553BB242B21188BE608"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Contract teaming</header> 
<subparagraph id="H43596452A6FC49FDA006940EE26B21C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a solicitation of offers for a bundled or consolidated contract that is issued by the head of an agency, a small business concern may submit an offer that provides for use of a particular team of subcontractors or a joint venture of small business concerns for the performance of the contract.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D1617FC3E0F417183352ABF3F13580D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Evaluation of offers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the agency shall evaluate the offer of a team or a joint venture of small business concerns in the same manner as other offers, with due consideration to the capabilities of all of the proposed subcontractors or members of the joint venture as follows:</text> 
<clause id="H1585DA0FF1E04E54A81936AB62FFBBFD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Teams</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When evaluating an offer of a small business prime contractor whose offer includes a proposed team of small business subcontractors, the head of the agency shall consider the capabilities and past performance of each first tier subcontractor that is part of the team as the capabilities and past performance of the team.</text></clause> <clause id="HA7EB77F0097E435894890306676D8E55"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Joint ventures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When evaluating an offer of a joint venture of small business concerns, if the joint venture does not have sufficient capabilities or past performance to be considered for award of a contract opportunity, the head of the agency shall consider the capabilities and past performance of each member of the joint venture as the capabilities past performance of the joint venture.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB42C94D83CD4705AD6B7999C3522FA5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Status as a small business concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participation of a small business concern in a team or a joint venture under this paragraph shall not affect the status of that concern as a small business concern for any other purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H08DF433A89C84EEE9972F3EDD7D26964"><enum>3.</enum><header>Team and joint ventures offers for multiple award contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(q)(1) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(q)(1)</external-xref>)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H04AB19A3A53A4D8FB3CE33127BB8F3F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">and joint venture</header-in-text></quote> before <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">requirements</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AB9835B244642C28729C345999075AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Each Federal agency</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB813684AC1D0460DAAFE49B7C3A8041B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H7B21B1094EFA4E8B99D332BEE61B38BB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal agency</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB64D2340904492196CCF2A85AF90A69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEBECE3DD0FB340DAA1DF5D53BB671F08" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HD990FB72BBF948A6B85E590B57A2C2BB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Teams</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When evaluating an offer of a small business prime contractor whose offer includes a proposed team of small business subcontractors for any multiple award contract above the substantial bundling threshold of the Federal agency, the head of the agency shall consider the capabilities and past performance of each first tier subcontractor that is part of the team as the capabilities and past performance of the offeror.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C8BBED4E4D84C21B0132A425B044736"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Joint ventures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When evaluating an offer of a joint venture of small business concerns for any multiple award contract above the substantial bundling threshold of the Federal agency, if the joint venture does not have sufficient capabilities or past performance to be considered for award of a contract opportunity, the head of the agency shall consider the capabilities and past performance of each member of the joint venture as the capabilities and past performance of the joint venture.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H378D180B1E494B8AAC2017251937388A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall issue any regulations necessary to carry out the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

