<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFEA44F847FC44DEAA32FEAD72F203267" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1233 IH: CLEARR Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1233</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide regulatory relief to community financial institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H37F355E41ED04591A24603A74EE24758" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1672CBC7818C42C7B3D5A371394D5430" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Lending Enhancement and Regulatory Relief Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>CLEARR Act of 2015</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9964CA05558F43C28F3A7ECDFA88DD3F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exception to annual privacy notice requirement under the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 503 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6803">15 U.S.C. 6803</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HC17265344D3B4E72AC3B6E04AD143E4A" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H675FCAFFF6D74218985FBB7071292147"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exception to annual notice requirement</header><text>A financial institution that—</text> <paragraph id="HA941C18C30064E06A471375931DF14C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides nonpublic personal information only in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(2) or (e) of section 502 or regulations prescribed under section 504(b), and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69921482856842B09F5AD07AF1848C59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has not changed its policies and practices with regard to disclosing nonpublic personal information from the policies and practices that were disclosed in the most recent disclosure sent to consumers in accordance with this section,</text>
					</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall not be required to provide an annual disclosure under this section until such time as the
			 financial institution fails to comply with any criteria described in
			 paragraph (1) or (2).</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H071393CE04EB403480C1C7317DB65E68"><enum>3.</enum><header>Community bank mortgage servicing asset capital requirements study</header>
 <subsection id="H00017E540D2D4CC3880E1EDBE7C4C75E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H53C2D61A010C4ED792FBA1F2E1FC5EB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Banking institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>banking institution</term> means an insured depository institution, Federal credit union, State credit union, bank holding company, or savings and loan holding company.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7864A038A1546D48DFA3DE4D73793F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basel III capital requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Basel III capital requirements</quote> means the Global Regulatory Framework for More Resilient Banks and Banking Systems issued by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision on December 16, 2010, as revised on June 1, 2011.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5BB9837B97B4CB79138D98F9D0A89B9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal banking agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal banking agencies</quote> means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H416BC6B375CC492CB89C64CBEE801B7E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mortgage servicing asset</header><text>The term <quote>mortgage servicing asset</quote> means those assets that result from contracts to service loans secured by real estate, where such loans are owned by third parties.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF780458DA674265BCE5A407293C5055"><enum>(5)</enum><header>NCUA capital requirements</header><text>The term <quote>NCUA capital requirements </quote> means the proposed rule of the National Credit Union Administration titled <quote>Risk-Based Capital</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 4340; January 27, 2015).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3846FA78FD1F46038C18E3D85316337B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nonsystemic banking institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>nonsystemic banking institution</quote> means any banking institution other than an institution identified by the Financial Stability Board as a <quote>global systemically important bank</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HCAA1AB9179644039A802F3C33377AF5D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Other definitions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H41A419151B9A4ED2B8D8556D41003CFC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Banking definitions</header><text>The terms <quote>bank holding company</quote>, <quote>insured depository institution</quote>, and <quote>savings and loan holding company</quote> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H063F72E0859C4AC39933FE9154F10FC4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Credit union definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>Federal credit union</quote> and <quote>State credit union</quote> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, under section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B39DB1CD6D040E7B0A15871A00D8EC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study of the appropriate capital for mortgage servicing assets</header>
 <paragraph id="H2862D291881D47E987C64236219E8576"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal banking agencies shall, jointly, conduct a study of the appropriate capital requirements for mortgage servicing assets for nonsystemic banking institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H826F370002174266866BDCADAD6C12EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Issues To be studied</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study required by this subsection shall include, with a specific focus on nonsystemic banking institutions—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7D401A90419B4494AE0A52F16F5EA0C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the risk to banking institutions of holding mortgage servicing assets;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57BFC5B31EAF49B58C23F65D7D813A52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the history of the market for mortgage servicing assets, including particularly the market for such assets in the period of the financial crisis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE77532B86D24A1E826844F85F22B6B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of banking institutions to establish a value for their mortgage servicing assets through periodic sales or other means;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F263415199445B693AC9C0B5E718BDE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>regulatory approaches to mortgage servicing assets in addition to capital requirements that could be used to address concerns about the value of and ability to sell mortgage servicing assets;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA829E55667574E0B922C85FB0D0351C2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of imposing the Basel III capital requirements and the NCUA capital requirements on nonsystemic banking institutions on their ability to compete in the mortgage servicing business, including the need for economies of scale to compete in that business, and on their ability to provide service to consumers to whom they have made a mortgage loan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0807A6D57FCD485484E1C95CDCB42549"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of what the mortgage servicing marketplace would look like if the Basel III capital requirements and the NCUA capital requirements on mortgage servicing assets were fully implemented;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H508323A5B5C7433191B3131DCCE104F1"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the significance of problems with mortgage servicing assets, if any, in banking institution failures and problem banking institutions, including specifically identifying failed banking institutions where mortgage servicing assets contributed to the failure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2828E6B37A8C4117B06AC90520BF3093"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the relevance of the Basel III capital requirements and the NCUA capital requirements on mortgage servicing assets to the banking systems of other significant developed countries.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D893FAC9387480D87891AFDE916B647"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal banking agencies shall issue a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives containing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2E69132BA47D49F98C0D5D2F205DB0D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the study required under paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6CEF80DD51C4B88A35E985EFE62B1B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any analysis on the specific issue of mortgage servicing assets undertaken by the Federal banking agencies prior to finalizing regulations implementing the Basel III capital requirements and the NCUA capital requirements.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H880719B54D594A3C83FA8798C5E25490"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Delay of rulemaking</header>
 <paragraph id="H28ED7C9C2D9740618EC3CFE8AA3F4D50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rules on mortgage servicing assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no regulation to implement the Basel III capital requirements or the NCUA capital requirements with respect to mortgage servicing assets for nonsystemic banking institutions shall take effect before the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date the report is issued under subsection (b)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C6FE056392D4173AECFA422CFA9BFB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final rule requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before any final rule is issued by a Federal banking agency with respect to capital requirements on mortgage servicing assets for nonsystemic banking institutions, the Federal banking agency shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2A7ADC9A0B5A446EA06C2413DD002F62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the related proposed rule was issued before the date on which the report is issued under subsection (b)(3), issue a new proposed rule for public comment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EEA983367AE413493281EAC970D1CDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider regulatory approaches to mortgage servicing assets that could address concerns about the value of and ability to sell mortgage servicing assets.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7740209941434E29A70720EBDA98D287"><enum>4.</enum><header>Community Institution Mortgage Relief</header>
 <subsection id="H98F731C99A8D488A92D72B46C39B27EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemption from escrow requirements for loans held by small creditors</header><text>Section 129D(c) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639d">15 U.S.C. 1639d(c)</external-xref>), as added by section 1461(a) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1F31C05933824C2DA1D70CD16AA64464"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) as subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) and moving such subparagraphs 2 ems to the right;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB488E02D62CC4004A48129E652E9F651"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Board</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H989D65EBC99B400EBBA15CA93CD69EAB" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H7DDAD068C2FA4E78972188F014F41C24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9568B5A62C45479B89AC773AC7A50F4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H83D7AEEEAAFC49EDAE079F7FB9C1DA70" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA827B18AAB6243829522EA9216EAF0CE" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of loans held by smaller creditors</header><text>The Board shall, by regulation, exempt from the requirements of subsection (a) any loan secured by a first lien on a consumer’s principle dwelling, if such loan is held by a creditor with assets of $10,000,000,000 or less.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF0043622A054DF28CC2593C6D0E57C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification to exemption for small servicers of mortgage loans</header><text>Section 6 of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2605">12 U.S.C. 2605</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BE2713F70414D36AEAED31510A27044" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HA5BE04D3848F4B0A91BC7219C8705672"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Small Servicer Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall, by regulation, provide exemptions to, or adjustments for, the provisions of this section for servicers that annually service 20,000 or fewer mortgage loans, in order to reduce regulatory burdens while appropriately balancing consumer protections.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4C99E668080646D8B282D889DB1FBE66"><enum>5.</enum><header>Access to Affordable Mortgages</header>
 <subsection id="HD2D35790E35C4F4688F0EC2A9FA6D891"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemption from property appraisal requirements for lower-Cost dwellings</header><text>Section 129H of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639h">15 U.S.C. 1639h</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H619D1CD9134245609445098E355368D0" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H9D60F3F33B7B4B8985AB0D441B57B0C9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exemption for higher-Risk mortgages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to a higher-risk mortgage loan of $250,000 or less if such loan appears on the balance sheet of the creditor of such loan for a period of not less than 3 years.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H89EA426F7C3749E29C207A0324298197"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption from penalties for failure To report appraisers</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 129E(k) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639e">15 U.S.C. 1639e(k)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>this section</quote> the following: <quote>, other than subsection (e),</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEEB3B4AC087F4EE992CB7B176CAC3140"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption from appraisal standard requirements for lower-Cost dwellings</header><text>Section 1110 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3339">12 U.S.C. 3339</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9FDE937646F14FF587C79F089E65619F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Each Federal financial institutions regulatory agency</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3934CE7BB2C2427DB98CCE8381F44F45" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7FAB860DDD0948E3ACB8DE4A63F545FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Real estate appraisals in connection with federally related transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal financial institutions regulatory agency</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD17235CC6931467DA6D374D8A1CB7323"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Each such agency or instrumentality</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65A895B8772A4C9F94E58A2FB61DFFD0" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H623116D7FD7446069EF8316E5CAB0C6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each such agency or instrumentality described under subsection (a)</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56A97661BEAE40648BE39FA88E7734DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H641075C825AD471D8D4B803ABE01A0B7" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE0D465DE463F4FE181DFFD1C22B9C16A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for certain higher-Risk mortgage loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Standards prescribed under this section shall not apply to a real estate appraisal or evaluation conducted in connection with a higher-risk mortgage loan (as defined in section 129H(f) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639h">15 U.S.C. 1639h(f)</external-xref>)) of $250,000 or less if such loan appears on the balance sheet of the creditor of such loan for a period of not less than 3 years.</text>
						</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDD4A97DFA2CA4D7EAD95CC97ED6EC386"><enum>6.</enum><header>Short form call report and examination cycle</header>
 <subsection id="HA0147ABB854B41D2B14D8DBC8303227E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(a) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1817">12 U.S.C. 1817(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73EF9277058A482B83711CF6F2127C30" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H5FFF2DA045F9490BB9D88D9E75841D37"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Short form reporting</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB909BDBABA23490C8E5F33FB32D5E880"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate Federal banking agencies shall issue regulations allowing for a reduced reporting requirement for covered depository institutions when making the first and third report of condition for a year, as required pursuant to paragraph (3).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3490665B68264B09BAC82DAD90469C96"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered depository institution defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>covered depository institution</quote> means an insured depository institution that—</text> <clause id="HE1D4323D902941D49294F5DE4D3B78FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a CAMELS composite rating of 1 or 2 under the Uniform Financial Institutions Rating System (or an equivalent rating under a comparable rating system) as of the most recent examination of such institution; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2B8AF86E000F4D79BA3480001F7C07BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>satisfies such other criteria as the appropriate Federal banking agencies determine appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H7FAF2FBE68B94F7A97254C476155B37B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Longer examination cycle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10(d) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1820">12 U.S.C. 1820(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA2AF956A3AC24823898ACD40122F719A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) through (10) as paragraphs (6) through (11), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA78B982EAB4037BB9842486422875B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in each of paragraphs (8) and (9), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (7)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35B93E2D29DC4C6C96EC21D9EABDCA0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H322E05F3C06743F498DE99636C4ACA63" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H9A121112970A47BE86A8988821270640"><enum>(5)</enum><header>24-month rule for certain institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an insured depository institution and notwithstanding paragraph (4), paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) shall apply with <quote>24-month</quote> substituted for <quote>12-month</quote> if the insured depository institution—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE3516B256FD547059C411CF15A17D630"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the requirements under subparagraphs (B) through (D) of paragraph (4); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H184FF681556947DB90E6A5B35DA94AC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a covered depository institution, as defined under section 7(a)(12)(B).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0F7AD1C8595A4CE69902DB12D3575E5C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Coordination among financial institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">Chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H61DA1C1751CA43D08CF48F54CB80E466"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after section 5332 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DD74D3FF3CE44FA86803A15D653BF49" style="USC">
					<section id="HC94C59880EA5478A944F2B8748B728CC"><enum>5333.</enum><header>Coordination among financial institutions</header>
 <subsection id="HAD31D5691DE54E5386EA815CEA1D4EE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an entry received via an automated clearing house, no receiving depository financial institution shall be required to verify that the entry is not a prohibited transaction, if the originating depository financial institution has warranted, pursuant to the automated clearing house rules governing such entry or otherwise, that the originating depository financial institution has complied with the sanctions programs administered by the Office of Foreign Assets Control in connection with such entry.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA5B645F96EEB444F900738B1810AF6B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7A05ABD56A02427699325319C7B59C05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Automated clearing house</header><text>The term <quote>automated clearing house</quote> means a funds transfer system governed by rules which provide for the interbank clearing of electronic entries for participating depository financial institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE478477691B242D3AAE64BC0E08C5E9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Depository financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>depository financial institution</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HCDBF4C471C0F417099AB7113BB36D793"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any insured depository institution, as such term is defined under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A44AC0CFF9B4FD8B7401A1819BA33A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any depository institution which is eligible to apply to become an insured depository institution under section 5 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1815">12 U.S.C. 1815</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75AA452FD42E4C6CA0259562D7F2189B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any insured credit union, as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H707F0E2FB9574CDF93BD17E894E1D22F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any credit union which is eligible to apply to become an insured credit union pursuant to section 201 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1781">12 U.S.C. 1781</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H775739485D50435FA06CBEF6C1614411"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entry</header><text>The term <quote>entry</quote> means an order to request for the transfer of funds through an automated clearing house.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD191525BE9A4EC0A89D9DE4D2BB5101"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Originating depository financial institution</header><text>The term <quote>originating depository financial institution</quote> means a depository financial institution that transmits entries via an automated clearing house for transmittal to a receiving depository financial institution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3E5C215E014E729554293AAACFABAF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibited transaction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>prohibited transaction</quote> means a funds transfer originated on behalf of a person to or from whom funds transfers are restricted by a sanctions program administered by the Office of Foreign Assets Control, including persons appearing on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30ED1C0EE53444168A94448622323192"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Receiving depository financial institution</header><text>The term <quote>receiving depository financial institution</quote> means a depository financial institution that receives entries via an automated clearing house from an originating depository financial institution for debit or credit to the accounts of its customers.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91FDB1C5266C426FA1758C718613A605"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the table of contents for such chapter by inserting after the item relating to section 5332 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5712AA9B5ED448499151B7F16453E018" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">5333. Coordination among financial institutions.</toc-entry>
					</toc>
					<after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HAC5B1D8161CA41E08FBC8D3B80F70559"><enum>8.</enum><header>Changes required to small bank holding company policy statement on assessment of financial and
			 managerial factors</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Before the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall revise the Small Bank Holding Company Policy Statement on Assessment of Financial and Managerial Factors (12 C.F.R. part 225—appendix C) to raise the consolidated asset threshold under such policy statement from $1,000,000,000 (as adjusted by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/250">Public Law 113–250</external-xref>) to $5,000,000,000.</text>
		</section><section id="H0BFBEC14E7D04773965D94B69195E18B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Safe harbor for certain loans held on portfolio</header>
 <subsection id="H139B595F24C74DFB83931B6783359FE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 129C of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639c">15 U.S.C. 1639c</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47E35996124D44A4AD81CD1DD2DDCA46" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H59EF4F51ECBF40B79843A5460F626B23"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Safe harbor for certain loans held on portfolio</header>
						<paragraph id="HA1B484AE0D2742C4A45078395BFA2256"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Safe harbor for creditors that are depository institutions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBDA31E2628B14197B7414E1CC44A42DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A creditor that is a depository institution shall not be subject to suit for failure to comply with subsection (a), (c)(1), or (f)(2) of this section or section 129H with respect to a residential mortgage loan, and the banking regulators shall treat such loan as a qualified mortgage, if—</text>
 <clause id="HE74ECFB0A1B644F0B74AC6F6BD9A1095"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the creditor has, since the origination of the loan, held the loan on the balance sheet of the creditor; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA55C1C89C9034409832E24887E5D1494"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all prepayment penalties with respect to the loan comply with the limitations described under subsection (c)(3).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DE5AB65FC9C4314BDEBB559ADDDBACB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for certain transfers</header><text>In the case of a depository institution that transfers a loan originated by that institution to another depository institution by reason of the bankruptcy or failure of the originating depository institution or the purchase of the originating depository institution, the depository institution transferring such loan shall be deemed to have complied with the requirement under subparagraph (A)(i).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E93BB0D033645AA8F7DD7560F61536B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safe harbor for mortgage originators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A mortgage originator shall not be subject to suit for a violation of section 129B(c)(3)(B) for steering a consumer to a residential mortgage loan if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H031C0AAF23794C21B25E9190DA6E920A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the creditor of such loan is a depository institution and has informed the mortgage originator that the creditor intends to hold the loan on the balance sheet of the creditor for the life of the loan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88CA5769D5C642A18714D5D69425353B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mortgage originator informs the consumer that the creditor intends to hold the loan on the balance sheet of the creditor for the life of the loan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77A6453C85AE4B488B1F68D7BD85FD66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HC04B062296BA48F1974031AF52BA9178"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Banking regulators</header><text>The term <quote>banking regulators</quote> means the Federal banking agencies, the Bureau, and the National Credit Union Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A433BE5B7374261BCBFA36ADC1C422E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>depository institution</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 19(b)(1) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/505">12 U.S.C. 505(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12CFE45AFBE84894AD2734D01D9970A0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Federal banking agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal banking agencies</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H684205D59849468898AE9053BF8F2D7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in the amendment made by this section may be construed as preventing a balloon loan from qualifying for the safe harbor provided under section 129C(j) of the Truth in Lending Act if the balloon loan otherwise meets all of the requirements under such subsection (j), regardless of whether the balloon loan meets the requirements described under clauses (i) through (iv) of section 129C(b)(2)(E) of such Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


