<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE7A6CAEBA289467EA7040AD1B660D461" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1188 IH: Credit Union Small Business Jobs Creation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1188</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150302">March 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Credit Union Act to provide certain credit unions with the authority to make additional member business loans, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H1463F44816B1444494E24140C268E048" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2B8ADEEA78D7495B8EF6B88AE16223D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Credit Union Small Business Jobs Creation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H65BE6B56F47B4AADBFE98C2348E31D40"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limits on member business loans</header> <subsection id="H042BF160BF294C48A4D0739064614932"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revised limitation and criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, section 107A(a) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1757a">12 U.S.C. 1757a(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3308EF63F194393AF9498D455C581CA" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HEA3A1C04EF644DC6AE16CBF36944A454"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header> 
<paragraph id="H1C6991BE9E474E3586FD7CA0BC874803"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an insured credit union may not make any member business loan that would result in the total amount of such loans outstanding at that credit union at any one time to be equal to more than the lesser of—</text> <subparagraph id="HA6EBC58AECF9404BA3176CC89EBEE560"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1.75 times the actual net worth of the credit union; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2ED65DC2E3A243CB9FC609B844E27C3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>12.25 percent of the total assets of the credit union.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCF60A883EDB42B9B59910BE7054A8F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional Authority</header><text>The Board may approve an application by an insured credit union upon a finding that the credit union meets the criteria under this paragraph to make 1 or more member business loans that would result in a total amount of such loans outstanding at any one time of not more than 27.5 percent of the total assets of the credit union, if the credit union—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H06423CF31BDF49CEA96DEC93F9765A17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>had member business loans outstanding at the end of each of the 4 consecutive quarters immediately preceding the date of the application, in a total amount of not less than 80 percent of the applicable limitation under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF703F18BA56547DD91C7774A397E86DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is well capitalized, as defined in section 216(c)(1)(A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA234C36B232242A3816C6723B7FF912A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>can demonstrate at least 5 years of experience of sound underwriting and servicing of member business loans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF27F743B83C748A1BEF3B26CCE19B73C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has the requisite policies and experience in managing member business loans; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H997E0A83DFF94C3EB086D4A08B955596"><enum>(E)</enum><text>has satisfied other standards that the Board determines are necessary to maintain the safety and soundness of the insured credit union.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA092DD7FDA5448EBE26D017314A5708"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of not being well capitalized</header><text>An insured credit union that has made member business loans under an authorization under paragraph (2) and that is not, as of its most recent quarterly call report, well capitalized, may not make any member business loans until such time as the credit union becomes well capitalized, as reflected in a subsequent quarterly call report, and obtains the approval of the Board.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7CA92FF8A9D24677A2317036C5938E27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header> 
<paragraph id="H9C2052B5ACC44285A1E70DA435D8C095"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tiered approval process</header><text>The Board shall develop a tiered approval process, under which an insured credit union gradually increases the amount of member business lending in a manner that is consistent with safe and sound operations, subject to the limits established under section 107A(a)(2) of the Federal Credit Union Act (as amended by this Act). The rate of increase under the process established under this paragraph may not exceed 30 percent per year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8C02658CC9F491EBCF0E04A2D586CF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking required</header><text>The Board shall issue proposed rules, not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, to establish the tiered approval process required under paragraph (1). The tiered approval process shall establish standards designed to ensure that the new business lending capacity authorized under the amendment made by subsection (a) is being used only by insured credit unions that are well managed and well capitalized, as required by the amendments made under subsection (a) and as defined by the rules issued by the Board under this paragraph.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8204007668664F649DBA1DD620FA2E25"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In issuing rules required under this subsection, the Board shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="H74FD570CC618410392D7C98769224F43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the experience level of the institutions, including a demonstrated history of sound member business lending;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAE19D804CC64D56A417645AB9F06623"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the criteria under section 107A(a)(2) of the Federal Credit Union Act, as amended by this Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H00B99842E69242C886BF2E70F79F6687"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other factors as the Board determines necessary or appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08DC7365B2A540FA89E6600BA6956045"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports to Congress on Member Business Lending</header> 
<paragraph id="HE24529DC43CF4BA594DF52481F698BA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report of the Board</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD6E0149F494F4308B0C185DF96F30B13"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Board shall submit a report to Congress on member business lending by insured credit unions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8C78DCA58AE40D6A9281DFE41542253"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H45D484E712F84ECDAC0C051E07B9A220"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the types and asset size of insured credit unions making member business loans and the member business loan limitations applicable to the insured credit unions;</text></clause> <clause id="H46A0574A50D14804B6513CD686C46875"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the overall amount and average size of member business loans by each insured credit union;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD05349223A33453E901DC686170183CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the ratio of member business loans by insured credit unions to total assets and net worth;</text></clause> <clause id="H55125F534AE644549F4A12DF79A04EC9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the performance of the member business loans, including delinquencies and net charge-offs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8EE2FB53C4C544E0A993BFD5BEA542F1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the effect of this section on the number of insured credit unions engaged in member business lending, any change in the amount of member business lending, and the extent to which any increase is attributed to the change in the limitation in section 107A(a) of the Federal Credit Union Act, as amended by this Act;</text></clause> <clause id="H2A05CF1CC4984E0D8EA7E131CA27A580"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number, types, and asset size of insured credit unions that were denied or approved by the Board for increased member business loans under section 107A(a)(2), as amended by this Act, including denials and approvals under the tiered approval process;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE22F84F44396416198A922F1C25C2E25"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the types and sizes of businesses that receive member business loans, the duration of the credit union membership of the businesses at the time of the loan, the types of collateral used to secure member business loans, and the income level of members receiving member business loans; and</text></clause> <clause id="H39CF00BA22C94180900E1F17A2D71487"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the effect of any increases in member business loans on the risk to the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund and the assessments on insured credit unions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01546B7E6EC34A3E943259A2FEC7E8B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO study and report</header> 
<subparagraph id="H96BC9D3C7B044B34ACA8AA62098963E4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the status of member business lending by insured credit unions, including—</text> <clause id="H9858D6A725FC43858E6D1F8E82496E7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>trends in such lending;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7E7412B9DD1E4A939CF1D6755C61B0D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>types and amounts of member business loans;</text></clause> <clause id="H0D54010A4C524C098A15BD22787B97CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of this section in enhancing small business lending;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0BD1F02152EC485A86B8FFAC2A9A82F6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative action, if any, with respect to such lending; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5F7CB2424644467596A7E94107B7B893"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any other information that the Comptroller General considers relevant with respect to such lending.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H453FE8CEF062457583E28938CDAA3E90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to Congress on the study required by subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC97184B21E4B44EEB46AF99CB21C3C5E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H98AE64906AA44EB7972EB6D7E72307E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Board</term> means the National Credit Union Administration Board;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EF63D949071401E91564988BED8D962"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>insured credit union</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BB552C6675B4F2DB42B1A4483DFCE5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>member business loan</term> has the meaning given that term in section 107A(c)(1) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1757a">12 U.S.C. 1757a(c)(1)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H788B84FCAD344ACAB0EC037C6B0FFC07"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>net worth</term> has the meaning given that term in section 107A(c)(2) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1757a">12 U.S.C. 1757a(c)(2)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC263FFF950C488CB73D9254D347FF47"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>well capitalized</term> has the meaning given that term in section 216(c)(1)(A) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1709d">12 U.S.C. 1709d(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

