<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB30B1209B08D426699176859AD5CCDF4" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1980 IH: Access to Consumer Energy Information Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1980</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To enhance consumer access to electricity information and allow for the adoption of innovative
			 products and services to help consumers manage their energy usage.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCE9075DA10EE457E8FF4379B2F1A5217" style="OLC">
 <section id="H932937C5C8B94810B93CD05183383345" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Consumer Energy Information Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>E–Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5C22035A5EAC4FA2813BD4FA7F121D4C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of Secretary</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text>
		</section><section id="H178A34ABFA33416D8E88ED38FBD20C40" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Consumer access to electric energy information</header>
 <subsection id="H4953F931F1D644C9A71429ECB3CCDE49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage and support the adoption of policies that allow electricity consumers access to their own electricity data.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H31BA72FD565D4DBD8AF4E44E87C18F7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility for State energy plans</header><text>Section 362(d) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6322">42 U.S.C. 6322(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA1F64B1164E34B25A657AA45E839A16B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (16), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD438708AFE8459F89D5B70AA0F61934"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (17) as paragraph (18); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAD906D369164743957494E55D9BAFC9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (16) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08ACE49137194F28ABA52D006E574B5B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H96DF6FDCD60246CFB08663897F7BF8CD"><enum>(17)</enum><text>programs—</text> <subparagraph id="HCDFE81523A134CBEB2151CBF8A94099D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to enhance consumer access to and understanding of energy usage and price information, including consumers’ own residential and commercial electricity information; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9AF78EDD0E44DA0976CD92A09D99DC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to allow for the development and adoption of innovative products and services to assist consumers in managing energy consumption and expenditures; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88A37640311F4923BED1974875FF870C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Voluntary guidelines for electric consumer access</header>
 <paragraph id="H773B6F3F42CA4A66A9538666B5EB38E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HA2FD1BF9D72F4E59B0A95AC601FD8430"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Retail electric energy information</header><text>The term <term>retail electric energy information</term> means—</text>
 <clause id="H93F8BBF1E4424189841F506ECEB35816"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the electric energy consumption of an electric consumer over a defined time period;</text> </clause><clause id="HC85D01DC35BC45718905E7D5432AECED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the retail electric energy prices or rates applied to the electricity usage for the defined time period described in clause (i) for the electric consumer;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H68FF35EB6BBE426086D248884882ED10"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the estimated cost of service by the consumer, including (if smart meter usage information is available) the estimated cost of service since the last billing cycle of the consumer; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H27A01B2FFB9E4E22B10474489DC89B54"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of nonresidential electric meters, any other electrical information that the meter is programmed to record (such as demand measured in kilowatts, voltage, frequency, current, and power factor).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC55AED8005244399A4ED4CD231A5E15A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Smart meter</header><text>The term <term>smart meter</term> means the device used by an electric utility that—</text> <clause id="HBDC9E5B2CA1346469DA77C4DF0F3288D"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCA13634900AD41CB850BB80E2F3C2309"><enum>(I)</enum><text>measures electric energy consumption by an electric consumer at the home or facility of the electric consumer in intervals of 1 hour or less; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6853123F0AB9474A91F5815F7099031E" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is capable of sending electric energy usage information through a communications network to the electric utility; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H9169D5A0F1E34E2787D4B9D616CC87AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the guidelines issued under paragraph (2).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51C8DAEDE2914E148E65681FC80D8A05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Voluntary guidelines for electric consumer access</header> <subparagraph id="HF522F6645544423098F00861F79807A6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall issue voluntary guidelines that establish model standards for implementation of retail electric energy information access in States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29DB64BA5145404180EBD4E7E97CE741"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Before issuing the voluntary guidelines, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HB1AD6DA41CC54B27BD7115AFC248A589"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consult with—</text>
 <subclause id="HF8CCEC20D8134D2D9FFCA40915F1F937"><enum>(I)</enum><text>State and local regulatory authorities, including the National Association of Regulatory Utility Commissioners;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEC45B7A7E07E49A19D7C9D858C9A42A3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other appropriate Federal agencies, including the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H83FB27C4AC9C4C5CA0E823554D7EAC3E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>consumer and privacy advocacy groups;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H77E77D524EFB4E4FA7287604FE532C56"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>utilities;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H0D3DE168C8FE4FD5A0A16E18CF6B092B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the National Association of State Energy Officials; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H64D3C37EB05246D8A780F329B6973581"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>other appropriate entities, including groups representing commercial and residential building owners and groups that represent demand response and electricity data devices and services; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H82959AAAE7A34D8FA6AB507F4031A30B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide notice and opportunity for comment.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD32D008F7C6742DEBF749B543490AB24"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State and local regulatory action</header><text>In issuing the voluntary guidelines, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be guided by actions taken by State and local regulatory authorities to ensure electric consumer access to retail electric energy information, including actions taken after consideration of the standard established under section 111(d)(19) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2621">16 U.S.C. 2621(d)(19)</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C8D7AC8FC7D4859A078157B40AC87BA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Contents</header>
 <clause id="H8E7306178C8D44E79C864F4C890C27DD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The voluntary guidelines shall provide guidance on issues necessary to carry out this subsection, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HC93F005B38344AEEA96380CC52DE30A8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the timeliness and specificity of retail electric energy information;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H99E85157109948C49849CD8F835E716C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>appropriate nationally recognized open standards for data;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H37C1360338274845B9CC99E6AEA3CA0F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the protection of data security and electric consumer privacy, including consumer consent requirements; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H16F281A4BDF044B49C502D380114ECB1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>issues relating to access of electric energy information for owners and managers of multitenant commercial and residential buildings.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCFE525AA65A14A2C8285E955EB1CF636"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The voluntary guide­lines shall include guidance that—</text> <subclause id="H02B35DF4246D4559A3924F7150BECE2D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>retail electric energy information should be made available to electric consumers (and third-party designees of the electric consumers) in the United States—</text>
 <item id="H3AB4C9DF944D49139FDE3313D296DCE4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in an electronic machine readable form, without additional charge, in conformity with standards developed through a voluntary, consensus-based, multistakeholder process;</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="HCF82B7271C8348769A735064A441E2DA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in as close to real-time as is reasonably practicable;</text> </item><item id="H29B2D041F4C542F59D0540A1747B0503"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>at the level of specificity that the data is transmitted by the meter or as is reasonably practicable; and</text>
 </item><item id="HE559B5E388A84565A8D265D007120248"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>in a manner that provides adequate protections for the security of the information and the privacy of the electric consumer;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H96B086765054466D8FFF5427FE7B2705"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">electric utilities should, when a smart meter is servicing a consumer, communicate energy usage information to a device or network of an electric consumer or a device or network of a third party authorized by the consumer, and where feasible should provide to the consumer or third-party designee, at a minimum, access to usage information (not including price information) of the consumer directly from the smart meter in as close to real-time as is reasonably practicable;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H04F71E702A374C268965AAE68E9CC41C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>retail electric energy information should be provided by the electric utility of the consumer or such other entity as may be designated by the applicable electric retail regulatory authority;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H968D847FCB01430FB03A7AFA453C20D3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>retail electric energy information of the consumer should be made available to the consumer through a website or other electronic access authorized by the electric consumer, for a period of at least 13 months after the date on which the usage occurred;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2703F5F774BE43B380FCFF48605BD3D3"><enum>(V)</enum><text>consumer access to data, including data provided to owners and managers of commercial and multifamily buildings with multiple tenants, should not interfere with or compromise the integrity, security, or privacy of the operations of a utility and the electric consumer;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE12301304D754FF69924D1E55D01208B"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>electric energy information relating to usage information generated by devices in or on the property of the consumer that is transmitted to the electric utility should be made available to the electric consumer or the third-party agent designated by the electric consumer; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H55B0CE6CD7DB44758E9C1C8DDFEE9DF5"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the same privacy and security requirements applicable to the contracting utility should apply to third-party agents contracting with a utility to process the customer data of that utility.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC00DF6745C5418DA3BC20E9B9AAB4F2"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Revisions</header><text>The Secretary shall periodically review and, as necessary, revise the voluntary guidelines to reflect changes in technology, privacy needs, and the market for electric energy and services.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A12C76191D045E4841FDB31758BC730"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Verification and implementation</header>
 <paragraph id="HD853F9AA2C594DCF8A14C5C5EBC624BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State may submit to the Secretary a description of the data sharing policies of the State relating to consumer access to electric energy information for certification by the Secretary that the policies meet the voluntary guidelines issued under subsection (c)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B0379C9BFB6482B90F885D234C22649"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall make Federal amounts available to any State that has data sharing policies described in paragraph (1) that the Secretary certifies meets the voluntary guidelines issued under subsection (c)(2) to assist the State in implementing programs described in section 362(d)(17) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16442566F5FF4656AE824BAE8A934667"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2016, to remain available until expended.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


