<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H66653DB246BA4FCE89CD6161A7BCAB75" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3643 IH: Interim Consolidated Storage Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3643</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150929">September 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000182">Mr. Neugebauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to enter into
			 contracts for the storage of certain high-level radioactive waste and
			 spent nuclear fuel, take title to certain high-level radioactive waste and
			 spent nuclear fuel, and make certain expenditures from the Nuclear Waste
			 Fund.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H06E555E9934E4333B54D1AFA4597263A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8AC1DBED004248E4A79DA361BFE08688" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Interim Consolidated Storage Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9F1D011CD7F945B091CCC6A385E3B7CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of interim consolidated storage facility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H639D8012DAC4435EBD6008310926AFBF" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H7BF486CC0A874E91ADE8E00C3DEDA306"><enum>(35)</enum><text>The term <quote>interim consolidated storage facility</quote> means a facility that possesses a specific license issued by the Commission that authorizes storage of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel received from the Secretary or from two or more persons that generate or hold title to high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel generated at a civilian nuclear power reactor.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H3545FDC121F24C8784DD815463611DAB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interim consolidated storage of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel</header>
 <subsection id="H24746EACD83946D3AE3CAC7B429431A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Storage of spent nuclear fuel</header><text>Section 135(h) of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10155">42 U.S.C. 10155(h)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in section 302, and subtitle I of title I</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HD37D599F2B6448D790B3A0D4BB9A337C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim consolidated storage</header><text>Title I of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10121">42 U.S.C. 10121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HE08D7073773B4DEB8CEF49501721D0C0" style="OLC">
					<subtitle id="H02ECD4EA853040059F6CEDAEC9504378"><enum>I</enum><header>Interim Consolidated Storage</header>
						<section id="H6ABE779670C349ABA5CAA7B8A4BD3D32"><enum>190.</enum><header>Interim consolidated storage</header>
 <subsection id="H9A319B9EF4544FF3AB882034B7D1D338"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may enter into contracts for the storage of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel with any person that holds a license for an interim consolidated storage facility.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5DD104A44B424F88BDBCEE4360AC6FE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of High-Level Radioactive Waste</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subtitle and section 302, the term <quote>high-level radioactive waste</quote> includes Greater than Class C waste as defined in section 72.3 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations. Nothing in this section or section 191 shall be interpreted to affect existing judicial interpretation of the term high-level radioactive waste or to require the disposal of Greater than Class C waste in a repository.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H71F4293DF34843F0AE85529570C92DAE"><enum>191.</enum><header>Contracts</header>
 <subsection id="HA3933396EDB24878900B9FD4193FC8C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into new contracts or modify existing contracts with any person who generates or holds title to high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel of domestic origin for the acceptance of title and subsequent storage of such waste or fuel at an interim consolidated storage facility, with priority for storage given to high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel located on sites without an operating nuclear reactor.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H79C0D77F6FAE4928A373C070FE802093"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contract terms</header><text>A contract entered into or modified under this section shall provide that acceptance by the Secretary, and transfer of title under subsection (d), of any high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel for an interim consolidated storage facility satisfies the Secretary’s responsibility under a contract entered into under section 302(a) to accept title to such waste or fuel for disposal, with respect to such accepted waste or fuel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H819F266ACD0B49DBB3968F3F59F63240"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall not require a person to settle claims against the United States for the breach of a contract entered into under section 302(a) for the disposal of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel as a condition precedent of entering into or modifying a contract under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA5E60DFB747F419F8677E35D14BE2765"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Title to material</header><text>Delivery, and acceptance by the Secretary, of any high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel for an interim consolidated storage facility shall constitute a transfer to the Secretary of title to such waste or fuel.</text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE59300468DD7434C81A4C7EBB8D1AB0A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nuclear waste fund</header><text>Section 302(d) of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10222">42 U.S.C. 10222(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HAD279DE21B784178B378BA2AAF0A6BBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>in a monitored, retrievable storage site</quote> and inserting <quote>in an interim consolidated storage facility or monitored retrievable storage site,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H109B1248C23843EAA77C0200A72E300D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF53DB3776EB44680B93E27252CAD4681"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a monitored, retrievable storage site</quote> and inserting <quote>an interim consolidated storage facility site, a monitored retrievable storage site,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BB59BAE2CCB4534BFB0072E9E19DB96"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>such repository, monitored, retrievable storage facility</quote> and inserting <quote>such repository, interim consolidated storage facility, monitored retrievable storage facility,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H925AA80D64504A6D819C483841EE2F0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD56655D0A3B427E97AA8D5E120E582F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (7);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5EC474BDA604DCC8FCCA0B1981EBA06"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (5) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H6D109080C0374A67BD057E075CB0EF44" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H121EEF63A40944F1890236C1CA42E176"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the fees and costs in connection with the storage of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel in an interim consolidated storage facility; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EA1D76DCF524697A6B6E3B36FF38A20"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>For purposes of the preceding sentence, fees and costs described in paragraph (6) shall not be considered amounts for the construction or expansion of any facility.</quote> after <quote>this or subsequent legislation.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB7BECE538914FC591E20E3E0C17698C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriations from the waste fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302(e)(2) of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10222">42 U.S.C. 10222(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6FBDD09971E84A73AB48A98D6217428B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(A)</quote> before <quote>The Secretary shall submit</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0937B4ADD03447D1845F4AA4471064F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69300F151D5C424986C03B32B2C6CFF8" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H425B03AA115244C7A5071822BABE258B" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), subject to subparagraph (C), necessary amounts shall be available to the Secretary from the Waste Fund without additional appropriations to pay for the following:</text>
 <clause id="HEB24EEF9D4DB4A8B861B6FBB5C08E971"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Costs described in subsection (d)(4) in connection with storage in an interim consolidated storage facility.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF11A5518F6DF4B8A93B0BA8DFA10D3B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs described in subsection (d)(5) in connection with an interim consolidated storage facility.</text> </clause><clause id="H2DC57D4ACA3340B3B90F75F8F8129A6F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fees and costs described in subsection (d)(6).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58CF062DEAE64AA3B8BB76990AB5C113" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary shall not expend, on fees for dry modes of storage of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel, amounts totaling more than the cumulative amount of interest generated by the Waste Fund each fiscal year, beginning in fiscal year 2016.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


