<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H337039E6D1E34E6398C80FA8DB5DDD65" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 992 IH: Veterans Air Travel Streamlining Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 992</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150213">February 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To waive the application fee for veterans with a service-connected disability rated at 50 percent
			 or more who apply to participate in the Transportation Security
			 Administration’s  Pre✓™ program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H86A08AE6C45043A7AA4F2A26BFF1D466" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA0650850E7FF4707949140E16045FCB4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Air Travel Streamlining Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4EB85480E3E4424D87257E55D7576198"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waiver of application fee for veterans applying for TSA Pre✓™</header> <subsection id="H62515BC4C29F4B8482FE3C4DB3BB395A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) shall waive the application fee for veterans with a service-connected disability rated at 50 percent or more who apply to participate in the TSA’s Pre✓™ program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE1898CF677B34B5593FB1FCD0F676B44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of verification system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the TSA and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a system to verify whether a veteran’s disability is service-connected and such veteran’s disability rating for veterans who apply to participate in the TSA’s Pre✓™ program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBFB1524FC8984361BD51F764B0483670"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed as in any way affecting the requirements for veterans described in this Act to otherwise meet the eligibility requirements for participation in the TSA’s Pre✓™ program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB91E8B7D28B3418EB2AE0787D65D8714"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>veteran</quote>, <quote>service-connected</quote>, and <quote>disability</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

