<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA7DFBABEC6F4472DA2B0DA54B1C93AED" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2100 IH: Girls Count Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2100</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150429">April 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to provide assistance to support the rights of women and girls in developing countries, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7E6363694289491A9987915D53A414A0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC51AEF2B04064A429F2AC92083371FCB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Girls Count Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC6257FBD250A40AD9173AE7D9E9E3D8D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD2B2C1476F4B46288A8CF85102F8953C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the United States Census Bureau’s 2013 international figures, 1 person in 12—or close to 900,000,000 people—is a girl or young woman age 10 through 24.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F1F7D44334F4B0DB971B54015BE9A0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Census Bureau’s data also asserts that young people are the fastest growing segment of the population in developing countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2AF8080E7BB54D30A442441B7CDE3DCC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Even though most countries do have birth registration laws, four out of ten babies born in 2012 were not registered worldwide. Moreover, an estimated 36 percent of children under the age of five worldwide (about 230 million children) do not possess a birth certificate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBEBF13A63254CBC980653D8A789DA16"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A nationally recognized proof of birth system is important to determining a child’s citizenship, nationality, place of birth, parentage, and age. Without such a system, a passport, driver’s license, or other identification card is difficult to obtain. The lack of such documentation can prevent girls and women from officially participating in and benefitting from the formal economic, legal, and political sectors in their countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6139185A4324D22A15D8A73DB3318AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The lack of birth registration among girls worldwide is particularly concerning as it can exacerbate the disproportionate vulnerability of women to trafficking, child marriage, and lack of access to health and education services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57A6ED17CA574633882769CB6D46A2B7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A lack of birth registration among women and girls can also aggravate what, in many places, amounts to an already reduced ability to seek employment, participate in civil society, or purchase or inherit land and other assets.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H688EFE908D454464B9AB40085906D4AB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Girls undertake much of the domestic labor needed for poor families to survive: carrying water, harvesting crops, tending livestock, caring for younger children, and doing chores.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E7DD16B04A942EA8103B8230F803A76"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Accurate assessments of access to education, poverty levels, and overall census activities are hampered by the lack of official information on women and girls. Without this rudimentary information, assessments of foreign assistance and domestic social welfare programs are difficult to gauge</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA195E5EE1556497B893C1BF4319E044D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>To help ensure that women and girls are considered in United States foreign assistance policies and programs, that their needs are addressed in the design, implementation, and evaluation of foreign assistance programs, and that women and girls have the opportunity to succeed, it is important that girls be counted and have access to birth certificates and other official documentation.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H15B77A33B95441348CCCD13B9D91802B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9F8FFB56AFCB416F8B466E1F7D994F74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourage countries to support the rule of law and ensure girls and boys of all ages are able to fully participate in society, including by providing birth certifications and other official documentation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B452510994B4E56BC00BA9E360BB65E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance training and capacity-building in key developing countries, local nongovernmental organizations, and other civil society organizations, including faith-based organizations and organizations representing children and families in the design, implementation, and monitoring of programs under this Act, to effectively address the needs of birth registries in countries where girls are systematically undercounted; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95B95ED999C04DDA8323F75445FBE797"><enum>(3)</enum><text>incorporate into the design, implementation, and evaluation of policies and programs measures to evaluate the impact that such policies and programs have on girls.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H1322B27F04294633AA27D6F75234D77E"><enum>4.</enum><header>United states assistance to support counting of girls in the developing world</header> <subsection id="H38DAB9B0BBC049AAAF784D65C5881EEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator are authorized to prioritize and advance ongoing efforts to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE816FA71128A4C2CB26719AF19853B13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support programs that will contribute to improved and sustainable Civil Registration and Vital Statistics Systems (CRVS) with a focus on birth registration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B815CB0A03C490BA69261B952BBBF87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support programs that build the capacity of developing countries’ national and local legal and policy frameworks to prevent discrimination against girls in gaining access to birth certificates, particularly where this may help prevent exploitation, violence, and other abuse; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB2A985E52EA42EF97C1FB68C9BCECFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support programs and key ministries, including programs and ministries relating to interior, youth, and education, to help increase property rights, social security, home ownership, land tenure security, inheritance rights, access to education, and economic and entrepreneurial opportunities, particularly for women and girls.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HA9A5C0622B0D49988BCC7A59932AA825"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with multilateral organizations</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator are authorized to coordinate with the World Bank, relevant United Nations agencies and programs, and other relevant organizations to encourage and work with countries to enact, implement, and enforce laws that specifically collect data on girls and establish registration programs to ensure girls are appropriately counted and have the opportunity to be active participants in the social, legal, and political sectors of society in their countries.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H75530F814453442E9FDA62511F528C93"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with private sector and civil society organizations</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator are authorized to work with the United States, international, and local private sector and civil society organizations, including faith-based organizations, to advocate for the registration and documentation of all girls and boys in developing countries, in order to help prevent exploitation, violence, and other abuses and to help provide economic and social opportunities.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1420D204014D441783C1F1692C441C1A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary and the Administrator shall include in relevant evaluations and reports to Congress the following information:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB6E614F4540F4CAE8FBDD2C88ADA3C9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To the extent practicable, a breakdown of United States foreign assistance beneficiaries by age, gender, marital status, location, and school enrollment status.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C36421521A94DC1B6B8D216728D5657"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description, as appropriate, of how United States foreign assistance benefits girls.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H648E8D1DA00F4442ACEAC69762F5DDDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Specific information, as appropriate, on programs that address the particular needs of girls.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H94A62E7BBB124176A4A790564532C281"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H66F98C17F7184DE8B7DF1C051FD4F524"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC31A79F9CEC54DEDADFE09F01077B66E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign assistance</header><text>The term <term>foreign assistance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 634(b) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394">22 U.S.C. 2394(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3240D69327184D42AEDD7CC8CE1074E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H76EE831330834299A177EA1651C8D394"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall expire on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


