<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9D0C22B1F09D451DBDDAEF4332FD899F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 653 IH: FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 653</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150202">February 2, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Freedom of Information
			 Act), to provide for greater public access to information, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H10EE0438C5994056A8978764DE1231E5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD1BABD2D61664E4583C9FB7940982529" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FOIA Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8346E936119E4B208478A08EC6556589"><enum>2.</enum><header>Freedom of Information Act amendments</header> <subsection id="HE7D606D99A8246589F87341FA0C18352"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Electronic accessibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 552 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCDED1FAD0D8F4AFBBD90B2A5DDD610DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1F277FC7383443F7B50DD6F73379C958"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause id="H727DD6F151A249759FF3063D55102FC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>for public inspection and copying</quote> and inserting <quote>in an electronic, publicly accessible format</quote> each place it appears;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB3F58B1C76A5468B80560C41DC2199F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H453DE7F63D8141ADBED90D024CAEACF0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (E) and inserting the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C8291A784394FCCB04F78A111DD190A" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="HD7E6D42C4B1F4AF09E3668844ABA303E" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">copies of all releasable records, regardless of form or format, that have been requested three or more times under paragraph (3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD757EE2EF48D4A02B06502B3EA2E1CFA" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a general index of the records referred to under subparagraphs (D) and (E);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause><clause id="H5E56E308F9A7498C9837827B80E5663E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the matter following subparagraph (F) (as added by clause (ii) of this subparagraph)—</text>
 <subclause id="H90050833A5514D40AA59085B523DE897"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (D)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (D) and (E)</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H6812DC29F60E4F27BB4054083B64DC68"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (E)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (F)</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6401D50758984BC888A452ED3367D010"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (7)—</text> <clause id="H0205635F6D3F49AC83BD1F75C123B579"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>that will take longer than ten days to process</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBDB46B36AED84F8CB78BBC2B124F17AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>automated</quote> after <quote>provides</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA46A92AA55D4EC5B4C4F30380771D81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>make publicly available upon request</quote> and inserting <quote>make available in an electronic, publicly accessible format</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62DD3A29B5E643D487D75ED86DDE8F91"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6ECFD0C9ADE47A3A2125BFDEACDF4AA" style="USC"> <subsection id="H0B865C490B124699AB2C0F6801CFC74F"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Consolidated online request portal</header> <paragraph id="HE24B98DE01F84BDD916DEEE0149F52A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request portal required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall ensure the operation of a consolidated online request portal that allows a member of the public to submit a request for records under subsection (a) to any agency from a single website. The portal may include any additional tools the Director of the Office of Management and Budget finds will improve the implementation of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H431F713848384B318FF348FED6B7B60D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This subsection shall not be construed to alter the power of any other agency to create or maintain an independent online portal for the submission of a request for records under this section. The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall establish standards for interoperability between the portal required under paragraph (1) and other request processing software used by agencies subject to this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H30876C1E243440E0BEC1327D32CD59AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presumption of openness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC4C116DFCC0C4722AA0A9FB2EBC569BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting after <quote>with the agency</quote> the following:</text>
 <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4E128E3B8E5A4DE39CBBC5E78FC3822E" style="USC"><text>, excluding—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H035A91BA914A4DFBBA87254D9E132CDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">records that embody the working law, effective policy, or the final decision of the agency; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H05FC50EB14F64D4A909315FF9EAB36A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>records or information created 25 years or more before the date on which a request is made under subsection (a)(3);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B8C467C07043248CFAFFC494BF6AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (9), by inserting before <quote>Any reasonably segregable portion</quote> the following: <quote>An agency may not withhold information under this subsection unless such agency reasonably foresees that disclosure would cause specific identifiable harm to an interest protected by an exemption, or if disclosure is prohibited by law.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D41382D5611407C883DFC3B75CAA42B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>The Office of Government Information Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 552 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H77FAA4BC6048474996855C9D195B8F6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(4)(A)(i), by striking <quote>the Director of the Office of Management and Budget</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Government Information Services,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8052C586FB0D4917B56685EA392BCC09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (h) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD094471775A4AAF9270837AE237F05A" style="USC"> <subsection id="H03C31BB82F42445CB95C256A120F590B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>The Office of Government Information Services</header> <paragraph id="HC82275C513264A2BA32A2C6FA48D6DBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Office of Government Information Services within the National Archives and Records Administration. The head of the Office is the Director of the Office of Government Information Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9F8508D62774C15A1FF0B3311C6FCD7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of FOIA policy, procedure, and compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Government Information Services shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE06F49E920A743EB9A52BA7C5C827F4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review policies and procedures of agencies under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D68FB829A42436F829D8DD841909959"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review compliance with this section by agencies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C4A8AF2A424C5BB0BCE54C75BAB323"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify methods that improve compliance under this section that may include—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30C2E0C913044A648E9D94AE693CC9FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the timely processing of requests submitted to agencies under this section;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HEADA813D36C243CAAAA1A82FE7A4C3D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the system for assessing fees and fee waivers under this section; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H714A7D39EB8A4213A02B15EC4CAA11CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the use of any exemption under subsection (b); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB8F63A8D8FE4E9A86B95787E921C2EF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review and provide guidance to agencies on the use of fees and fee waivers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H245D4008853A4F38AEB1BFDEF93D173B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mediation services</header><text>The Office of Government Information Services shall offer mediation services to resolve disputes between persons making requests under this section and agencies as a non-exclusive alternative to litigation and, at the discretion of the Office, may issue advisory opinions if mediation has not resolved the dispute.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H980F9210A873441AAF20423AB1139D8F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission of report</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB62F61F5DD6C4139A566363566E0EF8F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Government Information Services shall not less than annually submit to the committees described in subparagraph (C) and the President a report on the findings from the information reviewed and identified under paragraph (2), a summary of the Office’s activities under paragraph (3) (including any advisory opinions issued), and legislative and regulatory recommendations to improve the administration of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55457938D90D438B8B4270130984DAF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Electronic availability of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall make available any report submitted under paragraph (A) in a publicly accessible format.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA99CD6A4013D4B23A9C81030CA6BB955"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Congressional submission of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The committees described in this subparagraph are the following:</text> <clause id="H422F0F1436FF418E839D820916B3CDA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B6953C85C744379B4882DBC247E7C7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Judiciary of the Senate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AACCEEDB642409895A6BD041A4CCDD7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Direct submission of reports and testimony</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any report submitted under paragraph (A), any testimony, or any other communication to Congress shall be submitted directly to the committees and the President, without any requirement that any officer or employee outside of the Office of Government Information Services, including the Archivist of the United States and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, review such report, testimony, or other communication.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6ECF80BFFBB47A98C33CE03C877DFD6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Submission of additional information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Government Information Services may submit additional information to Congress and the President that the Director determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H209FDCE710EA4D70B1E0FF0825DF31F3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual meeting required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than once a year, the Office of Government Information Services shall hold a meeting that is open to the public on the review and reports by the Office and permit interested persons to appear and present oral or written statements at such meeting.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H276BDDFAA1334F75BFE1F4C6DFF2A1DC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public resources</header><text>Section 552(a)(6)(A) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFFE0B7362E0A41BA89D0716D523F40A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>of such determination and the reasons therefor, and of the right of such person to appeal to the head of the agency any adverse determination; and</quote> and inserting the following: “of—</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5DD1CAC968394DD5AA5AAD5C3F31D5FA" style="USC">
 <subclause id="HA745938DEA8C42C995E0088B4B76926B" indent="up2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such determination and the reasons therefor;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC27C26FA2201477FB0DA3C279EBA1982" indent="up2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the right of such person to seek assistance from the agency FOIA Public Liaison; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7F22E7E2D25B45B9829D25197A44588F" indent="up2"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the right of such person to appeal to the head of the agency any adverse determination, within a period determined by the agency that is not less than 90 days after the receipt of such adverse determination; and</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1F95A362C01462299CE440D38F925D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period and inserting the following: <quote>and the right of such person to seek dispute resolution services from the agency FOIA Public Liaison or the Office of Government Information Services.</quote></text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C0CC1CAE53B47AC812645CD6BB9C86F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional disclosure of information requirements</header><text>Section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DEB1FA01ED34DF29295B983636995E6" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="HC1FCD95888E14A70AC2B9A9061D8616B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Disclosure of information for increased public understanding of the Government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H072B3250A2D943E49F432977CB09B77F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the records of such agency to determine whether the release of the records would be in the public interest because it is likely to contribute significantly to public understanding of the operations or activities of the Government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8C3C02E9C0C415A81734B803AA084A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for records determined to be in the public interest under subparagraph (A), reasonably segregate and redact any information exempted from disclosure under subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DF0753258424729BC2F9308161FB4D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make available in an electronic, publicly accessible format, any records identified in subparagraph (A), as modified pursuant to subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF39B8AE30A84521A5AB081EDAC08C30"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Increased disclosure of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE40179BC34DF4534BC27F120753B71A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make information public to the greatest extent possible through modern technology to—</text>
 <clause id="H5CAB72B3623D4E2D84C21FD78EC66C45"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inform the public of the operations and activities of the Government; and</text> </clause><clause id="HADCA2A8B24474252B727A5F7D3F97AAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure timely disclosure of information; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H23240ECB66DF49FC9EA4DBAE647CA001"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish procedures for identifying categories of records that may be disclosed regularly and additional records of interest to the public that are appropriate for public disclosure, and for posting such records in an electronic, publicly accessible format.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H90F0B137EA7549FBB5BAF09FD78EF829"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report on categories of information for disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every two years thereafter, the Director of the Office of Information Policy of the Department of Justice, after consultation with agencies selected by the Director, shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Judiciary of the Senate a report that identifies categories of records that would be appropriate for proactive disclosure, and shall make such report available in an electronic, publicly accessible format.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4CF837C3B6AB4EDFB172416E444064C7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Agency FOIA report</header><text>Section 552(e) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H81E6AC7DB2D348D2A62BC6AD416E8A98"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H29B9DCBB0EA642A3B2E12183EFD205FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and to the Director of the Office of Government Information Services</quote> after <quote>the Attorney General of the United States</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8EABE410A5546479C872A2D163B5D63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (N), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CD02EBBC6644D4A9166934D43E455C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81A4713A8BD84EE2AFC91C00B353AA3C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H018F94DBC60947698CD3C16AD3AE01CC" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="H10187313468E4156B9609FEB85F7977B" indent="up1"><enum>(P)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of times the agency invoked a law enforcement exclusion under subsection (c);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B697F4D440141EEB50B7BCE3C770DF0" indent="up1"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>the number of times the agency engaged in dispute resolution with the assistance of the Office of Government Information Services or the FOIA Public Liaison;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79F92970F3364710A348787F6B729B5A" indent="up1"><enum>(R)</enum><text>the number of records that were made available in an electronic, publicly accessible format under subsection (a)(2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3CA54BCA728A4B2AB5AF420B8289135F" indent="up1"><enum>(S)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of times the agency assessed a search or duplication fee under subsection (a)(4)(A) and did not comply with a time limit under subsection (a)(6).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEE3E0ABB45146A492F36E66EF7F5000"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C24CD18D71B41BC9074A32769521527" style="USC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB4BD09EF0B594EBEAC4CFE23C19FF713"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electronic accessibility of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall make each such report available in an electronic, publicly accessible format. In addition, each agency shall make the raw statistical data used in its reports available in a timely manner in an electronic, publicly accessible format. Such data shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCC55C980F3974FFD8DE83A6341C4E9E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made available without charge, license, or registration requirement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H10240ACD1CF047D0A48DC138A4B74DF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>capable of being searched and aggregated; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8DEEFCD3C8804035A06D501EF5D2D6CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>permitted to be downloaded and downloaded in bulk.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE56787CAF64AC3B40D23E2B7C06FD6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H451E2D2D014B4D978C18C9F65D6612F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Committee on Government Reform and Oversight</quote> and inserting <quote>Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBEAE2285A234B3AAC6611F1BB8E3325"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Governmental Affairs</quote> and inserting <quote>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7F66C4BE9874B7DB166C84AC8957F31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>April 1</quote> and inserting <quote>March 1</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA8103A62933449FA7386DD7525EC181"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDB834C0C0C61495D99FC961282A6F195"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and the Director of the Office of Government Information Services</quote> after <quote>the Director of the Office of Management and Budget</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8BE13CDAE0B42A7B4249A7745A5063A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>by October 1, 1997</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H183EE9A90F8E46FFAA58CB55B6B9639C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (6) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0167A5E4C5043CA830D39E125DD5787" style="USC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF9B4419F8D044CBAA8355FEFCF4C98CC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Attorney General FOIA report</header> <subparagraph id="HFD8A21BA64E14AD4A33263E5B6ACDE08"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General of the United States shall submit to Congress and the President an annual report on or before March 1 of each calendar year which shall include for the prior calendar year—</text>
 <clause id="HBA9DCCC354F6401189D99B11B043ED34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a listing of the number of cases arising under this section;</text> </clause><clause id="H2C7DA54DDC9441CFACB51BC996E534BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each subsection under this section, each paragraph of the subsection, and any exemption, if applicable, involved in each case, the disposition of such case, and the cost, fees, and penalties assessed under subparagraphs (E), (F), and (G) of subsection (a)(4); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H95855094E8124C469CC0CCEB8F91C551"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the efforts undertaken by the Department of Justice to encourage agency compliance with this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA19DD8D5733C47418E2A79E7AE3AE4D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Electronic availability</header><text>The Attorney General of the United States—</text> <clause id="H3EF75CA1F10746E6B72DD4E3F0D483AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall make each report described under subparagraph (A) available in an electronic, publicly accessible format; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H951AE90F580148E7921CA2DF8C9CDD7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall make the raw statistical data used in each report available in an electronic, publicly accessible format, which shall be—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H3A7A32A5DF1C472688808AF3F5B57226"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made available without charge, license, or registration requirement;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HB224D2E2A3ED49E1AC067F0720A51C57"><enum>(II)</enum><text>capable of being searched and aggregated; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H942B7FBD3CF54F549F9DBCAA00D39CAF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>permitted to be downloaded, including downloaded in bulk.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFDF37942147F4F6FB1E1552EC1EE40B8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Search or duplication fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 552(a)(4)(A)(viii) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Any agency that does assess search or duplication fees after failing to comply with a time limit under paragraph (6) shall provide written notice to the requester of the circumstance that justifies the fees. If an agency fails to provide such notice, the agency may not assess search or duplication fees.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7F2D550FEE50483690CF59B04C178519"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office</header><text>Subsection (i) of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04B22EA5C80C4471AA2B5D49B3BE0FDB" style="USC"> <subsection id="HEAEB9351DD42472AB8C94FEC180FC6FF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Government Accountability Office shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7E7A4E89E69F478790F868238AEA2B1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct audits of administrative agencies on compliance with and implementation of the requirements of this section and issue reports detailing the results of such audits;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF7CA92EA64641478ABBF597647C1968"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">catalog the number of exemptions under subsection (b)(3) and agency use of such exemptions; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1444401265024D548249CCC087389AFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review and prepare a report on the processing of requests by agencies for information pertaining to an entity that has received assistance under title I of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5211">12 U.S.C. 5211 et seq.</external-xref>) during any period in which the Government owns or owned more than 50 percent of the stock of such entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCFB9E3474A5747DABD755DE44F724692"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Chief FOIA Officer responsibilities; Council; review</header><text>Section 552 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3625040D96D947AD8E79F47706AA0AF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsections (j) and (k); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H824B9A19CA0E42BBB7BC16F70DFCB799"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (i), the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H691FCD3BEDD64BE896B01DD3C713A500" style="USC"> <subsection id="H68670A56A00B4A038B90C74F0E26FE7E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Chief FOIA Officer</header> <paragraph id="HB1A9A3E3D0D046EA8E41225714AC325E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall designate a Chief FOIA Officer who shall be a senior official of such agency (at the Assistant Secretary or equivalent level).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A297A8D98C14B6AA7F8C7FE1892D3D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief FOIA Officer of each agency shall, subject to the authority of the head of the agency—</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B5FF4ECAE6E46ACBAC024500FDAD710"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have agency-wide responsibility for efficient and appropriate compliance with this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CA4727620B84E71A5078CF9892483C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitor implementation of this section throughout the agency and keep the head of the agency, the chief legal officer of the agency, and the Attorney General appropriately informed of the agency’s performance in implementing this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA371E6B388A94CBCB5201FEBD97EF946"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommend to the head of the agency such adjustments to agency practices, policies, personnel, and funding as may be necessary to improve its implementation of this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H740B44BF6BC4479F9ACE6E0875366C48"><enum>(D)</enum><text>review and report to the Attorney General, through the head of the agency, at such times and in such formats as the Attorney General may direct, on the agency’s performance in implementing this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A1E2291370D4780B0FA7B20D54E25B6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>facilitate public understanding of the purposes of the statutory exemptions of this section by including concise descriptions of the exemptions in both the agency’s handbook issued under subsection (g), and the agency’s annual report on this section, and by providing an overview, where appropriate, of certain general categories of agency records to which those exemptions apply;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC84AB035563243E99EEFEB6EE70F6226"><enum>(F)</enum><text>serve as the primary agency liaison with the Office of Government Information Services and the Office of Information Policy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AB3833E1B3748AD81E9010CD322F3E1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>designate one or more FOIA Public Liaisons.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H073B2DA630E14A0BBB0D467EA8AA298A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance review required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief FOIA Officer of each agency shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA6DBB2EB8A4342F2B2EBB42D38F383F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review, not less than annually, all aspects of the agency’s administration of this section to ensure compliance with the requirements of this section, including—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HE14EEF485B2C425A94BB4F9EDFF27A6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>agency regulations;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9288C261CB964BB292A4897D8BD1CDAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclosure of records required under paragraphs (2), (8), and (9) of subsection (a);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H835214FCD0A9435D908AB1D92101E40F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assessment of fees and determination of eligibility for fee waivers;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HC2B5C6D906D04040A8A999FDF55FFDC0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the timely processing of requests for information under this section;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HAE743F4C65D34E96AB050BD8A586B9EE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the use of exemptions under subsection (b); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5CAC0AB101F4420F8046D2003270A096"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dispute resolution services with the assistance of the Office of Government Information Services or the FOIA Public Liaison; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H51AB48AFCCDA403E80EF4D63D3BEBD54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations as necessary to improve agency practices and compliance with this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75AE9C375B7B42ADB4F0061DA19BE31D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Chief FOIA Officers Council</header> <paragraph id="H934AAC0865284188A48F63C4E5B06769"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the executive branch the Chief FOIA Officers Council (in this subsection, referred to as the <term>Council</term>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD079DEDBC99347AC862D924B2AC4F154"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Council shall consist of the following members:</text> <subparagraph id="H3E95AD718E6D441B9E9C5AE8CA503EBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BEBECF6AEC543C18176F8500FFB9402"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Information Policy at the Department of Justice.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1596BA80F7B447F99F1908EEDE7FAA3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Government Information Services at the National Archives and Records Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F847E9EBF014F8A8953E930BFC9726B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Chief FOIA Officer of each agency.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBF63FA18A4943D9BED420029F9C4676"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other officer or employee of the United States as designated by the Co-Chairs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62EA4EC8D33F49FC9F3574D232D0C541"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Co-Chairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Information Policy at the Department of Justice and the Director of the Office of Government Information Services at the National Archives and Records Administration shall be the Co-Chairs of the Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3AE4562B5A41D094B617DB8974F2EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Support services</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall provide administrative and other support for the Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE75878A1F4474CEB996BE7B86B7072C2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In performing its duties, the Council shall consult regularly with members of the public who make requests under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29510C2AC63C44189EAF50CF9839BC70"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Council include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H11A2B9644F2D472ABE61948DAC3E7EC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Develop recommendations for increasing compliance and efficiency under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5B52716C0C94363BCF5D73297BC3B21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Disseminate information about agency experiences, ideas, best practices, and innovative approaches related to this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD37134BE6FAD4436ABD9A98D8E92C21F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Identify, develop, and coordinate initiatives to increase transparency and compliance with this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1A946129D9A4941A6BB04953D2546DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Promote the development and use of common performance measures for agency compliance with this section.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B61CD082F6F41C8A2A2C35725AAA137"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEA95BEFF8EC943FB8F9B2E2F1AAE022C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regular meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall meet regularly and such meetings shall be open to the public unless the Council determines to close the meeting for reasons of national security or to discuss information exempt under subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6704F71EA454ED3B0C0615D05A2EE12"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than once a year, the Council shall hold a meeting that shall be open to the public and permit interested persons to appear and present oral and written statements to the Council.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD92449D267454AC1925FE7BBCEE073B9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 10 business days before a meeting of the Council, notice of such meeting shall be published in the Federal Register.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44CB9EE59D3349F68601566B5C19DA11"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Public availability of Council records</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the records, reports, transcripts, minutes, appendixes, working papers, drafts, studies, agenda, or other documents that were made available to or prepared for or by the Council shall be made publicly available.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE069C81B4704C818AC3C1E5E65738F9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Minutes</header><text>Detailed minutes of each meeting of the Council shall be kept and shall contain a record of the persons present, a complete and accurate description of matters discussed and conclusions reached, and copies of all reports received, issued, or approved by the Council.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B123B5C234843CEB01371962642C907"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <paragraph id="HDCDBD2FB0F2A44978D87018647F4B791"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Revision of regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each agency shall review the regulations of such agency and shall issue regulations on procedures for the disclosure of records under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, in accordance with the amendments made by this section. The regulations of each agency shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEEA579B715C1450CA42CB903A7E35BAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>procedures for engaging in dispute resolution; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78A527436F5646AABAE620F485C1F1BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>procedures for engaging with the Office of Government Information Services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9164D34222484F939C81655590C1FE53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Office of Government Information Services report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Office of Government Information Services shall submit to Congress a report on agency compliance with the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13D27BA97CB5489D877BB2A032B1D25A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on noncompliance</header><text>The head of any agency that does not meet the requirements of paragraph (1) shall submit to Congress a report on the reason for noncompliance not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01A408821D174AC285855E8355A163ED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inspector General review for noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any agency that fails to comply with the requirements of this subsection shall be reviewed by the Office of Inspector General of such agency for compliance with section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H572E17944FF841F5860C62AB90718944"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 552(f) of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9FBFD14D6C2F499A8B9AC5A81FB45AF0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inspector general review; adverse actions</header> <subsection id="HE1F8AD5929D04061B33A138DD7148B0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inspector general review</header> <paragraph id="HEE0BBC4B7D8641E3B7BED75B6C3CBC39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Inspector General of each agency shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H114B31B53D8E4B62805E48C9BA97FBCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>periodically review compliance with the requirements of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, including the timely processing of requests, assessment of fees and fee waivers, and the use of exemptions under subsection (b) of such section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FE17B69068146CFB4535EAFA6CD902D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations the Inspector General determines to be necessary to the head of the agency, including recommendations for disciplinary action.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA09ECBB9214D448CAB86381ADB8B95D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term under section 552(f) of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF50CF1D490C43ED8E042124F03695BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adverse actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The withholding of information in a manner inconsistent with the requirements of section 552 of title 5, United States Code (including any rules, regulations, or other implementing guidelines), as determined by the appropriate supervisor, shall be a basis for disciplinary action in accordance with subchapter I, II, or V of chapter 75 of such title, as the case may be.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HAA2720039259432BA51BD5088C7BD2D4"><enum>4.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized or appropriated.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


