<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE0E606C997E3441B86403712E46FFFDF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2902 IH: Safe Schools Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2902</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001193">Mr. MacArthur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000554">Mr. LoBiondo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to address and take action to prevent
			 bullying and harassment of students.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD96F70DBF30A4D18974DF12A68040C44" style="OLC">
 <section id="H04C05BAA89B44493BEFF2F6BD6E8B35A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Schools Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3438DB219C6C44E2A1278C63773DB20A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H67565708E8374EBB98D6C965FDDD7673"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Bullying and harassment foster a climate of fear and disrespect that can seriously impair the physical and psychological health of its victims and create conditions that negatively affect learning, thereby undermining the ability of students to achieve their full potential.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A9F40F990CB48A99A52425AE83E09B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Bullying and harassment contribute to high dropout rates, increased absenteeism, and academic underachievement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0801125AAA84B9FB27DD23E033C8F63"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Bullying and harassment include a range of behaviors that negatively impact a student’s ability to learn and participate in educational opportunities and activities that schools offer. Such behaviors can include hitting or punching, name-calling, intimidation through gestures or social exclusion, and sending insulting or offensive messages through electronic communications, such as Internet sites, e-mail, instant messaging, mobile phones and messaging, telephone, or any other means.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF523022C1F8E438DB956C7BC6B84CEA8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Schools with enumerated anti-bullying and harassment policies have an increased level of reporting and teacher intervention in incidents of bullying and harassment, thereby reducing the overall frequency and number of such incidents.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H793BDCCFF2524B1FA176FBCF71CE47FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Students have been particularly singled out for bullying and harassment on the basis of their actual or perceived race, color, national origin, sex, disability status, sexual orientation, gender identity, or religion, among other categories.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BF515BBAE614CD7BE808CC885310963"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Some young people experience a form of bullying called relational aggression or psychological bullying, which harms individuals by damaging, threatening, or manipulating their relationships with their peers, or by injuring their feelings of social acceptance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40B78C96BAD24D0FB6AD8D521F9CC6A5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Interventions to address bullying and harassment conduct to create a positive and safe school climate, combined with evidence-based discipline policies and practices, such as Positive Behavior Interventions and Supports (PBIS) and restorative practices, can minimize suspensions, expulsions, and other exclusionary discipline policies to ensure that students are not <quote>pushed-out</quote> or diverted to the juvenile justice system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52116B218047474DAF7F83EA7E5D8F3B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to one poll, 85 percent of Americans strongly support or somewhat support a Federal law to require schools to enforce specific rules to prevent bullying.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE55C32E518E4F2F936C82BF9BCC9C95"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Students, parents, educators, and policymakers have come together to call for leadership and action to address the national crisis of bullying and harassment.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE65AAF48DD4E40519050BEB7777E622F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Safe Schools improvement</header>
 <subsection id="HD7750F3F00D7452B9B5E73CD768ABCC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBE529F089B14524AE13AD89490F9A79" style="OLC">
					<part id="H4D8C5AF2BA034E0E9240512F288453B7"><enum>D</enum><header>Safe Schools improvement</header>
 <section id="HAD6EEB64867746E7B8BC019271BE880D"><enum>4401.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this part is to address the problem of bullying and harassment conduct of students in public elementary schools and secondary schools.</text>
						</section><section id="HAD78C4D2147A47D9A9009057B9165E64"><enum>4402.</enum><header>Anti-bullying policies</header>
 <subsection id="H91D1DCC9B69546858C7E678FD3FF8BD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bullying</header><text>In this part, the term <term>bullying</term> includes cyber-bullying through electronic communications.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7A5C5C44B1FD41D8B995D5E9F7F64567"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives a grant under this title shall require all local educational agencies in the State to carry out the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HACD8AC9D964D42E1AD8B96E734D9F6B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Establish policies that prevent and prohibit conduct, including bullying and harassment, that is sufficiently severe, persistent, or pervasive—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEDBB6CAA1C514658AA81D7D65F5E5586"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to limit a student’s ability to participate in, or benefit from, a program or activity of a public school or local educational agency; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77F24FBACA3B4B6B972DA1F24984DC9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to create a hostile or abusive educational environment, adversely affecting a student's education, at a program or activity of a public school or local educational agency, including acts of verbal, nonverbal, or physical aggression or intimidation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9D2850A79C1401F91F40954953A4E2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The policies required under paragraph (1) shall include a prohibition of bullying or harassment conduct based on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9926A6BD3AB7409F8F51F860D919E662"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a student’s actual or perceived race, color, national origin, sex, disability, sexual orientation, gender identity, or religion;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2522D8859AC46299150779902AF52D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the actual or perceived race, color, national origin, sex, disability, sexual orientation, gender identity, or religion of a person with whom a student associates or has associated; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBBAE7EDCCBF4309B1568EE7E55A859F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other distinguishing characteristics that may be defined by the State or local educational agency, including being homeless or the child or ward of a member of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H455C7BE329DB4A219BB632780C197093"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Provide—</text> <subparagraph id="H784058D8ACDE409E946FB66177885E2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>annual notice to students, parents, and educational professionals describing the full range of prohibited conduct contained in such local educational agency's discipline policies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5557195566E241739A3594629B9EF522"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grievance procedures for students or parents to register complaints regarding the prohibited conduct contained in such local educational agency's discipline policies, including—</text>
 <clause id="H2BF884E10B374DE09F4F2C87EC634DD0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the local educational agency officials who are designated as responsible for receiving such complaints; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3A3A138CC72A4FBDBA350B17198D1D72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>timelines that the local educational agency will establish in the resolution of such complaints.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CBB77694DF643DAA6509CE816BDB63B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Collect annual incidence and frequency of incidents data about the conduct prohibited by the policies described in paragraph (1) at the school building level that are accurate and complete and publicly report such data at the school level and local educational agency level. The local educational agency shall ensure that victims or persons responsible for such conduct are not identifiable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FA90D6BEDEA47F6B00C65A53F175C29"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Encourage positive and preventative approaches to school discipline that minimize students’ removal from instruction and ensure that students, including students described in paragraph (2), are not subject to disproportionate punishment.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB2DDA41296C84259AEBBF1957A90B919"><enum>4403.</enum><header>State reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The chief executive officer of a State that receives a grant under this title, in cooperation with the State educational agency, shall submit a biennial report to the Secretary—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE587AD5DCE064C688D38A1921F250A10"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the information reported by local educational agencies in the State pursuant to section 4402(b)(4); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7872CE59CEF24429818D37F6F31FAD2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describing the State's plans for supporting local educational agency efforts to address the conduct prohibited by the policies described in section 4402(b)(1).</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="H79F4F34BC7DA43C2AED66B9ADF4B479B"><enum>4404.</enum><header>Evaluation</header>
 <subsection id="H04C7ABC352B44096BE5A6ED1F772A1DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Biennial evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct an independent biennial evaluation of programs and policies to combat bullying and harassment in elementary schools and secondary schools, including implementation of the requirements described in section 4402, including whether such requirements have appreciably reduced the level of the prohibited conduct and have conducted effective parent involvement and training programs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H44D357A0DAFD491DA13E68C282B2391A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The Commissioner for Education Statistics shall collect data from States, that are subject to independent review, to determine the incidence and frequency of conduct prohibited by the policies described in section 4402.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA2539CC13B564EB396E8F7FAD5511E8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2017, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the President and Congress a report on the findings of the evaluation conducted under subsection (a) together with the data collected under subsection (b) and data submitted by the States under section 4403.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HF566243F94574C62B24E4BFBE492A829"><enum>4405.</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header>
 <subsection id="H3AE62EF222E34946989DAAFA20C86145"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal and State nondiscrimination laws</header><text>Nothing in this part shall be construed to invalidate or limit rights, remedies, procedures, or legal standards available to victims of discrimination under any other Federal law or law of a State or political subdivision of a State, including title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 or 505 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>, 794a), or the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>). The obligations imposed by this part are in addition to those imposed by title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD981615EC37B4C6E975DB523011998A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Free speech and expression laws</header><text>Nothing in this part shall be construed to alter legal standards regarding, or affect the rights (including remedies and procedures) available to individuals under, other Federal laws that establish protections for freedom of speech or expression.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC7A662FF29144A1C9E1164F3A2B50891"><enum>4406.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this part shall be construed to prohibit a State or local entity from enacting any law with respect to the prevention of bullying or harassment of students that is not inconsistent with this part.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8EE7CAA2BC4B4BAE8A21D056EAC8E5B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4304 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC80097986FEF40B88FCE934FAFF8C75B" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H4D8C5AF2BA034E0E9240512F288453B7" level="part">Part D—Safe Schools improvement</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HAD6EEB64867746E7B8BC019271BE880D" level="section">Sec. 4401. Purpose.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HAD78C4D2147A47D9A9009057B9165E64" level="section">Sec. 4402. Anti-bullying policies.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HB2DDA41296C84259AEBBF1957A90B919" level="section">Sec. 4403. State reports.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H79F4F34BC7DA43C2AED66B9ADF4B479B" level="section">Sec. 4404. Evaluation.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HF566243F94574C62B24E4BFBE492A829" level="section">Sec. 4405. Effect on other laws.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HC7A662FF29144A1C9E1164F3A2B50891" level="section">Sec. 4406. Rule of construction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


