<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD4A9A4F1BC045F3B995AEA84EF0D77B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1602 IH: Nurse Staffing Standards for Patient Safety and Quality Care Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1602</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150325">March 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish direct care registered nurse-to-patient
			 staffing ratio requirements in hospitals, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2D4151E5DB72422ABABC348EDE7185B1" style="OLC">
		<section id="HBA106CFC7B24476CA8A7769632168A38" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents; findings</header>
 <subsection id="H9660FDC2126C4BE1849A55DC58A4FAC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nurse Staffing Standards for Patient Safety and Quality Care Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H0A20221757E7420BBAB28A7417F74948"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HBA106CFC7B24476CA8A7769632168A38" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents; findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5DCB83DC1B90466EBAAB3B0E9CBFC821" level="section">Sec. 2. Minimum direct care registered nurse staffing requirement.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H201DFEB46E6648F0839C8389149E7DBA" level="section">Sec. 3. Enforcement of requirements through Federal programs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H07704CB95E9F4CEC96606A73E58649D0" level="section">Sec. 4. Nurse Workforce Initiative.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection><subsection id="H99D20A66D9824D6CA5462B1EE39032A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HDB94756EAA6644BFA7E09BFC6072BC8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Government has a substantial interest in promoting quality care and improving the delivery of health care services to patients in health care facilities in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E2670E44C78459C98A5499EC512246D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recent changes in health care delivery systems that have resulted in higher acuity levels among patients in health care facilities increase the need for improved quality measures in order to protect patient care and reduce the incidence of medical errors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98A97C7AD817489DAD32DDF96FC2AB0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Inadequate and poorly monitored registered nurse staffing practices that result in too few registered nurses providing direct care jeopardize the delivery of quality health care services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D58C25F75A7489AA3E0E1C1A99DCEF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Numerous studies have shown that patient outcomes are directly correlated to direct care registered nurse staffing levels, including a 2002 Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations report that concluded that the lack of direct care registered nurses contributed to nearly a quarter of the unanticipated problems that result in injury or death to hospital patients.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA839E72AA1644399CC0B31870B275B4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Requirements for direct care registered nurse staffing ratios will help address the registered nurse shortage in the United States by aiding in recruitment of new registered nurses and improving retention of registered nurses who are considering leaving direct patient care because of demands created by inadequate staffing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2E5B4F966E04B24962A86BB99585C99"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Establishing adequate minimum direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios that take into account patient acuity measures will improve the delivery of quality health care services and guarantee patient safety.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H682F98B79F4047A5BF37D21AD1BD5CC7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Establishing safe staffing standards for direct care registered nurses is a critical component of assuring that there is adequate hospital staffing at all levels to improve the delivery of quality care and protect patient safety.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5DCB83DC1B90466EBAAB3B0E9CBFC821"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minimum direct care registered nurse staffing requirement</header>
 <subsection id="HB47132DA6C66498383FB3BFCA4873C9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimum Direct Care Registered Nurse Staffing Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new title:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B3C714F7A4F4E49BB30E117EAE1291C" style="OLC">
					<title id="H64A6909793764EBE988A400EECC93964"><enum>XXXIV</enum><header>MINIMUM DIRECT CARE REGISTERED NURSE STAFFING REQUIREMENT</header>
						<section id="HFF2449B17CB0434F9207F0D09125FC5F"><enum>3401.</enum><header>Minimum nurse staffing requirement</header>
							<subsection id="HD925B7107AFC4BBA89E94AA35DA83AE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Staffing plan</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HA0E800BE92BB45D48CEA22C090038945"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A hospital shall implement a staffing plan that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC9744BD7EFB24FC1B8BC0EE8D14784E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides adequate, appropriate, and quality delivery of health care services and protects patient safety; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7AB4A187FFD04F10A806091837F5852D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is consistent with the requirements of this title.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FA33A7278544BDF939E025536B59B34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <subparagraph id="H1E3DB7D8B57B47C89BE33213303E8BF2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Implementation of staffing plan</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the requirements under paragraph (1) shall take effect not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5D9A433AFFD4DC4B6707629D2E7A721"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application of minimum direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios</header><text>The requirements under subsection (b) shall take effect as soon as practicable, as determined by the Secretary, but not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this title, or in the case of a hospital in a rural area (as defined in section 1886(d)(2)(D) of the Social Security Act), not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this title.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4147FC6DF32D4D59A774C508E01C1C24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum direct care registered nurse-to-Patient ratios</header>
 <paragraph id="HDA380D1A05944D8791295F984C14A1B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (4) and other provisions of this section, a hospital’s staffing plan shall provide that, at all times during each shift within a unit of the hospital, a direct care registered nurse may be assigned to not more than the following number of patients in that unit:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H04F01C605AE3428FA3D61846C6BDF239"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One patient in trauma emergency units.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8E9E7CE68214915B676FFCE944BD7B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One patient in operating room units, provided that a minimum of 1 additional person serves as a scrub assistant in such unit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H386AB12ACE524428A6FAC81B4A3BFF4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two patients in critical care units, including neonatal intensive care units, emergency critical care and intensive care units, labor and delivery units, coronary care units, acute respiratory care units, postanesthesia units, and burn units.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D104411F03F4D2187FC69AC3FADD818"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three patients in emergency room units, pediatrics units, stepdown units, telemetry units, antepartum units, and combined labor, deliver, and postpartum units.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39B852B7CFB14F9681658A5AC0997E28"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four patients in medical-surgical units, intermediate care nursery units, acute care psychiatric units, and other specialty care units.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FDE96E9CAE842878599902BDF90F5A9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Five patients in rehabilitation units and skilled nursing units.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H140C60862B43494482B3D97D44FBDB2F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Six patients in postpartum (3 couplets) units and well-baby nursery units.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABAB881A430B4521857A338F1874DE10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Similar units with different names</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may apply minimum direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios established in paragraph (1) for a hospital unit referred to in such paragraph to a type of hospital unit not referred to in such paragraph if such type of hospital unit provides a level of care to patients whose needs are similar to the needs of patients cared for in the hospital unit referred to in such paragraph.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H9FF7B2CCBCBB42B38A0265E3F1E4266A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restrictions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H048CB3276B2A493290C4043F5FF28498"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition against averaging</header><text>A hospital shall not average the number of patients and the total number of direct care registered nurses assigned to patients in a hospital unit during any 1 shift or over any period of time for purposes of meeting the requirements under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF0A89669CA64FAF9D9F45CD113574C0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition against imposition of mandatory overtime requirements</header><text>A hospital shall not impose mandatory overtime requirements to meet the hospital unit direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios required under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B484A079D3344009AAC7774E529228F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Relief during routine absences</header><text>A hospital shall ensure that only a direct care registered nurse may relieve another direct care registered nurse during breaks, meals, and other routine, expected absences from a hospital unit.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85579CC7F164477089E0BA7D71A13A17"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adjustment of ratios</header>
 <subparagraph id="H81B3867F0CC34F37815FA586FE82D498"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If necessary to protect patient safety, the Secretary may prescribe regulations that—</text> <clause id="HB1903D5959274EC39ED60F3F10E132B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increase minimum direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios under this subsection to further limit the number of patients that may be assigned to each direct care nurse; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEECB514DDB6D4878934DAB5C2345A670"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>add minimum direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios for units not referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H913AE36F8A9449E7B097C7ED1CFDB2EF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Such regulations shall be prescribed after consultation with affected hospitals and registered nurses.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBC45AA5DF79410B827096E376AEB126"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relationship to state-imposed ratios</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall preempt State standards that the Secretary determines to be at least equivalent to Federal requirements for a staffing plan established under this title. Minimum direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios established under this subsection shall not preempt State requirements that the Secretary determines are at least equivalent to Federal requirements for a staffing plan established under this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H008C507DA4C04F4E97417EBB5A813160"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exemption in emergencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements established under this subsection shall not apply during a state of emergency if a hospital is requested or expected to provide an exceptional level of emergency or other medical services. The Secretary shall issue guidance to hospitals that describes situations that constitute a state of emergency for purposes of the exemption under this paragraph.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B6294EFDA724497A668CF7269C72EB3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development and reevaluation of staffing plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H1F21C7D2A75C4261AB67A21F65CFF65F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Considerations in development of plan</header><text>In developing the staffing plan, a hospital shall provide for direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios above the minimum direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios required under subsection (b) if appropriate based upon consideration of the following factors:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5EDD251D5A194E4E9EBDBD85B6D91BA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of patients and acuity level of patients as determined by the application of an acuity system (as defined in section 3406(1)), on a shift-by-shift basis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H229412F641794E57B4811CCB597ACAA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The anticipated admissions, discharges, and transfers of patients during each shift that impacts direct patient care.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EBBD0B94F0D422AB3D529CB6EA969C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Specialized experience required of direct care registered nurses on a particular unit.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7958452E6E03456EA353A7B723107F5C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Staffing levels and services provided by licensed vocational or practical nurses, licensed psychiatric technicians, certified nurse assistants, or other ancillary staff in meeting direct patient care needs not required by a direct care registered nurse.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H679149428D5E4549B0F8C5C563751DBE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The level of technology available that affects the delivery of direct patient care.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7149E5BF1C404C4AAA6479B1CE8078DF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The level of familiarity with hospital practices, policies, and procedures by temporary agency direct care registered nurses used during a shift.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2076EEA6549D42EA9E899B7E21CD2028"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Obstacles to efficiency in the delivery of patient care presented by physical layout.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7B31D329C294377920E42BFD9F8D66A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation of staffing</header><text>A hospital shall specify the system used to document actual staffing in each unit for each shift.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H7894E896AC7144A4B6E7389B0C3C78B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual reevaluation of plan and acuity system</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC314FB7B09254B768ED70144CEF1E704"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A hospital shall annually evaluate—</text> <clause id="H06340512C0E94068ADF6AC7D28DF5E1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>its staffing plan in each unit in relation to actual patient care requirements; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2BC31F5AECE04A8EB6708419B6BAD0A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the accuracy of its acuity system.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78904D2F168B49D7B6E372A47B1ACD10"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Update</header><text>A hospital shall update its staffing plan and acuity system to the extent appropriate based on such evaluation.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H995147782D8C4BF5BB91ED3FF2D0A1D7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transparency</header>
 <subparagraph id="H66327A7118054E2BB5BC79811B1724F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Any acuity-based patient classification system adopted by a hospital under this section shall be transparent in all respects, including disclosure of detailed documentation of the methodology used to predict nursing staffing, identifying each factor, assumption, and value used in applying such methodology.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5A3DC60EF284547A3456596D6AA26E1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures to provide that the documentation submitted under subsection (e) is available for public inspection in its entirety.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB423945F5B5B46B7817B804289BE0C23"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Registered nurse participation</header><text>A staffing plan of a hospital shall be developed and subsequent reevaluations shall be conducted under this subsection on the basis of input from direct care registered nurses at the hospital or, where such nurses are represented through collective bargaining, from the applicable recognized or certified collective bargaining representative of such nurses. Nothing in this title shall be construed to permit conduct prohibited under the National Labor Relations Act or under the Federal Labor Relations Act.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7C0F3DEF7CF4F97851CE89F4922171E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acuity tool</header>
 <paragraph id="HAB9DD323285945D9BA708379E89A7D7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall develop a process to establish a national acuity tool that provides a transparent method for establishing nurse staffing requirements that exceed the minimum hospital unit direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios required under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C5A0EBF6119427F93798ECF103C218A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Each hospital unit shall adopt and implement the national acuity tool described in paragraph (1), and provide staffing based on such tool. Any additional direct care registered nursing staffing above the hospital unit direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios described in subsection (b) shall be assigned in a manner determined by such national acuity tool.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B90FCCCE5264A3182A635E1E3C4DE7F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Submission of plan to secretary</header><text>A hospital shall submit to the Secretary its staffing plan and any annual updates under subsection (c)(3)(B). A federally operated hospital may submit its staffing plan through the department or agency operating the hospital.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H3FEE545F9AA64F8882682FAE32CE7B98"><enum>3402.</enum><header>Posting, records, and audits</header>
 <subsection id="HE6E60E3421ED437495DD2CFE2C5C0AE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Posting requirements</header><text>In each unit, a hospital shall post a uniform notice in a form specified by the Secretary in regulation that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2BB7785A011547C384F835D0CBF20C5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>explains requirements imposed under section 3401;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H567F92EA5C794C5E9F6841B8F22D27D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes actual direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios during each shift; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H776BD9A1F4054A42820FEA3F14677125"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is visible, conspicuous, and accessible to staff, patients, and the public.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A9A1641336A417CB69D975B25C97E5D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Records</header> <paragraph id="H50E13E4151794848AC5150187DCA4936"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Maintenance of records</header><text>Each hospital shall maintain accurate records of actual direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios in each unit for each shift for no less than 3 years. Such records shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HECBEE44962B149CF8A3613817B71EFD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of patients in each unit;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF92BE92A12D4863A6D0809EEC4013CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the identity and duty hours of each direct care registered nurse assigned to each patient in each unit in each shift; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F57DD36CA014350B4172526EC8D1A39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a copy of each notice posted under subsection (a).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A95FCBE3A63403981A4AE492CD16C6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of records</header><text>Each hospital shall make its records maintained under paragraph (1) available to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H93EA5F96298B4E718F8CD5F9B72C7E45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H282F1AB29304447EBC8008404260529F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>registered nurses and their collective bargaining representatives (if any); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF81AD7ED6784FE48BC476F232A3F853"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the public under regulations established by the Secretary, or in the case of a federally operated hospital, under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <term>Freedom of Information Act</term>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FB1309F68624E4189FE5DA86003B780"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct periodic audits to ensure—</text> <paragraph id="H7039BB1E65D446CBAE215EEB517448BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implementation of the staffing plan in accordance with this title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BA5FCEC8AE84A5B9B7100B06A95E423"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accuracy in records maintained under this section.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA61C1D4A9AB34DB4A08CA778D845E681"><enum>3403.</enum><header>Minimum direct care licensed practical nurse staffing requirements</header> <subsection id="H1C257684033E42C69636C4D98141026B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>A hospital’s staffing plan shall comply with minimum direct care licensed practical nurse staffing requirements that the Secretary establishes for units in hospitals. Such staffing requirements shall be established not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this title, and shall be based on the study conducted under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H100FAA4995BD4D34BF5328E6E83D7606"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this title, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, shall complete a study of licensed practical nurse staffing and its effects on patient care in hospitals. The Director may contract with a qualified entity or organization to carry out such study under this paragraph. The Director shall consult with licensed practical nurses and organizations representing licensed practical nurses regarding the design and conduct of the study.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBC2F491E19024BFD9E4CF83578F3B263"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of registered nurse provisions to licensed practical nurse staffing requirements</header><text>Paragraphs (2), (3), (4)(A), and (5) of section 3401(b), section 3401(c), and section 3402 shall apply to the establishment and application of direct care licensed practical nurse staffing requirements under this section in the same manner that they apply to the establishment and application of direct care registered nurse-to-patient ratios under sections 3401 and 3402.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H35A32F8F4CFC48589F6DB773BCD5BE5A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The requirements of this section shall take effect as soon as practicable, as determined by the Secretary, but not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this title, or in the case of a hospital in a rural area (as defined in section 1886(d)(2)(D) of the Social Security Act), not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this title.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HBE42D4E11069465EB89B7DC10891C9D3"><enum>3404.</enum><header>Adjustment in reimbursement</header>
 <subsection id="H254981C4622F44E99C79B299EFAC6146"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicare reimbursement</header><text>The Secretary shall adjust payments made to hospitals (other than federally operated hospitals) under title XVIII of the Social Security Act in an amount equal to the net amount of additional costs incurred in providing services to Medicare beneficiaries that are attributable to compliance with requirements imposed under sections 3401 through 3403. The amount of such payment adjustments shall take into account recommendations contained in the report submitted by the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission under subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3C8A1D4E411F4996B5AFC15D7C41AF03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation for federally operated hospitals</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such additional sums as are required for federally operated hospitals to comply with the additional requirements established under sections 3401 through 3403.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD0506EED9FAB4C2C945E8D11C03905CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>MedPAC report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this title, the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (established under section 1805 of the Social Security Act) shall submit to Congress and the Secretary a report estimating total costs and savings attributable to compliance with requirements imposed under sections 3401 through 3403. Such report shall include recommendations on the need, if any, to adjust reimbursement for Medicare payments under subsection (a).</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H5FDB4A90F5D14C97A581EAF54EF2D439"><enum>3405.</enum><header>Whistleblower and patient protections</header>
 <subsection id="HD14986D0723C4D8AB1C00E6B8D183ABB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Objection to or refusal of assignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nurse may object to, or refuse to participate in, any activity, policy, practice, assignment or task if in good faith—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0C670E64E0024908B0DDDF57CF4F02A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nurse reasonably believes it to be in violation of section 3401 or 3403; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB6D896C772747D6A824A5BF83156343"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nurse is not prepared by education, training, or experience to fulfill the assignment without compromising the safety of any patient or jeopardizing the license of the nurse.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9207B34D8E0C4D85A8CD92E3F33FEBDE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retaliation for objection to or refusal of assignment barred</header>
 <paragraph id="H2EAA16C457A74550978BCB9BB30D4CFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No discharge, discrimination, or retaliation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No hospital shall discharge, retaliate, discriminate, or otherwise take adverse action in any manner with respect to any aspect of a nurse’s employment (as defined in section 3407(4)), including discharge, promotion, compensation, or terms, conditions, or privileges of employment, based on the nurse’s refusal of a work assignment under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36ED1B90D547410A8428CA0303139DF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No filing of complaint</header><text>No hospital shall file a complaint or a report against a nurse with a State professional disciplinary agency because of the nurse’s refusal of a work assignment under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H308A620AAE6F497FAD3F60E08D89E509"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nurse who has been discharged, discriminated against, or retaliated against in violation of subsection (b)(1) or against whom a complaint or report has been filed in violation of subsection (b)(2) may (without regard to whether a complaint has been filed under subsection (d) of this section or subsection (b) of section 3406) bring a cause of action in a United States district court. A nurse who prevails on the cause of action shall be entitled to one or more of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H730FA4B2E90C4D23B92FA7C7B559BB89"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reinstatement.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H32CE0C3074744013A856EE301CA23BFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Reimbursement of lost wages, compensation, and benefits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E8E73D44354F239DEF77779834239F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Attorneys’ fees.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H10CB46E5B9574CFEA5141B13EDCA9F45"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Court costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3EC1A9488774E1D937891823DCABAE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Other damages.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H98E297EC3CBF4AFE85B9045922401A4A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Complaint to Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nurse, patient, or other individual may file a complaint with the Secretary against a hospital that violates the provisions of this title. For any complaint filed, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HAE00EDAFAFF842AFABFD1FFED667EEFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receive and investigate the complaint;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H498AFA3CA439426BB9E9A0D636FA085B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine whether a violation of this title as alleged in the complaint has occurred; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC67CF322DF0948B4A5E78AC496B4D8D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such a violation has occurred, issue an order that the complaining nurse or individual shall not suffer any discharge, retaliation, discrimination, or other adverse action prohibited by subsection (b) or subsection (f).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE67E6C13D51240BC82A4B5E8BEBED84D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Toll-Free telephone number</header>
 <paragraph id="HDBC9247CA6E34FEA86EEEF12F73C720E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide for the establishment of a toll-free telephone hotline to provide information regarding the requirements under sections 3401 through 3403 and to receive reports of violations of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28C34C9A0D784621B80FA40BA99D4D24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to patients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital shall provide each patient admitted to the hospital for inpatient care with the hotline described in paragraph (1), and shall give notice to each patient that such hotline may be used to report inadequate staffing or care.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FDF6C4FC41F4390B5C7925ED807C584"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Protection for reporting</header>
 <paragraph id="HA435FADEF0174335A640D975C7E7623A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on retaliation or discrimination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital shall not discriminate or retaliate in any manner against any patient, employee, or contract employee of the hospital, or any other individual, on the basis that such individual, in good faith, individually or in conjunction with another person or persons, has presented a grievance or complaint, or has initiated or cooperated in any investigation or proceeding of any governmental entity, regulatory agency, or private accreditation body, made a civil claim or demand, or filed an action relating to the care, services, or conditions of the hospital or of any affiliated or related facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E5A4504BC3D48A5B771209B658A6229"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Good faith defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, an individual shall be deemed to be acting in good faith if the individual reasonably believes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA5D131CE386844F6B67F07F3E2A44A20"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information reported or disclosed is true; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEC645D37E8645A98265A260FCE680BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a violation of this title has occurred or may occur.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EA12D5395154AA488B89E1E5E81C38A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibition on interference with rights</header>
 <paragraph id="H0881AACBFFB048D6A5D108FDD656EA55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exercise of rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any hospital to—</text> <subparagraph id="HD6D47678E3A34B16A6E99270B3A2E027"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interfere with, restrain, or deny the exercise, or attempt to exercise, by any person of any right provided or protected under this title; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91DBB16A152B43CEA9B423361E8EA4C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coerce or intimidate any person regarding the exercise or attempt to exercise such right.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89AC5C8DAC7C423E9E54D0D2A2C64E73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Opposition to unlawful policies or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any hospital to discriminate or retaliate against any person for opposing any hospital policy, practice, or actions which are alleged to violate, breach, or fail to comply with any provision of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBF1C02BAC5DA4FF6A8C22BDDF1EA6783"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on interference with protected communications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital (or an individual representing a hospital) shall not make, adopt, or enforce any rule, regulation, policy, or practice which in any manner directly or indirectly prohibits, impedes, or discourages a direct care nurse from, or intimidates, coerces, or induces a direct care nurse regarding, engaging in free speech activities or disclosing information as provided under this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43F03A3006C24C848318EBA52E5F15CB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on interference with collective action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital (or an individual representing a hospital) shall not in any way interfere with the rights of nurses to organize, bargain collectively, and engage in concerted activity under section 7 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/157">29 U.S.C. 157</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE58B5A693488452F9578ADD46470DD93"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital shall post in an appropriate location in each unit a conspicuous notice in a form specified by the Secretary that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEF818E2E5C6E4DDF800B49AED1A74AAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">explains the rights of nurses, patients, and other individuals under this section;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H396B729E2CAE47BBBBDE22CAFD5E0002"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes a statement that a nurse, patient, or other individual may file a complaint with the Secretary against a hospital that violates the provisions of this title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54409DD92B0445DF9F4C46995A38522B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides instructions on how to file such a complaint.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AB9C38F79AA46358C64FFB9C64AE676"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H3FFA540A9ED9464A872E04A65F6DE572"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Refusal; retaliation; cause of action</header> <subparagraph id="HC9F37E16B0BE4607BE4FD34061DA8322"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a) through (c) shall apply to objections and refusals occurring on or after the effective date of the provision of this title to which the objection or refusal relates.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC26C1770B1E24FF5BB727D2CFA595CA9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a)(2) shall not apply to objections or refusals in any hospital before the requirements of section 3401(a) or 3403(a), as applicable, apply to that hospital.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83C7AEAAAF2B45B7BBC425781B9649C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protections for reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (f)(1) shall apply to actions occurring on or after the effective date of the provision to which the violation relates, except that such subsection shall apply to initiation, cooperation, or participation in an investigation or proceeding on or after the date of enactment of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DF4B1B2970A4C3EB29DDA35352CC730"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (h) shall take effect 18 months after the date of enactment of this title.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3F3ECD33484C4029A457C8415D685933"><enum>3406.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="H1254FF27F36C43D6A448D4C1521E4F6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enforce the requirements and prohibitions of this title in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H75FAE18903304A42AC6B00467BC1C05E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures for receiving and investigating complaints</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures under which—</text> <paragraph id="HB116A2F09A0F43228EDC2EBCDA6F29C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any person may file a complaint alleging that a hospital has violated a requirement or a prohibition of this title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98BF1517476545FA85B533DB72C73376"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such complaints shall be investigated by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F57BB401E024A7EBA89B6F2A4ACF53B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a hospital has violated a requirement of this title, the Secretary—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE40D6434160F4C459C431D8C84283CA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall require the facility to establish a corrective action plan to prevent the recurrence of such violation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E81D8387905495BAF6EFC680018213D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may impose civil money penalties, as described in subsection (d).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FA15B4D7C09434DB982EA2B545713FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header> <paragraph id="HBE64F6F5BB474D61B02136213BDB9E61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to any other penalties prescribed by law, the Secretary may impose civil penalties as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA9000AB51ABA4A97BED063B9C611B37A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Hospital liability</header><text>The Secretary may impose on a hospital found to be in violation of this title, a civil money penalty of not more than $25,000 for each knowing violation of a requirement of this title, except that the Secretary shall impose a civil money penalty of more than $25,000 for each such violation in the case of a participating hospital that the Secretary determines has a pattern or practice of such violations (with the amount of such additional penalties being determined in accordance with a schedule or methodology specified in regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A88A45818884B06A9F0D7BBFFE67FC6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Individual liability</header><text>The Secretary may impose on an individual who—</text> <clause id="HC47425BEBD9E463CBE2ABF9B5FB007D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is employed by a hospital found by the Secretary to have violated a requirement of this title; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEFE30CAE7437447F810944A4BAD28B3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>willfully violates this title,</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">a civil money penalty of not more than $20,000 for each such violation.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A0ED373B6AF4619AA9331A4B490E8B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The provisions of section 1128A of the Social Security Act (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty under this paragraph in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under such section 1128A.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F97F2AA93D84A869A7040347FA3EF09"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public notice of violations</header>
 <paragraph id="H8D14BEFD0A524E9F86F525FAFCC506E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Internet Web site</header><text>The Secretary shall publish on the Internet Web site of the Department of Health and Human Services the names of participating hospitals on which civil money penalties have been imposed under this subsection, the violation for which such penalty was imposed, and such additional information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91D537E013DC4B6F92086DEB2A4D893B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Change of ownership</header><text>With respect to a participating hospital that had a change of ownership, as determined by the Secretary, penalties imposed on the hospital while under previous ownership shall no longer be published by the Secretary of such Internet Web site after the 1-year period beginning on the date of change of ownership.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H617D0C249C254BB6A6A4DF3CB4717CA7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Offset</header><text>Funds collected by the Secretary under this section shall be used to offset the costs of enforcing this title.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDFB144A5C74F435ABE5D72E072405CC5"><enum>3407.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this title:</text> <paragraph id="H5FAC31190AF64B7382A3992C9A945F48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acuity system</header><text>The term <term>acuity system</term> means an established measurement tool that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H56A7504606624B4395A9BD1CC3EA79C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>predicts nursing care requirements for individual patients based on severity of patient illness, need for specialized equipment and technology, intensity of nursing interventions required, and the complexity of clinical nursing judgment needed to design, implement, and evaluate the patient’s nursing care plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C32F2DC5AC64E89868BF529FE0F0C9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>details the amount of nursing care needed, both in number of nurses and in skill mix of nursing personnel required, on a daily basis, for each patient in a nursing department or unit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB6D7C5611924238911CC8924E61D4A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>takes into consideration the patient care services provided not only by registered nurses but also by direct care licensed practical nurses and other health care personnel; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EA4E579B4134939A058A0294FD7A35B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is stated in terms that can be readily used and understood by nurses.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A551239BF0D443F972357ECB9D2B1F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct care licensed practical nurse</header><text>The term <term>direct care licensed practical nurse</term> means an individual who has been granted a license by at least one State to practice as a licensed practical nurse or a licensed vocational nurse and who provides bedside care for one or more patients.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H716D939AF0A44B06A05C66A3D6A0CC26"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Direct care registered nurse</header><text>The term <term>direct care registered nurse</term> means an individual who has been granted a license by at least one State to practice as a registered nurse and who provides bedside care for one or more patients.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H833A252BF8E34B2EB6D4DF0417E9A85E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employment</header><text>The term <term>employment</term> includes the provision of services under a contract or other arrangement.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A047B0AF5B342AE8E62D12A603ADEC8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hospital</header><text>The term <term>hospital</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1861(e) of the Social Security Act, and includes a hospital that is operated by the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, the Indian Health Services Program, or any other department or agency of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0AFFC536D884A3381A2EFF38B8BF35E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nurse</header><text>The term <term>nurse</term> means any direct care registered nurse or direct care licensed practical nurse (as the case may be), regardless of whether or not the nurse is an employee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99C94691A5944DA4BF512DC4B2EDBD06"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Staffing plan</header><text>The term <term>staffing plan</term> means a staffing plan required under section 3401.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FFBBDAB3B1C4F1498C5D67BA843D61C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State of emergency</header><text>The term <term>state of emergency</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9E9D8CC4756A4BCF8AF0AD8254DE586A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a state of emergency that is an unpredictable or unavoidable occurrence at an unscheduled or unpredictable interval, relating to health care delivery and requiring immediate medical interventions and care; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09AB7FAC53264FAC8A032C015F14CF4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a state of emergency that results from a labor dispute in the health care industry or consistent understaffing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H144FDD58A15241E69FDAF9F1C1930FDE"><enum>3408.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall be construed to authorize disclosure of private and confidential patient information, except in the case where such disclosure is otherwise required by law, compelled by proper legal process, consented to by the patient, provided in confidence to regulatory or accreditation agencies or other government entities for investigatory purposes, or provided pursuant to formal or informal complaints of unlawful or improper practices for purposes of achieving corrective and remedial action.</text></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D001AE3C63E40189CCE64791B09C9DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report containing recommendations for ensuring that sufficient numbers of nurses are available to meet the requirements imposed by title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act, as added by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCACCC4E67ED341FE82DFF8A22C521681"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report by HRSA</header>
 <paragraph id="H414202B205DE4D8CA5C3453BDD004324"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, in consultation with the National Health Care Workforce Commission, shall submit to Congress a report regarding the relationship between nurse staffing levels and nurse retention in hospitals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BF8A35036904694BCF9474D902A6CFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updated report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, in consultation with the National Health Care Workforce Commission, shall submit to Congress an update of the report submitted under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H201DFEB46E6648F0839C8389149E7DBA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement of requirements through Federal programs</header>
 <subsection id="HC35F64DC46BE4A66B5436AEA5D2813DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicare program</header><text>Section 1866(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF4C63171555E4F998C752B2820B67248"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (V);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53F848BF0E9C46DFAACE22E0F1FBA60B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subparagraph (W) added by section 3005(1)(C) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>—</text> <subparagraph id="H136F998D57744D508B3B11ED8E25EBEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the period at the end and inserting a comma;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72DF8444A55C478DA39F3ADB10127DB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by moving the indentation 2 ems to the left; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72A963A7290A429F80D99B6F961F8469"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by moving such subparagraph to immediately follow subparagraph (V);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD833B2A5DF22486F9831CD5EDDED7BC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subparagraph (W) added by section 6406(b)(3) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>—</text> <subparagraph id="HF396658C4FC14AC8A7A19FD8216E0B7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8EBD42498354886A8F051CAD8042756"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by moving the indentation 2 ems to the left;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF76603BCD154972B5AA88CA97ED292D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating such subparagraph as subparagraph (X); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6D89B56BDAB44A0857937E91462DB62"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by moving such subparagraph to immediately follow subparagraph (W), as moved under paragraph (2)(C); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H931D9CE893EC4398AE93B50758EA9E8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after the subparagraph (X), as redesignated and moved under paragraph (3), the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H56394079B6AC422694EA61EE4DA7CEA2" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HF3CC2464704A4D9C93D8618565F258EE" indent="up1"><enum>(Y)</enum><text>in the case of a hospital, to comply with the provisions of title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C3207BAAB3E4C168D06E66955727DC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medicaid program</header><text>Section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBA5FBBF1AAE14BD3B9FC7C7FDC33003A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (80);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD5DBDFFE7D490185394DD225C10566"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (81) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA5777A203C049B3B76F10FC1AFBD8D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (81) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HBE72F823463C45BBB73194F32EBF5E36" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HF7B5EC3565D843C6A46178BFD62AA023"><enum>(82)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that any hospital that receives a payment under such plan comply with the provisions of title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act (relating to minimum direct care registered nurse staffing requirements).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD11DED41704A4C17B5A5F330C5BCB2DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Health benefits program of the department of veterans affairs</header><text>Section 8110(a) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H1466CAE7C1E340B0B8CB736206F0C4A7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HD9BE38D794234A05831930BE1F33E164" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In the case of a Department medical facility that is a hospital, the hospital shall comply with the provisions of title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2166F0D539434247891D3D623F5E9486" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Nothing either in chapter 74 of this title or in section 7106 of title 5 shall preclude enforcement of the provisions of title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act with respect to a Department hospital through grievance procedures negotiated in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H414FD91AB031459EBDCD3CA1DD25A9E3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Health benefits program of the department of defense</header>
 <paragraph id="HE96AC81E3E1E4596AAB15A6E6D8A2A0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">Chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BFE4627A5F44DCA8F7F2FD791FF1D23" style="USC">
 <section id="H4693753804CA466FAA1281394D4A989F"><enum>1110c.</enum><header>Staffing requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of a facility of the uniformed services that is a hospital, the hospital shall comply with the provisions of title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7911F66106974494B25AF1F7A2864C9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1110b the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HFED242F54E974F74B34BBCC7BD2EADEA" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">1110c. Staffing requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1B6D0804BD6406F9C6D345FA251342B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Indian health services program</header><text>Title VIII of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1671">25 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HDA8FD2B8883449FE90F2E3C6CB35E97B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF727D17FB31D4B328CF8CE42F7C9733E"><enum>833.</enum><header>Staffing requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">All hospitals of the Service shall comply with the provisions of title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act (relating to minimum direct care registered nurse staffing requirements).</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0CD52641D1E3458F832BB40FFCA1D6BD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal labor-Management relations</header>
 <paragraph id="HD9CCC27111CC48638CCAA1A356366078"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7106 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H614C88B7995B45D7AEFB18CE85D5C0BD" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H61CD81BE28A2478B9382AA80FFA5A11A"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall preclude enforcement of the provisions of title XXXIV of the Public Health Service Act through grievance procedures negotiated in accordance with section 7121.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H499FC1D348C445C38E5374FB16F1BE5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 7106(a) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Subject to subsection (b) of this title,</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsections (b) and (c),</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H07704CB95E9F4CEC96606A73E58649D0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Nurse Workforce Initiative</header> <subsection id="H7B8C628675D44B40901C4CAE2BDE9D87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Scholarship and stipend program</header><text>Section 846(d) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/297n">42 U.S.C. 297n(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9C76A5D94BC149278323B28A50F17A3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and Stipend</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Scholarship</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BD816593E90408FAC6DEBE1B3E29F96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or stipends</quote> after <quote>scholarships</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H896915109FCC4CA983B690EDAA1D3835"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nurse retention grants</header><text>Section 831A(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/296p-1">42 U.S.C. 296p–1(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H02286F89E4A34BB7B975C1596E7B4034"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Grants for Career Ladder Program</header-in-text>.—</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Grants for Nurse Retention</header-in-text>.—</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0333D917F04CBDAD76B069D99E56B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E0BA87DB1E84F679B618B68BBA62F6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86585ACCB25F4850B2817CA132ABAE8E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1324F74C93F74474A4C0A5B3CC8905B3" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H916561BA7D0E4A54809F330C98A43672"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide additional support to nurses entering the workforce by implementing nursing preceptorship projects that establish a period of practical and clinical experiences and training for nursing students, newly hired nurses, and recent graduates of a direct care degree programs for registered nurses; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDF0FFDFC31F402F8AF9B391C870202B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to implement mentorship projects that assist new or transitional direct care registered nurses in adapting to the hospital setting.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


