<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB0E647C50CEB46FD910EAFEE0C7E2747" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2124 IH: Resident Physician Shortage Reduction Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2124</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the distribution of additional
			 residency positions, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA59C49E40845485890493D0852ECCC0B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF01C5A0DEB794A6DA8C7B187BE168A58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Resident Physician Shortage Reduction Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H51794FD66E694DCC953A80479FF6D816"><enum>2.</enum><header>Distribution of additional residency positions</header> <subsection id="HC8172D5FE1E14912B7B08668624F5197"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1886(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9937FBEB72946EB948C1743218A9CA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(F)(i), by striking <quote>paragraphs (7) and (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (7), (8), and (9)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BDD7E160B60421C87BC739312C50872"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(H)(i), by striking <quote>paragraphs (7) and (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (7), (8), and (9)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H176CADEB580248DB9BC15413E3B612F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(E), by inserting <quote>paragraph (9),</quote> after <quote>paragraph (8),</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC577829335A344A88401D996F45F36A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HF1CBDAF233804232AB7355A60863BE11" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H60743EDDE609477D93DA9B23988D0ABB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Distribution of additional residency positions</header>
							<subparagraph id="H8979C7C5694F4DFEA16953DA71D3146E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Additional residency positions</header>
 <clause id="H433B89CB6892455FA15C83F9EB84E9E8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 (and succeeding fiscal years if the Secretary determines that there are additional residency positions available to distribute under clause (iv)(II)), the Secretary shall, subject to clause (ii) and subparagraph (D), increase the otherwise applicable resident limit for each qualifying hospital that submits a timely application under this subparagraph by such number as the Secretary may approve for portions of cost reporting periods occurring on or after July 1 of the fiscal year of the increase.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0ED68D2BD0324EF28770EED29CCB5E36"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Number available for distribution</header><text>For each such fiscal year, the Secretary shall determine the total number of additional residency positions available for distribution under clause (i) in accordance with the following:</text>
 <subclause id="H1434ED7935ED4686A540D92DF8E6F58C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Allocation to hospitals already operating over resident limit</header><text>One-third of such number shall be available for distribution only to hospitals described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAA4DD2F46B024439A577A5CD4EDFB5E4"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Aggregate limitation</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iv)(I), the aggregate number of increases in the otherwise applicable resident limit under this subparagraph shall be equal to 3,000 in each such year.</text>
									</subclause></clause><clause id="HB4EA50667387453EA10BAD4941CA3DDD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Process for distributing positions</header>
 <subclause id="HBD7277540FB046B5BCBE1F81B39BE37B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Rounds of applications</header><text>The Secretary shall initiate 5 separate rounds of applications for an increase under clause (i), 1 round with respect to each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD8DFB315579C4008A8239F4828047721"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Number available</header><text>In each of such rounds, the aggregate number of positions available for distribution in the fiscal year under clause (ii) shall be distributed, plus any additional positions available under clause (iv).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFB7390426E7643EF819B428DF89818F8"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall notify hospitals of the number of positions distributed to the hospital under this paragraph as a result of an increase in the otherwise applicable resident limit by January 1 of the fiscal year of the increase. Such increase shall be effective for portions of cost reporting periods beginning on or after July 1 of that fiscal year.</text>
									</subclause></clause><clause id="H5459F9DB6FB4415EB32A1319363B9FE9"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Positions not distributed during the fiscal year</header>
 <subclause id="H7369BA6A3EF841A2ADD99B56680E05DB"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the number of resident full-time equivalent positions distributed under this paragraph in a fiscal year is less than the aggregate number of positions available for distribution in the fiscal year (as described in clause (ii), including after application of this subclause), the difference between such number distributed and such number available for distribution shall be added to the aggregate number of positions available for distribution in the following fiscal year.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD289ECAF5BBA4DFC843852B9069CBB88"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception if positions not distributed by end of fiscal year 2021</header><text>If the aggregate number of positions distributed under this paragraph during the 5-year period of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 is less than 15,000, the Secretary shall, in accordance with the provisions of clause (ii) and subparagraph (D) and the considerations and priority described in subparagraph (C), conduct an application and distribution process in each subsequent fiscal year until such time as the aggregate amount of positions distributed under this paragraph is equal to 15,000.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B88942AE52D417AB5A3E22AAD852562"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of distribution for positions to hospitals already operating over resident limit</header>
 <clause id="HA85BC52F0732468DA904BADD7E0FF0A0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), in the case of a hospital in which the reference resident level of the hospital (as specified in subparagraph (G)(iii)) is greater than the otherwise applicable resident limit, the increase in the otherwise applicable resident limit under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year described in such subparagraph shall be an amount equal to the product of the total number of additional residency positions available for distribution under subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) for such fiscal year and the quotient of—</text>
 <subclause id="H5B4B42ABD7CC4952A4D5ECA0479A170E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of resident positions by which the reference resident level of the hospital exceeds the otherwise applicable resident limit for the hospital; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE70C7323C4FD45AFB6CAADA28EC196DB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of resident positions by which the reference resident level of all such hospitals with respect to which an application is approved under this paragraph exceeds the otherwise applicable resident limit for such hospitals.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCC6D31DC428B499580424791083196DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A hospital described in clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="H34E910A50E4D4A19A1D022DAE9A89BCD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is not eligible for an increase in the otherwise applicable resident limit under this subparagraph unless the amount by which the reference resident level of the hospital exceeds the otherwise applicable resident limit is not less than 10 and the hospital trains at least 25 percent of the full-time equivalent residents of the hospital in primary care and general surgery (as of the date of enactment of this paragraph); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD40D905BD1374F7688D502E07FB02354"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall continue to train at least 25 percent of the full-time equivalent residents of the hospital in primary care and general surgery for the 5-year period beginning on such date.</text>
									</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">In the case where the Secretary determines that a hospital described in clause (i) no longer meets
			 the requirement of subclause (II), the Secretary may reduce the otherwise
			 applicable resident limit of the hospital by the amount by which such
 limit was increased under this subparagraph.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H0B83246AC3F34DEE854D56FA9CAC3AF3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Clarification regarding eligibility for other additional residency positions</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed as preventing a hospital described in clause (i) from applying for and receiving additional residency positions under this paragraph that are not reserved for distribution under this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09ECF31781EB4364B92AA4663E2029C9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Distribution of other positions</header><text>For purposes of determining an increase in the otherwise applicable resident limit under subparagraph (A) (other than such an increase described in subparagraph (B)), the following shall apply:</text>
 <clause id="H382E65D6A2F74ACAAD79AC7FE2CED780"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Considerations in distribution</header><text>In determining for which hospitals such an increase is provided under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall take into account the demonstrated likelihood of the hospital filling the positions made available under this paragraph within the first 5 cost reporting periods beginning after the date the increase would be effective, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F0696F362774BE4A98DEC9E555D8496"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Priority for certain hospitals</header><text>Subject to clause (iii), in determining for which hospitals such an increase is provided, the Secretary shall distribute the increase in the following priority order:</text>
 <subclause id="HD73379C1AD0C433FB3301439073EE9A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">First, to hospitals in States with—</text> <item id="HAE67112885234DAAB5167A1094118ED9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>new medical schools that received <quote>Candidate School</quote> status from the Liaison Committee on Medical Education or that received <quote>Pre-Accreditation</quote> status from the American Osteopathic Association Commission on Osteopathic College Accreditation on or after January 1, 2000, and that have achieved or continue to progress toward <quote>Full Accreditation</quote> status (as such term is defined by the Liaison Committee on Medical Education) or toward <quote>Accreditation</quote> status (as such term is defined by the American Osteopathic Association Commission on Osteopathic College Accreditation);</text>
 </item><item id="HB1B1409D08F3449484D276D6C1925895"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>additional locations and branch campuses established on or after January 1, 2000, by medical schools with <quote>Full Accreditation</quote> status (as such term is defined by the Liaison Committee on Medical Education) or <quote>Accreditation</quote> status (as such term is defined by the American Osteopathic Association Commission on Osteopathic College Accreditation); or</text>
 </item><item id="H056490072994498CBF6D7EB5926FC73F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the highest ratio of the total population of the State living in an area designated (under such section 332(a)(1)(A)) as a health professional shortage area, using data from March 23, 2010, to the total population of the State, using census data from July 1, 2009.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H9A17C161CA4C4B0988E283AFE8537179"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Second, to hospitals with which the Secretary cooperates under section 7302(d) of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB7F703C690A7464081F4F64DE94808A1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Third, to hospitals that emphasize training in community-based settings or in hospital outpatient departments.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCAA6A4F60D1943B9971CF70F8EA5DDFF"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Fourth, to hospitals that are meaningful EHR users (as defined in subsection (n)(3)) for the fiscal year which includes the date the hospital submits an application for such increase under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H36714457CE5E426FB1B9FBA2C8EC3C50"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Fifth, to all other hospitals.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HEDCD6EAE0C1C486E90D2EFF75797AC6A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Distribution to hospitals in higher priority group prior to distribution in lower priority groups</header><text>The Secretary may only distribute such an increase to a lower priority group under clause (ii) if all qualifying hospitals in the higher priority group or groups have received the maximum number of increases under such subparagraph that the hospital is eligible for under this paragraph for the fiscal year.</text>
								</clause><clause id="HCC950F8278D84291A81BD81085FCE2A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Requirements for use of additional positions</header>
 <subclause id="H4633D105B834402FB6532D49719B00A3"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subclause (II), a hospital that receives such an increase shall ensure, during the 5-year period beginning on the effective date of such increase, that—</text>
 <item id="H236A12998DCD47E1BD782788982137F4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>not less than 50 percent of the positions attributable to such increase that are used in a given year during such 5-year period are used to train full-time equivalent residents in a shortage specialty residency program (as defined in subparagraph (G)(v)), as determined by the Secretary at the end of such 5-year period;</text>
 </item><item id="HD1BA483685CF4CF2A3B5FDF0E955FF81"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the total number of full-time equivalent residents, excluding any additional positions attributable to such increase, is not less than the average number of full-time equivalent residents during the 3 most recent cost reporting periods ending on or before the effective date of such increase; and</text>
 </item><item id="HCA4B1D0FFC7F41C3952A127FFC63C6A8"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the ratio of full-time equivalent residents in a shortage specialty residency program (as so defined) is not less than the average ratio of full-time equivalent residents in such a program during the 3 most recent cost reporting periods ending on or before the effective date of such increase.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HAD4D0B0B10B64E05A599B78FEC807184"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Redistribution of positions if hospital no longer meets certain requirements</header><text>With respect to each fiscal year described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall determine whether or not a hospital described in subclause (I) meets the requirements of such subclause. In the case that the Secretary determines that such a hospital does not meet such requirements, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <item id="H76E1EE32F0554250BF5D12A9305B39A7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>reduce the otherwise applicable resident limit of the hospital by the amount by which such limit was increased under this paragraph; and</text>
 </item><item id="H7904CC13546749A893E8E32196B65E79"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>provide for the distribution of positions attributable to such reduction in accordance with the requirements of this paragraph.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD1B2716954D469C9AD3A552DE37AC72"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A hospital may not receive more than 75 full-time equivalent additional residency positions under this paragraph for any fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF88E2F055E6F4BE7A614C690B6B5B849"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Application of per resident amounts for primary care and nonprimary care</header><text>With respect to additional residency positions in a hospital attributable to the increase provided under this paragraph, the approved FTE per resident amounts are deemed to be equal to the hospital per resident amounts for primary care and nonprimary care computed under paragraph (2)(D) for that hospital.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5C12C7FDE5D468FABD3603092C47311"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Permitting facilities to apply aggregation rules</header><text>The Secretary shall permit hospitals receiving additional residency positions attributable to the increase provided under this paragraph to, beginning in the fifth year after the effective date of such increase, apply such positions to the limitation amount under paragraph (4)(F) that may be aggregated pursuant to paragraph (4)(H) among members of the same affiliated group.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38052D24345847CF9225E49D736E22EF"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="HA7D92502BBFE4A32BEFC06F4A0F72665"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Otherwise applicable resident limit</header><text>The term <term>otherwise applicable resident limit</term> means, with respect to a hospital, the limit otherwise applicable under subparagraphs (F)(i) and (H) of paragraph (4) on the resident level for the hospital determined without regard to this paragraph but taking into account paragraphs (7)(A), (7)(B), (8)(A), and (8)(B).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA94B0EDA046D451C9B610ABB9C1C01F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reference resident level</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in subclause (II), the term <term>reference resident level</term> means, with respect to a hospital, the resident level for the most recent cost reporting period of the hospital ending on or before the date of enactment of this paragraph, for which a cost report has been settled (or, if not, submitted (subject to audit)), as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H969ACF0F1A1D4A56AD8395A0C0651A31"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Resident level</header><text>The term <term>resident level</term> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (7)(C)(i).</text> </clause><clause id="HCF8189D43D454292940653DB2A359E02"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Shortage specialty residency program</header><text>The term <term>shortage specialty residency program</term> means the following:</text>
 <subclause id="HD34A4568AEC04AECABC067811B7D9320"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Prior to report on shortage specialties</header><text>Prior to the date on which the report of the National Health Care Workforce Commission is submitted under section 3 of the <short-title>Resident Physician Shortage Reduction Act of 2015</short-title>, any approved residency training program in a specialty identified in the report entitled <quote>The Physician Workforce: Projections and Research into Current Issues Affecting Supply and Demand</quote>, issued in December 2008 by the Health Resources and Services Administration, as a specialty whose baseline physician requirements projections exceed the projected supply of total active physicians for the period of 2005 through 2020.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDEDD19022F0B4854AEA6B90FD80FA506"><enum>(II)</enum><header>After report on shortage specialties</header><text>On or after the date on which the report of the National Health Care Workforce Commission is submitted under such section, any approved residency training program in a physician specialty identified in such report as a specialty for which there is a shortage.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C7A9CEB96294673835DE11067A197F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>IME</header><text>Section 1886(d)(5)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD07F8319B17C434ABB214A0A485823B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (v), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>subsections (h)(7) and (h)(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (h)(7), (h)(8), and (h)(9)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B9BBDB0C80542509662B781879B1B2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (x), as added by section 5505(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), as clause (xi) and moving such clause 4 ems to the left; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF57899414DDD4EBA9F79A1548A1EF6EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding after clause (xi), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block id="H06E3AFAD9DBB4CD284FEC9054F4BF319" style="OLC"> <clause id="H5B22CB2CA389433B8E2CA621F9A119B5"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>For discharges occurring on or after July 1, 2017, insofar as an additional payment amount under this subparagraph is attributable to resident positions distributed to a hospital under subsection (h)(9), the indirect teaching adjustment factor shall be computed in the same manner as provided under clause (ii) with respect to such resident positions.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9B03F744E1CA4A09A63D9773BD5C7F10"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study and report by national health care workforce commission</header>
 <subsection id="H494D3540B5AD4F07AF72A72B0CC1BB0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The National Health Care Workforce Commission established under section 5101 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) shall conduct a study of the physician workforce. Such study shall include the identification of physician specialties for which there is a shortage, as defined by the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA1424DB2AAB4414E94448192010BDE29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2018, the National Health Care Workforce Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under subsection (a), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Commission determines appropriate.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA7434AAE13FF4D6E84CBE958334CB37B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study and report on strategies for increasing diversity</header>
 <subsection id="HF087C08D54DA4FB48B583D68B018FC0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (in this section referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study on strategies for increasing the diversity of the health professional workforce. Such study shall include an analysis of strategies for increasing the number of health professionals from rural, lower income, and underrepresented minority communities, including which strategies are most effective for achieving such goal.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H14F1E69D512D494C9626D38322B4C91A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under subsection (a), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


