<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1790D78E68164A88B51B5B951D51E945" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2845 IH: AGOA Enhancement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2845</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150619">June 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To promote access to benefits under the African Growth and Opportunity Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H815D44F8FD4342918408C67D292F1628" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="HAB6591F4F6714DD0B4A41C7E975DDBEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AGOA Enhancement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0AD824F8946E40BA9FB081C6920D5DED" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to support efforts to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9F8257BCEF94CAB893A048CF0BB97A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the rule of law, promote free and fair elections, strengthen and expand the private sector, and fight corruption in sub-Saharan Africa; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29C0E666E7634D6882323255D53191C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote the role of women in social, political, and economic development in sub-Saharan Africa.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HBB2137C43F8B49DEA4460D7DD45DA6F1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Activities in support of transparency</header> <subsection id="H2411DA26DAD341118FBEB8E928852A2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>AGOA website</header> <paragraph id="H51EE8438A1944DDAAB4D885AFEE98E8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall establish a website for the collection and dissemination of information regarding the African Growth and Opportunity Act (in this section referred to as the <quote>AGOA website</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5BCE8A6AE49742A29606F6DA39A60AA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The President shall publish on the AGOA website the information described in paragraph (1), including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3C531A8314E9435D9D75FC92FFB0F7F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information and technical assistance provided at United States Agency for International Development regional trade hubs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7E3C77DF3FA74EB583C90CB49B2EF138"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a link to websites of United States embassies located in eligible sub-Saharan African countries.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB29B032B86E44319E968BA1D42448A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Actions by United States embassies</header><text>The Secretary of State should direct United States embassies located in eligible sub-Saharan African countries to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1FF84DF276AF49D19C8D673AB860379A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote the use by such countries of the benefits available under the African Growth and Opportunity Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB32545A6CE24721A31D961E472832D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include on a publicly available Internet website of such diplomatic missions a link to the AGOA website.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34D50C66F68E445E9430C6CDE05BD485"><enum>(b)</enum><header>AGOA Forum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President should, after each meeting of the United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum, publish on the AGOA website established under subsection (a) the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H746A98E1DB2943F4B22ED696D6170307"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All outcomes of the meeting of the Forum, including any commitments made by member countries and the private sector.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BEC904A95AC44F39D24B1F4AC4540C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of progress made with respect to any commitments made by member countries the private sector from the previous meeting of the Forum.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4D406B9EBD64E22B8DA8BCFDC33FF31"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other information</header><text>The President should disseminate information required by this section in a digital format to the public and publish such information on the AGOA website established under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF05BE5FF44F4671850281E5C2487191"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible sub-Saharan African country</term> means a country that the President has determined meets the eligibility requirements set forth in section 104 of the African Growth and Opportunity Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC587E60F8DBD43268E0C3BB29B00FF7F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Activities in support of trade capacity building</header>
 <subsection id="H75314A29B6ED4713ADAE9A4B8CDA3C95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President should take the following actions:</text> <paragraph id="HA13B34B1B84E48998BB703F183BA0EAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Develop and implement policies to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H027D36CF45DF4667BE80D47B39192275"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage and facilitate trans-boundary cooperation among eligible sub-Saharan African countries in order to facilitate trade; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CA5A3E3A6C7447AAEB9B1F44CD6CC74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage the provision of technical assistance to eligible sub-Saharan African countries to establish and sustain adequate trade capacity development.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE217A275AA79476EA4CC59D4038B1736"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Provide specific training for business in eligible sub-Saharan African countries and government trade officials of eligible sub-Saharan African countries on utilizing access to the benefits of the African Growth and Opportunity Act and other trade preference programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5487377135684DC181A0773E9E978C56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Provide capacity building for African entrepreneurs and trade associations on production strategies, quality standards, formation of cooperatives, and market research and market development.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD816205EA7754D87AF18430B359BF0D3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provide capacity building training to promote diversification of African products and value-added processing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94F5C3469E424A8C848CB98C1ABB1E50"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Provide capacity building and technical assistance funding for African businesses and institutions to help such businesses and institutions comply with United States counter-terrorism initiatives and policies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76963480D5214595BC3F6A97247B2EB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible sub-Saharan African country</term> means a country that the President has determined meets the eligibility requirements set forth in section 104 of the African Growth and Opportunity Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H654E6E1439964682944F09141E5E4A6C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Concurrent compacts under the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003</header>
 <subsection id="H53FA6F7D2DA74563B93B5BA869484CBD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 609 of the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7708">22 U.S.C. 7708</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2F34E8772956445CBF612595C7F7EC5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the first sentence of subsection (k);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H429A808DE01542678C41AF395FDAF2DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (k) (as so amended) as subsection (l); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H20173902FBF84A2BA5B9DBAAA7586573"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (j) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7D39AD388964BE49B8C66F4CE403EFB" style="OLC">
 <subsection commented="no" id="HABE4618BF52945CDBC4855850D5CABFD"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Concurrent compacts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible country that has entered into and has in effect a Compact under this section may enter into and have in effect at the same time not more than one additional Compact in accordance with the requirements of this title if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H23FF2C39FCF14350A57C838A3A5A168B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>one or both of the Compacts are or will be for purposes of regional economic integration, increased regional trade, or cross-border collaborations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF562DD68F3647C08C12D744F54ED071"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Board determines that the country is making considerable and demonstrable progress in implementing the terms of the existing Compact and supplementary agreements thereto.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43C0810EF616448C8DA4FF096AD998F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 613(b)(2)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7712">22 U.S.C. 7712(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the</quote> before <quote>Compact</quote> and inserting <quote>any</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H0AD21F14F43E43CFBB7F0C81289D9CB0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section apply with respect to Compacts entered into between the United States and an eligible country under the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


