<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H14D0440572DB414C95AEF76391FA898D" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3313 IH: Cyber Defense of Federal Networks Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3313</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to strengthen the ability of the Secretary of Homeland
			 Security to detect and prevent intrusions against, and to use
			 countermeasures to protect, agency information systems, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H175DA7D3CB9C473F8C8BDE84D6CF785A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H77C9D1BEA65248AF8BFAC6483D5FAAEE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cyber Defense of Federal Networks Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC43CB10567094E90B885473290B705C0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cyber defense of Federal networks</header> <subsection id="H4CF252788DDF4B77A0ED2B1508EF0AAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle C of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/141">6 U.S.C. 141 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C91175109854C7FBB52D6BE5430590B" style="OLC">
					<section id="H90B33A7E6DAE4F26A9449721E4CB137C"><enum>230.</enum><header>Cybersecurity plans</header>
 <subsection id="H916FCC4D61184155A8FB0BC9CED4CAD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Intrusion detection and response plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall develop and implement an intrusion detection and response plan to detect, identify, and remove intruders in agency information systems. The Secretary, in coordination with the Director, shall update such plan as necessary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2BF40B8DB1AE4715B44C5C424BA9D597"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The intrusion detection and response plan required under subsection (a) shall not apply to the Department of Defense or an element of the intelligence community.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD84698E3620B474D8B282B5121350571"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section and sections 231, 232, and 233:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H204DE79F036B4ACEB459F124736ABE7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFF4D5F7154A44D2E871F231C78FC084B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cybersecurity risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>cybersecurity risk</quote> has the meaning given such term in the second section 226 (relating to the national cybersecurity and communications integration center).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA9D77010890E49EBA1AC24C16B882024"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information system</header><text>The term <quote>information system</quote> has the meaning given such term in the second section 226 (relating to the national cybersecurity and communications integration center).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H213ECB16E59348B988D3BA8A881CBD8F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HED62BC5E455B433EB21C6F9F51899504"><enum>231.</enum><header>Advanced internal defenses</header>
						<subsection id="HC0B7FAE1030949B28C9FA0085BD05C76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Advanced network security tools</header>
 <paragraph id="HCD15E481781240E1BBFF9CE0DA0F10FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the Department’s efforts to continuously diagnose and mitigate cybersecurity risks advanced network security tools to improve visibility of network activity, including through the use of commercial and free or open source tools, to detect and mitigate intrusions and anomalous activity in agencies’ information systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83A52C885B114A43BAA89089F75253D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of plan</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall develop and implement a plan to ensure advanced network security tools, including tools described in paragraph (1), to detect and mitigate intrusions and anomalous activity are available for use by each agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA9E26DA5133459FB4FF732A6109113B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prioritizing advanced security tools</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and in consultation with the heads of appropriate agencies, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H69FE02642786404494C6BF34F916FDE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review and update operational capabilities to ensure appropriate prioritization and use of network security monitoring tools within such agency networks; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF338DBB8396C4D8CBF15F2E11649B509"><enum>(2)</enum><text>brief the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on such prioritization and use.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4FE6356B21148EC9BA1AAEDCA59259A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Improved metrics</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall review and update the metrics used to measure security under section 3554 of title 44, United States Code, to include measures of intrusion and incident detection and response times.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H17BC54EDDC6F4F31A63E51577120D11F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transparency and accountability</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall increase transparency to the public on agency cybersecurity postures, including by increasing the number of metrics available on Federal Government performance websites and, to the greatest extent practicable, displaying metrics for agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H300817CCE3D64C29A8EA4AF135C553AC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Maintenance of technologies</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 3553(b)(6) of title 44, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, operating, and maintaining</quote> after <quote>deploying</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H83509920ECA64CF791850361121E588A"><enum>232.</enum><header>Federal cybersecurity best practices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall regularly assess and require implementation of best practices for—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3BAF36F780454762BB5EBC28D31561CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>securing agency information systems against intrusion; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E490D6BF28A4C068525CCE388591F0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preventing data exfiltration from such systems in the event of an intrusion.</text>
						</paragraph></section><section id="H2B65571E4C8D4D18A2FF6A76A68A82A7"><enum>233.</enum><header>Assessment; reports</header>
 <subsection id="HAACC6995BCFD4A22AE8FCD37394CC979"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2AB000BAC4784C089A8D6F1B09EF2B6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8ABF2DE90D7A41AE937B139C0A15366C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intrusion assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>intrusion assessments</quote> means actions taken under the intrusion detection and response plan described in section 230 to detect, identify, and remove intruders in agency information systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12DE0BF2C2054329BECCE59C8BE463B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intrusion detection and response plan</header><text>The term <quote>intrusion detection and response plan</quote> means the intrusion detection and response plan described in section 230.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H371AED9A151F4F8281AA4403FC77D989"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and publish a report on the effectiveness of the approach and strategy of the Department’s capabilities and plans in securing agency information systems, including in the plans and assessments under sections 230, 231, and 232.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5E5F99EB865B4A11B13019EB98ECE0A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE86DCADE057F4C198007F782D28C027B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this section and 30 days after any update thereto, submit to the appropriate congressional committees the intrusion detection and response plan described in section 230; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31FC0CDC33164BC8A13CAED88882D174"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, submit to Congress—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC045EB5021DF4397AC453C03888784E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the implementation of such intrusion detection and response plan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC247DA4B24B74087A70E032064E8F02B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the findings of the intrusion assessments conducted pursuant to such intrusion detection and response plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1372ED549CF40BAB8D341FBBBEFE656"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the advanced network security tools referred to in section 231;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFED63BFEC8A94D9B8C22C982F896522C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information relating to the results of the assessment of the Secretary of Federal cybersecurity best practices under section 232; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H086CC5AF2A8743B19055BB07793BAB89"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the improved metrics referred to in section 231.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA01ED48B5E647419CFCDF67B9F7E5EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Paragraphs (1) and (2) of the second section 226 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148</external-xref>; relating to the national cybersecurity and communications integration center) are amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H036E9B186B3A4DD69753E86C6B3284AA" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HC37F57B566B047369D3F2E223E9CB320"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H79B4E0B995F745AEAE2D4702D958DA83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <quote>cybersecurity risk</quote> means threats to and vulnerabilities of information or information systems and any related consequences caused by or resulting from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, degradation, disruption, modification, or destruction of such information or information systems, including such related consequences caused by an act of terrorism; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H701025210FF74D9C9DDBA5E89F79D2E8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such term does not include any action that solely involves a violation of a consumer term of service or a consumer licensing agreement;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACFA8F8B705846FAA11259CC3873F2A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>incident</quote> means an occurrence that actually or imminently jeopardizes, without lawful authority, the integrity, confidentiality, or availability of information on an information system, or actually or imminently jeopardizes, without lawful authority, an information system;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H31961400FC2E4949A779970D531E3CC7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents for subtitle C of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by adding at the end the following new items:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66682D5AA1F549B78302B9C6850EBC5D" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 230. Cybersecurity plans.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 231. Advanced internal defenses.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 232. Federal cybersecurity best practices.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 233. Assessment; reports.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7421F79BD624E718ACB9AC96FDD2865" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duties of the Secretary of Homeland Security related to information security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3553(b)(6) of title 44, United States Code, is amended by striking subparagraphs (C) and (D) and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F9DA2472D254C64A725A5165FAC63DF" style="USC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF210DF0F3AA7401082CBCA85176A2126"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing incident detection, analysis, mitigation, and response information, disseminating related homeland security information, and providing remote or onsite technical assistance to the head of an agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB64F289CE929453B849576B9B7CEF28F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>compiling and analyzing data on agency information security and disseminating related homeland security information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5251E3B47A2C476AA93AAEF03936D90B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>developing and conducting targeted risk assessments, including assessments of the risk of terrorism, and operational evaluations for agency information and information systems in consultation with the heads of other agencies or governmental and private entities that own and operate such systems, that may include threat, vulnerability, and impact assessments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2E2EC21E3AC7490DA13E15C82DA55CF7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in conjunction with other agencies and the private sector, assessing and fostering the development of information security technologies and capabilities for use across multiple agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE75370F8937D45848A40015D31208425"><enum>(G)</enum><text>coordinating with appropriate agencies and officials to ensure, to the maximum extent feasible, that policies and directives issued under paragraph (2) are complementary with—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H4B6E4C2157BB4CD994726900510EC3F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>standards and guidelines developed for national security systems; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HFFC47BEC7CE44C72A4A2231C16A764F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>policies and directives issued by the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence under subsection (e)(1); and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H7F94CFF0FC064170A090AC0C45C03331"><enum>4.</enum><header>Directives and imminent threats</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3553 of title 44, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1244818CB8504B03A498C45E6B2BA0C0" style="USC"> <subsection id="H488F0D75698E4CD0854BAF2AB5D99CA0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Direction to agencies</header> <paragraph id="H790DE60A254D41B09EE5B14774011486"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header> <subparagraph id="HDBF64B11D6FA4E11BFDBAEC78399FC61"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3554, and subject to subparagraph (B), in response to a known or reasonably suspected information security threat, vulnerability, risk, or incident, including an act of terrorism, that represents a substantial threat to the information security of an agency, the Secretary may issue a directive to the head of an agency to take any lawful action with respect to the operation of the information system, including such systems owned or operated by another entity on behalf of an agency, that collects, processes, stores, transmits, disseminates, or otherwise maintains agency information, for the purpose of protecting the information system from, or mitigating, an information security threat or an act of terrorism.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD958E88E60F0433AAF8214B55E145041"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The authorities of the Secretary under this subsection shall not apply to a system described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (e).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E142BC5D2224EC6A8BA4388CE2712B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures for use of authority</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HDB6373CEACDA404AA8CB4D54599C0C1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in coordination with the Director and in consultation with Federal contractors, as appropriate, establish procedures under which a directive may be issued under this subsection, which shall include—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H03394C531C3E4AAC94171CBF677C57AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>thresholds and other criteria;</text> </clause><clause id="H77343F730F59427AA56174506E341B52"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>privacy and civil liberties protections; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3F596E35EA0547ADAC5BA13491BA214F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing notice to potentially affected third parties;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H964525E00E9B43ABB506AF77FDC38510"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specify the reasons for the required action and the duration of the directive;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4A92EC9BDC2492B81222E2CDAEF7716"><enum>(C)</enum><text>minimize the impact of a directive under this subsection by—</text> <clause id="H2927BC50F6A84511A86AD5682E5130D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>adopting the least intrusive means possible under the circumstances to secure the agency information systems; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8151228EEBBD41B895BD5BB2AF3751AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>limiting the directive to the shortest period practicable; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H501008745FA4479B8F70CDD1482927F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>notify the Director and the head of any affected agency immediately upon the issuance of a directive under this subsection.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46BE7EFCDB514A948B575D383C921546"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Imminent threats</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7162392B85D64BD283D50A452DD623F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines that there is an imminent threat, including a threat of terrorism, to agency information systems and a directive under this subsection is not reasonably likely to result in a timely response to the threat, the Secretary may authorize the use of protective capabilities under the control of the Secretary for communications or other system traffic transiting to or from or stored on an agency information system without prior consultation with the affected agency for the purpose of ensuring the security of the information, information system, or other agency information systems.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D89B23AF14E4656A3251E13C28D0292"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on delegation</header><text>The authority under this paragraph may not be delegated to an official in a position lower than an Assistant Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74C4E9441D6842AAB8FE0AC2A4B7890F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary shall immediately notify the Director and the head and chief information officer (or equivalent official) of each affected agency of—</text>
 <clause id="HB1548AF8AFC54FA9965E9AFA88DF526B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any action taken under this subsection; and</text> </clause><clause id="HAB5C05251439479F8D9C98E20D117DB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reasons for and duration and nature of the action.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3832342FF9E242E6A813FD0CA9C5710F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Other law</header><text>Any action of the Secretary under this paragraph shall be consistent with applicable law.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8905E4506364403C9030BC8680A23F96"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may direct or authorize lawful action or protective capability under this subsection only to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H82A7CBB540074100B767171E0647C0AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protect agency information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61099C5E2E254EE1870037FB92088820"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require the remediation of or protect against identified information security risks, including acts of terrorism, with respect to—</text>
 <clause id="H1DBFD0240E144754AABCE21992C077D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information collected or maintained by or on behalf of an agency; or</text> </clause><clause id="H2CD53B3903D34569ADF36A48CA38B32F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that portion of an information system used or operated by an agency or by a contractor of an agency or other organization on behalf of an agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H44BBDA298DA94DB296F44D870289036E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report to Congress regarding DHS functions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3553 of title 44, United States Code, as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95BA899F8C2A4CCF9E51FFD1C45F7328" style="USC">
 <subsection commented="no" id="HD99B73FA1E8A4CC6A5BD0AC54A2B5965"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than February 1 of every year, the Secretary shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, regarding the specific actions the Secretary has taken pursuant to subsections (b) and (h).</text>
				</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


