<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H4B2D5561E5384E9BBF42DF61E96BFC0B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 639 ENR: Improving Regulatory Transparency for New Medical Therapies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Fourteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the sixth day of January, two thousand and fifteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 639</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act with respect to drug scheduling recommendations by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and with respect to registration of manufacturers and distributors seeking to conduct clinical testing.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA9BDAC9BC06A492485C2C3A258B18CC3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1785E58CF6C74D3F90B6B126A3B37CF0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Regulatory Transparency for New Medical Therapies Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5ACBEC74AE1E4284912ED7DB6CE3C847"><enum>2.</enum><header>Scheduling of substances included in new FDA-approved drugs</header> <subsection id="HEEA34DF365574081B10BFAB403EB37DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective date of approval</header> <paragraph id="H79CE62600C9A441BA310DFF609673500"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date of drug approval</header><text>Section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9359F7C5DC3F48A2ABDEF143FBC787AF" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H79B62703024543118C969C719B29391F"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Date of approval in the case of recommended controls under the CSA</header> 
<paragraph id="HAA01BD896FF44D1FA68238C15CEE1ED3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an application under subsection (b) with respect to a drug for which the Secretary provides notice to the sponsor that the Secretary intends to issue a scientific and medical evaluation and recommend controls under the Controlled Substances Act, approval of such application shall not take effect until the interim final rule controlling the drug is issued in accordance with section 201(j) of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AD06EF1CE884D248513A4336496FC93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date of approval</header><text>For purposes of this section, with respect to an application described in paragraph (1), the term <term>date of approval</term> shall mean the later of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H44609B1F33684390A20E5ABC70A4ADA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date an application under subsection (b) is approved under subsection (c); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4EA86C1FDD2479AB6A902185EAAEDC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of issuance of the interim final rule controlling the drug.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6783AD542374C16A4FB30EEC10858E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date of approval of biological products</header><text>Section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A8585BCF5E6462F9792193AB8A148DB" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H89A17A4BC06341A386A2675F2460055C"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Date of approval in the case of recommended controls under the CSA</header> <paragraph id="HB0FDB6EA9FDE4D53BBFFBFF12915D62A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an application under subsection (a) with respect to a biological product for which the Secretary provides notice to the sponsor that the Secretary intends to issue a scientific and medical evaluation and recommend controls under the Controlled Substances Act, approval of such application shall not take effect until the interim final rule controlling the biological product is issued in accordance with section 201(j) of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9B13B3EF1DB47E0BA26F64997C02F3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date of approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, with respect to an application described in paragraph (1), references to the date of approval of such application, or licensure of the product subject to such application, shall mean the later of—</text> <subparagraph id="H77FF57DD8C0040DDA721537B8A1A36AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date an application is approved under subsection (a); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59521DA580054562B307D459D01D3BD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of issuance of the interim final rule controlling the biological product.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CD74E69679448308E44B92D91CA17E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date of approval of animal drugs</header> <subparagraph id="H33D0386465D54AB38540D96393D1C42A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 512 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360b">21 U.S.C. 360b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H972EA8BE88AA459DA0B136579EEE398B" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HA4FDFC0F4DCB4A5EB71DF6CFCD90DBBC"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Date of approval in the case of recommended controls under the CSA</header> 
<paragraph id="H2044FBAC2BC94E1AB6CB85164598889D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an application under subsection (b) with respect to a drug for which the Secretary provides notice to the sponsor that the Secretary intends to issue a scientific and medical evaluation and recommend controls under the Controlled Substances Act, approval of such application shall not take effect until the interim final rule controlling the drug is issued in accordance with section 201(j) of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B4325FCF1DC44E1A18AEE61387A1034"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date of approval</header><text>For purposes of this section, with respect to an application described in paragraph (1), the term <term>date of approval</term> shall mean the later of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0C64C80E09984C11B180898E01683057"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date an application under subsection (b) is approved under subsection (c); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99EF0D9973C5438B9114F26A78C0C9EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of issuance of the interim final rule controlling the drug.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E4BDFD2537A450BB9A88B89D89C8A85"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conditional approval</header><text>Section 571(d) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360ccc">21 U.S.C. 360ccc(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3618258FCE254F6FA104C06C5690B0BA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HF314DB59FD9F47B5B26D259187C9D789"><enum>(4)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1B39FB6EF1C24E7E99377150AB7F0F7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of an application under subsection (a) with respect to a drug for which the Secretary provides notice to the sponsor that the Secretary intends to issue a scientific and medical evaluation and recommend controls under the Controlled Substances Act, conditional approval of such application shall not take effect until the interim final rule controlling the drug is issued in accordance with section 201(j) of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA9C5F8E02C74BF2975E8ECAC3CC00BF" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of this section, with respect to an application described in subparagraph (A), the term <term>date of approval</term> shall mean the later of—</text> <clause id="HCFC045485E68487E8799C9278DEDC4C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date an application under subsection (a) is conditionally approved under subsection (b); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEABE74E366DE4CB18D91A39F6DE2DEFC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date of issuance of the interim final rule controlling the drug.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA60FFDF2ADE44E9380C49E169BB72F16"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Indexing of legally marketed unapproved new animal drugs</header><text>Section 572 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360ccc-1">21 U.S.C. 360ccc–1</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE65398834BA847F3B8FA5DE3F660203D" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H0A22C3008BEA4C928E0BC7A9D5527063"><enum>(k)</enum><text>In the case of a request under subsection (d) to add a drug to the index under subsection (a) with respect to a drug for which the Secretary provides notice to the person filing the request that the Secretary intends to issue a scientific and medical evaluation and recommend controls under the Controlled Substances Act, a determination to grant the request to add such drug to the index shall not take effect until the interim final rule controlling the drug is issued in accordance with section 201(j) of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE43060249BB74151B625D68557F2F3A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Date of approval for designated new animal drugs</header><text>Section 573(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360ccc-2">21 U.S.C. 360ccc–2(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0F142254DE44F31ADC751BED09107C6" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HDCED6EE6C32C47EBA5F7A3F3048B42ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of determining the 7-year period of exclusivity under paragraph (1) for a drug for which the Secretary intends to issue a scientific and medical evaluation and recommend controls under the Controlled Substances Act, the drug shall not be considered approved or conditionally approved until the date that the interim final rule controlling the drug is issued in accordance with section 201(j) of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H44B14309D20B4EFC8F44A7C437CDEE4D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scheduling of newly approved drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (i) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB0F93412DF5F4F5A8C8888F658D38AD7" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H35E1E202E21547B09C7D88A27D9EE868"><enum>(j)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8F8CB534026A4FB5A359E32B00A00A0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a drug referred to in subsection (f), if the Secretary of Health and Human Services recommends that the Attorney General control the drug in schedule II, III, IV, or V pursuant to subsections (a) and (b), the Attorney General shall, not later than 90 days after the date described in paragraph (2), issue an interim final rule controlling the drug in accordance with such subsections and section 202(b) using the procedures described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H410D7938CC2E46D9A7A1A98CE1242B27" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date described in this paragraph shall be the later of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0C255DB3D7C445998515F9E32404F053"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the Attorney General receives the scientific and medical evaluation and the scheduling recommendation from the Secretary of Health and Human Services in accordance with subsection (b); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3D0A8220CC546C98C3ADBBFEC297287"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the Attorney General receives notification from the Secretary of Health and Human Services that the Secretary has approved an application under section 505(c), 512, or 571 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, or indexed a drug under section 572 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, with respect to the drug described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA21FAE98883142119E90DC0B72C26B47" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A rule issued by the Attorney General under paragraph (1) shall become immediately effective as an interim final rule without requiring the Attorney General to demonstrate good cause therefor. The interim final rule shall give interested persons the opportunity to comment and to request a hearing. After the conclusion of such proceedings, the Attorney General shall issue a final rule in accordance with the scheduling criteria of subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section and section 202(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HCE874760EA7344618717258AC19776D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension of patent term</header><text>Section 156 of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8FFD021B7477443B951DC69EDBE6E5B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, or in the case of a drug product described in subsection (i), within the sixty-day period beginning on the covered date (as defined in subsection (i))</quote> after <quote>marketing or use</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5E1FAE39CBE40B39F56D1591461E950"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H221C7A8583D544ADB87E2D10FD32EF4C" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H16B82D3C0C47419C9494A23DB950EBAA"><enum>(i)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFF8B73DBEA0F4BF78032CB57B755A270"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For purposes of this section, if the Secretary of Health and Human Services provides notice to the sponsor of an application or request for approval, conditional approval, or indexing of a drug product for which the Secretary intends to recommend controls under the Controlled Substances Act, beginning on the covered date, the drug product shall be considered to—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB89ECE08E954CC3A27BD10C415F899A" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have been approved or indexed under the relevant provision of the Public Health Service Act or Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H718B75B967A843518089B171188629A3" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have permission for commercial marketing or use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA18E69CAA6FE4864837BE335F6291E15" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered date</term> means the later of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HED554AD005CF4F55852071A714B1763C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date an application is approved—</text> <clause id="HCB68A8F4095D46D087E45640B248650F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under section 351(a)(2)(C) of the Public Health Service Act; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H87C3C2070716440F997670FB3CC09BA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under section 505(b) or 512(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H092A56DC9E804043A6213298CB0F26DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date an application is conditionally approved under section 571(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4ACA90C773254F388B08B7912BA8922B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date a request for indexing is granted under section 572(d) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5325467A5EB45F5B5BA06A882A5DF4E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the date of issuance of the interim final rule controlling the drug under section 201(j) of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC03434081685415CBAB1FC8DBAF36649"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enhancing new drug development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H712C1E3C88BE4B89831E1EE381A34188" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA079927FD2024C3489ADFE2F7200CFBA"><enum>(i)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE72D615F43BF4C5287B5E6119254D774"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of registration to manufacture a controlled substance under subsection (d) for use only in a clinical trial, the Attorney General shall register the applicant, or serve an order to show cause upon the applicant in accordance with section 304(c), not later than 180 days after the date on which the application is accepted for filing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5D292F764F748ECB574585DB0AC56AF" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of registration to manufacture a controlled substance under subsection (a) for use only in a clinical trial, the Attorney General shall, in accordance with the regulations issued by the Attorney General, issue a notice of application not later than 90 days after the application is accepted for filing. Not later than 90 days after the date on which the period for comment pursuant to such notice ends, the Attorney General shall register the applicant, or serve an order to show cause upon the applicant in accordance with section 304(c), unless the Attorney General has granted a hearing on the application under section 1008(i) of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H771A8C835DC84EEBA7DDF3226E4D531F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Re-Exportation Among Members of the European Economic Area</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1003 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/953">21 U.S.C. 953</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA24E975F2E424C798055F77F396A2E15"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (f)—</text> <subparagraph id="H73ABC447F8F84F01B9E78E23D60E31FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5)—</text> 
<clause id="HE3B3316427FD4E30976FBAC3A4637908"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>(5)(A)</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H6AD252E77A974E0DA657BCB3506E76B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>, except that the controlled substance may be exported from a second country that is a member of the European Economic Area to another country that is a member of the European Economic Area, provided that the first country is also a member of the European Economic Area</quote> before the period at the end; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFDA4FBB53B844922A181E8F6FBA5F0BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58B56CA0DBB24DCBB896A2A9BA62D044" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HDEA22EEF91454C939EBA8D4073227E81" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subsequent to any re-exportation described in subparagraph (A), a controlled substance may continue to be exported from any country that is a member of the European Economic Area to any other such country, if—</text> 
<clause id="HD2B20AD6D6944F92AE9A0D5CDDA77659"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the conditions applicable with respect to the first country under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (6), and (7) are met by each subsequent country from which the controlled substance is exported pursuant to this paragraph; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6D83367F7316429482694671A4998DC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the conditions applicable with respect to the second country under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (6), and (7) are met by each subsequent country to which the controlled substance is exported pursuant to this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02225B2B61BC4A33BD22583DC28B157A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text> <clause id="HB2D27B6C5CC34010B3D56004A457BAC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(6)</quote> and inserting <quote>(6)(A)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H38A94DAD73914D82882A96DEEFB61A8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB51383F5CA23496A9221B5D4CEE1A119" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H43F43BDB9E30431997C49AC377DEE3CB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of re-exportation among members of the European Economic Area, within 30 days after each re-exportation, the person who exported the controlled substance from the United States delivers to the Attorney General—</text> 
<clause id="H43A2FD758EA24465A9C26C8335D9DDFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>documentation certifying that such re-exportation has occurred; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9317380B5D794320A751E77FBC019317"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information concerning the consignee, country, and product.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6FFA6841DB041FE9A87D7DEB997F444"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4A6735E74B5469B8B1FA619A2CF7E5A" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7F28028B46DA4229BB311B0654E8DBD8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (5) and (6) of subsection (f) in the case of any controlled substance in schedule I or II or any narcotic drug in schedule III or IV, the Attorney General shall not promulgate nor enforce any regulation, subregulatory guidance, or enforcement policy which impedes re-exportation of any controlled substance among European Economic Area countries, including by promulgating or enforcing any requirement that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE11364168B9C48A5AF608220112C6856"><enum>(1)</enum><text>re-exportation from the first country to the second country or re-exportation from the second country to another country occur within a specified period of time; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD104F4B11854F858B43FE9DE5FEF4F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information concerning the consignee, country, and product be provided prior to exportation of the controlled substance from the United States or prior to each re-exportation among members of the European Economic Area.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
</bill> 


