<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7590A6CDBBD2477CAC0D623A77FAF2D7" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1613 IH: Federal Vehicle Repair Cost Savings Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1613</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150325">March 25, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga of Michigan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000373">Mr. Ashford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To reduce the operation and maintenance costs associated with the Federal fleet by encouraging the use of remanufactured parts, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9F036274CC204A7C98C33C29BCA37786" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD292EF1F82D54399A81EEA3016F0D81C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Vehicle Repair Cost Savings Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8316E385EDBE4B2A9454202B5E38346A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that, in March 2013, the Government Accountability Office issued a report that confirmed that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H36C9D147DB884A66902017CA75E561D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there are approximately 588,000 vehicles in the civilian Federal fleet;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H502ACB70D7644C268FDE8F30BC579F1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal agencies spent approximately $975,000,000 on repair and maintenance of the Federal fleet in 2011;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAC49E2CA9174D59AF232CA85420D59E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>remanufactured vehicle components, such as engines, starters, alternators, steering racks, and clutches, tend to be less expensive than comparable new replacement parts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62C712F9DD404A0A804527ED32EDBE74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States Postal Service and the Department of the Interior both informed the Government Accountability Office that the respective agencies rely on the use of remanufactured vehicle components to reduce costs.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H35A0CB843A684CA2BD6F2A5440A36757"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H607B142A93DD48ACA4811BD75D12682B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of title 40, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A25B75D2A0040EAB84A536574DA0B3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>remanufactured vehicle component</term> means a vehicle component (including an engine, transmission, alternator, starter, turbocharger, steering, or suspension component) that has been returned to same-as-new, or better, condition and performance by a standardized industrial process that incorporates technical specifications (including engineering, quality, and testing standards) to yield fully-warranted products.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H958B5F3F59624BB7BCA5C35BA3DBB139"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirement to use remanufactured vehicle components</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The head of each Federal agency—</text> 
<paragraph id="H74A73880E1BE461B9458FBCEF7A81D45"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall encourage the use of remanufactured vehicle components to maintain Federal vehicles, if using such components reduces the cost of maintaining the Federal vehicles while maintaining quality; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFC65EF1592D4EA697ED84C7E8B3E022"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not encourage the use of remanufactured vehicle components to maintain Federal vehicles, if using such components—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0CEB78A199C2429DB81639C852FA0F20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>does not reduce the cost of maintaining Federal vehicles;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H363132E42B7F489994AC4BDA79600F1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lowers the quality of vehicle performance, as determined by the employee of the Federal agency responsible for the repair decision; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE737C105B19B4EDFB72FF6A445C53926"><enum>(C)</enum><text>delays the return to service of a vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

