<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDB663CF646C644FC9CF9E5DF8D0C582A" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2119 IH: To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require that State applications for State plan waivers under the Medicaid program be approved only if such applications are budget neutral, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2119</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150429">April 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000364">Mr. Shimkus</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require that State applications for State plan waivers under the Medicaid program be approved only if such applications are budget neutral, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0ED5D804702D4BB4B1BFBFC984F66FA3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF50615E31F744FF3A36507B27AE1690E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Budget neutrality required for State plan waivers under Medicaid</header> 
<subsection id="H3DEBC18BB46542C3A60E2A068FD258EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1115(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H15EBF694612A4567AA07A6D84E98E1A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6AC6D059FEE46778F7EEB2E2428F1F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAEA17591873242B99517493B5C61807B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H8E59AF487B56457695F9C75ACD95F426"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph id="H6F6405727AFC47068A6ED83E47023ED6" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Beginning with fiscal year 2016, the Secretary shall require, as a condition on the approval of a demonstration project in a State under this section, that the project be budget neutral, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with subparagraph (B) and subject to subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HACE422616E8947478EDA866BD3F3F9AE" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination by the Secretary under this paragraph on whether a demonstration project is budget neutral shall be based on—</text> <clause id="HC31697C637574E3CB7CA0C3B5E3272C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the historical Federal and State expenditures made under the State plan under title XIX, including any adjustments to such expenditures (other than adjustments to account for improper or otherwise unallowable payments) supported by data or other documentation; </text></clause> 
<clause id="H467F66878F2B446D95C5BB1801E5D93F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the State’s historical spending growth rates and population growth rates, including any adjustments supported by data or documentation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3C380A9CA75B4AF1B419404BB5B6C282"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other criteria determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFBDAE6A95A0D4EB2AA86CA1E004C38E0" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not determine that a demonstration project is budget neutral under this paragraph unless the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services certifies to the Secretary that the project is budget neutral.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCAD93799514B4585A221E508F72C61F9" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>budget neutral</quote> means, with respect to a demonstration project, that the Federal expenditures under the project in the State do not exceed the Federal expenditures that would otherwise have been made if the State had in effect a plan approved under title XIX. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB394EECB1BD847A9A19FB5F256BD2FFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) (as redesignated by paragraph (1))—</text> <subparagraph id="H25A43DE0C4794D93B3B1A2538D06348B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Congress concerning actions</quote> and inserting <quote>Congress on, and make available to the public information on, any actions</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0DA8FD2C8F2F4AC4B39665736B9DC0F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, including any data or other information relating to determinations of the Secretary under paragraph (3) that such demonstration projects are budget neutral</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H35E5DDFD0F684019B80B2C08E66F06DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue regulations to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a), including regulations specifying the criteria to be used in making determinations under paragraph (3) of section 1115(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315(d)</external-xref>), as inserted by subsection (a). </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


