<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD1BE9EFE20194C2E89945215B890B904" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3707 IH: Groundwork USA Trust Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3707</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151007">October 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Groundwork USA national
			 office, to provide grants to certain nonprofit organizations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H60B896CA0CA54E4EA07C3B1515B06227" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1E729033647448BD8E4735267F63B736" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Groundwork USA Trust Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB595837DC91D4663A172ABF42CBC2A06"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF0A0AFA24BF24F34B14FA97524CE86D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>locally organized and controlled entities that are linked together through a national program office have the ability to lead cost-effective projects and programs that are responsive to community needs and essential to improving the local environment, economy, and quality of life;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B649C8DE8D044E0B3A4F78824E3897A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>local community involvement with how land is being used is an essential component to the economic success of a neighborhood;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3645021D9894732A6DDA94C7222A0CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>underutilized and neglected vacant lands significantly erode nearby property values and burden municipal tax bases;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D29AAF4B6A34970AB5C88FC6F5F0F7F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>landscaping and maintenance, especially when local citizens are involved in the process, decreases negative stigma and generates civic pride, which in turn significantly reduces vandalism and illicit activities typically associated with idle lands;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6346F864EA25458983BF4D297401F325"><enum>(5)</enum><text>cleaning, landscaping, and tree planting within vacant and abandoned land and brownfields adds economic value to a community through increased occupancy rates, and improved sales appeal of nearby residential and commercial real estate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H761C15CDF9044D729FA915A0F500E94E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the transformation of idle lands and brownfields into cleaner, greener, community assets has been exemplified by a network of federally backed Groundwork USA Trusts for over 8 years.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1F93099BDC3843CD99BDA0977829841D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H78A4D40C5ADE4CA0BE7070A371906DFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Brownfields</header><text>The term <term>brownfields</term> means real property, the expansion, redevelopment, or reuse of which may be complicated by the presence or potential presence of a hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAFBB2AEB2B24F668E158289C77162A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible organization</header><text>The term <term>eligible organization</term> means a—</text> <subparagraph id="HF67EBAA62A58425A9C4CE924107DCAA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>nonprofit organization that applies for a grant award under section 4(b) to establish a Groundwork USA Trust; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2FA756F6E6841069CF1F73FCD7B74DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Groundwork USA Trust.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC4B48A635C94648BFB9BF87EC3185F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Groundwork USA national office</header><text>The term <term>Groundwork USA national office</term> means the independent, nonprofit, environmental business incorporated under the laws of the State of New York, which overseas and creates a link between local Groundwork USA Trust offices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16B6250AA7934B45BB41E7E920C13EF3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Groundwork USA trust</header><text>The term <term>Groundwork USA Trust</term> means an independent, nonprofit, environmental organization that works with communities to improve their environment, economy, and quality of life through local action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H225E98B2E52D473BB9655DA5661C4E6F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB037D3C5A4E746EB9503BE7E59157DF5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H9C02D875A64649689964EFC252A7149F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of groundwork USA trust program</header> <subsection id="H4A28C5E04F55442EB79B059DC3AFED9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of grant program</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Groundwork USA national office, is authorized to award grants to eligible organizations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEC8A74485D584A5B80FB681FFE20815C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible organization desiring a grant under the program shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary, in consultation with the Groundwork USA national office, may require.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HFEA663A9156146FCA4671FA4D576BC4B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Criteria for selection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each grant award provided under section 4(a) shall be made on the basis of the quality of the application submitted, taking into consideration such factors as the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5D9F7519701B410BAD4909C83703AC95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The population and demographics of the community and the environmental, community, or economic development issues which an eligible entity could help address.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02CEFA5C82834BE0A4A38804C9279A7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The level of experience with community and environmental improvement activities of an eligible organization and the role such organization will play in the implementation of Groundwork USA Trust activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE028F8458B0447DD9C844899D71F3F72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The level in which the community or local government in which the eligible organization is based is a current or past recipient of funding or assistance from the EPA Brownfields Program and demonstrated success in those efforts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4EA88E1073444BB80976BF6BFDE61EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The level in which the eligible organization has partnered with the National Park Service and demonstrated success in those efforts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99D8B5BBE4EE4903B0AE84AA764A554D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The level of community interest and commitment to learn about, evaluate, and partner with a Groundwork USA Trust.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECD8774FEDE54D94B52DD6F687DFA0D4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number and level of opportunities to improve the local environment for conservation, recreation, and economic development, including:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8432B3A815B2492EA13A2CD515B1EDD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The potential to facilitate the creation, improvement, and stewardship of parks, greenways, open space, and nature reserves and increase opportunities for recreation, conservation, food security, environmental education, and other environmental improvements in communities impacted by brownfields.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3F1FDA48EC9411EB14252E6962568FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The potential to stimulate economic and environmental rejuvenation of communities impacted by brownfield issues.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E4D124C4385459395A5B02A79AA5427"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The potential to increase the capacity of communities with limited means to improve their environment, economy, and quality of life.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD6F784E7AC34581A22F68D9D58F9134"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The potential to engage the local community in the planning and development of projects and programs to improve its local environment, including the assessment, cleanup, and reuse of brownfield sites for parks, recreation facilities, nature areas, gardens, trails, and other community benefits.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F82C0C2A41546E688A107E40C4D018D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The potential to contribute to the use or reuse of existing infrastructure.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18A683E5F5F44F4EBB40C2AE948E699D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The ability to address the issue of brownfields in the community or target area, including:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBBF5B01422714A89A32449C09B92B5FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The potential to leverage or stimulate funds from other sources to support the assessment and remediation of brownfields and their reuse for parks, recreation facilities, nature areas, and other community benefits.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1834C81E83CE4F5A81CAC0EE01B33FB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The potential to engage the local community in the planning and implementation of projects and programs to assess, cleanup, and reuse brownfields for parks, recreation facilities, nature areas, and other community benefits.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBF7B5811B204D6E8C38E86ED78D6211"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The potential to help reduce the threats to human health and the local environment associated with the presence of hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFF3DE58DCA440B9BBBF1CD519D9C8D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The potential to help address or facilitate the identification and reduction of threats to the health and welfare of populations at risk.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H6C598E9F7DDB40EABCB21420998AC8DB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A grant award provided under the program may be used to—</text> <paragraph id="H1EEFF764D57A4638B3748B1A2EE618F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide training, research, and technical assistance to individuals and organizations, as appropriate, to facilitate the inventory of brownfield sites, site assessments, remediation of brownfield sites, community involvement, or site preparation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H703BFA3541E34BE8A374B76E9E7A5676"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase the capacity of communities to improve and care for their local environment;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HECBD45AE466A4BFAA515CDDF050ABFA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reclaim vacant and derelict lands for conservation, recreation, and economic development;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6DBBFA72CF545CEA1ECD9E688C1B2DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>clean up and care for neglected areas to signal community pride and rejuvenation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H772C782A6F454A5797409048E96CC81B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>return brownfields to economically productive use while restoring blighted landscapes with healthy environments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37514A0C618D488FBE70F77C92BF8284"><enum>(6)</enum><text>integrate environmental education, food security, health and fitness, resource management, and job training;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3253179CF59C49688FD5BD5C5B13FEA0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>encourage businesses, local governments, nonprofits, and communities to work together for sustainable environmental care and enhancement;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5D185D375234F8ABA18628AFD092B7F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>support businesses, local governments, nonprofits, and communities in efforts to improve their local environment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2A4474C4A9C4213A42A0AEE679EB2B0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>raise the profile of urban environmental improvements as part of a comprehensive approach to smart growth strategies and rejuvenation of inner city communities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AC644FF10C048848A8561D7DB4BDA4F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>acquire real property and buildings to rehabilitate and improve upon for the local community and perform maintenance on such property and buildings, including mowing, irrigating, landscaping, painting, and providing structural repairs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A302D391FD44270A0F2FA13229DFF97"><enum>(11)</enum><text>expand operations and locations of offices to benefit a larger geographic area, and increase staff;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A155BFC843C4DCA8C0152AA134752E0"><enum>(12)</enum><text>develop information systems and utilize such systems for community- and regional-based research and data dissemination; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H872E353E49554010B1EEEAA4FBC53841"><enum>(13)</enum><text>develop programs that encourage regional and national partnering with other environmental organizations.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H03D1076294DD47DC8418A80F0565518C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Maximum grant award</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A grant award under the program shall not exceed $400,000 for any fiscal year.</text> </section><section id="H1D60342A564E4D588CC7B05E97CF4E49"><enum>8.</enum><header>Limitation on administrative costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may reserve not more than 15 percent of the amount made available under this Act to carry out the program in a fiscal year for administrative costs, including managing, administering, and assisting with technical support of operations for national and local Groundwork USA offices.</text>
 </section><section id="HBC719DB355F147DBBEC95BBED1B4D42F"><enum>9.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each grant recipient shall submit to the Secretary and the national Groundwork USA national office an annual report at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary, in consultation with the Groundwork USA national office, may require.</text>
 </section><section id="HCB1A1C0C92C44AFA926618587CDB14F9"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the program $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2021.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


