<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB9F53AD54BA446D190076AE101068A3E" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 644 PCS: America Gives More Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 56</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 644</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>February 23, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><action><action-date>April 16, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date>April 20, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permanently extend and expand the charitable
			 deduction for contributions of food inventory. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H06B6100FEA624248A3E2D779D1F99FBA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8C00C7DBCE5E48C1991A21BF6D86760D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>America Gives More Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5A4365E0CB0A456985BA606B890BBC51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension and expansion of charitable deduction for contributions of food inventory</header> <subsection id="H8FAE99ECA4974A69B838A0D13BCDA38C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permanent extension</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">Section 170(e)(3)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking clause (iv).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB9AE72454FEE40E5B74F1B083D9F46CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increase in limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 170(e)(3)(C) of such Code, as amended by subsection (a), is amended by striking clause (ii), by redesignating clause (iii) as clause (iv), and by inserting after clause (i) the following new clauses:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3720D27164374092AEE7F41676920A68" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H5B8246E6452F4B9A824BC937F3C46F73"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate amount of such contributions for any taxable year which may be taken into account under this section shall not exceed—</text>
 <subclause id="H44DE360018A347DDA4B27BCEBD7B4B5A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of any taxpayer other than a C corporation, 15 percent of the taxpayer’s aggregate net income for such taxable year from all trades or businesses from which such contributions were made for such year, computed without regard to this section, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H207D7343C90E4902AC442BCFB100779E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a C corporation, 15 percent of taxable income (as defined in subsection (b)(2)(D)).</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HEEB4D483E4684A109C162B39EE64C57D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Rules related to limitation</header> <subclause id="H1E3F7FAC9CD348FEBE4518E0ED18230C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Carryover</header><text>If such aggregate amount exceeds the limitation imposed under clause (ii), such excess shall be treated (in a manner consistent with the rules of subsection (d)) as a charitable contribution described in clause (i) in each of the 5 succeeding taxable years in order of time.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3028E2507E5042638F2D2FFB7A4565EA"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Coordination with overall corporate limitation</header><text>In the case of any charitable contribution allowable under clause (ii)(II), subsection (b)(2)(A) shall not apply to such contribution, but the limitation imposed by such subsection shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the aggregate amount of such contributions. For purposes of subsection (b)(2)(B), such contributions shall be treated as allowable under subsection (b)(2)(A).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE8830459F5D4E98B4CCC504C633213C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of basis for certain taxpayers</header><text>Section 170(e)(3)(C) of such Code, as amended by subsections (a) and (b), is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AF11D0EAC7045D299C9F1FCE5024CC5" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H0929FD95A5F54D298E4AE33B1E5F1464"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Determination of basis for certain taxpayers</header><text>If a taxpayer—</text> <subclause id="HC3DAB2D2AB8A4784BB4EE4AFD75E926C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>does not account for inventories under section 471, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA1DC240B541C4F98B5B466989DAA96B9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not required to capitalize indirect costs under section 263A,</text> </subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">the taxpayer may elect, solely for purposes of subparagraph (B), to treat the basis of any apparently wholesome food as being equal to 25 percent of the fair market value of such food.</continuation-text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H03453C6CEA1F446182AE2BD092D0F907"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determination of fair market value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 170(e)(3)(C) of such Code, as amended by subsections (a), (b), and (c), is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H259896B026C74D29B65E7BAD22F2E7F7" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H710472B3813F4564AF52B583BEB411FF"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Determination of fair market value</header><text>In the case of any such contribution of apparently wholesome food which cannot or will not be sold solely by reason of internal standards of the taxpayer, lack of market, or similar circumstances, or by reason of being produced by the taxpayer exclusively for the purposes of transferring the food to an organization described in subparagraph (A), the fair market value of such contribution shall be determined—</text>
 <subclause id="H33B48B433BE24C2887401FAAF3CC7D53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>without regard to such internal standards, such lack of market, such circumstances, or such exclusive purpose, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6F242F8C3C19455D8D9098962EC6C75A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by taking into account the price at which the same or substantially the same food items (as to both type and quality) are sold by the taxpayer at the time of the contribution (or, if not so sold at such time, in the recent past).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6B00430741D6426E8BDFF02BF3C9B8B5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective Date</header>
 <paragraph id="HD80C40FEE84546B0BEAC0547440774D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amendments made by this section shall apply to contributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act, in taxable years ending after such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF390D25565924A03A7C9E8A0180D17F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation; applicability to C corporations</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (b) shall apply to contributions made in taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H620074B3B9634590A110EA6E9C9C58A2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rule allowing certain tax-free distributions from individual retirement accounts for charitable
			 purposes made permanent</header>
 <subsection id="H7CB4A259B7B5489E9486C05A36338B7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408">Section 408(d)(8)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subparagraph (F).</text> </subsection><subsection id="H5D52E363882D4A3B94837C79B552BD22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to distributions made in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2014.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HDC60CFDD1A144D718E29A2935D455B26"><enum>4.</enum><header>Special rule for qualified conservation contributions made permanent</header>
			<subsection id="H30C360828A7A44C68614947B7435828D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="HFBB243BC126B49B69D4EA1660B5E9602"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals</header><text>Subparagraph (E) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170(b)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to contributions of qualified conservation contributions) is amended by striking clause (vi).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H916F61BC2A814C529DBE9CF8E96C1A34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Corporations</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 170(b)(2) of such Code (relating to qualified conservation contributions) is amended by striking clause (iii).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H835B445E4BE64524AC023D330EBE4E80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contributions of capital gain real property made for conservation purposes by Native Corporations</header>
 <paragraph id="H4A0405B403AF44598819EF41DA170D8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 170(b)(2) of such Code is amended by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D), and by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5C1E5EF442A4A918F3309268935D676" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="H6AFE0C7102BE4A45A836FFDEC3A38564"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified conservation contributions by certain Native Corporations</header>
 <clause id="H438F0A7872524BA98DE30084E6C97FF5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any qualified conservation contribution (as defined in subsection (h)(1)) which—</text> <subclause id="HE3E80819980948E49AB9BE3F6D51DF94"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is made by a Native Corporation, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H557458A6F5FC4720BF24BE9A05B74181"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is a contribution of property which was land conveyed under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act,</text>
								</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">shall be allowed to the extent that the aggregate amount of such contributions does not exceed the
			 excess of the taxpayer’s taxable income over the amount of charitable
 contributions allowable under subparagraph (A).</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H1B78A6E8C7FA487396ED9765D2B258BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Carryover</header><text>If the aggregate amount of contributions described in clause (i) exceeds the limitation of clause (i), such excess shall be treated (in a manner consistent with the rules of subsection (d)(2)) as a charitable contribution to which clause (i) applies in each of the 15 succeeding taxable years in order of time.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC4081D3919644E4C8309F1135F53347C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Native Corporation</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>Native Corporation</term> has the meaning given such term by section 3(m) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H546AE71772C542F7BA6A53969B6FB7B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subparagraph id="H5369B617ED11417B8B97674E7704C03C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 170(b)(2)(A) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>subparagraph (B) applies</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (B) or (C) applies</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FD6EFF59E2C414F8B1A61743D8FE2A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 170(b)(2)(B)(ii) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>15 succeeding years</quote> and inserting <quote>15 succeeding taxable years</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8366E6B77AB345EB93E73E351775B158"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Valid existing rights preserved</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection (or any amendment made by this subsection) shall be construed to modify the existing property rights validly conveyed to Native Corporations (within the meaning of section 3(m) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act) under such Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H031D1D23EFC2492E99AE05FD25288D3B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to contributions made in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2014.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H316425696B44476E8BE329FBD54789EA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Modification of the tax rate for the excise tax on investment income of private foundations</header>
 <subsection id="H5DD06A1CA0D04ABA87E329A0A3A31F66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4940">Section 4940(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>1 percent</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC2F7F1A61FE54A859221104B8F9B686E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elimination of reduced tax where foundation meets certain distribution requirements</header><text>Section 4940 of such Code is amended by striking subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2DEB1F92F50342F68D7548DC07843C82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H480CE748A0764E5ABB221ABB8E7E59B8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act shall not be entered on either PAYGO scorecard maintained pursuant to section 4(d) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20150212">Passed the House of Representatives February 12, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
	<endorsement><action-date>April 20, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


