<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2ED5D5181339448CA19A1C26E52F3236" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3750 IH: First Responders Passport Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3750</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20151009">October 9, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To waive the passport fees for first responders proceeding abroad to aid a foreign country suffering from a natural disaster.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8404242FE98640A7BD328DA450F00C89" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H95EDAF718E434BF0B6EBCAD8EE5D7C09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Responders Passport Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0D9BCDE953894C2EABB8ACF427DBE629"><enum>2.</enum><header>Persons excused from payment of fees for execution and issuance of passports</header> <subsection id="H290F5EB6C21B4A3895CBCE5FC152696A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 1 of the Passport Act of June 4, 1920 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/214">22 U.S.C. 214</external-xref>), is amended, in the third sentence, by inserting after <quote>to attend a funeral or memorial service for such member;</quote> the following: <quote>from an individual who has contracted with the United States Government, including a volunteer, who is proceeding abroad to aid a foreign country suffering from a qualifying natural disaster as authorized by the Secretary;</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB54706286AD947EBAE9F7FDEDD928E7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of the first full fiscal year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the number of waivers of fees for the execution and issuance of passports to first responders under section 1 of the Act of June 4, 1920, as amended by subsection (a) of this section, for such fiscal year.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

