<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7843D8B5E5274EDC8C810AAD3597D085" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2910 IH: Mexican Wolf Transparency and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2910</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To ensure the United States Fish and Wildlife Service’s Mexican wolf nonessential experimental
			 population 10(j) rule has no force or effect, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HAB2D9D078EB743A4A69EBC2EF4B6BD47" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF81522BB0671440A948D9F3DECB7A44F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mexican Wolf Transparency and Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFC60DE3303064A7C8E56E54F71BE1620" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>No force or effect<editorial></editorial></header> <subsection id="H18EFABEAB46F4B31B921C3E4BA6C048D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE3DF67DDBCC1429D95617DE31D975C69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Mexican wolf population has increased by 10 percent in recent years, including increases in population in each of the last 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H304EFFD618F94347A255B29DBBE28D0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the end of 2014, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service documented a presence of a minimum of 109 Mexican wolves on the landscape. The Service further stated on a conference call on January 17, 2015 that there are an additional 250 Mexican wolves in captivity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4F9F078C0F84541944DA95735350487"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Mexican wolf population not in captivity increased 31 percent in 2014.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BCD0773DA7647479FC60BCE1A5E3286"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Nearly 90 percent of the Mexican wolf’s original habitat was within the borders of Mexico.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H307DD21A2C814A2291A078B4D89ACE26"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Fish and Wildlife Service, under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), has been using the same recovery plan for the Mexican wolf since the early 1980s.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA2F1E3CDBA44A15B8852080B367B09E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>That plan is not based on the best available science and is significantly out of date.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB6A08310AE24531AC41DB4EFF0F8700"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Officials have been calling for years for an updated recovery plan that includes metrics that, if met, will allow for delisting of the Mexican wolf.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F0A353B46934E779ABE1573B3357A67"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The United States Fish and Wildlife Service has failed to issue and comply with an updated recovery plan despite acknowledging that the current plan is not in compliance with that Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A92307466D04D58BCDFF768E17F4DDE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>New rules issued for the Mexican wolf dramatically expand to parts of New Mexico and Arizona, the border of Mexico, and the border of Texas the area for an experimental program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF4B1BE033664634B673D587944FE6BF"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 10(j) nonessential experimental population program for the Mexican wolf failed to secure funding before being implemented.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C903D0BD90B43459DC298CF814C1BA3"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any future recovery plan for the Mexican wolf must incorporate the recovery work underway in Mexico.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9DB89C2F0C844A8BBD1ACFCA72A1F3B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No force or effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service of the endangered status for the Mexican wolf (Canis lupus baileyi) under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), published January 16, 2015 (80 Fed. Reg. 2488), and the listing of such species as an endangered species under that Act pursuant to such determination, shall have no force or effect.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8087C0C6AE0F4196A3095F21737D3573"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The final rule entitled <quote>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Revision to the Regulations for the Nonessential Experimental Population of the Mexican Wolf</quote>, published January 16, 2015 (80 Fed. Reg. 2512) shall also have no force or effect.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


