<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1B11C94A7B9A4AA9911BD74146DC0905" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 526 IH: Furthering Asbestos Claim Transparency (FACT) Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 526</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150126">January 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 11 of the United States Code to require the public disclosure by trusts established
			 under section 524(g) of such title, of quarterly reports that contain
			 detailed information regarding the receipt and disposition of claims for
			 injuries based on exposure to asbestos; and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFA87448D8747452A8E52C2B3B6B8D947" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE691E493D3A54E6FB426604013C865B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Furthering Asbestos Claim Transparency (FACT) Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H812C1F7BC4864CEA98D0B21DFD44714B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 524(g) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H588AD854DB8043BBB0A67C04C8AD4E51" style="traditional">
 <paragraph id="H11245C9EDF6944C6A36FBEE3FAB20FE5" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A trust described in paragraph (2) shall, subject to section 107—</text> <subparagraph id="HDBA3AD0C63F8434B9C948B643FDAF146"><enum>(A)</enum><text>file with the bankruptcy court, not later than 60 days after the end of every quarter, a report that shall be made available on the court’s public docket and with respect to such quarter—</text>
 <clause id="HF9510815302C40099B92A0B13F63DF61"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes each demand the trust received from, including the name and exposure history of, a claimant and the basis for any payment from the trust made to such claimant; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCF07F5E9FCAC4E0EA7F1C557CD48C29C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any confidential medical record or the claimant’s full social security number; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34F7025E78B64C88B3971E7EABD96BCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon written request, and subject to payment (demanded at the option of the trust) for any reasonable cost incurred by the trust to comply with such request, provide in a timely manner any information related to payment from, and demands for payment from, such trust, subject to appropriate protective orders, to any party to any action in law or equity if the subject of such action concerns liability for asbestos exposure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HFAE36660B53F44D397A87B79D74ACC11"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date; application of amendments</header>
 <subsection id="H6BDF005C6FE347E4951E063F9F4D871B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9290A08F9936471FA2ADEDBFF6F53372"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of amendments</header><text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to cases commenced under title 11 of the United States Code before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


