<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCA741A9ECF0E4C0C826AE39070D0FD92" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 341 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to require States to recognize the military experience of veterans when issuing licenses and credentials to veterans, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 341</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150114">January 14, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to require States to recognize the military experience of
			 veterans when issuing licenses and credentials to veterans, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H073134EBC1C54F689A609FF25876079C" style="OLC">
		<section id="HBD88A97BB6F149ACA3A1039DD53BDFC4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requirement that States recognize military experience of veterans when issuing licenses and
			 credentials to veterans</header>
 <subsection id="H91176A1654F246D7877E0C8BF4762645"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4102A(c) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraph (9) and inserting the following new paragraph (9):</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EC98EBC331C490F8FB65ABB29B09DA2" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HD282987674F2437E86654B90AE087F1A" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H93FAA7BB24D04E1FB353C3CB2BE57C98"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of a grant or contract under which funds are made available to a State under subsection (b)(5) in order to carry out section 4103A or 4104 of this title, the State shall—</text>
 <clause id="HA6AA2274F91B4A1097CB90E24A616C11" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a program under which the State administers an examination to each veteran seeking a license or credential issued by the State and issues such license or credential to such veteran without requiring such veteran to undergo any training or apprenticeship if the veteran—</text>
 <subclause id="H649721F13D754F61AA946FF767008852"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives a satisfactory score on completion of such examination, as determined by the State; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H277D357E555344E392B13676B3441C41"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has not less than 10 years of experience in a military occupational specialty that, as determined by the State, is similar to a civilian occupation for which such license or credential is required by the State; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3D450DF2E07C46198EC26ADA90B5D57F" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submits each year to the Secretary a report on the exams administered under clause (i) during the most recently completed 12-month period that includes, for the period covered by the report, the number of veterans who completed an exam administered by the State under clause (i) and a description of the results of such exams, disaggregated by occupational field.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB41FAC848174F97914EC73DBB82C700" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than once each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress and the Secretary of Defense a report summarizing the information received by the Secretary under subparagraph (A)(ii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6A43A684E3FE47C4A22C0ACB82E57410"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H95C9476667904792B6A87C1A9F12C9E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exams</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 4102A(c)(9) of such title, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to grants and contracts described in such subparagraph awarded after such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H380913A1A1B64BDDA984480F9FC271F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 4102A(c)(9), as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and the Secretary of Labor shall submit the first report under such subparagraph not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


