<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFAF6CD75C6114C9ABB250CB5533CBDC4" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 998 IH: Preclearance Authorization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 998</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150213">February 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001150">Mrs. Miller of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish the conditions under which the Secretary of Homeland Security may establish
			 preclearance facilities, conduct preclearance operations, and provide
			 customs services outside the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2B549A6969434DB8B818815D1CB39BE4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H387D01B837B44E2D970CCACD62BAAE0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preclearance Authorization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFC245ED6B1CD49DFBC2337B16EA9713C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text>
 </section><section id="H9783655C2A194A44AEB91B78D7A24262"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of preclearance operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Pursuant to section 1629 of title 19, United States Code, and subject to section 5, the Secretary of Homeland Security may establish U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations in a foreign country to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEEC87F84BB534D348E80125EBCB17C09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevent terrorists, instruments of terrorism, and other security threats from entering the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EDDB6DA208D4F6EA69BE1595DBE19DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent inadmissible persons from entering the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE087BA059CB440D834C4EBD7AF513B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure merchandise destined for the United States complies with applicable laws;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE944A23E173E4499B8D3EDFD8595AA3B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure the prompt processing of persons eligible to travel to the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB65B17E75AB4D3DB564047EE7B549E9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>accomplish such other objectives as the Secretary determines necessary to protect the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H0222C0386DB0482A8C9D3694B802FFB3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notification and certification to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="HFFA6B18EC94343CABED827FD0C7DEBBD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 180 days before entering into an agreement with the government of a foreign country to establish U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations in such foreign country, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H69A761A610B84B11B78A4B5CB804444A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A copy of the proposed agreement to establish such preclearance operations, including an identification of the foreign country with which U.S. Customs and Border Protection intends to enter into a preclearance agreement, and the location at which such preclearance operations will be conducted.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E92786E53A44FD6A7A2F070E123CA12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An estimate of the date on which U.S. Customs and Border Protection intends to establish preclearance operations under such agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04EFA12FB7064D0E9139B59A1B96C97F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The anticipated funding sources for preclearance operations under such agreement, and other funding sources considered.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BCFF90F1C9A419CA44E90BD6DEFC713"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the impact such preclearance operations will have on legitimate trade and travel, including potential impacts on passengers traveling to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C9E9A07E7DF43B88D8EE0991E4A4371"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A homeland security threat assessment for the country in which such preclearance operations are to be established.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC711050AC056408190338BD4695C6ECF"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the impacts such preclearance operations will have on U.S. Customs and Border Protection domestic port of entry staffing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9BD5F098F2F468995B9695633B7CBBF"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on potential economic, competitive, and job impacts on United States air carriers associated with establishing such preclearance operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8B1842BE6FE54C6998971EDFDEE72140"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Information on the anticipated homeland security benefits associated with establishing such preclearance operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7A852CC3F0D3413AA4C1BA84DB19E14F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Information on potential security vulnerabilities associated with commencing such preclearance operations, and mitigation plans to address such potential security vulnerabilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F4A4F7182D141AB9ADE27D7858EF4B7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A U.S. Customs and Border Protection staffing model for such preclearance operations, and plans for how such positions would be filled.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8F29205B10D64D58ADE4B43B3A49694F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Information on the anticipated costs over the next five fiscal years associated with commencing such preclearance operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H07DC590CFACF47288A3C1A526D556AAC"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A copy of the agreement referred to in subsection (a) of section 5.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DFF1DAD971B42D4955F73F74087FDE5"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Other factors that the Secretary of Homeland Security determines to be necessary for Congress to comprehensively assess the appropriateness of commencing such preclearance operations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D56D5E618064C5AA8C92A6B1F5C99D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certifications relating to preclearance operations established at airports</header><text>In the case of an airport, in addition to the notification requirements under subsection (a), not later than 90 days before entering into an agreement with the government of a foreign country to establish U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations at an airport in such foreign country, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H30C67D4DF0574378B7EB430C2E4922C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A certification that preclearance operations under such preclearance agreement would provide homeland security benefits to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75EFC8AD66C04947BD85B1009AA36F90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A certification that preclearance operations within such foreign country will be established under such agreement only if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9C08B029AF094347B91FCE69497A8E98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least one United States passenger carrier operates at such airport; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66971B3522A74AD5ADB4292006CFEC9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the access of all United States passenger carriers to such preclearance operations is the same as the access of any non-United States passenger carrier.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63A725BD833D43559D3FCF152AAF7BD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A certification that the Secretary of Homeland Security has considered alternative options to preclearance operations and has determined that such options are not the most effective means of achieving the objectives specified in section 3.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H302191A6FC4A449F946429FA402A1895"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A certification that the establishment of preclearance operations in such foreign country will not significantly increase customs processing times at United States airports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9313A2BF16994784B7FEF920919AFD2F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An explanation of other objectives that will be served by the establishment of preclearance operations in such foreign country.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H932D623700274B8FA625633FEE270970"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A certification that representatives from U.S. Customs and Border Protection consulted publically with interested parties, including providers of commercial air service in the United States, employees of such providers, security experts, and such other parties as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, before entering into such an agreement with such foreign government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05BC0CA215D44BB69769B9889B560F84"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A report detailing the basis for the certifications referred to in paragraphs (1) through (6).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EFF1C060D24425DB5E5AA1D8BC25D53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification of existing agreements</header><text>Not later than 30 days before substantially modifying a preclearance agreement with the government of a foreign country in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a copy of the proposed agreement, as modified, and the justification for such modification.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H321AF8A5D0A64BF7984D7826682DCA09"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Remediation plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H99A7D749D5714A4E9A1887AC24164E6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall monthly measure the average customs processing time to enter the 25 United States airports that support the highest volume of international travel (as determined by available Federal passenger data) and provide to the appropriate congressional committees such measurements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D2ECAE158B64DD086D2E2DAC4C4ACB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Based on the measurements described in paragraph (1), the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall quarterly assess whether the average customs processing time referred to in such paragraph significantly exceeds the average customs processing time to enter the United States through a preclearance operation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD303A510947E44069FE3B2DC25E7404C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Based on the assessment conducted under paragraph (2), if the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection determines that the average customs processing time referred to in paragraph (1) significantly exceeds the average customs processing time to enter the United States through a preclearance operation described in paragraph (2), the Commissioner shall, not later than 60 days after making such determination, provide to the appropriate congressional committees a remediation plan for reducing such average customs processing time referred to in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD33624FF87A5425F9B5D784294B1D74D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 30 days after submitting the remediation plan referred to in paragraph (3), the Commissioner of United States Customs and Border Protection shall implement those portions of such plan that can be carried out using existing resources, excluding the transfer of personnel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H476C28E799C54730BBAD7BEB0020B1A6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Suspension</header><text>If the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection does not submit the remediation plan referred to in paragraph (3) within 60 days in accordance with such paragraph, the Commissioner may not, until such time as such remediation plan is submitted, conduct any negotiations relating to preclearance operations at an airport in any country or commence any such preclearance operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E026CD92D4E45168892635004005929"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Stakeholder recommendations</header><text>The remediation plan described in paragraph (3) shall consider recommendations solicited from relevant stakeholders.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBF6098D3766E4DBEB9FB13E1B52AB70B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Classified report</header><text>The assessment required pursuant to subsection (a)(5) and the report required pursuant to subsection (b)(7) may be submitted in classified form if the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that such is appropriate.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H06D93020B1DD4F7E8B9509337A5418A3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Aviation security screening at preclearance airports</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H08BF3DDC8A2C4B23988B0EA9B35BFDAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Aviation security standards agreement</header><text>Prior to the commencement of preclearance operations at an airport in a foreign country under this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall enter into an agreement with the government of such foreign country that delineates and requires the adoption of aviation security screening standards that are determined by the Administrator to be comparable to those of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAE5A9B976E0C4819AC106BBB725DFD5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aviation security rescreening</header><text>If the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration determines that the government of a foreign country has not maintained security standards and protocols comparable to those of the United States at airports at which preclearance operations have been established in accordance with an agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (a), the Administrator shall require the rescreening in the United States by the Transportation Security Administration of passengers and their property before such passengers may deplane into sterile areas of airports in the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1C83DE2E86E7446BAA7645D7463D05DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selectees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any passenger who is determined to be a selectee based on a check against a terrorist watch list and arrives on a flight originating from a foreign airport at which preclearance operations have been established in accordance with an agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (a), shall be required to undergo security rescreening by the Transportation Security Administration before being permitted to board a domestic flight in the United States.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H184B5EEF809F4E28A4D1B9CBE4492D0A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Lost and stolen passports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may not enter into or renew an agreement with the government of a foreign country to establish or maintain U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations at an airport in such foreign country unless such government certifies—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0B03DD95BE8E4D7195A24556BF6108AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that it routinely submits information about lost and stolen passports of its citizens and nationals to INTERPOL’s Stolen and Lost Travel Document database; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7DA1CC3259149CDA26A1A5E70EC2493"><enum>(2)</enum><text>makes available to the United States Government such information through another comparable means of reporting.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HDA18CF5DC610451E99AFD0BB02CFF621"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except for subsection (c) of section 4, this Act shall apply only to the establishment of preclearance operations in a foreign country in which no preclearance operations have been established as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


