<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H212E3668FA8349F7B2C5037AA2C89A15" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1351 IH: Homeowners’ Defense Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1351</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150310">March 10, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a State-sponsored national catastrophic risk consortium to ensure the availability and affordability of homeowners’ insurance coverage for catastrophic events.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HFB67B0568B344CCB9DD8C6132F523D88" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC60E6012E95C41D28DF60759F9B19D2D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HFDA095970C1847879BE447D78BF0F74C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeowners’ Defense Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H464C05E58488491392C9AED90D9CAEC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="HC60E6012E95C41D28DF60759F9B19D2D" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8E913E6C1BC34EA0A8B2ABB183D233E9" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings and purpose.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H15D4C9AB79174D2997ABEA11E0CA5A8A" level="section">Sec. 3. Establishment; status; principal office; membership.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFF080A0A7D764B6C8EA9F51FABA35289" level="section">Sec. 4. Functions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA34929A6233845F3A6833061797B3DDC" level="section">Sec. 5. Powers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAA346F3FF3BA46E3AC8B40C10C54A6D5" level="section">Sec. 6. Nonprofit entity; conflicts of interest; audits.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA0BCEE917FB2492AB9E18A1B5AD993FE" level="section">Sec. 7. Management.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4449A934ADD945B8A2C73F300357CCCA" level="section">Sec. 8. Staff; experts and consultants.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4577C50CC17549AE84C0D3BB5560BE4D" level="section">Sec. 9. Federal liability.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB34D92A3A22C4DFEA7DF7B6CFA197355" level="section">Sec. 10. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E913E6C1BC34EA0A8B2ABB183D233E9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> 
<subsection id="H69A3AB7EFC95494AB09A7207486D4CA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H451D616FF77643E98DD6B38198F4BC5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States has a history of catastrophic natural disasters, including hurricanes, tornadoes, flood, fire, earthquakes, and volcanic eruptions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06F3E11590BC448280CDD146B89537FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">although catastrophic natural disasters occur infrequently, their costs are likely to escalate in the coming years, in part because of weather-related exposure, coastal development patterns, and increasing property values along the hurricane-prone or earthquake-vulnerable coastlines of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34F868AA73B442FC8174254DCF2701EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such disasters generate large economic losses and a major component of those losses comes from damage and destruction to homes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA05552031AFE4951AF5643A989BBDA5B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for the majority of Americans, their investment in their home represents their single biggest asset and the protection of that investment is paramount to economic and social stability;</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6F405CE53904D9CBE7EFA5894DEF7B7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States needs to take and support State actions to be better prepared for and better protected from catastrophes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D4F7659D40341ACAC83611340D34F39"><enum>(6)</enum><text>as the risk of catastrophic losses grows, so do the risks that any premiums collected by private insurers for extending coverage will be insufficient to cover future catastrophes, and private insurers, in an effort to protect their shareholders and policyholders (in the case of mutually owned companies), have thus significantly raised premiums and curtailed insurance coverage in States exposed to major catastrophes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1669FBEB78EA4F8E815D4600118DD6F3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>such effects on the insurance industry have been harmful to economic activity in States exposed to major catastrophes and have placed significant burdens on residents of such States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21B25E50A60C4DDA8AD2C428295CA18E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, and Wilma struck the United States in 2005, causing over $200,000,000,000 in total economic losses, and insured losses to homeowners in excess of $50,000,000,000;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4817EF15DC234534ABEAF378EA867CB4"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hurricane Sandy struck in 2012 along the Northeastern region of the United States, causing over $40,000,000,000 in property damages over a wide area;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H946AA0777F88434D892301D3018F776E"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the current disaster risk management system, the Federal Government and, hence, taxpayers pay for rebuilding through government grants and low-interest loans, and the Federal Government will likely continue to provide significant levels of financial resources to pay for recovery from future catastrophes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9049C68118984DD999DB7C3C982D0EFF"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alternative catastrophe risk-management approach, one that has continued to grow and is now perceived in the marketplace as a viable method of financing mega-catastrophes, would have the Federal Government support State-based efforts aimed at combining disaster risks into diversified portfolios, and developing a common documentation, legal, and operational framework for issuing catastrophe bonds that are transferred to the private sector; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60DB7C5F28694C92844A94918338B583"><enum>(12)</enum><text>a number of entities in the public sector have already sought protection through catastrophe bonds, and other alternative risk transfer instruments, which package catastrophe risk as securities that are actively bought and sold in the capital markets.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H78FAD2086FFB48E39B03F0890831BD92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to establish a State-sponsored national catastrophic risk consortium to ensure the availability and affordability of homeowners’ insurance coverage for catastrophic events.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15D4C9AB79174D2997ABEA11E0CA5A8A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment; status; principal office; membership</header> 
<subsection id="H35A770F8BA7C498CABF5B7EB593DCD47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established an entity to be known as the <term>National Catastrophe Risk Consortium</term> (in this Act referred to as the <term>Consortium</term>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4627CD5B7BF54EF58EAE2E434825456F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Status</header><text>The Consortium is not a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7CD952E952C4CF988467C6B590486C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Principal office</header><text>The principal office and place of business of the Consortium shall be such location within the United States determined by the Board of Directors to be the most advantageous for carrying out the purpose and functions of the Consortium.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF2486858CDC64A899C92D1886292E972"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any State that has established a reinsurance fund or has authorized the operation of a State residual insurance market entity, or State-sponsored provider of natural catastrophe insurance, shall be eligible to participate in the Consortium.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF080A0A7D764B6C8EA9F51FABA35289" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Functions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Consortium shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4B36F015CD054892814F53C1EA46EAB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with all States, particularly those participating in the Consortium, to gather and maintain an inventory of catastrophe risk obligations held by State reinsurance funds, State residual insurance market entities, and State-sponsored providers of natural catastrophe insurance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01CC6B6BB0554C05A7DFE3ABDECD16A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at the discretion of the affected members and on a conduit basis, issue securities and other financial instruments linked to the catastrophe risks insured or reinsured through members of the Consortium in the capital markets;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA23722B9035E4EF7B13CBD82C9962FB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinate reinsurance contracts between participating, qualified reinsurance funds and private parties;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EFCD0BBB37C42C1BA3161253E12D0EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>act as a centralized repository of State risk information that can be accessed by private-market participants seeking to participate in the transactions described in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9987EB397B14492AA7435F564B6AAF73"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish a catastrophe risk database to perform research and analysis that encourages standardization of the risk-linked securities market;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AC2A9D34CF349839A9B84B55CA364C3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>perform any other functions, other than assuming risk or incurring debt, that are deemed necessary to aid in the transfer of catastrophe risk from participating States to private parties; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6BD570F5369475CAC0040656F409902"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit annual reports to Congress describing the activities of the Consortium for the preceding year, and the first such annual report shall include an assessment of the costs to States and regions associated with catastrophe risk and an analysis of the costs and benefits, for States not participating in the Consortium, of such nonparticipation.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA34929A6233845F3A6833061797B3DDC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Powers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Consortium—</text> <paragraph id="H1A536E46C6754B699B513ABBBBF8F948"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may make and perform such contracts and other agreements with any individual or other private or public entity however designated and wherever situated, as may be necessary for carrying out the functions of the Consortium; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H879ADD94AC574E7BA39BFA0764C00637"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall have such other powers, other than the power to assume risk or incur debt, as may be necessary and incident to carrying out this Act.</text></paragraph></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA346F3FF3BA46E3AC8B40C10C54A6D5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Nonprofit entity; conflicts of interest; audits</header> <subsection id="H67B8267B832343E2A42AEF9C86E55662"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nonprofit entity</header><text>The Consortium shall be a nonprofit entity and no part of the net earnings of the Consortium shall inure to the benefit of any member, founder, contributor, or individual.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F84D5A92DD84D6C93CD04CBB51AA7B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><text>No director, officer, or employee of the Consortium shall in any manner, directly or indirectly, participate in the deliberation upon or the determination of any question affecting his or her personal interests or the interests of any Consortium, partnership, or organization in which he or she is directly or indirectly interested.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H00A0AADC00BD4B84AF78DAFAA3091DC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header> <paragraph id="HFE82D77E0E99418095B7819756F732B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual audit</header><text>The financial statements of the Consortium shall be audited annually in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified public accountants.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE8C86F8069F4FE4B9EC58CF22911D07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The report of each annual audit pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be included in the annual report submitted in accordance with section 4(7).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H112C164F897441BE9C090721303285C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on election and lobbying activities</header> <paragraph id="HA7B2851A5C0F4269994B21C1C3913335"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Consortium may not—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9F1C0312FDF349EFA2E36B682B4A9535"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make any contribution to a candidate for election for Federal office or to a political committee;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAD3E74FA0674EE2AACD1308A06BF288"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employ or retain—</text> 
<clause id="H9F5855B6A95045C5A50B88052BBEBDF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a registered lobbyist under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1601">2 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause> <clause id="H4ED1765C6BFF43E299322C49D49C1029"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an organization that employs one or more lobbyists and is registered under section 4(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(a)(2)</external-xref>); or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H21BDCEE8283847D9B151624E24D31DE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide any thing of value, other than educational materials or information, to any elected official of the Federal Government.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of this paragraph, the terms <term>contribution</term>, <term>candidate</term>, <term>Federal office</term>, and <term>political committee</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 301 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/431">2 U.S.C. 431</external-xref>).</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E2E93F2CA3349FC9B3D7030B9006616"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consortium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Consortium may not—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HADF76B3185054FA78FB68BFC85F64C41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make any contribution to a candidate for election for any State or local office or to any committee, club, association, or other group that receives contributions or makes expenditures for the purpose of influencing any such election;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8EDE72F50879445684A59DE4F688C1CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employ or retain any person who engages in influencing legislating (as such term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4911">section 4911(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4911">26 U.S.C. 4911(d)</external-xref>)) of any State or local legislative body; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1E0FF7F04B647B28FDBF93E67DA93F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide any thing of value, other than educational materials or information, to any elected official of any State or local government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0BCEE917FB2492AB9E18A1B5AD993FE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Management</header> <subsection id="HA565F43370A345D8A1FBC8458D2FCC92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of directors; membership; designation of chairperson</header> <paragraph id="H460BCDE556A84C1AB0F20516FA5B4818"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board of directors</header><text>The management of the Consortium shall be vested in a board of directors (referred to in this Act as the <term>Board</term>) composed of not less than 3 members.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA61F8177C22C4052BD7E5DA571C6F175"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, or the designee of the Secretary, shall serve as the chairperson of the Board.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A1A99B2182547C18A21C8A0A3A22D03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The members of the Board shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6D553FFC592F442B86479188240EB634"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Commerce, or the designees of such Secretaries, respectively, but only during such times as there are fewer than two States participating in the Consortium; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDCB5949C6CA479B9F6F42C2E2AE4038"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a member from each State participating in the Consortium, who shall be appointed by such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5239DFC25BFB4E12895E27493F1EC352"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bylaws</header><text>The Board may prescribe, amend, and repeal such bylaws as may be necessary for carrying out the functions of the Consortium.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H018C0F6435AA43E7ABBCB2BAF69A684F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compensation, actual, necessary, and transportation expenses</header> <paragraph id="H4A8111787AB14BCFA5EDD60599B7088E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-Federal employees</header><text>A member of the Board who is not otherwise employed by the Federal Government shall be entitled to receive the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, as in effect from time to time, for each day (including travel time) during which such member is engaged in the actual performance of duties of the Consortium.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5B3BA5F457E4E88969E30EC5C4FBBF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text>A member of the Board who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall serve without additional pay (or benefits in the nature of compensation) for service as a member of the Consortium.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92ABA7AD5451483C932A7C843AE60555"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Members of the Consortium shall be entitled to receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, equivalent to those set forth in subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC99530F03C943E99B0576D676ECD537"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the Board shall constitute a quorum.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB2BE05FA06D549789E070140F666F3E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Executive director</header><text>The Board shall appoint an executive director of the Consortium on such terms as the Board may determine.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4449A934ADD945B8A2C73F300357CCCA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Staff; experts and consultants</header> 
<subsection id="HE8CD00A5A76E44D0A6D3ED7F799C201E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Staff</header> 
<paragraph id="HA4C1C0DCA37C45C99A91619BC6D7C00D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Board of the Consortium may appoint and terminate such other staff as are necessary to enable the Consortium to perform its duties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC98476A99374E61BEB8C0348CDB4105"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Board of the Consortium may fix the compensation of the executive director and other staff.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H66A6C5A5912C4C698BA45482BEC504B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Experts and consultants</header><text>The Board shall procure the services of experts and consultants as the Board considers appropriate.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4577C50CC17549AE84C0D3BB5560BE4D"><enum>9.</enum><header>Federal liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Government and the Consortium shall not bear any liabilities arising from the actions of the Consortium. Participating States shall retain all catastrophe risk until the completion of a transaction described in paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 4.</text></section> 
<section id="HB34D92A3A22C4DFEA7DF7B6CFA197355"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

