<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H791BE843FC1D4289A0546288AF9240A7" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3828 IH: The Land-Grant Opportunity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3828</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151026">October 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to provide
			 for an equitable distribution of formula funds between land-grant colleges
			 and universities, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HEE88D45567C746139D4F8857FB69968E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7109C00AA4D64D429A99065145DBF73E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The Land-Grant Opportunity Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H430EE0CF2FB84C50BF18CF922FD27EC9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Equitable distribution of formula funds to land-grant colleges and universities</header> <subsection id="HEBF91FDA1E1647F7B33EF1B6E078C5CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle G of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3221">7 U.S.C. 3221 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA668FCE628C4EBBADAF2D36432AB5F4" style="OLC">
					<section id="H472260B273844F44A22D0FFF08AE7609"><enum>1449A.</enum><header>Formula for distribution of extension funds to land-grant colleges and universities</header>
 <subsection id="H79470D5DFD7F489FBE3F1B198A2277E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD59F77DB66B44330943A226647A24E1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>1862-institution; 1890-institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>1862-institution</term> and <term>1890-institution</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7601">7 U.S.C. 7601</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H064D842D59B44D2DB17CF976846BF635"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution formula State</header><text>The term <term>distribution formula State</term> means a State—</text> <subparagraph id="H5A42105282C34D4197917B5C4CB28970"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which at least one 1862-institution and at least one 1890-institution are located;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H254D13EBD6B04134884ED387AF520E95"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that provides matching funds in an amount equal to more than 50 percent of the extension funds to be distributed to such land-grant colleges and universities; and</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H303C8F1728AA42AA8C25513BB71E499D"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0B8DB624AB0F47A6AF1C65E52D305CC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to any 1890-institution in such State, that does not provide matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of Federal funds available to be distributed to such institution under section 1444; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H27C3EC6C3B0B49309CF445EF32B1FA82" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any 1862-institution in such State, that does not provide matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of Federal funds available to be distributed to such institution under the Act of May 8, 1914 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/341">7 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Smith-Lever Act).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95E2A7DE249B4AD89DBADB423C18DAD2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>extension funds</term> means funds distributed—</text> <subparagraph id="HDAFAC223AA87498F89799FAC87CF3DC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an 1890-institution, under section 1444; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E0B1519E20F4AD5AEBC336C1B1B0EFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an 1862-institution, under the Act of May 8, 1914 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/341">7 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Smith-Lever Act).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F5A4BB2925446588270A4A414A37191"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fully matched ratio</header><text>The term <term>fully matched ratio</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D1DA85AB44342ECA6350D7BE72A8AD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an 1862-institution, if the State provided matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of Federal funds available to be distributed to the institution under the Act of May 8, 1914 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/341">7 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Smith-Lever Act), for a fiscal year, the ratio that the sum of the amount of funds that would be distributed to such institution under such Act for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State would provide to such institution for such fiscal year would bear to, with respect to each other land-grant college or university in the State, the sum of the amount of funds that would be distributed to such land-grant college or university in the State under such Act or under section 1444, as the case may be, for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State would provide to such college or university for such fiscal year; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02D46474A61F4CA091621B1D02671E33"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an 1890-institution, if the State provided matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of Federal funds available to be distributed to the institution under section 1444 for a fiscal year, the ratio that the sum of the amount of funds that would be distributed to such institution under such Act for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State would provide to such institution for such fiscal year would bear to, with respect to each other land-grant college or university in the State, the sum of the amount of funds that would be distributed to such land-grant college or university in the State under section 1444 or under the Act of May 8, 1914 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/341">7 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Smith-Lever Act), as the case may be, for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State would provide to such college or university for such fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7DE3F87AE4649478107512958B97167"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Shortfall percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>shortfall percentage</term> means, with respect to a shortfall State, the percentage that equals 100 percentage points minus the number of percentage points by which a shortfall State is deficient in providing matching funds below 50 percentage points, as described in paragraph (6)(B).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD5965093D10249C2B6D0F8A6C26A1D80"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Shortfall State</header><text>The term <term>shortfall State</term> means a State—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H488F6D1730624033A6B7673FE22BF25C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which at least one 1862-institution and at least one 1890-institution are located; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAA70EFAE57424481A61F24E49D16CBF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that provides matching funds in an amount equal to 50 percent or less of the extension funds to be distributed to such land-grant colleges and universities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3DFA4EF93F84079B4E570B341C5A64D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of Non-Federal Sources of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than September 30, 2016, and each September 30 thereafter, each land-grant college or university in a distribution formula State shall submit to the Secretary a report describing for the preceding fiscal year—</text>
 <paragraph id="H80F1FBFBC75F4AACBC74C3970DEA478F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sources of non-Federal funds made available by the State to the land-grant college or university for agricultural extension and education to meet the requirement of section 1449; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0053EF15A33433389B674F013DE0F06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of such funds generally available from each source.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A71C33FDD874D9DB421D47D8685390A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution formula</header> <paragraph id="HA21E108D612D4A83B11F5863C52E2017"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with fiscal year 2016, in the case of a distribution formula State, the amount of extension funds to be distributed to land-grant colleges and universities in such State shall be distributed for a fiscal year in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HA424BAD0E71A4919B6CB4E9BD7BFB678"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formula</header>
 <subparagraph id="H14FF8C971ABA414FA4861C76BB0E2A2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the extension funds available to be distributed to a land-grant college or university in a distribution formula State for a fiscal year, such funds shall be distributed such that the ratio described in subparagraph (B) for land-grant colleges and universities in the State is made to equal the fully matched ratio for land-grant colleges and universities in the State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC286B5D08AB94320A5A14E1EB44C04A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjusted distribution ratio</header><text>The ratio described in this subparagraph is—</text> <clause id="H8A1BF78EA63E42598700F4231A688F82"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ratio that, in the case of an 1862-institution in a State, the sum of the amount of funds to be distributed to such institution under the Act of May 8, 1914 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/341">7 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Smith-Lever Act), for a fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State provides to such institution for such fiscal year bears to, with respect to each other land-grant college or university in the State, the sum of the amount of funds to be distributed to such land-grant college or university in the State under such Act or under section 1444, as the case may be, for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State provides to such college or university for such fiscal year; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD16A69266AD64448A9B3F1099399A23A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ratio that, in the case of an 1890-institution in a State, the sum of the amount of funds to be distributed to such institution under section 1444 for a fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State provides to such institution for such fiscal year bears to, with respect to each other land-grant college or university in the State, the sum of the amount of funds to be distributed to such other land-grant college or university in the State under section 1444 or under the Act of May 8, 1914 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/341">7 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Smith-Lever Act), as the case may be, for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State provides to such college or university for such fiscal year.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA891BF370104B4C8E859A570CBA0F9A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of shortfall States</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF1011C53774A4829B86133C34F70E25F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the formula described in paragraph (2)(A) shall apply with respect to the distribution of extension funds to land-grant colleges and universities in a shortfall State in the same manner as such formula applies to the distribution of extension funds to land-grant colleges and universities in a distribution formula State for a fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF567FFDE87EA4AD7BA6805F5741BC8A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount of Federal funds available for distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a shortfall State, the total amount of extension funds available to be distributed to the land-grant colleges and universities in such State shall equal the product of—</text>
 <clause id="H12B8593240CC45D0B44F82CF0DC7CEF6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total amount which such colleges and universities are eligible to receive under the Act of May 8, 1914 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/341">7 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Smith-Lever Act), and section 1444 for a fiscal year; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H06726A6077854CF7A054B72718FBF22F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the shortfall percentage for such State and such fiscal year.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3BC9C3CBF88B4F868E4CBF661952890B"><enum>1449B.</enum><header>Formula for distribution of research funds to land-grant colleges and universities</header> <subsection id="H4EC38E38A0F5465FB6A141A6EB4B43DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H251D519759684B0B955D78CB21E8B451"><enum>(1)</enum><header>1862-institution; 1890-institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>1862-institution</term> and <term>1890-institution</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7601">7 U.S.C. 7601</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D146633316B485C8C1F4945DBCDCB92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution formula State</header><text>The term <term>distribution formula State</term> means a State—</text> <subparagraph id="HFA7EB90727B44FD8A86FCC265BB4ACAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which at least one 1862-institution and at least one 1890-institution are located;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3695897E2B3A475B995AB113EBFC3576"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that provides matching funds in an amount equal to more than 50 percent of the research funds to be distributed to such land-grant colleges and universities; and</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D200771D8B846E5A211CD232EE95194"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H678BAE99C6B74238A4AB099CC105FB3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to any 1890-institution in such State, that does not provide matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of Federal funds available to be distributed to such institution under section 1445; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7758A8B9A1AA4F438409BD81BCC40139" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any 1862-institution in such State, that does not provide matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of Federal funds available to be distributed to such institution under the Act of March 2, 1887 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/361a">7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Hatch Act of 1887).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08C6BA7F7FF849CEA58BC712BCA32B2A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fully matched ratio</header><text>The term <term>fully matched ratio</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HD881293219F3456FA814A9435C579E9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an 1862-institution, if the State provided matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of Federal funds available to be distributed to the institution under the Act of March 2, 1887 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/361a">7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Hatch Act of 1887), for a fiscal year, the ratio that the sum of the amount of funds that would be distributed to such institution under such Act for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State would provide to such institution for such fiscal year would bear to, with respect to each other land-grant college or university in the State, the sum of the amount of funds that would be distributed to such other land-grant college or university in the State under such Act or under section 1445, as the case may be, for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State would provide to such college or university for such fiscal year; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H211B030AEFD94F3CA14F198DA1A9CAA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an 1890-institution, if the State provided matching funds in an amount equal to the amount of Federal funds available to be distributed to the institution under section 1445 for a fiscal year, the ratio that the sum of the amount of funds that would be distributed to such institution under such Act for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State would provide to such institution for such fiscal year would bear to, with respect to each other land-grant college or university in the State, the sum of the amount of funds that would be distributed to such land-grant college or university in the State under section 1445 or under the Act of March 2, 1887 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/361a">7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Hatch Act of 1887), as the case may be, for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State would provide to such college or university for such fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF0A05AFC58433C8EF1ADE2FD269833"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Research funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>research funds</term> means funds distributed—</text> <subparagraph id="H7E096AD6020E4079B648A442BD6C0939"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an 1890-institution, under section 1445; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF800FA189C0B4C2D9322D50E422BC136"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an 1862-institution, under the Act of March 2, 1887 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/361a">7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Hatch Act of 1887).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7522234532504159AA16DFBB7C23E36D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Shortfall percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>shortfall percentage</term> means, with respect to a shortfall State, the percentage that equals 100 percentage points minus the number of percentage points by which a shortfall State is deficient in providing matching funds below 50 percentage points, as described in paragraph (6)(B).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF6577E1AF68E415FB1EA955C294906C0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Shortfall State</header><text>In this section, the term <term>shortfall State</term> means a State—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEF0157F9A63D4501BAB17F2ABC386474"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which at least one 1862-institution and at least one 1890-institution are located; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5286B8CB7BEB45E9B052D8CA92BA58C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that provides matching funds in an amount equal to 50 percent or less of the research funds to be distributed to such land-grant colleges and universities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD80FE772B074F31AE803FE5A42F2DED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of Non-Federal Sources of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than September 30, 2016, and each September 30 thereafter, each land-grant college or university in a distribution formula State shall submit to the Secretary a report describing for the preceding fiscal year—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA9DE1BD4F48A47259337BC6C3DAF4CE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sources of non-Federal funds made available by the State to the land-grant college or university for agricultural research to meet the requirement of section 1449; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFCBBF39A1134A97A016F211EAA86F2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of such funds generally available from each source.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63974A837861495E8FB3C4213B079A22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution formula</header> <paragraph id="HA62B2E1F2F9D460CBDD54B14CE417DCA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with fiscal year 2016, in the case of a distribution formula State, the amount of research funds to be distributed to land-grant colleges and universities in such State shall be distributed in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HA6B3F05DA8DE4B84996724F4EA68F4A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formula</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF61C021F18694E32A8B6024010F0EBC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the research funds available to be distributed to a land-grant college or university in a distribution formula State for a fiscal year, such funds shall be distributed such that the ratio described in subparagraph (B) for land-grant colleges and universities in the State is made to equal the fully matched ratio for land-grant colleges and universities in the State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95F7E5C48A0B404DB158F4D292218E8E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjusted distribution ratio</header><text>The ratio described in this subparagraph is—</text> <clause id="HBB752AC781E2489F8459C75960D4A638"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ratio that, in the case of an 1862-institution in a State, the sum of the amount of funds to be distributed to such institution under the Act of March 2, 1887 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/361a">7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Hatch Act of 1887), for a fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State provides to such institution for such fiscal year bears to, with respect to each other land-grant college or university in the State, the sum of the amount of funds to be distributed to such other land-grant college or university in the State under such Act or under section 1445, as the case may be, for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State provides to such college or university for such fiscal year; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF215542BABD042D2BF005F65EB1E08DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ratio that, in the case of an 1890-institution in a State, the sum of the amount of funds to be distributed to such institution under section 1445 for a fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State provides to such institution for such fiscal year bears to, with respect to each other land-grant college or university in the State, the sum of the amount of funds to be distributed to such land-grant college or university in the State under section 1445 or under the Act of March 2, 1887 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/361a">7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Hatch Act of 1887), as the case may be, for such fiscal year and the amount of matching funds the State provides to such college or university for such fiscal year.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11E93FAFD4A54415AA604ECC1EE4614B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of shortfall States</header>
 <subparagraph id="H442C0DFE1FF940CB9C6CE796DB165FB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the formula described in paragraph (2)(A) shall apply with respect to the distribution of extension funds to land-grant colleges and universities in a shortfall State in the same manner as such formula applies to the distribution of extension funds to land-grant colleges and universities in a distribution formula State for a fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6CEB0132B3B4903AFA01F69BF383716"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount of Federal funds available for distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a shortfall State, the total amount of extension funds available to be distributed to the land-grant colleges and universities in such State shall equal the product of—</text>
 <clause id="H79068E44507B4C85B7D824F00DA38D04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total amount which such colleges and universities are eligible to receive under the Act of March 2, 1887 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/361a">7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Hatch Act of 1887), and section 1445 for a fiscal year; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDDC92E038CE141799B7173F293902E8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the shortfall percentage for such State and such fiscal year.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H4348C6DDABA94A73944773551F03E9E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 1449 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3222d">7 U.S.C. 3222d</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9D390689311B42D1BF43F2D8B8AC0469"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>subtitle, the State shall provide</quote> and inserting <quote>subtitle, the State shall provide to eligible institutions, with respect to the maximum amount such institutions are eligible to receive under sections 1444 and 1445,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFCF223F82754A749F08A9D24D9274C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0ECA143E7FD94E149ECF797BA73A1BC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) and (f) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


