<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAC91ED8F960C47C49F0F70A42D11CB6E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1479 IH: Repeal of the Obamacare Bay State Boondoogle Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1479</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150319">March 19, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000755">Mr. Brady of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to apply budget neutrality on a State-specific basis in the calculation of the Medicare hospital wage index floor for non-rural areas.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H114C1D320AB449868570D82E4CC508F5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6F08A7474CE14C6F8900AE388539D6F6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Repeal of the Obamacare Bay State Boondoogle Act</short-title></quote>. </text> </section> <section id="H4BC52D13665C403A9AD1C8C79838313D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Applying budget neutrality on a State-specific basis in the calculation of the Medicare hospital wage index floor for non-rural areas</header> <subsection id="H473E43FD9C604F79863FEF13C12C59BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1886(d)(3)(E) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(3)(E)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD44A5174EEB3498180714D891D584410" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H913E3665AB4B4021B781C7FF85F805E0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Application of budget neutrality relating to floor on wage area index in non-rural areas</header> 
<subclause id="HA49B5E8158A141FAA5A6CBBECCB8FB42"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Application on a State-specific basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of discharges occurring on or after April 1, 2015, for purposes of applying section 4410(b) of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, the Secretary shall administer such section 4410(b) and paragraph (e) of section 412.64 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, as if paragraph (e)(4)(ii) of such section 412.64, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this clause, had never applied and by using the methodology promulgated in the Federal Register on August 19, 2008 (73 Fed. Reg. 48570) (applied as if such methodology had been fully implemented for fiscal year 2011 using a 100 percent State-specific adjustment to the area wage index).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H384276833E32485EBE2DCB373402BE45"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in subclause (I) shall be construed as preventing the Secretary, for discharges occurring on or after April 1, 2015, from modifying the regulations under such section 412.64 to be consistent with subclause (I) in carrying out the budget neutrality requirements of such section 4410(b).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H2B07047794EF48D0B924DFC5EA370FED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment terminating application of budget neutrality on a nationwide basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3141 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting <quote>and before April 1, 2015,</quote> after <quote>2010,</quote>.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

