<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAF1C6BA452954DD88FFC84DB501CE7D0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3199 IH: To prohibit statutory sanctions relief by the United States with respect to Iran unless the Senate provides its advice and consent to ratification of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3199</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit statutory sanctions relief by the United States with respect to Iran unless the Senate
			 provides its advice and consent to ratification of the Joint Comprehensive
			 Plan of Action.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3CA04EFAEF5B418D84CB7960D9A82B93" style="OLC">
		<section id="H8E8ACD9650D04EB3AE4C8C7ABAC046B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on statutory sanctions relief by the United States with respect to Iran unless the
			 Senate provides its advice and consent to ratification of the Joint
			 Comprehensive Plan of Action</header>
 <subsection id="H909B933B259340A49E836C0DCE1B240D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 135 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2160e">42 U.S.C. 2160e</external-xref>), as added by section 2 of the Iran Nuclear Agreement Review Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/17">Public Law 114–17</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 201), or any other provision of law, action involving any measure of statutory sanctions relief by the United States may not be taken unless the Senate provides its advice and consent to ratification of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action under article II, section 2 of the United States Constitution.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA79759D0ACD43A4A346BB6C4E54CFEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H17FA08368AF941E1A72A58261F2CDFC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Action involving any measure of statutory sanctions relief by the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>action involving any measure of statutory sanctions relief by the United States</term> has the meaning given the term in section 135(c)(3) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2160e">42 U.S.C. 2160e(c)(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBFF12C19F7F4670B263CBE046BEE8BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action</term> means the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, signed at Vienna July 14, 2015, by Iran and by the People’s Republic of China, France, Germany, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom and the United States, with the High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, and all implementing materials and agreements related to the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB980BE3AC3704D7C850855E20A076C9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section takes effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and applies with respect to action involving any measure of statutory sanctions relief by the United States provided before, on, or after such date of enactment.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


