<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7FE92BC0A3A641699DABA61265ADDFB8" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3873 IH: International Cyber Policy Oversight Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3873</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151102">November 2, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of State to produce a comprehensive strategy relating to United States
			 international policy with regard to cyberspace, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H62915766A497425885D9322080397927" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5FF1129CA0CA435E89CF882B26246A96" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Cyber Policy Oversight Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD8CD11B3240B4DF0BDF017FEC8EAD701"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of State international cyberspace policy strategy</header> <subsection id="H3066BB8722034E5FB6249D7B0A4E4D44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall produce a comprehensive strategy, with a classified annex if necessary, relating to United States international policy with regard to cyberspace.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H57F0AA0856C44C5E9275DD17990DCFA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required in subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2B8CFB42E3604D78AAEAAE58CA82C692"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A review of actions and activities undertaken by the Secretary of State to date to support the goal of the President’s International Strategy for Cyberspace, released in May 2011, to <quote>work internationally to promote an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable information and communications infrastructure that supports international trade and commerce, strengthens international security, and fosters free expression and innovation</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08EB062269CA45BCAFE4D0C01576016A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A plan of action to guide the Secretary of State’s diplomacy with regard to countries, including conducting bilateral and multilateral activities to develop the norms of responsible international behavior in cyberspace, and status review of existing discussions in multilateral fora to obtain agreements on international norms in cyberspace.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4508A24250C34DF4AC3BD3F827D70956"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A review of the alternative concepts with regard to international norms in cyberspace offered by other prominent country actors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DC7BFE80D864156A9259C72DED89D10"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A detailed description of threats to United States national security in cyberspace from other countries, state-sponsored actors and private actors, to United States Federal and private sector infrastructure, United States intellectual property, and the privacy of United States citizens.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H269E53724AE34F3181590381065A559E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A review of policy tools available to the President to deter countries, state-sponsored actors, and private actors, including those outlined in Executive Order 13694, released on April 1, 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94B31F5719A2484D98AD28EDC0BE6A94"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A review of resources required by the Secretary of State, including the Office of the Coordinator for Cyber Issues, to conduct activities to build responsible norms of international cyber behavior.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F82B93753D5422DAEE2116278CF925C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary of State shall consult, as appropriate, with other United States Government agencies, the United States private sector, and United States nongovernmental organizations with recognized credentials and expertise in foreign policy, national security, and cybersecurity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8AFE3E47F83F421B9674666EB3799179"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Release</header><text>The Secretary of State shall publicly release the strategy required in subsection (a) and brief the appropriate congressional committees upon its release, including on the classified annex, if the strategy includes such an annex.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


