<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC4B023BDF744423B8EEF787EBEF90FCF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3936 IH: VET Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3936</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary
			 carries out Veteran Engagement Team events where veterans can complete
			 claims for disability compensation and pension under the laws administered
			 by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF13CAF52B6924F71BF6FB1FB44DA0E01" style="OLC">
 <section id="H63D76DF1219144159A3B6463331F5DBB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Engagement Teams Act</short-title></quote> or <quote>VET Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC3500CD500B449D18930EF73FB955AA4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on Department of Veterans Affairs Veteran Engagement Team events</header> <subsection id="HA946E00DAF024796A2D75FD7EC91FC42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="HBE1AB5E3F60B4844BBF97B3ECDBEA0BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>Beginning not later than October 1, 2016, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a three-year pilot program under which the Secretary shall carry out events, to be known as <quote>Veteran Engagement Team events</quote>. The Secretary shall ensure that such events are carried out—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF929DAE82D8A4B07BD5B7991E3F64733"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the first year during which the Secretary carries out the pilot program, at least once a month in a location within the jurisdiction of each of 10 regional offices of the Department of Veterans Affairs, including at least two regional offices in each of the five districts of the Veterans Benefits Administration under the organization of such Administration in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAC5B78F56204927A41D7EF07399F0F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during each of the second and third years during which the Secretary carries out the pilot program, at least once a month in a location within the jurisdiction of each of 15 regional offices of the Department, including at least three regional offices in each such district.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17576CD8B047412FBE581039180E17DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Veteran Engagement Team events</header><text>During each Veteran Engagement Team event, the Secretary shall provide assistance to veterans in completing and adjudicating claims for disability compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, and for pension under chapter 15 of such title. The Secretary shall ensure that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H80707D0ACFFA417F8DFC325CB155D6D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all Veteran Engagement Team events occur during the normal business hours of the sponsoring regional office;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H253A26F5000D4ECB9FF858E5DD236D4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the events are carried out at different locations within the jurisdiction of each regional office and at least 50 miles from any regional office;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5398D75BFF2C46A897F49D55EFC4EE34"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a sufficient number of physicians (to be available for opinions only), veteran service representatives and rating veteran service representatives, and other personnel are available at the events to initiate, update, and finalize the completion and adjudication of claims;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD68FD04D811E440A8D694A25ADC66E89"><enum>(D)</enum><text>veterans service organizations have access to the events for purposes of providing assistance to veterans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B3E4BFE5EBC450FB16BDC08CD70D0A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a veteran who is unable to complete and adjudicate a claim at an event is informed of what additional information or actions are needed to finalize the claim.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7206BCF0883490B9E7566132EE4E3AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Location</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting locations for Veteran Engagement Team events under this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H787129CDAEA24DCB8F672F76686CE304"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate with veteran service organizations and State and local veterans agencies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3289F2F8348E431DA22DD3DBDBEE2EF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to select locations that are community-based and easily accessible.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF43B0E649D514636BC03390F3EC8CC64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of personnel</header> <paragraph id="H2CF2F84EB45E47FBA959B7043C2DF5EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Physicians</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not permanently transfer any physician employed by the Veterans Health Administration for the purpose of staffing a Veteran Engagement Team event.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C3EC0AA293F4C9ABB494FBD9F020A6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment of salaries</header><text>Any amount payable to an employee of the Department for work performed at a Veteran Engagement Team event is payable only from amounts otherwise available for the payment of the salary of the employee. No additional amounts are authorized to be appropriated under this section for the payment of salaries for Department employee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H849255BB5B4045CB8EAEB174358F1BC0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other authorities</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program under this section, the Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="H6974B140E08349089263960F5098F1C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with States, local governments, nonprofit organizations, and private sector entities to use facilities to host Veteran Engagement Team events for no or minimal costs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30696175DADA473FA11F774AB980572B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accept, on a without compensation basis, services provided by non-Department physicians in rendering medical opinions relating to claims for compensation and pension.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86F19A5D61FF4299B72855F6FE16AFFF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Customer satisfaction surveys</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program under this section, the Secretary shall collect and analyze information about the customer satisfaction of veterans who have received assistance at an Veteran Engagement Team event.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3158D0FE1AEF45989F58F5F90273811F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 30, 2017, and annually thereafter beginning on October 1, 2017, for the duration of the program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation and effectiveness of the events. Such report shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H07349638B5354235973C64B88C9F18A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and types of claims completed and adjudicated at the events;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2F931B57AA342F3BBF79A3D8489BFFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number and types of claims for which assistance was sought at the events that were not completed or adjudicated at the events and the reasons such claims were not completed or adjudicated; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40160A2EC572493490BBFD4D73710D42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of the customer satisfaction of veterans who have received assistance at an event based on the information collected under subsection (e).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


