<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD9801AACD00A439A997AD874044EF4FA" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3244 IH: Providing Innovative Care for Complex Cases Demonstration Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3244</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a pilot program to improve care for
			 the most costly Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries through the use of
			 comprehensive and effective care management while reducing costs to the
			 Federal Government for these beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HED5D9422513548F987BD073DBA18D3B4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7C986122EFC3455D8106E045D6173775" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Innovative Care for Complex Cases Demonstration Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2DE5E7A1A27942A68998E82D84575655"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program to improve care for highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XVIII of the Social Security Act is amended by inserting after section 1866E (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc-5">42 U.S.C. 1395cc–5</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7AA83D8CA76344CA83D7CC53D6069E27" style="traditional">
 <section id="H51EF361DC6064B9EB663031EB5E40342"><enum>1866F.</enum><header>Program to improve care for highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF908719283F44820871D87ADF30740F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct under this section a pilot program (in this section referred to as the <quote>program</quote>) to demonstrate improvements in patient care and cost savings for the highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries through enrollment of such beneficiaries with participating organizations. Under the program, the Secretary shall, through a competitive process, enter into a contract with one or two selected organizations to offer benefits for items and services in service areas identified under subsection (b)(1)(A) to the highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries (identified under subsection (c)(1)) in the service area involved. The program shall be designed in a manner to provide comprehensive and integrated care management and services through a network of health care providers to meet the specialized needs of such identified beneficiaries.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H2284BEF833B44F7996E69946C8A422B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conduct of program</header>
						<paragraph id="H7718302CC24D415E90DD1BF674A97E89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Period of operation and scope</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD3DCFCF38E3346E8A6AA3A4BE41BFC49"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial conduct</header><text>The program shall initially be conducted over a 3-year period, beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, in at least 4 service areas, each identified by the Secretary and each including at least 3 contiguous counties.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C0548ECB72D4E2D80544D539D82391B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expansion and extension</header><text>The Secretary may expand the program to additional service areas and extend its duration if the Secretary determines, in consultation with the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, that such expansion and extension will result in additional savings to the Medicare program and will meet the quality performance standards established under subsection (d)(3)(A)(iii).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5364ABED85E54EDF89F2805746167273"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Relation to part D</header>
 <clause id="HEA355D60DAD0404C9E932A0A89E4B591"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall design and implement the program in such manner as to preserve the operation of part D, including payment, noninterference, and beneficiary protections under such part.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7545D9D6E3A540FF82C5D032BF0C9C6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Coordination mechanisms</header><text>The Secretary shall identify mechanisms that may be used, in the case of a highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiary who is enrolled with a participating organization under the program and in a prescription drug plan offered by a PDP sponsor under part D or a qualified retiree prescription drug plan offered by a sponsor under section 1860D–22, in order to enhance coordination of the individual’s care between the organization and the respective sponsor.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9D2580B9057545DF80AC4709B020BB11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number of participating organizations per service area</header><text>Under the program the Secretary shall enter into a contract with at least one selected organization (and no more than 2 selected organizations) in each service area identified and covered under the program.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H697097C8A51A43B789FAD9D5A335E2B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identification and enrollment of highest cost Medicare fee-for-Service beneficiaries</header>
						<paragraph id="HC700E2E23235447E8EFF34566D7B0EAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification</header>
 <subparagraph id="H80BDF356ACDB42E38E3DDF705FC1281C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the program, the Secretary shall develop criteria to identify, subject to subparagraph (B), Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries with projected total costs under parts A and B in the highest 10th percentile of all Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries on an ongoing basis. Such criteria shall be developed in a manner so as to identify such beneficiaries using the most recent national data available for a 2-year period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0565B8A9F3D641DFA35BB80FF92F2614"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Refinement of eligibility criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In identifying highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries under this paragraph, the Secretary shall develop such criteria in a manner that eliminates, to the extent practicable, the identification of individuals who otherwise appear to meet such criteria only because of a single, isolated high-cost incident, item, or service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA7D90966A44B4FBCBB32D1ECBCC6C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible beneficiary initial outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall inform the highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries residing in an area covered by the program of the program and provide them with information about the program and the process for enrollment and disenrollment from participation organizations in such area. Such information shall include information about such organizations, about rights and protections under the program, a contact telephone number where beneficiaries can obtain additional information about the program, and the use of an advance directive (as defined in section 1866(f)(3)) in connection with participation in the program.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HE41A626A03984AA89EF53DC9458A3FCC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Auto-enrollment and disenrollment procedures</header>
 <subparagraph id="H15C0024502A84152B17713A6E8B53E97"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the program, the highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries residing in a service area covered under the program—</text>
 <clause id="H446A863F78D0455696D16D617D21DC93"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be enrolled, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, with a participating organization offered under the program to such a resident in such area; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7B583958A0F0469089DE3CD252F28931"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may change or terminate such enrollment in a form and manner so specified.</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">In specifying such form and manner, the Secretary shall take into account the form and manner in which individuals may change or terminate an enrollment under a Medicare Advantage plan under part C, including permitting special disenrollment periods described in section 1851(e)(4).</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H231AD6E5534B4986AF122843A99795C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Default organization selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subparagraph (A), if there are two participating organizations in a service area, the Secretary shall identify, to the extent possible, and enroll the beneficiary in the participating organization which has providers in its network from whom the beneficiary has received services under the Medicare fee-for-service program in the previous year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H659282C429C84B669363A4E26BCC415A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Timeframes</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), there shall be an initial enrollment period of 12 months, during which a highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiary may also opt out of participation in the program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1CCBF3DA4CC4783BFF5B37BF21F3D58"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Extension of certain guaranteed issuance rights to Medigap coverage in case of disenrollment</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 1882(s)(3) shall apply to a Medicare beneficiary enrolled with a participating organization under this section who had previous coverage under a medicare supplemental insurance policy and who terminates enrollment with the participating organization in the same manner as such section applies to an individual described in subparagraph (B)(v) of such section with respect to enrollment with a health plan, regardless of the time period of participation in the program and without regard to subparagraph (E)(ii) of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12A76F589B574C52942FD8D9DE0436D1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of Medicare fee-for-service benefits to enrollees through program</header><text>The provisions of section 1851(i) shall apply to individuals enrolled with a participating organization under the program in the same manner as they apply to an individual enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan under part C.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05FA387427C84B97A96E176EEA96CBE6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Relation to part D, employer-based prescription drug coverage, and medicare supplemental coverage</header><text>Except as specifically provided, nothing in this section shall be construed as intending to impact on benefits or coverage furnished under a prescription drug plan under part D, under a group health plan (including under a qualified retiree prescription drug plan as defined in section 1860D–22(a)(2)), or under a medicare supplemental policy.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60D459B9ADCE4188BD35C68FD78B353D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Participating organization requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H71F1407689044B2DA9A610C2C85A5823"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of participating in the program, except as provided in this subsection, a participating organization must meet the same requirements that apply to a Medicare Advantage organization and an MA plan that is not an MA–PD plan under part C, including requirements relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2579664D51A14680BCE7937C9A637690"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coverage of items and services under parts A and B; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E05363E8FAF4A62B3338CE585FA2318"><enum>(B)</enum><text>beneficiary protections under part C.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8882B4541D214079AAFD7E6573617CC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><text>Under the program, the Secretary may waive the requirements of this title and title XI but only to the extent necessary to permit participating organizations—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCB4847DA7B144BF6BCED44B80DD693FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide care management, custodial care, transportation, in-home assistance, and other services that are not otherwise covered under this title;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC148CF2600D74BA589F51F0ADC9968FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to structure patient incentives, such as a reduction or elimination of cost-sharing, for services and benefits under parts A and B and the use of in-home technology, to improve beneficiary adherence to treatment protocols and the effectiveness of treatment for enrolled beneficiaries with chronic clinical conditions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB4637954D294F4EBEC54E1229513551"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to maintain provider and pharmacy networks that do not otherwise meet network adequacy standards.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3F85E3200A54AE2A4ECF423CAB1B4B5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quality and reporting requirements</header> <subparagraph id="HC128EC05A2EB40069A1A6A73A4CEE149"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the program, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="H0D40B39C170C45CEA9F33E6578BD7C6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine appropriate measures (including, to the extent feasible, outcome measures) to assess the quality of care being provided under the program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAC4DF1F79D674DD9B9FDDF7309033B50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish requirements for participating organizations to report, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, information on such measures;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBAA086738751474696678086F290871C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>establish quality performance standards on such measures to assess the quality of care being provided by such organizations under the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD39725B263E24DDFA7B957FA9D85EC31"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>seek the input of stakeholders (in a manner similar to that provided for under section 1848(r)) in determining such measures, requirements, and standards.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0595E98566F5440C9C17EB3B0C49EA84"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination of participation for failure to meet quality performance standards</header><text>The Secretary may terminate participation of an organization under the program for failure to meet the quality performance standards established under subparagraph (A)(iii).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2DF54DE7F8404F3788A806DE0BD9A83E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Quality performance standards</header><text>In establishing quality performance standards under subparagraph (A)(iii) in the case of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H7A1748535E88405B90148AA82B4C491E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a provider-based organization (such as an accountable care organization), the Secretary may apply the quality measurement system used under the Medicare shared savings program under section 1899(b)(3); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9E0C3834B0A548549A0A85D7D99F990F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an MA organization, the Secretary may require that only an organization with a rating (under the star quality rating system under section 1853(o)(4)) of 4 stars or higher be permitted to participate in the program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B0798969B854ABC812DD665A8D647EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of integrated model of care</header><text>The Secretary shall develop care management requirements for participating organizations that provides an integrated care model and that includes the following elements:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H94FC82518AF243DFB8969AF15B0158B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Provision of person-centered, comprehensive, and integrated care management and services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H497666F6028549D7ACF174C1BB41EEE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provision of services through—</text>
 <clause id="HC62B651BFF754401946729620466349B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of a network of providers characterized as best-in-class, such as centers of excellence; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H450501EE2E1D4D62BFAAD7A52052FD07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of an interdisciplinary management team that includes a nurse coordinator (or other appropriate health care professional) assigned to each enrolled beneficiary and that shares a common health information technology platform.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AEFEAA3087D4DC7B603884B76339573"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An evidence-based model of care with appropriate networks of providers and specialists.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H715C7A60FF8648D68A99B0CBFEEA64BF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For each beneficiary enrolled with the organization under the program, the organization—</text>
 <clause id="H011E54F426774F1EA9B1AF2DF6F98600"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducts an initial assessment and an annual reassessment of the beneficiary’s physical, psychosocial, and functional needs, including an evaluation and plan with respect to the beneficiary’s chronic conditions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5259CAF6162C4DE58A1A4BA600778458"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides for regular in-person visits to the beneficiary by a care provider and provides the beneficiary with access to a specialized team, including a hospitalist physician; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC24404A75DE547B7A6A8A825B668D5AD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>develops a plan, in consultation with the beneficiary as feasible, that identifies goals and objectives with respect to the beneficiary, including measurable outcomes as well as specific services and benefits to be provided.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA67942D45DC643D48DF34FF47A0729EB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Payments</header>
 <paragraph id="HB604B17E18C64CB38762C096E6526A80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each individual enrolled with a participating organization under the program, the Secretary shall make a monthly capitated payment to the organization in the same manner as such a payment would be made under part C for an individual enrolled in an MA-plan (that was not an MA–PD plan) offered by a Medicare Advantage organization, except that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE0CFA4FBC8EC42DC92A261A591AC01B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notwithstanding section 1853, the amount of the payment shall be determined, subject to subparagraph (B), in an amount equivalent to 98 percent of the projected cost, under the Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B for the highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9E427F024D84BBE9A6B9F47F721A554"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of such payment shall be adjusted, in a manner specified by the Secretary, to take into account differences in costs among different geographic areas and among high cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries (including outlier costs for the most costly such beneficiaries).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B1EDEA9D83747B0975C6AF67167C5CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Projection based upon historical data</header><text>In applying paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary shall use historical fee-for-service spending and enrollment data for the highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries, trended forward to the first year of the program, and, for subsequent years of the program, increased by projected growth in such spending for such beneficiaries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84E2E631EB2D438589CF1CE75D9D100B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relationship to payment for covered part D drugs</header><text>In the case of an individual who is enrolled with a participating organization under the program—</text> <subparagraph id="H0047C636DEEB4FB29271C520DAAA5496"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the individual is enrolled with a prescription drug plan under part D, payment for covered part D drugs for such individual is made under such prescription drug plan under such part and not under the program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H571354D239414297BAF2147AC4D8D0B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the individual is covered under a qualified retiree prescription drug plan under section 1860D–22, payment for covered part D drugs for such individual is made under such plan and not under the program.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DCFE0A6E36B4D458F3A4881EBE6FA56"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation and report to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="HAAF3289BB76C4F84A111A0B67BDB1499"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct an independent evaluation of the program. Such evaluation shall include an analysis of the impact of the program on coordination of care, expenditures by participating organizations and plans, the program’s impact on reducing expenditures under this title, beneficiary access to services and providers, the quality of health care services furnished to beneficiaries, and beneficiary experiences with auto-enrollment and disenrollment under the program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EFEC339B7A44AFE82CAF6E170CFBD85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date that Medicare beneficiaries are first enrolled under the program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the performance of the program. Such report shall include the results of the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1) and the program’s impact on reducing expenditures under this title and on improving the quality of care for the highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiaries enrolled under the program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H272D32DBE83148348F9137A560F2111F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H972FE56F94CF41EE8847D8742E95717B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiary</header><text>The term <term>highest cost Medicare fee-for-service beneficiary</term> means a Medicare fee-for-service beneficiary who has been identified under subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24BEA3FE7EDC4C61B1395AE3842CE98C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medicare fee-for-service beneficiary defined</header><text>The term <term>Medicare fee-for-service beneficiary</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="H0FB14059D97242C086702A7ACEFE16CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is entitled to benefits under part A, and enrolled under part B, regardless of the basis for entitlement or eligibility to benefits under any such part; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20C9AFF3C8154F5181A5EE0826F12A15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan under part C.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C995D7A4CC14BF2B9DF76AC7AACE2B5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>Unless the context indicates otherwise, the term <term>program</term> means the program under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2567927741664B08B8D043156D486B22"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Participating organization</header><text>The term <term>participating organization</term> means a selected organization that has entered into a contract to participate in the program.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB519B0094B5E43509F585AC8EA0A3D21"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Selected organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>selected organization</term> means a provider-based organization (such as an accountable care organization) or MA organization (as defined for purposes of part C) that the Secretary determines—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4CC5D5AEFD6849A7A20BF28A4A6558F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets the requirements to provide services to the highest cost Medicare fee-for-services beneficiaries under the program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56EB9018F9FF4A57A57ED9BCF604A029"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is accredited by the National Committee for Quality Assurance or otherwise is certified as meeting quality standards.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


