<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H720BB141FEC849BB9204B1E7B1363C18" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3948 IH: Student Loan Transfers Disclosure Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3948</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Truth in Lending Act to include requirements for the transfer of servicing of
			 postsecondary education loans, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE926A6577E3944CB994B184E5298D259" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="HE0DCEA53290C471F8DFBA21E8F5C1282" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Loan Transfers Disclosure Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC1C11993136C4A1499162E5F88F08617"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improved consumer protections for student loan servicing</header> <subsection id="H1829C92E71054E54AE9891EF286103CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 2 of title I of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1601">15 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC16D3AB714D443699000005074E0F8F2" style="USC">
					<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CF1455FE15E4324AEB880101AEE8205"><enum>140B.</enum><header>Transfer of servicing of postsecondary education loans</header>
						<subsection id="H3D84BF25DE064A849B42DB8F0F6DE6E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of servicing</header>
 <paragraph id="H30455D178D1D4C4F8CB3A709575980CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosure required</header><text>A postsecondary education lender shall disclose to each person who applies for a postsecondary education loan, at the time of application for such loan, whether there may be a transfer of servicing of such loan at any time during which a balance is due on such loan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H063D127A7B61496FA6D031819864DE1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No liability</header><text>A postsecondary education lender shall not be liable to a borrower for failure to comply with paragraph (1) if the application for a postsecondary education loan was made before the rules or regulations established under subsection (f) take effect.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H845BBA48E4D64EBBB1118E1B7B41A14A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice by transferor servicer at time of transfer of servicing</header>
 <paragraph id="H95F88F1B509F45FC92C4D7F69C1BE358"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A transferor servicer shall notify the borrower under a postsecondary education loan of any transfer of student loan servicing for the postsecondary education loan. Such notice shall be made to the borrower—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD4E81B91BA354444AB0958366ECC3E59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 15 days before the effective date of transfer of the student loan servicing; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89CCFD2C7A5B4AA1B987E93A1B1830AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than 30 days after the effective date of transfer of the student loan servicing, if the transfer of such servicing is preceded by—</text>
 <clause id="H6E599D22498145F98195216A5847B3FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>termination of the contract for such servicing for cause;</text> </clause><clause id="H5BB7782A1A8C4089AC45498DE0DE74DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commencement of bankruptcy proceedings of the transferor servicer; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H53B7C4F5C41840828A57FC631A254A30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other situation in which the Bureau determines that such exception is warranted.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E6277FE56E14D2BA9B0B478BAB8D6FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The notice required under paragraph (1) shall be made in writing and, if the transferor servicer has an email address for the borrower, sent by email, and shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA16A3CFD8C3D47AB8ED23D00C2A08868"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effective date of the transfer;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE278DAC523A34A3099174F28B7DFC369"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name, address, website, and toll-free or collect-call telephone number of the transferee servicer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA61B34E2DE7C459597EDFDA805A8D38B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a toll-free or collect-call telephone number for an individual employed by the transferor servicer, or the office or department of, the transferor servicer that the borrower may contact for inquiries relating to the transfer of servicing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA01D3B8CDE054B158BA8142B13D4DA23"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name and toll-free or collect-call telephone number for an individual employed by the transferee servicer, or the office or department of, the transferee servicer that the borrower may contact for inquiries relating to the transfer of servicing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8071D922E12949C7AFEFCFFD2CC34A84"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the date on which the transferor servicer will stop accepting payments relating to the postsecondary education loan to be transferred and the date on which the transferee servicer will begin to accept such payments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C565D89236D45C6B2F1AED852C15E8F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a statement that the transfer of student loan servicing of the postsecondary education loan does not affect any term or condition of the postsecondary education loan other than terms directly related to such student loan servicing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C27A1A3AA5E437BB77E1ACA553E0033"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a statement disclosing—</text> <clause id="HCCE5FF8BD7DA480B987077AF80345D3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether borrower authorization for recurring electronic funds transfers will be transferred to the transferee servicer; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H758B2A31B0FD425AB340ED6CF15F8FB8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if any such recurring electronic funds transfers cannot be transferred, information as to how the borrower may establish new recurring electronic funds transfers in connection with transfer of servicing to the transferee servicer;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DBE6413450A44B6BA1B00209AFA35B3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a statement disclosing—</text> <clause id="H406001CE1C0F438EBDB81B503DEBB018"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the application of all payments and charges relating to the postsecondary education loan to be transferred as of the effective date of the transfer, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H64A8553BD3544850B952AFF06C5290EB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date the last payment of the borrower was received;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H00BEFBB7B4224E19893031E9CC134440"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date the last late fee, arrearage, or other charge was applied; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H00FFCA2D3F2844CEBDDCAC1349769C65"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the amount of the last payment allocated to principal, interest, and other charges;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H97E6309C873A43B8942323D33ACBE496"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of such loan as of the effective date of the transfer, including whether the borrower is in default on the loan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD6DB5C07706B489186E2F2C4073B0737"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether any application for an alternative repayment arrangement submitted by the borrower is pending; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9CBD862920264BA5B2FDB93E999613B5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an itemization and explanation for all arrearages claimed to be due as of the effective date of the transfer;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H154BA02B370C4A76A03250622B55B616"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of any benefit, alternative repayment arrangement, or other term or condition arranged between the transferor servicer and the borrower that is not included in the terms of the loan agreement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67F2759919A4463FB7502BCEFAAD3C9D"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of any item under subparagraph (H) that will not apply upon transfer, including an explanation of why such item will not apply; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76EEA1D334DB41E2BF68AD03B1842F65"><enum>(K)</enum><text>information on how to file a complaint against the transferor servicer with the Bureau.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35F8B2C3573F4C68A76000C16076FCC8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice by transferee servicer at time of transfer of servicing</header> <subparagraph id="HB942F50D36C04119ABEA5DEA21CB66E4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A transferee servicer shall notify the borrower under a postsecondary education loan, in writing, of any transfer of student loan servicing of a postsecondary education loan. Such notice shall be made to the borrower—</text>
 <clause id="H7FC0D8E1212D4830948B7DE38557B7B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 15 days before the effective date of transfer of the student loan servicing; or</text> </clause><clause id="HD5DE84DDD78642CCB4535AF2D7078C54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than 30 days after the effective date of transfer of the student loan servicing, if the transfer of such servicing is preceded by—</text>
 <subclause id="HC6C5656ED26F4098A0BEA7FA89F5EC44"><enum>(I)</enum><text>termination of the contract for such servicing for cause;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H9060578947194C79841495C07B3F37A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>commencement of bankruptcy proceedings of the transferor servicer; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2790E2C1347345179764243DF29C4E2F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other situation in which the Bureau determines that such exception is warranted.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59CAD21B18904CFC8FACE85C65891E46"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The notice required under subparagraph (A) shall be made in the same manner and include the same information, as applicable, as described in paragraph (2).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3F49FA0668C847A4B1A8B83DE8C996E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of improperly received loan payments during transfer period</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB0D5D061FBDD4C13B8DE157B536365F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 60-day period beginning on the effective date of transfer relating to a postsecondary education loan to be transferred, a late fee may not be imposed on the borrower with respect to any payment on such loan, and no such payment may be treated as late for any other purposes if—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAA685C31F1204ED683AA8EBFF6E7F27B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the payment is received by the transferor servicer instead of the transferee servicer (who should properly receive payment) before the due date applicable to such payment; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H770305D5C9A6457281D19B296CB49E4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the payment is received by the transferee servicer instead of the transferor servicer (who should properly receive payment) before the transfer is complete.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9E792D137059449DB8EADEF2F07A59C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, a transferor servicer shall notify a borrower, both in writing and by telephone, regarding any payment described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23E1C814554243EEBE33A69140C3BFF8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Electronic fund transfer authority</header><text>A transferee servicer shall make available to a borrower whose student loan servicing is transferred to the transferee servicer a simple, online process through which the borrower may transfer to the transferee servicer any existing authority for an electronic fund transfer that the borrower had provided to the transferor servicer.</text>
						</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5D1CDFA3930452CB600904992926154"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Servicer liability</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08153DF7DEA84BCE8EE2CAA988D297B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date of regulations</header><text>A student loan servicer shall not be liable to a borrower for failure to comply with the requirements of subsection (b) with respect to a transfer of student loan servicing before the regulations under subsection (f) take effect.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35CE01EB42F04664991F0810B158E908"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mitigating action</header><text>A student loan servicer or a postsecondary education lender shall not be liable to a borrower for failure to comply with a requirement under this section if, not later than 60 days after discovering an error and before the commencement of an action under section 130 or the receipt of written notice of the error from the borrower, the student loan servicer notifies the borrower of the error and makes any adjustments in the appropriate account that are necessary to ensure that the borrower will not be required to pay an amount greater than the amount that the borrower otherwise would have paid.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE92F9151D9CD4BE5838DFCE2ADFC8C1B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Bureau, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, is authorized to prescribe such rules and regulations, make such interpretations, and grant such reasonable exemptions, in accordance with, and as may be necessary to achieve the purposes of, this chapter.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H260C94305F7C4DCAB325843769BABA1C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E3B9D97888E4AD4A39A207386125F50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alternative repayment arrangement</header><text>The term <term>alternative repayment arrangement</term> means an agreed upon arrangement between a loan holder (or, for a Federal Direct Loan or a Federal Perkins Loan, the Secretary of Education or the institution of higher education that made such loan, respectively) or student loan servicer and a borrower—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0DA0AC6AC03C44FC9D9E5AD633B5C04C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is different than the terms of an existing postsecondary education loan arrangement or agreement; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56CB7FC690544083870F5E4DB0EEDA43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pursuant to which remittance of a monthly payment—</text> <clause id="H17380960E688417FA290960477565047"><enum>(i)</enum><text>satisfies the terms of the postsecondary education loan; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H01EB64AE183146F784E7DD47DEF67B62"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not required for a period of 1 or more months in order to satisfy the terms of the postsecondary education loan arrangement or agreement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F445F31E44545ACAEB3FA6E3B15A3EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date of transfer</header><text>The term <term>effective date of transfer</term> means the date on which the first payment is due to a transferee servicer from a borrower under a postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H472353F6E68742228E5B0D37431B51FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal Direct Loan</header><text>The term <term>Federal Direct Loan</term> means a loan made under part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAE8A0792D4C4D26B151042E7816F142"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal Perkins Loan</header><text>The term <term>Federal Perkins Loan</term> means a loan made under part E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087aa">20 U.S.C. 1087aa et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA16BFD4021A6461289AF7196A367B491"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C7FB4D9D4AC4949B50446A7BAD50663"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Late fee</header><text>The term <term>late fee</term> means a late fee, penalty, or adjustment to principal, imposed because of a late payment or delinquency by the borrower under a postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC30289AE646A4E51AE3A2D5E9F40E6BF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Loan holder</header><text>The term <term>loan holder</term> means a person who owns the title to or promissory note for a postsecondary education loan (except for a Federal Direct Loan or a Federal Perkins Loan).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6A28F0A2B3E4870BE4002DFA269ABDB"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Postsecondary education expense</header><text>The term <term>postsecondary education expense</term> means any expense that is included as part of the cost of attendance (as that term is defined in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>)) of a student.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0091A509530F4016886E45138E62EBCD"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Postsecondary education lender</header><text>The term <term>postsecondary education lender</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6EE934F9D8F74BFCA079CDCCF3FA55E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H4FCF21E61A28479C95ECA7F412B4761D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a financial institution, as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>) that solicits, makes, or extends postsecondary education loans;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H777B03940EF24170984FCAEAD1DAD3C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Federal credit union, as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>) that solicits, makes, or extends postsecondary education loans; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H3C1EC47B90D4406CB1222CC704E3ED9C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other person engaged in the business of soliciting, making, or extending postsecondary education loans; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE80376CDE6D8471DAC31A32989E6A21C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H07D98129A477400FA3B5E8BDE4868634"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9EAF3AF04FBF4459B745CA28B2363B7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an institution of higher education with respect to any Federal Perkins Loan made by the institution.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC4D3C638B1840E690E5F5D2E63F1EA8"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Postsecondary education loan</header><text>The term <term>postsecondary education loan</term> means a loan that is—</text> <subparagraph id="H035CE46D896E4F0D9168E18313A6252C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, D, or E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071 et seq.</external-xref>, 1087a et seq., 1087aa et seq.);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14825CD54FEF4C598E90693AC7DC620F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issued or made by a postsecondary education lender and is—</text> <clause id="HD68EF91ED3734713B374F3B059557B7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>extended to a borrower with the expectation that the amounts extended will be used in whole or in part to pay postsecondary education expenses; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H07B6995FAC574F7E92CFD29F9E3ADAA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>extended for the purpose of refinancing or consolidating 1 or more loans described in subparagraph (A); or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D96962324AE4A21A0E0952993304D73"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a private education loan (as defined in section 140(a)).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBC6158AE39F400CAB5ED414A7C626B4"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Student loan servicer</header><text>The term <term>student loan servicer</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC2DE2C9BE4C94D10B4CDDB53B6D0DCA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a person who performs student loan servicing;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CF85C6B105547B98CD704D73EA86160"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a person performing student loan servicing for a postsecondary education loan on behalf of an institution of higher education or the Secretary of Education under a contract or other agreement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7991F026877840498A84746F64818FAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include the Secretary of Education to the extent the Secretary directly performs student loan servicing for a postsecondary education loan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B1EFFF308C545F98A6802B0C0FF87EF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include an institution of higher education, to the extent that the institution directly performs student loan servicing for a Federal Perkins Loan made by the institution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5735DE291E5F42A094ABDA49E70D1221"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Student loan servicing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>student loan servicing</term> means, with respect to a postsecondary education loan, any of the following activities:</text> <subparagraph id="H9C6D057858B64FA8B32C28A6F942A3B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Receiving any scheduled periodic payments, or notification of such payments, from a borrower under a postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC98BC56B8F924EBBB3820D91C9B5C48F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Applying payments described in subparagraph (A) to an account of the borrower pursuant to the terms of the postsecondary education loan or of the contract governing the servicing of the postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H863D43DEDA3C46A391FD0C4277810E1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>During a period in which no payment is required on the postsecondary education loan—</text> <clause id="H6848451B47F745358CBDAEEE2649EB9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintaining account records for the loan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3D26438C1E7740408BC3238185B02B99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communicating with the borrower on behalf of the loan holder or, with respect to a Federal Direct Loan or Federal Perkins Loan, the Secretary of Education or the institution of higher education that made the loan, respectively.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H378559A9B872495C8CDD8A1D6B37C2AC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Interacting with a borrower to facilitate the activities described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), including activities to help prevent default by the borrower of the obligations arising from the postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FC53E0913A7493593BF2ECB0AF023D2"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Transfer of servicing</header><text>The term <term>transfer of servicing</term> means the assignment, sale, or transfer of any student loan servicing of a postsecondary education loan from a transferor servicer to a transferee servicer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60FDC585F46640CEAB55F9FBB76CD799"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Transferee servicer</header><text>The term <term>transferee servicer</term> means the student loan servicer to whom any student loan servicing of a postsecondary education loan is assigned, sold, or transferred.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05E7A4410CFF466EBCDC95273436A1D1"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Transferor servicer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>transferor servicer</term> means the student loan servicer who assigns, sells, or transfers any student loan servicing of a postsecondary education loan to another person.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE3785879DD234AEF8DCFDA8C0224F0C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for chapter 2 of title I of the Truth in Lending Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 140A the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H042BC46F9EC549B49693663BF1A23753" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">140B. Transfer of servicing of postsecondary education loans.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDE31A122D7D0474887AC81C1CE40E779"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to the Higher Education Act of 1965</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H309068AB83C945058E014A4F68679E5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 487(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DC9A67A5168470D8541A4F1FCAB9389" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H0C9CEC92711348C3B6D5DF605C80B1C4"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will—</text> <subparagraph id="H76C914F6E59341D7AEA7A4341681F0F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comply with the disclosure requirements for postsecondary education lenders under section 140B(a) of the Truth in Lending Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24CE123DA1FE452DB04AE1FB7B2F924C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that each third party servicer with which the institution has entered into a contract complies with the applicable requirements for student loan servicers under section 140B of such Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31FB1DBBE5754B40AA8B26CF9931EB1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 463A(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087cc-1">20 U.S.C. 1087cc–1(b)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4F9012959E7F4FBFB5653532FA62F0F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (8);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H871F1074D1A84B488043C62507AA3B98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (9) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9A2B61826404B0D9B374064E6545650"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E0F74286AB8499093FD30ED0FF3451C" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H0B66679AC1A347FAB25E3235276A6B66"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the disclosures for postsecondary education lenders and student loan services under section 140B of the Truth in Lending Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


