<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4052FC1903D84076834734124DBE1721" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2591 IH: Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2591</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150601">June 1, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow taxpayers to designate overpayments of tax as
			 contributions and to make additional contributions to the Homeless
			 Veterans Assistance Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE78C2CBBF2B6441B9784CF1D84D6DDB8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8E9B2969E4154A369961A93518CF0945" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H74C8E70433FF45F6A1925D52BF73FB37" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Contributions to the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund</header> <subsection id="H19A05B51A07D442592B8C50B1B5E5A70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HA9B2693CD5A44FF0BE5A36B4847067CE" style="OLC">
					<part id="HF67DDFFAE4324B368E579272C84FA837"><enum>IX</enum><header>Contributions to the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund</header>
						<toc container-level="part-container" idref="HF67DDFFAE4324B368E579272C84FA837" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H344BD5D6444C4AB89EDC31B06EB84F61" level="section">Sec. 6098. Contributions to the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="H344BD5D6444C4AB89EDC31B06EB84F61"><enum>6098.</enum><header>Contributions to the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund</header>
 <subsection id="HFF894B81A45A4818881595D6952059BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every individual, with respect to the taxpayer’s return for the taxable year of the tax imposed by chapter 1—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD7382982C8704DCC898FA2537F146D38"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may designate that a specified portion (not less than $1) of any overpayment of tax shall be paid over to the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund in accordance with the provisions of section 9512, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H639A7C1064FD4534925CED2F023A50D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in addition to any payment (if any) under paragraph (1), may make a contribution to the United States of an additional amount which shall be paid over to such Fund.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BCE853A9CFD4B95AA06EC366C5C23F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Manner and time of designation and contribution</header><text>A designation and contribution under subsection (a) may be made with respect to any taxable year—</text> <paragraph id="H352BE3D6F563419CBA5BD4FBB9C8E47E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the time of filing the return of the tax imposed by chapter 1 for such taxable year, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H075AB4177E7A4838A25F51A611BAEBBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at any other time (after such time of filing) specified in regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Such designation and contribution shall be made in such manner as the Secretary prescribes by regulations except that, if such designation is made at the time of filing the return of the tax imposed by chapter 1 for such taxable year, such designation shall be made either on the first page of the return or on the page bearing the taxpayer’s signature.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H8571A513604F4196B8BB1DEFAB6BD141"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Overpayments treated as refunded</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title, any portion of an overpayment of tax designated under subsection (a) shall be treated as—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1DFB3AB7A9754172A89C913DF3D2B6E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>being refunded to the taxpayer as of the last date prescribed for filing the return of tax imposed by chapter 1 (determined without regard to extensions) or, if later, the date the return is filed, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HACB94FBFB0D940B08A64AE118C8BB0D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a contribution made by such taxpayer on such date to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H220394EC332A4B6C96F674ACE455F358"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund</header><text>Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A07F16F451640D7A2CB3D6108C2FC14" style="OLC">
					<section id="H5352985E7DE043BE8E977C7BCE8A4B2C"><enum>9512.</enum><header>Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H9A891F6C848441D49201FB16BE1D8CBA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of Trust Fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <term>Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund</term>, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to such fund as provided in this section or section 9602(b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD0F35F300F4E48BCB99F7FD2BE855561"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to Trust Fund</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund amounts equivalent to the amounts designated and contributed under section 6098.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HFD773D1F88FC44BAAE335BE9514C584D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures</header>
 <paragraph id="H4E35AB0436AE44FB98B2522F47CE2E40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), amounts in the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund shall be available (and shall remain available until expended) to the Department of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Department of Labor Veterans' Employment and Training Service and the Department of Housing and Urban Development, for the purpose of providing services to homeless veterans, through—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H096F4564C84041649152CCF2839216AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development and implementation of new and innovative strategies to prevent and end veteran homelessness, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H636BC6D8DE914620925F8F32A0F7D25B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any homeless veteran program administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Labor Veterans' Employment and Training Service, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE23565F505D404A8D9F2E89DBA29927"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional allocations</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs is authorized to make transfers from the amounts described in paragraph (1) to the Department of Labor Veterans' Employment and Training Service and the Department of Housing and Urban Development for the purpose of supporting programs that serve homeless veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3B8C4B9BA9545C7B2DD6C616A381909"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advance notice</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in collaboration with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall submit a detailed expenditure plan for any amounts in the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs and Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and of the Senate not later than 60 days prior to any expenditure of such amounts.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C998B38D725437EA0A2008A9DEEAF2C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>President’s annual budget information</header><text>Beginning with the President's annual budget submission for fiscal year 2017 and every year thereafter, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Labor, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall include a description of the use of funds from the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund from the previous fiscal year and the proposed use of such funds for the next fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC2E33536986B4D069AC12E99FF26B79E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical Amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HE575B3D95C7F443AAE38CA2DE16C38E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The table of parts for subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H548854A9B2BC49E7884DD36977173C78" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="HF67DDFFAE4324B368E579272C84FA837" level="part">Part IX. Contributions to the Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2279B44CA96B40848D94433A6FECF7A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subchapter A of chapter 98 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA416680493554F1E9CEC2EE3F789D472" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9512. Homeless Veterans Assistance Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA26C09F02927469B85D9517832288A6A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


