<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H39A735585D65401182EDE126CD0B4E68" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2038 IH: To authorize the conveyance of certain Coast Guard property in Tok, Alaska, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2038</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150427">April 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the conveyance of certain Coast Guard property in Tok, Alaska, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8CB0E0C67DA04FA0AA49848B3745BD49" style="OLC">
		<section commented="no" id="H7671911764004684AEE9E3CAC83344EA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Conveyance of Coast Guard property in Tok, Alaska</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H80B63257F48749A8B15D99B43FAF50F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commandant of the Coast Guard may convey all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the covered property, upon payment to the United States of the fair market value of the covered property.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H99EF3A3243604D2BA22965D6CCCF0322"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Right of first refusal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tanana Chiefs’ Conference shall have the right of first refusal with respect to purchase of the covered property under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H68A452463A344B198D9D69E25CE6BDA3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exact acreage and legal description of the covered property shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Commandant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE48B9F2F33F14D3FA25053D776870E6A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fair market value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fair market value of the covered property shall be—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8E16565A98814054BF726DFFE141AC89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determined by appraisal; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H040D9DA377E149BE83EE8A527B38872C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to the approval of the Commandant.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAF838A6F396A4053A7E1A8DB099CB134"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Costs of conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsibility for all reasonable and necessary costs, including real estate transaction and environmental documentation costs, associated with a conveyance under this section shall be determined by the Commandant and the purchaser.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H41B9D39CFA9240A6A83BBD3D9D8B2763"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commandant may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with a conveyance under this section as the Commandant considers appropriate and reasonable to protect the interests of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1BE6A5CE114040B097842516F7CA3314"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Deposit of proceeds</header><text>Any proceeds received by the United States from a conveyance under this section shall be deposited in the Coast Guard Housing Fund established under section 687 of title 14, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H10D358C3766849DF96A852E7B11CB99F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Covered property defined</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H84D90E950F12426D88FEE5D7F430F50F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered property</term> means the approximately 3.25 acres of real property (including all improvements located on the property) that are—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFA7DB425AABC422F92364DF94170AB25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located in Tok, Alaska;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8EF392776EA4481BB440E5D72B9BC9B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under the administrative control of the Coast Guard; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF58095FA991D47EA884DE1F2CAC5B74C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>described in paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE57CDC1DB0D243E58DE9A7AF84D23DEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Description</header><text>The property described in this paragraph is the following:</text>
 </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">2-PLEX – Jackie Circle, Units A and B</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="idA9F92FE40A2B428792652934571AB6C9"><enum></enum><text>Lots 11, 12 and 13, Block <quote>G</quote>, Second Addition to Hartsell Subdivision, Section 20, Township 18 North, Range 13 East, Copper River Meridian, Alaska as appears by Plat No. 72-39 filed in the Office of the Recorder for the Fairbanks Recording District of Alaska, bearing seal dated 25 September 1972, all containing approximately 1.25 Acres.</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">4-PLEX – West <quote>C</quote> and Willow, Units A, B, C and D</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="idF8ECDC29DCFF41DBB99118E2E8196F8A"><enum></enum><text>Beginning at a point being the SE corner of the SE <fraction>1/4</fraction> of the SE <fraction>1/4</fraction> Section 24, Township 18 North, Range 12 East, Copper River Meridian, Alaska; thence running westerly along the south line of said SE <fraction>1/4</fraction> of the NE 1/4 260 feet; thence northerly parallel to the ease line of said SE <fraction>1/4</fraction> of the NE 1/4 335 feet; thence easterly parallel to the south line 260 feet; thence south 335 feet along the east boundary of Section 24 to the point of beginning; all containing approximately 2.0 acres.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


