<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6CC53BAD124047F48E0FFE6D30C6895B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2786 IH: Cross-Border Rail Security Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2786</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150615">June 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001150">Mrs. Miller of Michigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to submit a report on
			 cross-border rail security, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H82C5BA3EB7EA4B69BFB26C662D276D46" style="OLC">
 <section id="H64ACE074CB08466CBF18EB60F5C12303" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cross-Border Rail Security Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H102BE3F11A244B3995555511B6A3CEA6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cross-border rail security</header> <subsection id="HCDE8FF36442642ECB2406DF46656FEF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7CC4D5E8F95E40DF9EAA921C552CA565"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of shipments entering the United States by rail annually that are determined to be high-risk by the Commissioner.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE81DBDADFDB45238B53A4C85AE57395"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Specific details on the status of radiation detection units, by type, at each rail crossing on the northern and southern land borders as of such date of enactment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H458D5E370FA74695BF61BE365E5F6796"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of whether additional radiation detection equipment is necessary to ensure that all such high-risk cross-border rail shipments are examined with appropriate equipment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22F47AF4953544AC84BB37D4D54C6942"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A plan for ensuring that all relevant CBP personnel receive adequate training and guidance on the proper use of CBP’s Automated Targeting System for such high-risk cross-border rail shipments, the use of appropriate radiation detection equipment for examination of such high-risk cross-border rail shipments, and requirements for recording examination results.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A54F73908CA49138BAA695FD8A24C25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO audit</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall periodically audit U.S. Customs and Border Protection operations at rail crossings on the northern and southern international borders to ensure rail shipments are targeted, examined, and the results of such examinations properly documented.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


