<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDBF042079F774E33B299EAD22A6DE13B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2923 IH: Maritime and Energy Workforce Technical Training Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2923</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Energy to award grants to expand programs in maritime and energy
			 workforce technical training, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HACC643ABED1B456B83AF4C74C30BC750" style="OLC">
 <section id="H85225E8403294EC4B171EC54709DD298" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maritime and Energy Workforce Technical Training Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9A6EABF1BEFA4C269F315D34141B0286"><enum>2.</enum><header>Maritime and energy workforce technical training enhancement</header> <subsection id="H4119731AA95F4614B33CE2FC5A6F61BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants required</header> <paragraph id="HA8C2F97D954F46D8B94DF12962E3FD36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall award grants to enable eligible community colleges and other public institutions of higher education to expand upon existing programs in maritime and energy workforce technical training, including by admitting more students, training faculty, expanding facilities, creating new maritime career pathways from associate degree to baccalaureate degree programs and awarding credit for prior learning experience, or increasing cooperation with the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Veterans Affairs, or the National Science Foundation. In developing the grant program, the Secretary may award a grant to a nonprofit organization with a track record of at least 10 years of expertise in working with community colleges on developing workforce development programs, to provide assistance to the Secretary in carrying out the requirements of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5315A28403A94AB8A15889AA0F9C93CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall give priority in the award of grants under this section to eligible institutions that have entered into a partnership with the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Transportation, or the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3EE8C66FB9C40D1966F6323D5BA440C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be in amounts of not less than $1,000,000 and not more than $1,500,000.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA6D582B038C4A1A8A5A438A3CAEB1B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requests for proposals</header>
 <paragraph id="H4FA3183B27014EEA9BEBB95B99F59D21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 2 years, the Secretary shall issue a request for proposals from eligible institutions for grants under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06A5F79DC9DC4B789ADC9E1E130DE4CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposals</header><text>An eligible institution that seeks the award of a grant under this section shall submit an application therefor to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDEB4A1FAEA6440B0933662CD46CD0B33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstration of a willingness and ability to participate in a partnership described in subsection (a)(2), if any; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6F06ADE3364421B89CD86E9B39D7185"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a commitment, and demonstration of an ability, to maintain maritime and energy workforce technical training programs after the end of the grant period.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8F8030641B24F57A65B676BCC1376CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant uses</header>
 <paragraph id="H9A6287DDB921461E9390E1B571D52522"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section shall use grant amounts to carry out any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3E7C8F26390F426E89D61C829969CE62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Training related to maritime or energy transportation, logistics, and supply chain management.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C07B6ABFC9E4B8FA35EE2E16A154BDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Training related to shipbuilding and ship repair.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC9665179351436BBD0C76E0FA6D31FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhancement of academic and workforce training programs, to include certifications and apprenticeships, providing training for maritime and energy employment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5FBF486C3A944C78E798E6100966765"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Salary supplementation for faculty in maritime or energy training and education.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1890E22FE828480A89DE4FAE005DCFD1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Operation and maintenance of maritime or energy related equipment and technology for use in instructional programs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB17B4EAAFF984304B21AB4646A10AC7A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Acquisition of marine vessels, safety equipment, ship simulators, electronic navigation devices, fire suppression equipment, physical and chemical measuring instruments, sampling devices, and other assets and equipment for use in maritime or energy related training and education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF4B6313B6F047AEA1CDD7B7E2EA1E8E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Renovation or construction of buildings to house maritime or energy training and education programs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2247C4EBD5784396ACD0F3C749BB8F1B"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tuition reimbursement for successful completion of a maritime or energy course, program, or certification.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DED4643549A4D28A081B58D216B5F1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on construction</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section may use not more than 50 percent of the grant amount to carry out paragraph (1)(G).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8D567F7B0034A94B256F0F97A756DD6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Admissions preference</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section shall give preference in admission to maritime or energy training and education programs to veterans, to the extent practicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B0D86CFB3A24ECEBDE88F870932E312"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Period of use of funds</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section may use the grant funds for a period of three years after the award of the grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE05A5241BC4430BB503A1C0B5EC35B9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF7823D6E624A406A9687705654EA570A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>eligible institution</quote> means a community college or other public postsecondary educational institution located in close proximity to marine or port facilities in the Gulf of Mexico, Atlantic Ocean, Pacific Ocean, or Great Lakes offering a maritime training and education program, and which has an established association with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0FB68F85389B476594BC573F980C302C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a port authority or other established seaport or inland port facility; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58F7D4ACB6714FE292930EC5AF9BF3EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Veterans Affairs, or other appropriate government agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AEF8546A23B44DAA30DC8FEB5BBB54D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>veteran</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E8AECD73B7F4070B16B509B11B90577"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for each of fiscal years 2016, 2017, and 2018, $12,000,000 to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3143FA1EFCD04081BE6C4E63F657945F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Centers of Excellence in Maritime and Energy Workforce Technical Training</header>
			<subsection id="H0521FB87D5904C74A1B476B8899B30A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants for establishment of centers</header>
 <paragraph id="H5EBBE419C9ED4C1F949A522CC629B553"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Labor, shall award a grant to no more than 10 eligible institutions to enable the eligible institutions to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE61927BDDFBF45AF9C09598C6C8A55AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish Centers of Excellence in Maritime and Energy Workforce Technical Training (in this section referred to as the <quote>Centers</quote>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE31BC0DF7E2494181497BE90DE54A30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enable eligible institutions to improve and expand maritime and energy workforce training opportunities for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, Federal employees, and civilians by implementing new programs in such training areas as—</text>
 <clause id="HB081E7DE3B3548A2B0AE7081AC8CED6C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>port related transportation systems, maritime and energy logistics and supply chain management, small vessel repair, maintenance of navigation and deck cargo systems, maintenance of sophisticated training equipment, port related transportation, logistics, and supply chain management, shipbuilding and ship repair, operation and maintenance of equipment and technology for use in maritime and energy employment training; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9A1FF12886EC468281BF7569DC9E10B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>job placement in maritime and energy related employment fields.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F96B5BCEB194804B4D2200622684FC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall give priority in the award of grants under this section to eligible institutions that have in force, or demonstrate the willingness and ability to enter into, memoranda of understanding with the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Veterans Affairs, or other appropriate government agencies, or a cooperative agreement with an appropriate private sector entity, which memorandum of understanding or cooperative agreement provides for either, or both, of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDE9ECA25AE2F4FEBAC4FF0A8D6D39F2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The provision of resources, whether in cash or in kind, to the Center.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42110FD3DF9D4CFFAEBEAF785AA166C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Assistance for the Center in building maritime or energy training capacity, or in training Federal employees in maritime fields.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0A130FA1AC146C4BF9E44E94EC38748"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be in amounts of not more than $1,500,000 per Center.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07CE1E3C2DF64A3BBA23CDEB65527F0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requests for proposals</header> <paragraph id="HA35A6B2A6ABB4062B98338373F4AA48C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a request for proposals from eligible institutions for a grant under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCACEBB77E8CD4EEBA1C40B9D783F963B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposals</header><text>An eligible institution that seeks the award of the grant under this section shall submit an application therefor to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63A218D491264405B76628F98475C5F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant uses</header>
 <paragraph id="H8AC07248E1764FAD803A1ED9F0E5F031"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section shall use the grant amount for purposes as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1DF74EF64EF64867BE45542BB0340CFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To develop an agenda for maritime and energy training and education.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0D1C34F43A9489D897866E7CD40EC8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To fund expansion of maritime and energy training and education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE3147B1EDAF408680961A38ED2440BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To publish or otherwise disseminate findings relating to best practices in maritime and energy training and education.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62ED629ACA544E949C4E949A1C1E240A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of use of funds</header><text>Eligible institutions awarded grants under this section may use the grant amount for a period of five years after the award of the grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD470EC59E96E44D2A061B586BC23D726"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8D228D149EFA4CC38A42187C5ADE814C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>eligible institution</quote> means a community college or other public educational institution located in close proximity to port or other marine facilities on the Gulf of Mexico, Atlantic Ocean, Pacific Ocean, or Great Lakes that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H83E2B6519C784AD6A537594EFE1E87A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operates an existing maritime or energy workforce training program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEE7C1AC610E40788D85FF48F0683487"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offers accredited programs in academic areas such as port related transportation, logistics, and supply chain management and shipbuilding and ship repair, among other areas relevant to maritime or energy related workforce training;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A8B76C245D8492481CCC8584C6729A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is well recognized in the field of maritime workforce training; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACB6DF15EE174A7BA98DE09EAFC3DC50"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has an established association with—</text>
 <clause id="H63C8B49D3AC6478D9438A36DCF453473"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a port authority; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF64CC7C82AE24BD2991A625E1D7C8E2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Veterans Affairs, or other appropriate government agencies.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA1F22B43B5B4468AEACDEFE961F7DDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>veteran</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86FFA5859EB34349B53890C9A471B613"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for each of fiscal years 2016, 2017, and 2018, $12,000,000 to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


