<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Received-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7DCDC7A0905D4FE198285D238DBCB8B5" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2042 : Ratepayer Protection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2042</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>June 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To allow for judicial review of any final rule addressing carbon dioxide emissions from existing
			 fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating units before requiring
			 compliance with such rule, and to allow States to protect households and
			 businesses from significant adverse effects on electricity ratepayers or
			 reliability.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE87218BE27CB408EA3273837B77540E9" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD8238EC2A3C845C792AFF4D1BAA98795" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ratepayer Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD1715B67812247E8823E1D544FD10330"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extending compliance dates of rules addressing carbon dioxide emissions from existing power plants pending judicial review</header> <subsection id="H1373611E4F3D48848636771BD153F7EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of compliance dates</header> <paragraph id="H115EE22ADA2C436E8588A9B04AFEF67A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>Each compliance date of any final rule described in subsection (b) is deemed to be extended by the time period equal to the time period described in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H159432860E4D47E8A63CDA2AEC4B4AC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>compliance date</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HD8770E339A074E75ADCEF7A4F9CECED9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means, with respect to any requirement of a final rule described in subsection (b), the date by which any State, local, or tribal government or other person is first required to comply; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C531AD0C8BE4205A4CCC8E3F80EE994"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the date by which State plans are required to be submitted to the Environmental Protection Agency under any such final rule.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H289E6BE67C36421BA46B66C5400A33E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final rules described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A final rule described in this subsection is any final rule to address carbon dioxide emissions from existing sources that are fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating units under section 111(d) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(d)</external-xref>), including any final rule that succeeds—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5952E80947E141518565CEB478148776"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the proposed rule entitled <quote>Carbon Pollution Emission Guidelines for Existing Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> published at 79 Fed. Reg. 34830 (June 18, 2014); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFEE2206B5B64DE8A2132CA7C939BBEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the supplemental proposed rule entitled <quote>Carbon Pollution Emission Guidelines for Existing Stationary Sources: EGUs in Indian Country and U.S. Territories; Multi-Jurisdictional Partnerships</quote> published at 79 Fed. Reg. 65482 (November 4, 2014).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF4CDDD3E0224E7991AA2DD62DB3F021"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The time period described in this subsection is the period of days that—</text> <paragraph id="H62120F6FA7B64873814839B807C20C35"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begins on the date that is 60 days after the day on which notice of promulgation of a final rule described in subsection (b) appears in the Federal Register; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7ED9C3D8CF814F61AC4429EDD6A5777C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ends on the date on which judgment becomes final, and no longer subject to further appeal or review, in all actions (including actions that are filed pursuant to section 307 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7607">42 U.S.C. 7607</external-xref>))—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7DB5011A072E42E999045409E86B2598"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that are filed during the 60 days described in paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89FC4ECD094E4A6EBDED5C778EA25EF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that seek review of any aspect of such rule.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CC16B7B9DD54C73A2AB553BFA336413"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress encourages the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in promulgating, implementing, or enforcing any final rule described in subsection (b), to specifically address how the megawatt hours discharged from a pumped hydroelectric storage system will be incorporated into State and Federal implementation plans adopted pursuant to any such final rule.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6CAF0A497E1549FE895E78C9A80E6D60"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ratepayer protection<editorial></editorial></header>
 <subsection id="HBDCCDB5C09C04B6EA9D997E9F6ADF988"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effects of plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State shall be required to adopt or submit a State plan, and no State or entity within a State shall become subject to a Federal plan, pursuant to any final rule described in section 2(b), if the Governor of such State makes a determination, and notifies the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, that implementation of the State or Federal plan would—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC66A8A477C7543E98D72CC049CC9844C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have a significant adverse effect on the State’s residential, commercial, or industrial ratepayers, taking into account—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD5B53F58EA144BEABD2EB15E624876EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rate increases that would be necessary to implement, or are associated with, the State or Federal plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H461BE1214CE046F796A34BBDB93F22DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other rate increases that have been or are anticipated to be necessary to implement, or are associated with, other Federal or State environmental requirements; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A52F05B614A49F4AD438040F85B389B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a significant adverse effect on the reliability of the State’s electricity system, taking into account the effects on the State’s—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H14DE0CE7D3394D35827D5E3CB902CE77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing and planned generation and retirements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H528C27F0BFDD48A090808C217C827727"><enum>(B)</enum><text>existing and planned transmission and distribution infrastructure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09886CAADD1D47DF9107A2646E1349CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>projected electricity demands.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F0F26640CCD43BDBC32F96C4D8B7B3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In making a determination under subsection (a), the Governor of a State shall consult with—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC2926B3C14F74F1897EF02491395FB9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the public utility commission or public service commission of the State;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9A7EB45171343BAB9B74B8C03E09EA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the environmental protection, public health, and economic development departments or agencies of the State; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DC326B7BAE34CD4A58521D898359360"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Electric Reliability Organization (as defined in section 215 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824o">16 U.S.C. 824o</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2A59E50C54804432972FF39D1EC33A88"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of hydropower as renewable energy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In issuing, implementing, and enforcing any final rule described in section 2(b), the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall treat hydropower as renewable energy.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20150624">Passed the House of Representatives June 24, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


