<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD37B0A87E6974F8082FFECA250FEC94A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1512 IH: To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to designate at least one city in the United States each year as an “American World War II City”, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1512</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150319">March 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001156">Mr. McHenry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000819">Mr. Walker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to designate at least one city in the United States
			 each year as an <quote>American World War II City</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H11EBBE236FCE43348C13EA3FF2CE01B1" style="OLC">
		<section id="H17AD92F92CCE4F23819EBB7692C2DDAC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Designation of American World War II Cities</header>
 <subsection id="H84186828BBC74941A6D4D4E43E02DA6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall designate at least one city in the United States each year as an <term>American World War II City</term>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8AF836697503402DBEEC0062676E2605"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for designation</header><text>After the designation made under subsection (c), the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall make each designation under subsection (a) based on the following criteria:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2D2DE98C3F1844899F05C20C3CB95576"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Contributions by a city to the war effort during World War II, including those related to defense manufacturing, bond drives, service in the Armed Forces, and the presence of military facilities within the city.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE638C0A903AF4E27B31E1B5ECCF7548C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Efforts by a city to preserve the history of the city’s contributions during World War II, including through the establishment of preservation organizations or museums, restoration of World War II facilities, and recognition of World War II veterans.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06048BE1AB1642B9A08E3A59F1EF2828"><enum>(c)</enum><header>First American World War II City</header><text>The city of Wilmington, North Carolina, is designated as an <term>American World War II City</term>.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

