<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H498ACA655A0747DEA03BE787DCA191EB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1954 IH: Energize Emerging Opportunities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1954</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000458">Mr. Fincher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To align exemptions for general solicitation of investment in commodity pools similar to the exemption provided for general solicitation of securities under the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HBFF6D6861DA14AE3B37455DC69ABE53D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1A0CE79BC4384F8EA2F653E60C9A8A7D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energize Emerging Opportunities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9E52732A09C14A94B7E372A6139DCA73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption for general solicitation of investment in commodity pools</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H452E489E8CE74CA2B021B7638FA996F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revise section 4.7(b) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EE68811ADD14D388B9CC1BF0E89FF6F" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA7390864190544F0B1825C7F3C4F719F"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><italic>Relief available to commodity pool operators</italic>. Upon filing the notice required by paragraph (d) of this section, and subject to compliance with the conditions specified in paragraph (d) of this section, any registered commodity pool operator who sells participations in a pool solely to qualified eligible persons in an offering which qualifies for exemption from the registration requirements of the Securities Act pursuant to section 4(2) of that Act or pursuant to Regulation S, 17 CFR 230.901 <italic>et seq</italic>., and any bank registered as a commodity pool operator in connection with a pool that is a collective trust fund whose securities are exempt from registration under the Securities Act pursuant to section 3(a)(2) of that Act and are sold solely to qualified eligible persons, may claim any or all of the following relief with respect to such pool:</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BA098EC252D416282DB565379EA4131"><enum>(2)</enum><text>revise section 4.13(a)(3)(i) of such title to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F7DB8CBA2174EF7BAE6845273A98347" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HF4C5AA273CAF40CCB3F15A98C3E4424B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interests in the pool are exempt from registration under the Securities Act of 1933, and such interests are offered and sold pursuant to section 4 of the Securities Act of 1933 and the regulations thereunder;</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

