<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9DBD9A459E1F47BD8C2F4763A3D2A059" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2128 IH: Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2128</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000755">Mr. Brady of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000064">Mr. Young of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000613">Mr. Dold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exempt certain stock of real estate investment trusts from the tax on foreign investments in United States real property interests, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8BDBC7A4FAA24F1283BA1817C27B67FB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCAE2E95C082F49D0BA81FD638EDFFB4E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; etc</header> 
<subsection id="HA23EBF78A8D04742AC28CE501AEAC38A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46FB48B9D262483A9993BE4713E33225"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amendment of 1986 Code</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC30EAA35D77B4F3DAEB5D982682D2E1E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exception from FIRPTA for certain stock of real estate investment trusts</header> 
<subsection id="HC47FCDECBC0D4F25989401A86317D663"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modifications of ownership rules</header> 
<paragraph id="H2B04F6BBCB224CEB90343D8B6DBDB450"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">Section 897</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H956C3AFF6AD24308987F20E19D83B1D0" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD6FD62799CE4457FBE7CAD5C15DC4F40"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Special rules relating to real estate investment trusts</header> <paragraph id="H5147DE4E4BBD4D1D8E82E839F01A68E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Increase in percentage ownership for exceptions for persons holding publicly traded stock</header> <subparagraph id="H3D44443B79A244939F483CC1EF51A1B2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Dispositions</header><text>In the case of any disposition of stock in a real estate investment trust, paragraphs (3) and (6)(C) of subsection (c) shall each be applied by substituting <quote>more than 10 percent</quote> for <quote>more than 5 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H63B655B9F9CB4161BDE993A5481F30E9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Distributions</header><text>In the case of any distribution from a real estate investment trust, subsection (h)(1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>10 percent</quote> for <quote>5 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF205502ECE5C4D39A4DCA4139EB37648"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stock held by qualified shareholders not treated as USRPI</header> <subparagraph id="H96385CF047DF4006A552A9B72A8E683C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B)—</text> 
<clause id="HAD6161FBB9874BD9BD34282E80243391"><enum>(i)</enum><text>stock of a real estate investment trust which is held directly by a qualified shareholder shall not be treated as a United States real property interest, and</text></clause> <clause id="HED8C47B5D95342F99A44EA719B92CA92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notwithstanding subsection (h)(1), any distribution to a qualified shareholder shall not be treated as gain recognized from the sale or exchange of a United States real property interest to the extent the stock of the real estate investment trust held by such qualified shareholder is not treated as a United States real property interest under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H737E1AA574714F62B205CDA4A264CA06"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified shareholder with 1 or more applicable investors—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5A6AA2F200C4DE6B1482CE4CE9A5457"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraph (A)(i) shall not apply to so much of the stock of a real estate investment trust held by a qualified shareholder as bears the same ratio to the value of the interests (other than interests held solely as a creditor) held by such applicable investors in the qualified shareholder bears to value of all interests (other than interests held solely as a creditor) in the qualified shareholder, and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E1C4720DEF94F8880522B16CD393E0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a percentage equal to the ratio determined under clause (i) of the amounts realized by the qualified shareholder with respect to any disposition of stock in the real estate investment trust or with respect to any distribution from the real estate investment trust attributable to gain from sales or exchanges of a United States real property interest shall be treated as amounts realized from the disposition of United States real property interests.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H652B2284B13C439796B41B013D371B9C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable investor</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable investor</term> means, with respect to any qualified shareholder holding stock in a real estate investment trust, a person (other than a qualified shareholder) which—</text> 
<clause id="H441767274D3146FA83D2605EEC57E1ED" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>holds an interest (other than an interest solely as a creditor) in such qualified shareholder, and</text></clause> <clause id="H74299EC753F444F2BCF099E499725851" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>holds more than 10 percent of the stock of such real estate investment trust (whether or not by reason of the person's ownership interest in the qualified shareholder).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C8724211D3D46979F2CE7180DADF401" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Constructive ownership rules</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (B)(i) and (C), the constructive ownership rules under subsection (c)(6)(C) shall apply.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H861A45AE542E4659B8DB1A24228CE943"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified shareholder</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDC951563DA50478A970BFEFC64E5EE86"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified shareholder</term> means a foreign person—</text> <clause id="H0805DBA0A41F4F258A11CED01A5FAD4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is eligible for benefits of a comprehensive income tax treaty with the United States which includes an exchange of information program,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDB8E35BC0DA840DFAF18578E73E70CB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is a qualified collective investment vehicle,</text></clause> <clause id="H4BA5DF7F1C10481CAF76D72AFDCDDD82"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the principal class of interests of which is listed and regularly traded on 1 or more recognized stock exchanges (as defined in such comprehensive income tax treaty), and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1CBC2DF7E75141AD8E7BA65C9F2F5A16"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>which maintains records on the identity of each person who, at any time during the foreign person’s taxable year, holds directly 5 percent or more of the class of interest described in clause (iii).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D26433D519B4466BE3358BF974D430C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified collective investment vehicle</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified collective investment vehicle</term> means a foreign person—</text> 
<clause id="H3DF90D5CF6E4404AA24FF07B00B919EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which, under the comprehensive income tax treaty described in subparagraph (A)(i), is eligible for a reduced rate of withholding with respect to ordinary dividends paid by a real estate investment trust even if such person holds more than 10 percent of the stock of such real estate investment trust, or</text></clause> <clause id="H2E2E94A6F18D4E6CABFEAF87FEE5CBDB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is designated as a qualified collective investment vehicle by the Secretary and is either—</text> 
<subclause id="HB891122ADAD548EC9C1E24E203C28E57"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fiscally transparent within the meaning of section 894, or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6C75D3C9B43E4D26B119542AB5AD565A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>required to include dividends in its gross income, but entitled to a deduction for distributions to persons holding interests (other than interests solely as a creditor) in such foreign person.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H99D955ABA9614B8C8B350EB672B461F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H446C930D4BA94D648F9284B32AA17290"><enum>(A)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">Section 897(c)(1)(A)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>or subsection (k)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote> in the matter preceding clause (i).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BE77F9C81714A1F9644C9DA65863AEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/857">Section 857(b)(3)(F)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>or section 897(k)(2)(A)(ii)</quote> after <quote>897(h)(1)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB84AEDC26BD1478BB10764762267A584"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of domestic control</header> 
<paragraph id="H7B3E9A7A59F347A5A537F952481E4141"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Special ownership rules</header> 
<subparagraph id="H443F8DD6EA9A4BB08EC5FB09C8259AF6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">Section 897(h)(4)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31D20AF0A35744B58F735A5EF45DFDDC" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HB1F4976900EF49FB9AE269947B337A36"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Special ownership rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining the holder of stock under subparagraphs (B) and (C)—</text> 
<clause id="H1102E5B4968E465E9331F839F65A1993"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of any class of stock of the qualified investment entity which is regularly traded on an established securities market in the United States, a person holding less than 5 percent of such class of stock at all times during the testing period shall be treated as a United States person unless the qualified investment entity has actual knowledge that such person is not a United States person,</text></clause> <clause id="H085778E4744B4BEFB8A75083FC8B25A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any stock in the qualified investment entity held by another qualified investment entity—</text> 
<subclause id="H147CBB4B414A4434B07F37828BF204A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any class of stock of which is regularly traded on an established securities market, or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H95C4793B0B7C42A29B9242D3D96CBE95"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which is a regulated investment company which issues redeemable securities (within the meaning of section 2 of the Investment Company Act of 1940),</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">shall be treated as held by a foreign person, except that if such other qualified investment entity is domestically controlled (determined after application of this subparagraph), such stock shall be treated as held by a United States person, and</continuation-text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0542DEEAECCE419B8E59CDA5C33AE4CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any stock in the qualified investment entity held by any other qualified investment entity not described in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (ii) shall only be treated as held by a United States person in proportion to the stock of such other qualified investment entity which is (or is treated under clause (ii) or (iii) as) held by a United States person.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC69DD7DBD324161A3609DE455C3817D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The heading for paragraph (4) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">section 897(h)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">and special rules</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Definitions</header-in-text></quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F14B2A74F784FF4A51120C3F6900747"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Clause (ii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">section 897(h)(4)(A)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>and for purposes of determining whether a real estate investment trust is a domestically controlled qualified investment entity under this subsection</quote> after <quote>real estate investment trust</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H960DE179FD644B15B08712BDC96B1294"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <paragraph id="H6639FAAABF3040BDA5A8518EA5D2CB4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of enactment and shall apply to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6C32EFB2F8AE47CBA0777C4634B7BF1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any disposition on and after the date of the enactment of this Act, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C360FBE57BF4F8CA18B3E540A0C1652"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any distribution by a real estate investment trust on or after the date of the enactment of this Act which is treated as a deduction for a taxable year of such trust ending after such date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC80638EA3854EF6B7E7A603384C7889"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of domestic control</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (b)(1) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0410B9C71D5B4F6AB4E4F4D254A0C580"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (b)(2) shall take effect on January 1, 2015.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6906AEFCAC0043D1B9F901A1B5D763D0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exception for interests held by foreign retirement or pension funds</header> 
<subsection id="H8822D133B86A4F53AE72DC66F8F31836"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 897, as amended by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/2">section 2,</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7A44C6EEE1D2473A873222B333E676FD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H3F4337043CD8461BA21DE66D3D45747F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Exception for interests held by foreign pension funds</header> <paragraph id="H8FE4269E18E841A4957D5DB4C54090E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall not apply to any United States real property interest held by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6116CF3A635D4B0B974F90021B0D8430"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a qualified foreign pension fund, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD165CB117FC4075B81D3B7047A07085"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any entity all of the interests of which are held by a qualified foreign pension fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76B70FBB88E94272A727BFAF4AFD1148"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified foreign pension fund</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>qualified foreign pension fund</quote> means any trust, corporation, or other organization or arrangement—</text> <subparagraph id="H6F7C0CD3783D4CF1BCC9A0878DA5359B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is created or organized under the law of a country other than the United States,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA436A20E51FC4E74B507D062C9E3348D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is established to provide retirement or pension benefits to participants or beneficiaries that are current or former employees (or persons designated by such employees) of one or more employers in consideration for services rendered,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53EEDAF92AD141FCB909B63556C33531"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which does not have a single participant or beneficiary with a right to more than five percent of its assets or income,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00F0AF116ED84933B555380C22C7BCBC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>which is subject to government regulation and provides annual information reporting about its beneficiaries to the relevant tax authorities in the country in which it is established or operates, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1A1B13EC1C84302B8F08891E0404B36"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with respect to which, under the laws of the country in which it is established or operates—</text> 
<clause id="H77AA45AB48FE49D9A787D7AEC42A6692"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contributions to such trust, corporation, organization, or arrangement which would otherwise be subject to tax under such laws are deductible or excluded from the gross income of such entity or taxed at a reduced rate, or</text></clause> <clause id="HF59F41ABA7D149CEBE09F52F67F8283F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>taxation of any investment income of such trust, corporation, organization or arrangement is deferred or such income is taxed at a reduced rate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5088B0EE1041419EB814D8B765E91366"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H146B2205C38E4E299831E1D3978E4BE7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption from withholding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1445">Section 1445(f)(3)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>any person</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HED89B76EBFEE47D788910BF3285FBAD6" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person other than—</text> <subparagraph id="H833E8C72298B42C9AC2105A5EC1A162E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a United States person, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF22535FADC884709966FC49FF98C4E8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, an entity with respect to which section 897 does not apply by reason of subsection (l) thereof.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="HAFF92E91FAAC4C71B2426CA855D3BC36"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to dispositions and distributions after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


