<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5FDA0C844BAD406DA40B1F49D2F80CB7" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3289 IH: Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3289</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prevent the waste of gas produced under oil and gas leases on Federal land and to collect
			 royalty on all gas production.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA2EE1C3C98B246CCA5B9C747E81AF7E3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF81163401906426B8A8A754C0797E925" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD1F28A9725494E6094D452071D6E6404"><enum>2.</enum><header>Gas waste reduction and enhancement of gas measuring and reporting</header> <subsection id="HBF86B49BAA0144CB899B6BCBEF57EAB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1711">30 U.S.C. 1711 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H1CA874AA23094E47BBA5CD8A96B039E9" style="OLC">
					<section id="H06D60D2EF95843B395E353D7A8350273"><enum>118.</enum><header>Gas waste reduction and enhancement of gas measuring and reporting</header>
						<subsection id="HF30C994293754C4793F6AF314E313219"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules for preventing and reducing waste of gas via venting, flaring, and fugitive releases</header>
 <paragraph id="HEC2BA285CCFC406D9120D6686F73013E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to issue rules</header><text>The Secretary shall issue rules that establish requirements for reducing and preventing the waste of gas, including by venting, flaring, and fugitive releases, from covered operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H598C11596A2D4603A808E67ACE2C098E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content of rules</header><text>The rules shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H20D7544D6EC14D33A8B90E70046CC84D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require that 99 percent of all gas produced that is subject to a mineral leasing law be captured annually within 5 years of enactment of the <short-title>Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act</short-title>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H172E10213377466D828F2F794BA71341"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require flaring of gas, rather than venting, in all instances in which gas capture is not viable;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C6BA52C27E24251A3CCC7F5B0F67091"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require that every application for a permit to drill a production well—</text>
 <clause id="H821EB0AC8A7545DC8843A5B2050C3BBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrate sufficient infrastructure is in place to capture produced gas; and</text> </clause><clause id="H12581E6349944DA68E198FD7A81FB358"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be subject to public comments for a period of 30 days;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B89A12E1A0443479F05C207279EAB97"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prohibit all new wells from flaring, within 2 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act</short-title>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E4682B5AE4D43DC9B0BFB0A9AA1E2AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the operator of any covered operation that routinely flares gas before the effective date of the prohibition under subparagraph (D) to submit a gas capture plan to the Secretary no later than 6 months after such effective date that ensures the requirement in subparagraph (A) will be met;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D5A4D8F52124B9DBAA9CA38F9880789"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the operator of any covered operation that routinely flares gas before the effective date of the prohibition under subparagraph (D) to demonstrate a yearly decrease in the amount of gas flared, as a fraction of gas produced, to meet the requirement under subparagraph (A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58F90F409C5042878DD60D816A375C0E"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set performance standards based on modern equipment, to be updated every 5 years, that minimize gas loss from—</text>
 <clause id="H657F92B53002403D95B55E405459C48B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>storage tanks;</text> </clause><clause id="H590F8394ADB24FB5AAA497F95EB4B6D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>dehydrators;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3E90DF7E46AC4CA2A6143B5E05A95186"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>compressors;</text> </clause><clause id="H7EB657591E51405EBF073EC404E8BA0E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>open-ended valves or lines;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF932DE92B5E14F06948A036B38AFB377"><enum>(v)</enum><text>pumps; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0B1E1090673D40AAB1CFE29E64371ABD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other equipment for which the Secretary considers such standards are necessary;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49F4E47596F24975944E9D61BCC55F66"><enum>(H)</enum><text>require the replacement of all high-bleed gas-actuated pneumatic devices with low-bleed or no-bleed devices;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36D94FBC94C4469F926E0A4BF56FAAE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set performance standards based on modern procedures and equipment, to be updated every 5 years, that minimize gas loss from—</text>
 <clause id="H530A8792120343D886A6EE0A32D53A1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>downhole maintenance;</text> </clause><clause id="HCAB73212B9094FB997295342950287D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>liquids unloading;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H370CF9CE22F844B28A4BDAC3E2112F75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>well completion; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0E3D87B897CF4EE99FBD430B8A685DFD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other procedures for which the Secretary considers such standards are necessary;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H068279E211324C6AAE6D36F8BAB80F66"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require all operators to have regularly scheduled leak detection programs that assess the entire covered operation using an infrared camera or other equipment with equivalent sensitivity and the ability to survey similarly large areas;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD48FBE54AC2E4143BE7661F49A3EC442"><enum>(K)</enum><text>require any leaks found during leak detection programs required under subparagraph (J), or otherwise, to be repaired within 2 weeks; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC50D0BEC86F4BCA8F320C1C35E4BB66"><enum>(L)</enum><text>require recordkeeping for—</text> <clause id="HD8D370F04AB34DF287A0F617702AB1C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>equipment maintenance;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H334A6DC36E6D4BD280F7045718153130"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>leak detection and repair;</text> </clause><clause id="HD5E22DEBCB624931A86E8800D8226ACD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>venting events;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H53545C9D85ED41158E9C54B29E5D54FD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>flaring events; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2C00BFA719F84604A3A77078717AEA54"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other operations for which the Secretary considers such requirements are necessary.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE106D66BDB2B4DD7A49357674E23CFB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gas measuring, reporting, and transparency requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H0A477CA44DCC4673B7B74E547D1E1067"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, in accordance with this subsection, establish new requirements for measuring and reporting the production and disposition of all gas subject to the mineral leasing laws to allow for more accurate accounting of all such gas that is consumed or lost by venting and flaring, and of fugitive releases of such gas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62A4D23C42FD4AD79344ECC39EEE57E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Measuring and reporting requirements</header><text>To account for all gas referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall issue rules requiring oil or gas operators to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB18063FEE95A42B4A5ECFE6593EA1DBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>measure all production and disposition of gas with such accuracy that fugitive gas releases can be calculated;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H759BFC7AEEB541A5917329B11F625C45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>install metering devices to measure all vented and flared gas; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0442B5E4F174C8094452435E0A48F52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>report to the Secretary the volumes of gas measured under the requirements under subparagraph (A), including—</text>
 <clause id="H4F0696D6B66F4760BA4AC3FEC2333ECE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all new measured values for production and disposition, including vented and flared volumes; and</text> </clause><clause id="H261C6187AD2A4E61B4772FA60AD721B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fugitive releases based on guidelines for their calculation established by the Secretary in the rule.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB5EC75C5DEE4900A471F1CB22967E8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>The Secretary shall make all new data produced under the requirements established by the Secretary under this subsection, including calculated fugitive releases and volumes of gas lost to venting and flaring, publicly available through the Internet—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEB3AD7AE24F1402DA3911114C91AE83E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>without a fee or other access charge;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEF7EB86C54A4CBEA6D953B66A3BA473"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a searchable, sortable, and downloadable manner, to the extent technically possible; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E44F8EDD6264F06A6A3E63B197E8BFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as soon as technically practicable after the report by the operator is filed.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC059B61560A2463CA5B7054B8B687E40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Except as otherwise specified in this section, the requirements established by the Secretary under this section shall apply to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H27BA48628FD645FBAC965E4D1A53F407"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the construction and operation of any covered operation initiated after the date of the issuance of rules under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E2489CBCD25470F80B005628DD74DA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date of the issuance of such rules, any covered operation initiated before the date of the issuance of such rules.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9073B506208F4CFFB763672B0070845C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement Mechanisms</header>
 <paragraph id="H656B8D9894A440469B9A895B9F2DC612"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall include in the rules issued under this section consistent enforcement mechanisms for covered operations that are not in compliance with the requirements established by the rules.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA4A8D7BFA49483F9316790C2A2CCF97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The enforcement mechanisms under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H1CF388E0643B4228BDF82C545CFD7067"><enum>(A)</enum><text>civil penalties for unauthorized venting and flaring, which shall—</text>
 <clause id="H1FA23D3D20794242B3BC9B779B783B21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>apply in lieu of the penalties under section 109; and</text> </clause><clause id="HAAEAE8A7E6AB44FFB145FBE1653FA077"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include production restrictions and civil monetary penalties equivalent to 3 times the market value of the vented or flared gas; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29D33D440A134D53B643F8DC9497AB84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>civil penalties that apply to noncompliance with other new or existing procedures, which shall—</text> <clause id="H6195AC988E7D479A828DE73A032CAC35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>apply in addition to or in lieu of the penalties under section 109;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H125B85C3192E4A83AD631763D286CDFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include production restrictions or monetary penalties, or both; and</text> </clause><clause id="H1FFEA55B68224C8C81F2F280CABF0E69"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of monetary penalties, be proportional to market conditions.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAD14AD6F8404F2895C714EE1E0CE09E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2C6F81D76FBB4FFF8FF137F1D3A77BCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered operations</quote> means all oil and gas operations that are subject to mineral leasing law or title V of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1761">30 U.S.C. 1761 et seq.</external-xref>), regardless of size, including production, storage, gathering, processing, and handling operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F5CD69CD2DE4D4FA70CE7462091C2E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flare and flaring</header><text>The term <quote>flaring</quote> means the intentional and controlled burning of gas that occurs in the course of oil and gas operations to limit release of gas to the atmosphere.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70C0286ADD134B4DA348381B46646F25"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fugitive release</header><text>The term <quote>fugitive release</quote> means the unintentional and uncontrolled release of gas into the atmosphere in the course of oil and gas operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC45F1ECC6CD64229A2F83810A27A676B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gas capture plan</header><text>The term <quote>gas capture plan</quote> means a plan that includes specific goals, including equipment and timelines, for capturing, gathering, and processing gas produced under an oil or gas lease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5727A35A079247A39A287128C0989587"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gas release</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>gas release</quote> includes all gas that is discharged to the atmosphere via venting or fugitive release.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CAFF9B0BD314B438D899DB628AE2598"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Vent and venting</header><text>The term <quote>venting</quote> means the intentional and controlled release of gas into the atmosphere in the course of oil and gas operations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H37F7526646E04B40A82DA7FD92034366"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1 of that Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title I the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C62193C06DA4426BE63E8D8C4CA0F3F" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H1CA874AA23094E47BBA5CD8A96B039E9" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H06D60D2EF95843B395E353D7A8350273" level="section">Sec. 118. Gas waste reduction and enhancement of gas measuring and reporting.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC54D4D420E94E43A75663FAEB336F39"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall issue rules required by the amendments made by this section by not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1810B5873C4C40458594BE6D724C137D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assessment of venting, flaring, and fugitive releases</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date the Secretary of the Interior first receives data submitted under the requirements established under subsection (b) of section 118 of the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982, as amended by this section, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA94E7B3219734CF697DD06E05063C51F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit a report to Congress describing—</text> <subparagraph id="H4FE6A4FAE331427BBAD123EAA183ADBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the volume of fugitive releases, and gas consumed or lost by venting and flaring, from covered operations (as those terms are used in such section);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFB13FA2E31242D088759C7A734655DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional rules the Secretary considers necessary to further curtail venting, flaring, and fugitive releases, or the rational basis for not issuing new rules if the Secretary considers new rules are not necessary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C86A869508245D191E5957FE1B05C8A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for new statutory authority necessary to limit venting, flaring, or fugitive releases; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAADBD57F66764B82A08563DF4A65B5E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue rules described in the report under paragraph (1)(B) within 1 year after the date of the submission of the report.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H873525341F3844129766C6814DAFC546"><enum>3.</enum><header>Royalty collection for all gas produced on federal lands</header>
			<subsection id="HFFAE535C177D4D5095224F89E8943170"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment on all production</header>
 <paragraph id="H4568ECD9057D415EA680005B94EC97A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), royalties otherwise authorized or required under the mineral leasing laws (as that term is defined in the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1701">30 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>)) to be paid for gas shall be assessed on all gas produced under the mineral leasing laws, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA9C9FD59F07E4F8DBECCDD1CBC9B97AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gas used or consumed within the area of the lease tract for the benefit of the lease (commonly referred to as <quote>beneficial use gas</quote>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AEFBEF07DA3419CA9FF1C646B4A1362"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all gas that is consumed or lost by venting, flaring, or fugitive releases through any equipment during upstream operations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H652BD944546A4061BEC6953AC266F7EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="HDD086E6EE82A41E78F31678FBD09FA1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gas vented or flared in an acute emergency situation that poses danger to human health that occurs for no longer than 48 hours; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0D388FD619248569088260512A1B20F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>gas injected into the ground on a lease tract in order to enhance production of an oil or gas well or for some other purpose.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB752F251FD9F4A27A067D1D6B19B95FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H9F3F07513B134984910C91BA1CABE31A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mineral Leasing Act</header><text>The Mineral Leasing Act is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HB00D8B3E0E154226969A49191ED93802"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 14 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/223">30 U.S.C. 223</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following: <quote>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act (including this section), royalty shall be assessed with respect to oil and gas, other than gas described in section 3(a)(2) of the <short-title>Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act</short-title>, without regard to whether oil or gas is removed or sold from the leased land.</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H963E913093BE45778310C5E62EDC8ABA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 17 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/226">30 U.S.C. 226</external-xref>), by striking <quote>removed or sold</quote> each place it appears;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A78A77E2B484A6888CFFAE155B05C71"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 18 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/226">30 U.S.C. 226</external-xref>), by striking <quote>except oil or gas used for production purposes on the claim, or unavoidably lost</quote> each place it appears;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD952F03715854366B9BD9851EF17A9C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in section 19 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/226">30 U.S.C. 226</external-xref>), by striking <quote>except oil or gas used for production purposes on the claim, or unavoidably lost</quote> each place it appears;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61F05C6F1D89490083FCF6BD81B4F8AA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in section 22 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/251">30 U.S.C. 251</external-xref>), by striking <quote>sold or removed</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34D5FB6CB9A64F3DB4033DCE13B9FA08"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in section 31 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/188">30 U.S.C. 188</external-xref>), by striking <quote>removed or sold</quote> each place it appears.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF664B50F71F342A8ADFC818E60075D6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outer continental shelf lands act</header><text>The Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE3EAF55DD21C44CB90C38E32535C7681"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 6(a)(8) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1335">43 U.S.C. 1335(a)(8)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>saved, removed, or sold</quote> each place it appears; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3FB0FDC3CC844F9B22A40F262BF538A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 8(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(a)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <clause id="H0BF5FD42E6644799BFD47383C859F96F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>saved, removed, or sold</quote> each place it appears; and</text> </clause><clause id="H26A2AE3FAAAA44CA9D46C839563ADB22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block id="H89B88CCAE9154271800661C8147BB104" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H7520DD01ED01483FA6D2E44DD1E45C8D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act (including this section), royalty under this Act shall be assessed with respect to oil and gas, other than gas described in section 3(a)(2) of the <short-title>Natural Gas Environmental and Economic Security Act</short-title>, without regard to whether oil or gas is removed or sold from the leased land.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA298F15D0747499585003D86AC295DAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply only with respect to leases issued on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


