<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H72D76541A2C54DEA9383E3EEFD955147" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1706 IH: Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1706</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the overall health and well-being of young people, including the promotion of
			 comprehensive sexual health and healthy relationships, the reduction of
			 unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections (STIs), including
			 HIV, and the prevention of dating violence and sexual assault, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5E24AC6F548F453FB8DEEE0A320E6F20" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0AEC105E4C2944BE8DBE22123AD9086C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4AF1167FB64D49D3BBFB8A305C120346"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes; sense of congress</header> <subsection id="H412DB552A7694ABCA4A8BDD691646040"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are to provide young people with comprehensive sex education programs that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H897CB9A1716E44A2994798E414E71F5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide the information and skills all young people need to make informed, responsible, and healthy decisions in order to become sexually healthy adults and have healthy relationships;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H708F623B65FC44A7AC9B24C9030B6594"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide information about the prevention of unintended pregnancy, sexually transmitted infections (including HIV), dating violence, sexual assault, bullying, and harassment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FE6D3A55DFD46B7B06314C03F8D07C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote and uphold the rights of young people to information in order to make healthy and responsible decisions about their sexual health.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAFFA1C3191514E0AA7964E809DCABBED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Finding on required resources</header><text>In order to provide the comprehensive sex education described in subsection (a), the Congress finds that increased resources are required for sex education programs that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF552E2277C1044FDAB90E4B80F02679C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are evidence-based, having been proven through rigorous evaluation to change sexual behavior or incorporate characteristics of effective programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16936B7DEF2C4A0FAEAA5485F7FC9C99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cover a broad range of topics, including medically accurate, complete, age and developmentally appropriate information about all the aspects of sex needed for a complete sex education program, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE9B0241A6AA34A279B8BFF6DC014DB5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>anatomy and physiology;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D85518EADC34AD793E8153C963B3309"><enum>(B)</enum><text>growth and development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FE51FDB0FA94863B32A1A5C82EA49E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>healthy relationships;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC41FA7C5325E42EF97AB9FC02F1E8500"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the prevention of unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections (STIs), including HIV, through abstinence and contraception;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7AB6A8CD938466FBD9B7AB95FDA77DF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>gender, gender identity, and sexual orientation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8610A8E15AA7446C902DBDC4464741E7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>protection from dating violence, sexual assault, bullying, and harassment;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED4B69FF74A443D1BEAF9485D55029F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are gender and gender identity-sensitive, emphasizing the importance of equality and the social environment for achieving sexual and reproductive health and overall well-being;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84576314E8984E7D96F1ABA3446CF59B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote educational achievement, critical thinking, decisionmaking, self-esteem, and self-efficacy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H221C03AEF6B14914B047633864A7A6F0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>help develop healthy attitudes and insights necessary for understanding relationships between oneself and others and society;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA7422E01CF04FEE9A56DCEAE6910E96"><enum>(6)</enum><text>foster leadership skills and community engagement by—</text> <subparagraph id="H4F14BAD566F64E5E80FD4034072D5F31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promoting principles of fairness, human dignity, and respect; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC4B284EBB2D4643ACD70C9142D133C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engaging young people as partners in their communities; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H192CD32F104646799F1BADD74D55FE44"><enum>(7)</enum><text>are culturally and linguistically appropriate, reflecting the diverse circumstances and realities of young people.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCCD55150D3B47ADBA2EB285B78A09FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HDB9F7FE4C99449CD83CB2B2BC42141B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>federally funded sex education programs should aim to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5FCA8150BDB84B4AA4C3D66EBAC721EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide information about a range of human sexuality topics, including human development, relationships, personal skills, and sexual behavior data including abstinence, sexual health, and society and culture;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H425816D95EC74C3E8B500BA79E07D72A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote safe and healthy relationships;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCC91EE91E374BFFBEB006986C5148FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduce unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections, including HIV;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCEAD02EF6C94760B19F716A897A2564"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promote gender equality;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H924A5B82874942899D53B6B37E23565E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>use, and be informed by, the best scientific information available;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC2E15DE8CFC4A8CA2656D27B17C69CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>be built on characteristics of effective programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84DFAB86CB4A4D3B99A6D48E968A1C82"><enum>(G)</enum><text>be culturally competent and inclusive of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and questioning (LGBTQ) youth;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E78DD27995C433BB0F3E2C5D3F4D60A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>expand the existing body of evidence on comprehensive sex education programs through program evaluation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7B76E6426234290ABC130B3EDFA2832"><enum>(I)</enum><text>expand training programs for teachers of comprehensive sex education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F37AA9655184B33B93557B125941A25"><enum>(J)</enum><text>build on the personal responsibility education programs funded under section 513 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/713">42 U.S.C. 713</external-xref>) and the President’s Teen Pregnancy Prevention program, funded under title II of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 3253), and on programs supported through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8106903699404ACDBD1AC215296D7F12"><enum>(K)</enum><text>promote and uphold the rights of young people to information in order to make healthy and responsible decisions about their sexual health; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H789904DE1F214DFA98F7C6B93E7F563E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no Federal funds should be used for health education programs that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE192A5EC2E4C49959CEFA76D6AAE1A9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withhold health promoting or life-saving information about sexuality-related topics or HIV;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CD76D8E231F4FF79E8AB5CD4CB22152"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are medically inaccurate or have been scientifically shown to be ineffective;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H242DFA4DCE7E435FB4EB6F53C401DFB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote gender stereotypes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7810875E7C5A49E4AB3BF18FF8986F7E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of sexually active adolescents;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36BB24BA8432468588682B84F18D3995"><enum>(E)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of survivors of sexual abuse or assault;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A93213AC84C42C4A7B9B8532C5080B7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of LGBTQ youth; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF41243272163464CA59F75FCD44C62A0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>are inconsistent with the ethical imperatives of medicine and public health.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC6C2D04A61E24C5C94802EDBE7097A7F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for comprehensive sex education for adolescents</header>
 <subsection id="HE98D5C0BD9354CDEA069A671A693DDBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Adolescent Health and the Associate Commissioner of the Family and Youth Services Bureau of the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities to carry out programs that provide adolescents with comprehensive sex education, as described in subsection (f).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H865FA31185D84F5AAC401817689E9AC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF5C63B2B87DA4D0CA02F26267C144905"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means a public or private entity that focuses on adolescent health or education or has experience working with adolescents, which may include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFC94DEC1EF134DE3998A27D6D3E1B773"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State educational agency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8D4D1972BCB400796EF7C087827080F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC14D7A46E4C74447BA3EE44CD9A59602"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a tribe or tribal organization, as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H597C2FECF8794AF09EA01EB39F4EE26E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a State or local department of health;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7788B7A30A67479F8925122A02DEB744"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a State or local department of education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73E41DB5D36946A9A66398E4C0DA3ADC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H62B6DBE787D14F5CA1BDBCE18397D85D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a nonprofit or public institution of higher education; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CDBC23E031240E8BEB623099BEBA808"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a hospital.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BF42210ADC94326A1910CAD85CC8A47"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including the evaluation plan described in subsection (g)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD58F12EE99B748CB9E573D0B6AA7204C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <paragraph id="H094D52CDA9F1425B8051E4550F023528"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are State or local public entities, with an additional priority for State or local educational agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H725C369903E0477699907CAE605BB33E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are entities not currently receiving funds under—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4585542F42C42DFAE0792023F7FF902"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 513 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/713">42 U.S.C. 713</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C5134C19E834D2FB22E8968EC3BD204"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the President’s Teen Pregnancy Prevention program, funded under title II of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 3253); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3A09F0DD30D461B8B67F71530BA3202"><enum>(C)</enum><text>programs supported through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E34AE7CA7F74639AABED4B1AB7676DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>address health disparities among young people that are at highest risk for not less than 1 of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3F14CBBBF93F4423AF106059CA1140A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Unintended pregnancies.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H656007921EDF4108B568C20757C6EC9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Sexually transmitted infections, including HIV.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0D5278A05FC430C8179D257BB378E70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Dating violence and sexual assault.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F6465CDFAA5463BAC92EB98DACC169C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="H8DAD0604EB274181A6F6D8CA8D780A9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use grant funds to carry out a program that provides adolescents with comprehensive sex education that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB7B31A9C989A4BFA945F24728D356F4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>replicates evidence-based sex education programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B9B1E8553724A99A23D394BACCC51B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>substantially incorporates elements of evidence-based sex education programs; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9C913E7FA6D43DBA03BF4B1FCE70588"><enum>(C)</enum><text>creates a demonstration project based on generally accepted characteristics of effective sex education programs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA54D83F06B094E3F9AE2B2354CB3DE01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of sex education programs</header><text>The sex education programs funded under this section shall include curricula and program materials that address—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA7CDABB5E7EA4F2D8B3302BAA0BD59C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>abstinence and delaying sexual initiation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D941D707A8C42FF9758283C1B13F549"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the health benefits and side effects of all contraceptive and barrier methods as a means to prevent pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections, including HIV;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBB97AA021DB45D1A8292CC550C2CCDE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>healthy relationships, including the development of healthy attitudes and skills necessary for understanding—</text>
 <clause id="H097CE0DC09B946758F0828B1EC8B96B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>healthy relationships between oneself and family, others, and society; and</text> </clause><clause id="HDAFAC4AEA992462CB8C00C0E3F705D73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the prevention of sexual abuse, teen dating violence, bullying, harassment, and suicide;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB6BA3F8EEE3472F8F1BDE5BC4AEBF80"><enum>(D)</enum><text>healthy life skills including goal-setting, decisionmaking, interpersonal skills (such as communication, assertiveness, and peer refusal skills), critical thinking, self-esteem and self-efficacy, and stress management;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AE01521B2C64796AC13B5C63140471F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how to make responsible decisions about sex and sexuality, including—</text> <clause id="H7412810495DA405DB31F3A604FED566C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how to avoid, and how to avoid making, unwanted verbal, physical, and sexual advances; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5007F3DCAFE541E4B5FED3C1F22797DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how alcohol and drug use can affect responsible decisionmaking;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H456C83F1F06D4D30863879C0484EB5A1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the development of healthy attitudes and values about such topics as adolescent growth and development, body image, gender roles and gender identity, racial and ethnic diversity, and sexual orientation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD93A91258ECD49E0B7BCECC49686659F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>referral services for local health clinics and services where adolescents can obtain additional information and services related to sexual and reproductive health, dating violence and sexual assault, and suicide prevention.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BA236CF663C401587C61C740053CD85"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation; report</header>
 <paragraph id="H7644875A0E424F0BBC897B96E22D6798"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Independent evaluation</header><text>Each eligible entity applying for a grant under this section shall develop and submit to the Secretary a plan for a rigorous independent evaluation of such grant program. The plan shall describe an independent evaluation that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9A3697AB555F4DB89C180509EE89EEF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses sound statistical methods and techniques relating to the behavioral sciences, including random assignment methodologies, whenever possible;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69ED5650BD4D45149949F5A66ACF45A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uses quantitative data for assessments and impact evaluations, whenever possible; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45FC4D7EF78140F882C662923927CC58"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is carried out by an entity independent from such eligible entity.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H949B6E4980A547258866B554ADA09B74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of evaluated programs; budget</header>
 <subparagraph id="H92565FFF656F4D7C85296E7A5B1A53F6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Selection of evaluated programs</header><text>The Secretary shall choose, at random, a subset of the eligible entities that the Secretary has selected to receive a grant under this section to receive additional funding to carry out the evaluation plan described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29E1778FC1754B709AC4ADE123FBCA7D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Budget for evaluation activities</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Adolescent Health, shall establish a budget for each eligible entity selected under subparagraph (A) for the costs of carrying out the evaluation plan described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF73EBCD55133457DBEF10470DD5C7106"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funds for evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall provide eligible entities who are selected under paragraph (2)(A) with additional funds, in accordance with the budget described in paragraph (2)(B), to carry out and report to the Secretary on the evaluation plan described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EC3CE567C154D5EB4FE051AC7592100"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Performance measures</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall establish a common set of performance measures to assess the implementation and impact of grant programs funded under this section. Such performance measures shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4FD06C5BB1704C1DA8956D8599891C63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>output measures, such as the number of individuals served and the number of hours of service delivery; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC23B4D92CF8E4F81B02F34A5A6A3A5C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>outcome measures, including measures relating to—</text> <clause id="H7970B1F417044065A66E4BC8B40F41E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the knowledge that youth participating in the grant program have gained about—</text>
 <subclause id="HE707FBD248614C8F8CAD0B161327C538"><enum>(I)</enum><text>adolescent growth and development;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HED22A219A4314D04AD747AD2110EEB13"><enum>(II)</enum><text>relationship dynamics;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3702489686D84667B5E6FF09753D0E13"><enum>(III)</enum><text>ways to prevent unintended pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections, including HIV; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H1AF79633E3AA4B5A8B7D8C34FF1632E8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>sexual health;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H5A61DDB2A7DC43DBA8F106AD95414B57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the skills that adolescents participating in the grant program have gained regarding—</text> <subclause id="H56F96D9CC091468880DC0CAE47D3B387"><enum>(I)</enum><text>negotiation and communication;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF2514C64E23146198A41866AACFE4BFF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>decisionmaking and goal-setting;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD096423462A44316966021B8323430D4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>interpersonal skills and healthy relationships; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD061A66FF3F5427F83A87DC0C3594C2B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>condom use; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HBBEAB525F65D4782B8D29C95CDE8D0AB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the behaviors of adolescents participating in the grant program, including data about—</text>
 <subclause id="HD7B394462CB94FF09D7C5A970EDF2E96"><enum>(I)</enum><text>age of first intercourse;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H3D469FBBFE67407CAC139EA3D7F3EA29"><enum>(II)</enum><text>number of sexual partners;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6ADB01104E654FD4B8A943F907486BA8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>condom and contraceptive use at first intercourse;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF6C41E7429274716AF3B480101261882"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>recent condom and contraceptive use; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5B853F2B4D7B46A8A204AD3FE08267C8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>dating abuse and lifetime history of intimate partner violence (IPV), sexual assault, dating violence, bullying, harassment, and stalking.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7326768EC7E2427FA194C5F8D541D6C4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report to the secretary</header><text>Eligible entities receiving a grant under this section who have been selected to receive funds to carry out the evaluation plan described in paragraph (1), in accordance with paragraph (2)(A), shall collect and report to the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4DAC8CA030554410B74B8A6B8F600D82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the independent evaluation described in paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FBB822F0D174DFAB0EC85088B6A3113"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information about the performance measures described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74881E94918A4BE6ABDC0BB9DF202302"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Effective programs</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall publish on the website of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, a list of programs funded under this section that the Secretary has determined to be effective programs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H224A7701BD4B468FA0F3FDA327A517E1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants for comprehensive sex education at institutions of higher education</header>
 <subsection id="H6628511E333543B98E5DC229F203E130"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Office of Adolescent Health, the Associate Commissioner of the Family and Youth Services Bureau of the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education to enable such institutions to provide young people with comprehensive sex education, described in subsection (e)(2), with an emphasis on reducing HIV, other sexually transmitted infections, and unintended pregnancy through instruction about—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA690F60AB032407399A85B11E969A28E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>abstinence and contraception;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H53F74F05B2094222A5EEDAF9E11B02EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reducing dating violence, sexual assault, bullying, and harassment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52F964201A8543BBA4DF4E7668D9B28E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increasing healthy relationships; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBA68322D42542379812C61917CA1B17"><enum>(4)</enum><text>academic achievement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H698D2585A7934A718F363F02030FA18E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H0C5E6AE71F9840B38ADE583152198FA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An institution of higher education desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAFFB1B0391BA4D54A2B441EC623BDC83"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an institution of higher education that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4F7726BE2E6745F7B0B6D30A49EFE0B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has an enrollment of needy students as defined in section 318(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059e">20 U.S.C. 1059e(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE6A515570E44B69A18C318C54C3FFC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is a Hispanic-serving institution, as defined in section 502(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2610BB6220FF4060AD8970A0EEC62586"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is a Tribal College or University, as defined in section 316(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAC1C17071AB48BBBC093B311F014283"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is an Alaska Native-serving institution, as defined in section 317(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C85C5A3BE9B469699F077048A30D108"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is a Native Hawaiian-serving institution, as defined in section 317(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE544287D9B704059B0752BC19C1EE700"><enum>(6)</enum><text>is a Predominately Black Institution, as defined in section 318(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059e">20 U.S.C. 1059e(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBA4E138DAC5411BA0A4126D34188BF4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>is a Native American-serving, nontribal institution, as defined in section 319(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059f">20 U.S.C. 1059f(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD965276CFA7A4999A48F02EB1209623E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>is an Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution, as defined in section 320(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059g">20 U.S.C. 1059g(b)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98E5637DE8124233A694171EE8057202"><enum>(9)</enum><text>is a minority institution, as defined in section 365 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067k">20 U.S.C. 1067k</external-xref>), with an enrollment of needy students, as defined in section 312 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9C0932974E54A6D8163951C8CE817CC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H6E1832F20211462A9A667449D0AF9DDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An institution of higher education receiving a grant under this section may use grant funds to integrate issues relating to comprehensive sex education into the academic or support sectors of the institution of higher education in order to reach a large number of students, by carrying out 1 or more of the following activities:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF6D3E23EF45345788ED17CE403756CC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Developing educational content for issues relating to comprehensive sex education that will be incorporated into student orientation, general education, or core courses.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89E3F63D0EFF47A084997B35F8A2CB73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Developing and employing school-wide educational programming outside of class that delivers elements of comprehensive sex education programs to students, faculty, and staff.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95682CF0884F47689EC2DD841A31BC84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Creating innovative technology-based approaches to deliver sex education to students, faculty, and staff.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H839E69EACF0546C6A352574AAB1934AE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Developing and employing peer-outreach and education programs to generate discussion, educate, and raise awareness among students about issues relating to comprehensive sex education.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DA4C67A08044DF89E7D7DC1ED0E8899"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of sex education programs</header><text>Each institution of higher education’s program of comprehensive sex education funded under this section shall include curricula and program materials that address information about—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2FFDD77C30F449B6B0C6A1F1EDD58C20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>safe and responsible sexual behavior with respect to the prevention of pregnancy and sexually transmitted infections, including HIV, in addition to the teachings of—</text>
 <clause id="HF02B2461E9D64D47BBDA30C10CB05ACB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>abstinence;</text> </clause><clause id="H3D048A88AF6049419DACF59630F9CFC9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a reduced number of sexual partners; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEBDAFC129948425C9F5F8596912C87CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the use of condoms and contraception;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4260761A30F14C8DB802315C5EDE157E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>healthy relationships, including the development of healthy attitudes and insights necessary for understanding—</text>
 <clause id="H62CF8BF524044101AB7BB1E4FE768E63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relationships between oneself, family, partners, others, and society; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD9F42AB08C0148C99BE338342053A2B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the prevention of sexual abuse, dating violence, bullying, harassment, and suicide; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H525C54DB7A30439ABC62C1920630429E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>referral services to local health clinics where young people can obtain additional information and services related to sexual and reproductive health, dating violence and sexual assault, and suicide prevention.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D78AF613BCD42D885B425F3CC7F20BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Optional components of sex education</header><text>Each institution of higher education’s program of comprehensive sex education may also include information and skills development relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03CAF6B0FCDE4DD685CD7FF09F3C6F07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how to make responsible decisions about sex and sexuality, including—</text> <clause id="H14B020223D824AE0A22643EE5924C634"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how to avoid, and avoid making, unwanted verbal, physical, and sexual advances; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE8490834A9C54AB996D5DD493BFD3B66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how alcohol and drug use can affect responsible decisionmaking;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52B4895B0DF242D09A6E9C5D415BF449"><enum>(B)</enum><text>healthy life skills, including—</text>
 <clause id="H2CD45BD3BF734E279300A1E1C761C962"><enum>(i)</enum><text>goal-setting and decisionmaking;</text> </clause><clause id="HD57808AE71B14A62BB1BD45467FDDA26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>interpersonal skills, such as communication, assertiveness, and peer refusal skills;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5EFB327FA7DA44B48FA5EFC606B15188"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>critical thinking;</text> </clause><clause id="HB23A789152AA4C68AAD9FE44B3CCFE99"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>self-esteem and self-efficacy; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H600319CBCABD45CC9E96C227D1F6FBB0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>stress management;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H440EF37A505A40A2A80FB6656D50DC35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the development of healthy attitudes and values about such topics as body image, gender roles and gender identity, racial and ethnic diversity, and sexual orientation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE340891F3CFC46578A3F50A903C8B3F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>parenting, including—</text> <clause id="H4DE92766025D400BA1BBEA23DBADEA67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>financial and emotional responsibilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA167BA008CEB4894A5AB9B620465DAE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communication skills;</text> </clause><clause id="HCA16DC7270A2481D909C3D4262C2201F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>problem solving; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEA35A90FA1124867A881204A8956E385"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>caretaking.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E59C2DBB47D45E4BB462423569230AD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation; report</header><text>The requirements described in section 3(g) shall apply to eligible entities receiving a grant under this section in the same manner as such requirements apply to eligible entities receiving grants under section 3.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE1AA0B1BFF734C5B931BDCD7A0EA9B62"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants for pre-service and in-service teacher training</header>
 <subsection id="H123A72A8CBCC4EC2B40A9C246B82BDE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H915ABFE095894B0CBC30F3078B4E5FD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H98287A30180742EABA727E542245C028"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD095C16BE7DB4A5682B919EF80DB5116"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State educational agency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCF11B278DA4417F808037059ADBEB87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87F8B08352734E2798AD075548CE3A3D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a tribe or tribal organization, as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE99EE320CBE3444E91C344D27CF546C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a State or local department of health;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE52F253EF9BC46B3A63D35ED864030A5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a State or local department of education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E58427A76D544849F00CA8788295073"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a nonprofit institution of higher education;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E8D203D9710431BA6453BE13D408338"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a national or statewide nonprofit organization that has as its primary purpose the improvement of provision of comprehensive sex education through training and effective teaching of comprehensive sex education; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC141F53902B44898E9228041B613BD8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a consortium of nonprofit organizations that has as its primary purpose the improvement of provision of comprehensive sex education through training and effective teaching of comprehensive sex education.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DF12FAE249F48A9ABBF75E2119315EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA9BE70206DFB45C0B8F18CF3E644CAE2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header>
 <paragraph id="H9B4CF28F90204C97AB86CF77A76F10D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required activity</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use grant funds for professional development and training of targeted faculty, school administrators, teachers, and staff, in order to increase effective teaching of comprehensive sex education for elementary school and secondary school students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCEC4601347741E2B5308D3B473E886B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible activities</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may use grant funds to—</text> <subparagraph id="H4EFA3E62FD9E4C608F7FC10E1B01D752"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strengthen and expand the eligible entity’s relationships with—</text>
 <clause id="H8A258781AE114659913C37361EF84F41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>institutions of higher education;</text> </clause><clause id="H82D0F828D2D7408C9132E6E4BC4E0AE8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>State educational agencies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE500873D18524D07BBFD20C1C56D9891"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>local educational agencies; or</text> </clause><clause id="H937989533709409ABFF11C0AC38EC021"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other public and private organizations with a commitment to comprehensive sex education and the benefits of comprehensive sex education;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59510AA2502A4D73B7DB447064261C25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support and promote research-based training of teachers for comprehensive sex education and related disciplines in elementary and secondary schools as a means of broadening student knowledge about issues related to human development, relationships, personal skills, and sexual behavior, including abstinence, sexual health, and society and culture;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CFC1ECCF47E4C36B2CF36685C62DF03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the dissemination of information on effective practices and research findings concerning the teaching of comprehensive sex education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1778D151192F43DEA8B8EAFA14F87F4A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support research on—</text> <clause id="H6DD28A44E91A4C8486D6176B6F2681A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>effective comprehensive sex education teaching practices; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5FAB6E1B4CDE41D8A3EB24FB98F92BA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the development of assessment instruments and strategies to document—</text> <subclause id="H1A0863DACF4D4E8B9CAFDFAE7EB7A300"><enum>(I)</enum><text>student understanding of comprehensive sex education; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H139A80BF4E99435C9F09568D37BC3649"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the effects of comprehensive sex education;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96C6080D50394C7782309369704B3CC3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>convene national conferences on comprehensive sex education, in order to effectively train teachers in the provision of comprehensive sex education; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09F8AD9DA9F74D4CA616B41BEF49AEB2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>develop and disseminate appropriate research-based materials to foster comprehensive sex education.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC0665BD79AD4666B15181FB13B8662C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may award subgrants to nonprofit organizations that possess a demonstrated record of providing comprehensive sex education, State educational agencies, or local educational agencies to enable such organizations or agencies to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF1E7B4B2B3AD4AFDBE3278E0AC386CC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>train teachers in comprehensive sex education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45D81F0B9FE947309AAB8FD0B092E6B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support Internet or distance learning related to comprehensive sex education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE57BF3DB04D644D28D8CCAE940766F5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote rigorous academic standards and assessment techniques to guide and measure student performance in comprehensive sex education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57C6F8A2BB214B04BC80919CCE9EF1F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>encourage replication of best practices and model programs to promote comprehensive sex education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA4045DE393B49A49F51B08F3195670D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>develop and disseminate effective, research-based comprehensive sex education learning materials;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F424B63E184361AF8488288059F819"><enum>(F)</enum><text>develop academic courses on the pedagogy of sex education at institutions of higher education; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE76BBC8DC7C4B22959B0B63B41C9576"><enum>(G)</enum><text>convene State-based conferences to train teachers in comprehensive sex education and to identify strategies for improvement.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H90B01485EF4E40DE9B6490B4BE123DAA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report to congress</header>
 <subsection id="H15727F4A568B407099490D28FEF613E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for a period of 5 years, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the activities to provide adolescents and young people with comprehensive sex education funded under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDC694E28FD474BDFB009E11627D7AD9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report elements</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H7B331E241FA84BC785DC0F5BE95BCA72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement of whether the Secretary has met the purposes described in section 2(a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF06548CA69A48BB94E123BE698038AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information about—</text> <subparagraph id="HFAEA714CFFEE4925B786EAE40A3221DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of eligible entities and institutions of higher education that are receiving grant funds under sections 3 and 4 of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7B9F808A0CD4AA48F9390170345516E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the specific activities supported by grant funds awarded under sections 3 and 4 of this Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DE3B83048814FEAAB6386D244268873"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of adolescents served by grant programs funded under section 3;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBACCA4544B344068238DC5DCBC0C2C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of young people served by grant programs funded under section 4; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H079D0EDF9A084391825147573384A9C9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the status of program evaluations described under sections 3 and 4 of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCD9EB5E6A89E4DB3A6D11A321614279E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Programs funded under this Act shall not discriminate on the basis of actual or perceived sex, race, color, ethnicity, national origin, disability, sexual orientation, gender identity, or religion. Nothing in this Act shall be construed to invalidate or limit rights, remedies, procedures, or legal standards available to victims of discrimination under any other Federal law or any law of a State or a political subdivision of a State, including title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), and section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="HB9D0B462F0B7409EA9414EF9F5E6A6D9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds provided under this Act may be used for health education programs that—</text> <paragraph id="HD190FA59DB224B9F917216AAFE9643F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deliberately withhold health promoting or life-saving information about sexuality-related topics, including HIV;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2359B547EC284FA7983A15F83EAAB41C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are medically inaccurate or have been scientifically shown to be ineffective;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE2F50132A1642949E047EED75184408"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote gender stereotypes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6FE50D351274FD9A984BAB25BAC7505"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of sexually active youth or lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and questioning (LGBTQ) youth;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H765FB66BA69845A6952548074354452C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of survivors of sexual abuse or assault; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H09DDF6028ECC44CB9122528416CE1761"><enum>(6)</enum><text>are inconsistent with the ethical imperatives of medicine and public health.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HC7027DD8FEBC4D0CA6619CA61D266A01"><enum>9.</enum><header>Amendments to other laws</header>
 <subsection id="HCE23F689D53A42F89CB75E9BE872BB2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to the public health service act</header><text>Section 2500 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300ee">42 U.S.C. 300ee</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (b) through (d) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H12BFAA61DB6445A39D20B7B877E59E4D" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H187F234442F948BEBFB39F07E799E5CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of programs</header><text>All programs of education and information receiving funds under this title shall include information about the harmful effects of intravenous substance abuse and unsafe sexual activity, and the benefits of abstaining from such activities.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA1C7ABA2F07475FA7AEA997BC57FB6D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</header><text>Section 9526(a) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7906">20 U.S.C. 7906(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB55F941D245044CABF6D661755E95850"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A4E91187E48495180F6326E47CD25AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H536CBBF84BE1431FA9F2A58AB8FD8ABB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9437660B61C743F8BC3E912DB9FD0547"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDF23C2A0F06441869D947996612B697F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD81F6F21FE304AB9ABBE85CDDDB15A8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Age and developmentally appropriate</header><text>The term <term>age and developmentally appropriate</term> means suitable for a particular age or age group of children and adolescents, based on developing cognitive, emotional, and behavioral capacity typical for that age or age group.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD7372FD8D594B63A5B04A467342C85E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adolescents</header><text>The term <term>adolescents</term> means individuals who are ages 10 through 19 at the time of commencement of participation in a program supported under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H050B135BEBE64A4B91F7CF17B5943394"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Characteristics of effective programs</header><text>The term <term>characteristics of effective programs</term> means the aspects of evidence-based programs, including development, content, and implementation of such programs, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H65DCF880D46F46C4925DC9F5DB0A6F07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have been shown to be effective in terms of increasing knowledge, clarifying values and attitudes, increasing skills, and impacting upon behavior; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8228879A27914AD99A51D2DCFA2A4B3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are widely recognized by leading medical and public health agencies to be effective in changing sexual behaviors that lead to sexually transmitted infections, including HIV, unintended pregnancy, and dating violence and sexual assault among young people.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC753712E4606415F9E9673B6557B959A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Comprehensive sex education</header><text>The term <term>comprehensive sex education</term> means a program that—</text> <subparagraph id="H5666692388DC44F6881B086061131EF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes age- and developmentally appropriate, culturally and linguistically relevant information on a broad set of topics related to sexuality including human development, relationships, decisionmaking, communication, abstinence, contraception, and disease and pregnancy prevention;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04176E6F5F844BCAA6CA317CCA4C8E5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides students with opportunities for developing skills as well as learning information;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB67826CB806F420985E14EAE0A0B18CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is inclusive of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and heterosexual young people; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83743EFA08A44E3A84885EC1B1F6583E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>aims to—</text> <clause id="HF6E90FBC3D484DDAB6C119585DD4AC3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide scientifically accurate and realistic information about human sexuality;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFE76083E010A4B68B677E08AD6CD15EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide opportunities for individuals to understand their own, their families', and their communities' values, attitudes, and insights about sexuality;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H55E08B5AABDB439FA99732D4B17DE4DE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>help individuals develop healthy relationships and interpersonal skills; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE2FDD337955A44B483D311A8A0185EAF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>help individuals exercise responsibility regarding sexual relationships, which includes addressing abstinence, pressures to become prematurely involved in sexual intercourse, and the use of contraception and other sexual health measures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7073A6D879B849A8A19E5A00DC275691"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Evidence-based program</header><text>The term <term>evidence-based program</term> means a sex education program that has been proven through rigorous evaluation to be effective in changing sexual behavior or incorporates elements of other sex education programs that have been proven to be effective in changing sexual behavior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE15138D4B2643B5BF36C986F7DBE075"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H643251B40BB543E4AF8A95FD679E070D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Medically accurate and complete</header><text>The term <term>medically accurate and complete</term>, when used with respect to a sex education program, means that—</text> <subparagraph id="H45DA72A2FBF54BBA8D331AAEE3FF19EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the information provided through the program is verified or supported by the weight of research conducted in compliance with accepted scientific methods and is published in peer-reviewed journals, where applicable; or</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20814588F74D41F3AF6F509FCB944A1D"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6EC18984CFF8441682E9E4E7A4EB963F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the program contains information that leading professional organizations and agencies with relevant expertise in the field recognize as accurate, objective, and complete; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87AB540DBE0E4CEFBDE1EB0C0D223E06" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the program does not withhold information about the effectiveness and benefits of correct and consistent use of condoms and other contraceptives.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6705CBD918754309AAE9A434CE8AA952"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C4481AB262D4C6A80F387EA16DAEFEC"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Young people</header><text>The term <term>young people</term> means individuals who are ages 10 through 24 at the time of commencement of participation in a program supported under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H452884E600CF400F85C37C67D56AFC4A"><enum>11.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

