<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H98519E800EF348D2ACA6E51CD040F703" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 185 IH: Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 185</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reform the process by which Federal agencies analyze and formulate new regulations and guidance
			 documents.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCAC1B8B4BA2146C9BBE5ADDDC9E191FF" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE117340B3FEF449E8B9DBD7D2E28265F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HC83353EB368A412CBA4E2013FAFFC2F9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/551">Section 551</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="HC68595EB28E846489C4AC9453AF54D5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H89EFA8F24C37424E80DF0820E0642594"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H8F86EEDAEBC64741B848180F2DB373DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H58A92280E432488DB530E2B141647568" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H3308FFDBEEBF4797A4DAB450AC997F88"><enum>(15)</enum><text><term>major rule</term> means any rule that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs
			 determines is likely to impose—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HDF93E322FCED4064A275197D5CC70BB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an annual cost on the economy of $100,000,000 or more, adjusted annually for inflation;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H734E623AB8884B1D82C5640421470FD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, local, or
			 tribal government agencies, or geographic regions;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H898C503F43214F68B4B59DB003ECA462"><enum>(C)</enum><text>significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or on
			 the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with
			 foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets; or</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEB60D27E9C7422EAC2E4225BA21F27F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>significant impacts on multiple sectors of the economy;</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93A1DDD623904DAC9F73DEACEF2924DE"><enum>(16)</enum><text><term>high-impact rule</term> means any rule that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs
			 determines is likely to impose an annual cost on the economy of
			 $1,000,000,000 or more, adjusted annually for inflation;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H76DEC5FE176A4DE9826ED4DEB260AB54"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>negative-impact on jobs and wages rule</quote> means any rule that the agency that made the rule or the Administrator of the Office of
			 Information and Regulatory Affairs determines is likely to—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H8860965352DF4944B8CBFE1DEDBBEE16"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in one or more sectors of the economy that has a 6-digit code under the North American Industry
			 Classification System, reduce employment not related to new regulatory
			 compliance by 1 percent or more annually during the 1-year, 5-year, or
			 10-year period after implementation;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H005AA61DAA2B4883B43AEE5FDE8C0073"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in one or more sectors of the economy that has a 6-digit code under the North American Industry
			 Classification System, reduce average weekly wages for employment not
			 related to new regulatory compliance by 1 percent or more annually during
			 the 1-year, 5-year, or 10-year period after implementation;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39E85AE948634525BCC13D63D9434783"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in any industry area (as such term is defined in the Current Population Survey conducted by the
			 Bureau of Labor Statistics) in which the most recent annual unemployment
			 rate for the industry area is greater than 5 percent, as determined by the
			 Bureau of Labor Statistics in the Current Population Survey, reduce
			 employment not related to new regulatory compliance during the first year
			 after implementation; or</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33373D23FA1E433AA804CADB6CD1FA31"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in any industry area in which the Bureau of Labor Statistics projects in the Occupational
			 Employment Statistics program that the employment level will decrease by 1
			 percent or more, further reduce employment not related to new regulatory
			 compliance during the first year after implementation;</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3006795E7C7B42DE8424ADBC188CFDF9"><enum>(18)</enum><text><term>guidance</term> means an agency statement of general applicability and future effect, other than a regulatory
			 action, that sets forth a policy on a statutory, regulatory or technical
			 issue or an interpretation of a statutory or regulatory issue;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HD62F05C6F3E144D3B91EF2438FBCDDE5"><enum>(19)</enum><text><term>major guidance</term> means guidance that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs finds is
			 likely to lead to—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H37AAB53194FB4213AD6DC7C9B33C3C0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an annual cost on the economy of $100,000,000 or more, adjusted annually for inflation;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBB6356EA8FB4A38951F11B953772E51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, local or
			 tribal government agencies, or geographic regions;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9B69C60A7064C98B506E8F57EB44C7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or on
			 the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with
			 foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets; or</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB99CE76728224CEBA899E939E88E4676"><enum>(D)</enum><text>significant impacts on multiple sectors of the economy;</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H147D49DF701842729E05051FCED1F7A9"><enum>(20)</enum><text>the <term>Information Quality Act</term> means section 515 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</external-xref>, the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act
			 for Fiscal Year 2001, and guidelines issued by the Administrator of the
			 Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs or other agencies pursuant to
			 the Act; and</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H95A799739EFA40ABA5EC338795068B10"><enum>(21)</enum><text>the <term>Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</term> means the office established under section 3503 of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44 and any successor to
			 that office.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H50AA701E0AEE4505A5669D397B04E770"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rule making</header>
			<subsection id="HCE6D125F9A4D4E5AB1A02DE326376D7B"><enum>(a)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/553">Section 553(a)</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>(a) This section applies</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Applicability</header-in-text>.—This section applies</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H23C1E6BBE43449E2B3C4AAE707CFCC17"><enum>(b)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/553">Section 553</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking subsections (b) through (e) and
			 inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H370F91E4A65442B4AB953E74756F2410" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H8B1AC2B00172474BB7FD32DE1BC69625"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule making considerations</header><text>In a rule making, an agency shall make all preliminary and final factual determinations based on
			 evidence and consider, in addition to other applicable considerations, the
			 following:</text>
						<paragraph id="H4135CEE9627F43298133571B59EB7DC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The legal authority under which a rule may be proposed, including whether a rule making is required
			 by statute, and if so, whether by a specific date, or whether the agency
			 has discretion to commence a rule making.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H8AC2351539774079BCCFDAF897538CB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Other statutory considerations applicable to whether the agency can or should propose a rule or
			 undertake other agency action.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H336298E7C22449DE944A19A8013D4ED4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The specific nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with a rule (including
			 the degree and nature of risks the problem poses and the priority of
			 addressing those risks compared to other matters or activities within the
			 agency’s jurisdiction), whether the problem warrants new agency action,
			 and the countervailing risks that may be posed by alternatives for new
			 agency action.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H68DF3B4FFE234C3FB1303B30D2FAB97B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whether existing rules have created or contributed to the problem the agency may address with a
			 rule and whether those rules could be amended or rescinded to address the
			 problem in whole or part.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HFF0B1F5236D74C7385EEA3239B90A550"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any reasonable alternatives for a new rule or other response identified by the agency or interested
			 persons, including not only responses that mandate particular conduct or
			 manners of compliance, but also—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H273B00B53C884EF89D3DCE750C48E4FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the alternative of no Federal response;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01C232759C1743939306029926DA01E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>amending or rescinding existing rules;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H352493F486FB4617805277BE3D3CF293"><enum>(C)</enum><text>potential regional, State, local, or tribal regulatory action or other responses that could be
			 taken in lieu of agency action; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E9B48A5E3545C68DD9E4EFD9C77182"><enum>(D)</enum><text>potential responses that—</text>
								<clause id="HB2B3CD54377C4FEA8F61BCA995AE5028"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specify performance objectives rather than conduct or manners of compliance;</text>
								</clause><clause id="H4965EB4E32094F4BBB56921F13D8BAE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish economic incentives to encourage desired behavior;</text>
								</clause><clause id="H7C823ED0C385458EB742DEFE2D26F0DB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide information upon which choices can be made by the public; or</text>
								</clause><clause id="HB18D3EA9E60E4819961FFA629B2D463B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>incorporate other innovative alternatives rather than agency actions that specify conduct or
			 manners of compliance.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7944F57496874C50AF7C3CA2B2625EEF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text>
							<subparagraph id="HE36F473BE72C4A67886BEB5C37D9C113"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential costs and benefits associated with potential alternative rules and other responses
			 considered under section 553(b)(5), including direct, indirect, and
			 cumulative costs and benefits and estimated impacts on jobs (including an
			 estimate of the net gain or loss in domestic jobs), wages, economic
			 growth, innovation, and economic competitiveness;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0B986FC9BCF4A1E88956F6CE87530E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>means to increase the cost-effectiveness of any Federal response; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F62BA51D248429782582EE5F7ED566D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incentives for innovation, consistency, predictability, lower costs of enforcement and compliance
			 (to government entities, regulated entities, and the public), and
			 flexibility.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABFB7876FFA6414F848A4388D04B62F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advance notice of proposed rule making for major rules, high-Impact rules, negative-Impact on jobs
			 and wages rules, and rules involving novel legal or policy issues</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a rule making for a major rule, a high-impact rule, a negative-impact on jobs and
			 wages rule, or a rule that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising
			 out of statutory mandates, not later than 90 days before a notice of
			 proposed rule making is published in the Federal Register, an agency shall
			 publish advance notice of proposed rule making in the Federal Register. In
			 publishing such advance notice, the agency shall—</text>
						<paragraph id="H7137A09D0418441D8F866D38BDE11F41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include a written statement identifying, at a minimum—</text>
							<subparagraph id="HCF0E533602E343438EB837770939BB09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with a rule, including data and
			 other evidence and information on which the agency expects to rely for the
			 proposed rule;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H266B30285E144C76864CAC45FB9A3F66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the legal authority under which a rule may be proposed, including whether a rule making is required
			 by statute, and if so, whether by a specific date, or whether the agency
			 has discretion to commence a rule making;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9B321BCC0E74B2EAD9A62F894610407"><enum>(C)</enum><text>preliminary information available to the agency concerning the other considerations specified in
			 subsection (b);</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89CB4B0C5D1B4AAFAA291F35C6949D77"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of a rule that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory
			 mandates, the nature of and potential reasons to adopt the novel legal or
			 policy position upon which the agency may base a proposed rule; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84E417281F6C4B11974EDD60483C415E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an achievable objective for the rule and metrics by which the agency will measure progress toward
			 that objective;</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52762ED85694492C9B47F1A35E2B7F5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit written data, views or argument from interested persons concerning the information and
			 issues addressed in the advance notice; and</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H2C727D661B3140FBBB84753D6AC22B72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide for a period of not fewer than 60 days for interested persons to submit such written data,
			 views, or argument to the agency.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE820BE29402B40BD890E2BEECD2662CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notices of proposed rule making; determinations of other agency course</header>
						<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCCAB57CD64B34CB3A1680B35AB847CD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Before it determines to propose a rule, and following completion of procedures under subsection
			 (c), if applicable, the agency shall consult with the Administrator of the
			 Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs. If the agency thereafter
			 determines to propose a rule, the agency shall publish a notice of
			 proposed rule making, which shall include—</text>
							<subparagraph id="HDE74AC047DBB4CD3A55C5B7B578A2315" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement of the time, place, and nature of public rule making proceedings;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H839B23BCB58646D9BDBBA8FEFFC832E5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reference to the legal authority under which the rule is proposed;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ED116B064E24DA98180EA5E2E531CFA" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the terms of the proposed rule;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF565EFE84AAE4A4785626054CD5DE281" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of information known to the agency on the subject and issues of the proposed rule,
			 including but not limited to—</text>
								<clause id="H3BC07020ECA243BEA6CDB541B2EA94EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a summary of information known to the agency concerning the considerations specified in subsection
			 (b);</text>
								</clause><clause id="HA47825990CB44965A3454A444A8ED820"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary of additional information the agency provided to and obtained from interested persons
			 under subsection (c);</text>
								</clause><clause id="H678143B3AE654A63A91A1760AECD37D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a summary of any preliminary risk assessment or regulatory impact analysis performed by the agency;
			 and</text>
								</clause><clause id="HFD6B7AD1927D415A8EB451E7F7DCABC7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>information specifically identifying all data, studies, models, and other evidence or information
			 considered or used by the agency in connection with its determination to
			 propose the rule;</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD76F002EF8164F5EBBC38A34EED31414" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum>
								<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H307EB9AA2F62490EA02379D212587749"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a reasoned preliminary determination of need for the rule based on the information described under
			 subparagraph (D);</text>
								</clause><clause id="H8A75FE3B5634455F8ECA178904B33176" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an additional statement of whether a rule is required by statute; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="HDCE2076A638948808FBAA89077306288" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an achievable objective for the rule and metrics by which the agency will measure progress toward
			 that objective;</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7900B2C338F40B9A227C5A57D33D1E5" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a reasoned preliminary determination that the benefits of the proposed rule meet the relevant
			 statutory objectives and justify the costs of the proposed rule (including
			 all costs to be considered under subsection (b)(6)), based on the
			 information described under subparagraph (D);</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE72D853A41C4E86AFD3A3C9009971CB" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a discussion of—</text>
								<clause id="H470E4A6F63DB4BA6B34B85B958708A78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alternatives to the proposed rule, and other alternative responses, considered by the agency
			 under subsection (b);</text>
								</clause><clause id="HD8F6FCBE1F64441F9A014FC325B9E4C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the costs and benefits of those alternatives (including all costs to be considered under subsection
			 (b)(6));</text>
								</clause><clause id="HD42145F59D0847F19B6515D3F7BE262B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether those alternatives meet relevant statutory objectives; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="H544757E8F6404EB5BEAFE7BB28184171"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>why the agency did not propose any of those alternatives; and</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD35030BA8FCD4704AFAD1AB3B8C48C20" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum>
								<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC72663DD065C40B2BCD8A93F980E94BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a statement of whether existing rules have created or contributed to the problem the agency seeks
			 to address with the proposed rule; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="H79AABB43CF3D4F46AD83795E9CEACE07" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if so, whether or not the agency proposes to amend or rescind any such rules, and why.</text></clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph" indent="subsection">All information provided to or considered by the agency, and steps to obtain information by the
			 agency, in connection with its determination to propose the rule,
			 including any preliminary risk assessment or regulatory impact analysis
			 prepared by the agency and all other information prepared or described by
			 the agency under subparagraph (D) and, at the discretion of the President
			 or the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs,
			 information provided by that Office in consultations with the agency,
			 shall be placed in the docket for the proposed rule and made accessible to
			 the public by electronic means and otherwise for the public’s use when the
			 notice of proposed rule making is published.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C3AEC66893C4C8A98DF47A9708809E1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
							<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAC4D0A67A45D4C55BC92A56E661C3242"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the agency undertakes procedures under subsection (c) and determines thereafter not to propose a
			 rule, the agency shall, following consultation with the Office of
			 Information and Regulatory Affairs, publish a notice of determination of
			 other agency course. A notice of determination of other agency course
			 shall include information required by paragraph (1)(D) to be included in a
			 notice of proposed rule making and a description of the alternative
			 response the agency determined to adopt.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEF7875B8AD243F29348C305FCD233FC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If in its determination of other agency course the agency makes a determination to amend or rescind
			 an existing rule, the agency need not undertake additional proceedings
			 under subsection (c) before it publishes a notice of proposed rule making
			 to amend or rescind the existing rule.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">All information provided to or considered by the agency, and steps to obtain information by the
			 agency, in connection with its determination of other agency course,
			 including but not limited to any preliminary risk assessment or regulatory
			 impact analysis prepared by the agency and all other information that
			 would be required to be prepared or described by the agency under
			 paragraph (1)(D) if the agency had determined to publish a notice of
			 proposed rule making and, at the discretion of the President or the
			 Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs,
			 information provided by that Office in consultations with the agency,
			 shall be placed in the docket for the determination and made accessible to
			 the public by electronic means and otherwise for the public’s use when the
			 notice of determination is published.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B4E9F4DBFED46D08F6C3FE777C38A31" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>After notice of proposed rule making required by this section, the agency shall provide interested
			 persons an opportunity to participate in the rule making through
			 submission of written data, views, or arguments with or without
			 opportunity for oral presentation, except that—</text>
							<subparagraph id="HFB749A4E0B7D4F9F8D90848DB08D57E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if a hearing is required under paragraph (4)(B) or subsection (e), opportunity for oral
			 presentation shall be provided pursuant to that requirement; or</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89215E4E3A5B4626875B14477A3D6C45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>when other than under subsection (e) of this section rules are required by statute or at the
			 discretion of the agency to be made on the record after opportunity for an
			 agency hearing, sections 556 and 557 shall apply, and paragraph (4), the
			 requirements of subsection (e) to receive comment outside of the
			 procedures of sections 556 and 557, and the petition procedures of
			 subsection (e)(6) shall not apply.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The agency shall provide not fewer than 60 days for interested persons to submit written data,
			 views, or argument (or 120 days in the case of a proposed major or
			 high-impact rule).</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B3F05CEFD064171B03A33AD6FB3E80D" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum>
							<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0A5A0A89C4C946758F92091268DC8F29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Within 30 days of publication of notice of proposed rule making, a member of the public may
			 petition for a hearing in accordance with section 556 to determine whether
			 any evidence or other information upon which the agency bases the proposed
			 rule fails to comply with the Information Quality Act.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H512A5A07380B4F6686746E43083DA3E3" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum>
								<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H137B1A6A9AB44B3CBC35807E5F50787D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The agency may, upon review of the petition, determine without further process to exclude from the
			 rule making the evidence or other information that is the subject of the
			 petition and, if appropriate, withdraw the proposed rule. The agency shall
			 promptly publish any such determination.</text>
								</clause><clause id="H981DB54DF5C24CC791B385C5E650ABAB" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the agency does not resolve the petition under the procedures of clause (i), it shall grant any
			 such petition that presents a prima facie case that evidence or other
			 information upon which the agency bases the proposed rule fails to comply
			 with the Information Quality Act, hold the requested hearing not later
			 than 30 days after receipt of the petition, provide a reasonable
			 opportunity for cross-examination at the hearing, and decide the issues
			 presented by the petition not later than 60 days after receipt of the
			 petition. The agency may deny any petition that it determines does not
			 present such a prima facie case.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5B3D61B8DE4481C8CE860DCF78E7348" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>There shall be no judicial review of the agency’s disposition of issues considered and decided or
			 determined under subparagraph (B)(ii) until judicial review of the
			 agency’s final action. There shall be no judicial review of an agency’s
			 determination to withdraw a proposed rule under subparagraph (B)(i) on the
			 basis of the petition.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36786FE9E1ED4E7DBC001D2BB4F62A8A" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Failure to petition for a hearing under this paragraph shall not preclude judicial review of any
			 claim based on the Information Quality Act under chapter 7 of this title.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0AC62603248042D7A499226077B60649"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Hearings for high-Impact rules</header><text>Following notice of a proposed rule making, receipt of comments on the proposed rule, and any
			 hearing held under subsection (d)(4), and before adoption of any
			 high-impact rule, the agency shall hold a hearing in accordance with
			 sections 556 and 557, unless such hearing is waived by all participants in
			 the rule making other than the agency. The agency shall provide a
			 reasonable opportunity for cross-examination at such hearing. The hearing
			 shall be limited to the following issues of fact, except that participants
			 at the hearing other than the agency may waive determination of any such
			 issue:</text>
						<paragraph id="H649AA35345554D7E83837A9E97205856"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whether the agency’s asserted factual predicate for the rule is supported by the evidence.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HF68589C5BCB84156BA7C308CB4C5BC51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether there is an alternative to the proposed rule that would achieve the relevant statutory
			 objectives at a lower cost (including all costs to be considered under
			 subsection (b)(6)) than the proposed rule.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HAB11792C1B9E4718A77376B5A603FE32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If there is more than one alternative to the proposed rule that would achieve the relevant
			 statutory objectives at a lower cost than the proposed rule, which
			 alternative would achieve the relevant statutory objectives at the lowest
			 cost.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H56784DE83713433BBB8EF106DE47A296"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whether, if the agency proposes to adopt a rule that is more costly than the least costly
			 alternative that would achieve the relevant statutory objectives
			 (including all costs to be considered under subsection (b)(6)), the
			 additional benefits of the more costly rule exceed the additional costs of
			 the more costly rule.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HA465395BA07546F689544AD6CD282D2F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Whether the evidence and other information upon which the agency bases the proposed rule meets the
			 requirements of the Information Quality Act.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H5C1FF399C5B94ADFB1AFDCA22B9D3589"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Upon petition by an interested person who has participated in the rule making, other issues
			 relevant to the rule making, unless the agency determines that
			 consideration of the issues at the hearing would not advance consideration
			 of the rule or would, in light of the nature of the need for agency
			 action, unreasonably delay completion of the rule making. An agency shall
			 grant or deny a petition under this paragraph within 30 days of its
			 receipt of the petition.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">No later than 45 days before any hearing held under this subsection or sections 556 and 557, the
			 agency shall publish in the Federal Register a notice specifying the
			 proposed rule to be considered at such hearing, the issues to be
			 considered at the hearing, and the time and place for such hearing, except
			 that such notice may be issued not later than 15 days before a hearing
			 held under subsection (d)(4)(B).</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H316292084D8B4123A04BAC0C20C7089F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Final rules</header>
						<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7FAF094563254C3EA51C6216309B2944"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The agency shall adopt a rule only following consultation with the Administrator of the Office of
			 Information and Regulatory Affairs to facilitate compliance with
			 applicable rule making requirements.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HF00C6604A7D74FAFA96CA003DFFB6509" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The agency shall adopt a rule only on the basis of the best reasonably obtainable scientific,
			 technical, economic, and other evidence and information concerning the
			 need for, consequences of, and alternatives to the rule.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H3225CB75E2774A31AAD89B1DA8AC0A74" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
							<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDC96A35C6BDA4CD2A1D25BE715334B1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the agency shall adopt the least costly rule considered
			 during the rule making (including all costs to be considered under
			 subsection (b)(6)) that meets relevant statutory objectives.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H553AC49C3FBD4241B34DBEAAE92C5EA5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The agency may adopt a rule that is more costly than the least costly alternative that would
			 achieve the relevant statutory objectives only if the additional benefits
			 of the more costly rule justify its additional costs and only if the
			 agency explains its reason for doing so based on interests of public
			 health, safety or welfare that are clearly within the scope of the
			 statutory provision authorizing the rule.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AC60A0417C441DB928A435EA828B379" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>When it adopts a final rule, the agency shall publish a notice of final rule making. The notice
			 shall include—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H59D7C2F21A474AD89F41994FCAABD742"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a concise, general statement of the rule’s basis and purpose;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18EA1E0293954FCE9AB08FDC966A899D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the agency’s reasoned final determination of need for a rule to address the problem the agency
			 seeks to address with the rule, including a statement of whether a rule is
			 required by statute and a summary of any final risk assessment or
			 regulatory impact analysis prepared by the agency;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5F98D689E58492FB6CAEA961FF3B7D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the agency’s reasoned final determination that the benefits of the rule meet the relevant statutory
			 objectives and justify the rule’s costs (including all costs to be
			 considered under subsection (b)(6));</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD42C0A0D631F45A59C683D588FF4EAA8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the agency’s reasoned final determination not to adopt any of the alternatives to the proposed rule
			 considered by the agency during the rule making, including—</text>
								<clause id="H39A2A34A2D6A4A7C829A7CE1D563632E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency’s reasoned final determination that no alternative considered achieved the relevant
			 statutory objectives with lower costs (including all costs to be
			 considered under subsection (b)(6)) than the rule; or</text>
								</clause><clause id="HC2149CF3058440249BEF5F9CBFF7FDD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the agency’s reasoned determination that its adoption of a more costly rule complies with
			 subsection (f)(3)(B);</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BFCEDA389E742B98AE96CBA01D7E9A5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the agency’s reasoned final determination—</text>
								<clause id="H36410A09A9674110A83215E0B0AD970F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that existing rules have not created or contributed to the problem the agency seeks to address with
			 the rule; or</text>
								</clause><clause id="H267055C572BD472DB1FF967C9AE18995"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that existing rules have created or contributed to the problem the agency seeks to address with the
			 rule, and, if so—</text>
									<subclause id="H68DEAA564F8B4EB8A806F973753BC849"><enum>(I)</enum><text>why amendment or rescission of such existing rules is not alone sufficient to respond to the
			 problem; and</text>
									</subclause><subclause id="H6F46CDA66F704D4F89EB8D07EB1F2F29"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether and how the agency intends to amend or rescind the existing rule separate from adoption of
			 the rule;</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AF5E0FA32C14CC0A1D962A31F6E500E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the agency’s reasoned final determination that the evidence and other information upon which the
			 agency bases the rule complies with the Information Quality Act;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A8C20422BDC411AB38C5310E4B5F7E7"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agency’s reasoned final determination that the rule meets the objectives that the agency
			 identified in subsection (d)(1)(E)(iii) or that other objectives are more
			 appropriate in light of the full administrative record and the rule meets
			 those objectives;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60361970CA954AEA98D5403A2D3BA123"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agency’s reasoned final determination that it did not deviate from the metrics the agency
			 included in subsection (d)(1)(E)(iii) or that other metrics are more
			 appropriate in light of the full administrative record and the agency did
			 not deviate from those metrics;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H232E9F394B5C474C815D33E87782E226"><enum>(I)</enum>
								<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD06710D917C9490C8EC2FFE65916EA6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any major rule, high-impact rule, or negative-impact on jobs and wages rule, the agency’s plan
			 for review of the rule no less than every ten years to determine whether,
			 based upon evidence, there remains a need for the rule, whether the rule
			 is in fact achieving statutory objectives, whether the rule’s benefits
			 continue to justify its costs, and whether the rule can be modified or
			 rescinded to reduce costs while continuing to achieve statutory
			 objectives; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="H581C56DF987041F0A9B431C1BBAD640F" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>review of a rule under a plan required by clause (i) of this subparagraph shall take into account
			 the factors and criteria set forth in subsections (b) through (f) of
			 section 553 of this title; and</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5511869DBAB642FDB31B81C96B6712A8"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any negative-impact on jobs and wages rule, a statement that the head of the agency that made
			 the rule approved the rule knowing about the findings and determination of
			 the agency or the Administrator of the Office of Information and
			 Regulatory Affairs that qualified the rule as a negative impact on jobs
			 and wages rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">All information considered by the agency in connection with its adoption of the rule, and, at the
			 discretion of the President or the Administrator of the Office of
			 Information and Regulatory Affairs, information provided by that Office in
			 consultations with the agency, shall be placed in the docket for the rule
			 and made accessible to the public for the public’s use no later than when
			 the rule is adopted.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H6CA7B8A306B14870B980127CE7237371"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exceptions from notice and hearing requirements</header>
						<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB6A85CB40E6D48A5B6B99C04A5FE7A35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except when notice or hearing is required by statute, the following do not apply to interpretive
			 rules, general statements of policy, or rules of agency organization,
			 procedure, or practice:</text>
							<subparagraph id="H86D485F347594CB0ADE813A3361530CC" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (c) through (e).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7EA77E5EC1643638BC8A9D9ECAAC730" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (f).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E6783A6E9C841D383953373FBDFC90D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Subparagraphs (B) through (H) of subsection (f)(4).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33BEC943D05A46FDA15740740CB7AB2D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
							<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H83E1B9A09D514F679F4E27D787FEB4F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>When the agency for good cause, based upon evidence, finds (and incorporates the finding and a
			 brief statement of reasons therefor in the rules issued) that compliance
			 with subsection (c), (d), or (e) or requirements to render final
			 determinations under subsection (f) of this section before the issuance of
			 an interim rule is impracticable or contrary to the public interest,
			 including interests of national security, such subsections or requirements
			 to render final determinations shall not apply to the agency’s adoption of
			 an interim rule.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC920341FF02D4E2CAE38FF436D5CA60A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If, following compliance with subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the agency adopts an interim
			 rule, it shall commence proceedings that comply fully with subsections (d)
			 through (f) of this section immediately upon publication of the interim
			 rule, shall treat the publication of the interim rule as publication of a
			 notice of proposed rule making and shall not be required to issue
			 supplemental notice other than to complete full compliance with subsection
			 (d). No less than 270 days from publication of the interim rule (or 18
			 months in the case of a major rule or high-impact rule), the agency shall
			 complete rule making under subsections (d) through (f) of this subsection
			 and take final action to adopt a final rule or rescind the interim rule.
			 If the agency fails to take timely final action, the interim rule will
			 cease to have the effect of law.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DC95A435E8C4BB4AA26E0A99C2F8099" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other than in cases involving interests of national security, upon the agency’s publication of an
			 interim rule without compliance with subsection (c), (d), or (e) or
			 requirements to render final determinations under subsection (f) of this
			 section, an interested party may seek immediate judicial review under
			 chapter 7 of this title of the agency’s determination to adopt such
			 interim rule. The record on such review shall include all documents and
			 information considered by the agency and any additional information
			 presented by a party that the court determines necessary to consider to
			 assure justice.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F69122F8AB64CF5A36412B07D45FDC4" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>When the agency for good cause finds (and incorporates the finding and a brief statement of reasons
			 therefor in the rules issued) that notice and public procedure thereon are
			 unnecessary, including because agency rule making is undertaken only to
			 correct a de minimis technical or clerical error in a previously issued
			 rule or for other noncontroversial purposes, the agency may publish a rule
			 without compliance with subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f)(1)–(3) and
			 (f)(4)(B)–(F). If the agency receives significant adverse comment within
			 60 days after publication of the rule, it shall treat the notice of the
			 rule as a notice of proposed rule making and complete rule making in
			 compliance with subsections (d) and (f).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FAAD9364C5448B8A67AFAD895EB3BBA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Additional requirements for hearings</header><text>When a hearing is required under subsection (e) or is otherwise required by statute or at the
			 agency’s discretion before adoption of a rule, the agency shall comply
			 with the requirements of sections 556 and 557 in addition to the
			 requirements of subsection (f) in adopting the rule and in providing
			 notice of the rule’s adoption.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H99CEF05E02C24C4BBBF273C8AFC63298"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Date of publication of rule</header><text>The required publication or service of a substantive final or interim rule shall be made not less
			 than 30 days before the effective date of the rule, except—</text>
						<paragraph id="HD3B3FD08A4DD404A9DD0DF9AE9493FF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a substantive rule which grants or recognizes an exemption or relieves a restriction;</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H2FC342D549A04E3E818BFDD13B55543E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>interpretive rules and statements of policy; or</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HC13B8CC5A4214970B072DEA867060747"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as otherwise provided by the agency for good cause found and published with the rule.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB58C5F2FE95144F2B66DBB8092704634"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Right To petition</header><text>Each agency shall give an interested person the right to petition for the issuance, amendment, or
			 repeal of a rule.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H2AF82239519F420F92A57F46CCC7C119"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Rule making guidelines</header>
						<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD0192740AE074CE9A5CBC6A92DCB6A3E"><enum>(1)</enum>
							<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC219495677FF46B0B6B7441976DD341F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall establish guidelines
			 for the assessment, including quantitative and qualitative assessment, of
			 the costs and benefits of proposed and final rules and other economic
			 issues or issues related to risk that are relevant to rule making under
			 this title. The rigor of cost-benefit analysis required by such guidelines
			 shall be commensurate, in the Administrator’s determination, with the
			 economic impact of the rule.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D48C1ED133D4446935F205EE04C8689" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To ensure that agencies use the best available techniques to quantify and evaluate anticipated
			 present and future benefits, costs, other economic issues, and risks as
			 accurately as possible, the Administrator of the Office of Information and
			 Regulatory Affairs shall regularly update guidelines established under
			 paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CED9D12A243437C946BBEE7F978EEE6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall also issue guidelines
			 to promote coordination, simplification and harmonization of agency rules
			 during the rule making process and otherwise. Such guidelines shall assure
			 that each agency avoids regulations that are inconsistent or incompatible
			 with, or duplicative of, its other regulations and those of other Federal
			 agencies and drafts its regulations to be simple and easy to understand,
			 with the goal of minimizing the potential for uncertainty and litigation
			 arising from such uncertainty.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H12BB009DDA024F82A904E20202F0E3E4" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To ensure consistency in Federal rule making, the Administrator of the Office of Information and
			 Regulatory Affairs shall—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H3C7C600526AA47729AD9FF6A56911178"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue guidelines and otherwise take action to ensure that rule makings conducted in whole or in
			 part under procedures specified in provisions of law other than those of
			 subchapter II of this title conform to the fullest extent allowed by law
			 with the procedures set forth in section 553 of this title; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9462CD70B60840888328E6AF0DD60424"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue guidelines for the conduct of hearings under subsections 553(d)(4) and 553(e) of this
			 section, including to assure a reasonable opportunity for
			 cross-examination. Each agency shall adopt regulations for the conduct of
			 hearings consistent with the guidelines issued under this subparagraph.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EB1754501F34FA9BF7507B123F73BC6" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall issue guidelines
			 pursuant to the Information Quality Act to apply in rule making
			 proceedings under sections 553, 556, and 557 of this title. In all cases,
			 such guidelines, and the Administrator’s specific determinations regarding
			 agency compliance with such guidelines, shall be entitled to judicial
			 deference.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75FE06B42E3A40A8846548BCEA3AFF0C"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Inclusion in the record of certain documents and information</header><text>The agency shall include in the record for a rule making, and shall make available by electronic
			 means and otherwise, all documents and information prepared or considered
			 by the agency during the proceeding, including, at the discretion of the
			 President or the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory
			 Affairs, documents and information communicated by that Office during
			 consultation with the Agency.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HBD1FA915DD2F4E2581EAAC4C9B8D0E77"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Monetary policy exemption</header><text>Nothing in subsection (b)(6), subparagraphs (F) and (G) of subsection (d)(1), subsection (e),
			 subsection (f)(3), and subparagraphs (C) and (D) of subsection (f)(5)
			 shall apply to rule makings that concern monetary policy proposed or
			 implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the
			 Federal Open Market Committee.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC3C8BC00C9FF4F18AB70B5F14CCAD7CD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Agency guidance; procedures to issue major guidance; presidential authority to issue guidelines for
			 issuance of guidance</header>
			<subsection id="H56C15C02B28A4838AA242FBD7C84EFEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">Chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/553">section 553</external-xref> the following
			 new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H449C25B4FEC34245ADECBAE6E3DCFBC9" style="USC">
					<section id="HD049F7D820144342ABD099523EA3E5AC"><enum>553a.</enum><header>Agency guidance; procedures to issue major guidance; authority to issue guidelines for issuance of
			 guidance</header>
						<subsection id="H38679E39AD954FCF8CCDD727719F85A7"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Before issuing any major guidance, or guidance that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising
			 out of statutory mandates, an agency shall—</text>
							<paragraph id="HCF2E6CA50DFE4B69B99ACD20FFEAB7E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make and document a reasoned determination that—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HB7951F09C2FC41AA8E00AA76FAC3BF8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assures that such guidance is understandable and complies with relevant statutory objectives and
			 regulatory provisions (including any statutory deadlines for agency
			 action);</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB7747D76D14CF3B320B4A8C4B39AA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>summarizes the evidence and data on which the agency will base the guidance;</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF160AEDE85F444E58DCCA87CE3FEB7B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifies the costs and benefits (including all costs to be considered during a rule making under
			 section 553(b) of this title) of conduct conforming to such guidance and
			 assures that such benefits justify such costs; and</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19548C24F4D54D6A9F94F391AC620314"><enum>(D)</enum><text>describes alternatives to such guidance and their costs and benefits (including all costs to be
			 considered during a rule making under section 553(b) of this title) and
			 explains why the agency rejected those alternatives; and</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD79AD7482D6A429E9C1E1D5BAE68040C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>confer with the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs on the issuance
			 of such guidance to assure that the guidance is reasonable,
			 understandable, consistent with relevant statutory and regulatory
			 provisions and requirements or practices of other agencies, does not
			 produce costs that are unjustified by the guidance’s benefits, and is
			 otherwise appropriate.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Upon issuing major guidance, or guidance that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of
			 statutory mandates, the agency shall publish the documentation required by
			 subparagraph (1) by electronic means and otherwise.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H461316FE674842AD9EE336BEFDC9570B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Agency guidance—</text>
							<paragraph id="H1ED66236AF8A4BEFAF4BDB4610242EEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not legally binding and may not be relied upon by an agency as legal grounds for agency action;</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HDFFD4D36A33F4C0990AB986CE8A7CEB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall state in a plain, prominent and permanent manner that it is not legally binding; and</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HB56411EA3C844D37A89B03EB03280037"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall, at the time it is issued or upon request, be made available by the issuing agency to
			 interested persons and the public by electronic means and otherwise.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Agencies shall avoid the issuance of guidance that is inconsistent or incompatible with, or
			 duplicative of, the agency’s governing statutes or regulations, with the
			 goal of minimizing the potential for uncertainty and litigation arising
			 from such uncertainty.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H2AFCF4E98A1A4EBD97AE6FD68480ABE9"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall have authority to issue
			 guidelines for use by the agencies in the issuance of major guidance and
			 other guidance. Such guidelines shall assure that each agency avoids
			 issuing guidance documents that are inconsistent or incompatible with, or
			 duplicative of, the law, its other regulations, or the regulations of
			 other Federal agencies and drafts its guidance documents to be simple and
			 easy to understand, with the goal of minimizing the potential for
			 uncertainty and litigation arising from such uncertainty.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB61B323B733F41F4AB88EE487A7FC733"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after
			 the item relating to section 553 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H64B06E69207749BDA399C4DD5288DB30" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">553a. Agency guidance; procedures to issue major guidance; authority to issue guidelines for
			 issuance of guidance.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HBF6C53DF7DFD4ADAB94E11A468D95E2A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Hearings; presiding employees; powers and duties; burden of proof; evidence; record as basis of
			 decision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/556">Section 556</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (e) and inserting the
			 following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H8BBA0257CD4049B1B03AA59A88E118F3" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HDA93FE7B8BC645568D15D711B4C76932"><enum>(e)</enum>
					<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2B953BFED5084446B6CA36CAC02C2EF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The transcript of testimony and exhibits, together with all papers and requests filed in the
			 proceeding, constitutes the exclusive record for decision in accordance
			 with section 557 and shall be made available to the parties and the public
			 by electronic means and, upon payment of lawfully prescribed costs,
			 otherwise. When an agency decision rests on official notice of a material
			 fact not appearing in the evidence in the record, a party is entitled, on
			 timely request, to an opportunity to show the contrary.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H433725727BA94F978860114893EBE15B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, in a proceeding held under this section pursuant
			 to section 553(d)(4) or 553(e), the record for decision shall also include
			 any information that is part of the record of proceedings under section
			 553.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8041292BE5B541C7B3B9687496C97131"><enum>(f)</enum><text>When an agency conducts rule making under this section and section 557 directly after concluding
			 proceedings upon an advance notice of proposed rule making under section
			 553(c), the matters to be considered and determinations to be made shall
			 include, among other relevant matters and determinations, the matters and
			 determinations described in subsections (b) and (f) of section 553.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HC9E2993FD4FF4749BD97FCF4B17D4C63"><enum>(g)</enum><text>Upon receipt of a petition for a hearing under this section, the agency shall grant the petition in
			 the case of any major rule, unless the agency reasonably determines that a
			 hearing would not advance consideration of the rule or would, in light of
			 the need for agency action, unreasonably delay completion of the rule
			 making. The agency shall publish its decision to grant or deny the
			 petition when it renders the decision, including an explanation of the
			 grounds for decision. The information contained in the petition shall in
			 all cases be included in the administrative record. This subsection shall
			 not apply to rule makings that concern monetary policy proposed or
			 implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the
			 Federal Open Market Committee.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HCBD6498F21CD40C2974E1A5EA665BFF0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Actions reviewable</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/704">Section 704</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="HBB89F7EC59E04C6CA49D0219AA308D8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Agency action made</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) Agency action made</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HAB821B5EE0CF4DDFB615A3D4C8AE3CD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: “Denial by an agency of a correction request or, where
			 administrative appeal is provided for, denial of an appeal, under an
			 administrative mechanism described in subsection (b)(2)(B) of the
			 Information Quality Act, or the failure of an agency within 90 days to
			 grant or deny such request or appeal, shall be final action for purposes
			 of this section.</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBAAA41DD166D4408B28F81658558697F" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HE8CDEDEE7FED466C985C0E08B9089CCC"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Other than in cases involving interests of national security, notwithstanding subsection (a) of
			 this section, upon the agency’s publication of an interim rule without
			 compliance with section 553(c), (d), or (e) or requirements to render
			 final determinations under subsection (f) of section 553, an interested
			 party may seek immediate judicial review under this chapter of the
			 agency’s determination to adopt such rule on an interim basis. Review
			 shall be limited to whether the agency abused its discretion to adopt the
			 interim rule without compliance with section 553(c), (d), or (e) or
			 without rendering final determinations under subsection (f) of section
			 553.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H9064CAFDC0A947FC81672116991ACA06"><enum>7.</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/706">Section 706</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H1672E2D0F51741059D3DAAB8F98EC0B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>To the extent necessary</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) To the extent necessary</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H0E8877832A304DAB811BB5EABDB022C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A) of subsection (a) (as designated by paragraph (1) of this section), by
			 inserting after <quote>in accordance with law</quote> the following: <quote>(including the Information Quality Act)</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB9B77E5BCF65476F9E2E33013BDEDFB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H158952ACBCCF4B7F9FFBEDE9DDFFC2D9" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H34A9AB335C54445E8B17F6655B2F2BD1"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The court shall not defer to the agency’s—</text>
						<paragraph id="H15209143DCB248839E357B280382874C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>interpretation of an agency rule if the agency did not comply with the procedures of section 553 or
			 sections 556–557 of chapter 5 of this title to issue the interpretation;</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HEE256ED9D4304867947ABD7734D63710"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determination of the costs and benefits or other economic or risk assessment of the action, if the
			 agency failed to conform to guidelines on such determinations and
			 assessments established by the Administrator of the Office of Information
			 and Regulatory Affairs under section 553(k);</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H28D700DC925746D0B4751BDA50081D9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determinations made in the adoption of an interim rule; or</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H402B947EC1AF46659FDD2B7703CEF6C5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>guidance.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF200708CAA76414EA31BECDF52D5F781"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The court shall review agency denials of petitions under section 553(e)(6) or any other petition
			 for a hearing under sections 556 and 557 for abuse of agency discretion.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H2B13A19479164AF2B3C8B4296620C418"><enum>8.</enum><header>Added definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/701">Section 701(b)</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="HEAD0646B79104BE8B584F72BC7F49915"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB5C5288440614536A83CFF04D37E431E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end, and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H149CCBBD2FB64DA2B06D47F3499A53BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HEABD2A9340E04BD2A13874F3933D2D6A" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H9BF3FDEE14364F4DBACD0F5029C91DDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text><term>substantial evidence</term> means such relevant evidence as a reasonable mind might accept as adequate to support a conclusion
			 in light of the record considered as a whole, taking into account whatever
			 in the record fairly detracts from the weight of the evidence relied upon
			 by the agency to support its decision.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H490CD09964464A52BA9678C3F86DD085"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act to—</text>
			<paragraph id="H1C42DC42ABA24C478ECA80784EA75E83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sections 553, 556, and 704 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H398C071302C145CB9651FE50F5C484FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subsection (b) of section 701 of such title;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA469C16FEC8E44F6A5E52D3A74F6BAF5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 706(b) of such title; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H7CDA48739000401389A14BB1FC20ADF8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>subsection (c) of section 706 of such title,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="section">shall not apply to any rule makings pending or completed on the date of enactment of this Act.</continuation-text></section></legis-body>
</bill>


