<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC2E174A639BC46E7A4D237581A0CF0F4" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2787 IH: East Rosebud Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2787</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150615">June 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain segments of East Rosebud Creek in
			 Carbon County, Montana, as components of the Wild and Scenic Rivers
			 System.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFC70843213E94D89A2344BB94361B72C" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCAE9999BC02D4C51984EE8D7223F8AB4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>East Rosebud Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H59796309A0184098BD4558603123BE57"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection id="H40E6C8FC1B0C4E3D8E1AC3091C0FDFB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H209316B428FE48A591AEF53D08F7745C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>East Rosebud Creek is cherished by the people of Montana and visitors from across the United States for its clean water, spectacular natural setting, and outstanding recreational opportunities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E669A11D4FA441D89E2D747E53B177B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recreational activities, including fishing, hunting, camping, paddling, hiking, rock climbing, and wildlife watching, on East Rosebud Creek and the surrounding land generate millions of dollars annually for the local economy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C86EEBACC0644118F53F1752D5A24B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>East Rosebud Creek—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF980C34739743B6864DF9E23FEF71DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a national treasure;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9A3C0AAE09841EC926547543D3E13F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>possesses outstandingly remarkable values; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF217A72B96CD46F79B7CEA2CCDE78EE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>merits the high level of protection afforded by the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1271">16 U.S.C. 1271 et seq.</external-xref>) in order to maintain the benefits provided by the Creek, as described in paragraphs (1) and (2), for future generations to enjoy; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07130FA99DE84C70ADEF121CB786EAEA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designation of select public land segments of East Rosebud Creek under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1271">16 U.S.C. 1271 et seq.</external-xref>) would recognize the importance of maintaining the values of the Creek while preserving public access, respecting private property rights, allowing appropriate maintenance of existing infrastructure, and allowing historical uses of the Creek, such as recreational uses, livestock management activities, motorized uses, or forest management activities, to continue.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04EC67614C9048FEBE4A121487186C68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to designate East Rosebud Creek in the State of Montana as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System to preserve and protect for present and future generations the outstandingly remarkable scenic, recreational, and geologic values of the Creek.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9127D8C6CC23426A801729DA0434EA42"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of wild and scenic river segments</header>
 <subsection id="HD01F0B862BE6447EAEF040C41854991E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H1E60DE9AE5194783A0A42F43BC769543" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H292F219C677E4F3BBB01EEDA46E13BA7"><enum>(213)</enum><header>East rosebud creek, montana</header><text>The portions of East Rosebud Creek in the State of Montana, consisting of—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C44861065DA4528AE9DE74616B0E4C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the 13-mile segment exclusively on public lands within the Custer National Forest from the source in the Absaroka-Beartooth Wilderness downstream to the point at which the Creek enters East Rosebud Lake, including the stream reach between Twin Outlets Lake and Fossil Lake, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture as a wild river; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38A456FFA9E74A8589FADC1C1A774818"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 7-mile segment exclusively on public lands within the Custer National Forest from immediately below, but not including, the outlet of East Rosebud Lake downstream to the point at which the Creek enters private property for the first time, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC6BC95FC56294E2A830966B38C5EE697"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header>
 <paragraph id="H8E215799C0DA4765AA15104BA2EFC13E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in the paragraph added to section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) by subsection (a) of the Act creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone outside the designated boundary of the river segment designated by that paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52956F6CB362448D97EB5CAF68F8E571"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outside activities</header><text>The fact that an activity or use can be seen or heard within the boundary of the river segment designated by the paragraph added to section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) by subsection (a) of this Act shall not preclude the activity or use outside the boundary of the river segment.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


