<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE877BC4F148043419F72B2E7A5D4F70E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 831 IH: Supporting Afterschool STEM Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 831</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To support afterschool and out-of-school-time science, technology, engineering, and mathematics
			 programs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB0A52A2D56CD40C285CC36152181F65C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H083CC6D4204548F782ECE2B1E3060EB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Afterschool STEM Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H54E8B809CF21452D8D34D4A4562FF1E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H42AF1FC1CFF64C9C9E4A2F5B53A5ED5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Numerous authoritative studies document that the proficiency of students in the United States in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (<quote>STEM</quote>) will have a major impact on the Nation's future economic competitiveness and on the preeminence of the United States in scientific inquiry and technological innovation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA5C2DC58FEF4C6FA39FCA380CE78EDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Results from the National Assessment of Educational Progress, the Trends in International Mathematics and Science Study, the Programme for International Science Assessment, and other sources show that students in the United States are not demonstrating sufficient achievement in the STEM subjects and are not keeping pace with students in other countries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27BC2759BD164DAB817E4ABB2FE1B1DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research demonstrates the importance of afterschool programs in engaging students in STEM fields and building STEM-relevant skills and proficiencies, especially for girls, students from populations traditionally underrepresented in STEM fields, and students from low socioeconomic circumstances.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1664F1BC3974EEF99EE3BA179484D50"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A National Research Council consensus study confirmed the importance of learning that occurs in out-of-school-time settings such as afterschool programs and science centers, and proposed a set of <quote>strands of science learning</quote> framework that articulated capabilities fostered by informal learning environments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H519209F62D584420A17D6BB443DBCEFD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to a 2013 study entitled <quote>Defining Youth Outcomes for STEM Learning in Afterschool</quote>, the afterschool field is confident in its ability to help young people develop interest in STEM and STEM learning activities, develop capacities to productively engage in such activities, and come to value them. The afterschool field is also confident that it can impact skills such as problem-solving abilities, demonstrating STEM skills, career awareness, and 21st century skills, such as teamwork, that are important to the workforce and national economic goals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC18DF1D788964FFCA5EBA9B0BF9AAAE2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Federal Government should use its resources as effectively as possible to increase opportunities for students to be exposed to STEM subjects outside of the school day and to build a balanced kindergarten through grade 12 STEM education portfolio that fosters learning in school as well as in out-of-school-time programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C846EA497304E4199A247A24D12F47F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Afterschool programs have long partnered with other youth-serving and community organizations to meet the needs of students. Cross-sector collaborations between afterschool programs, schools, science centers, institutions of higher education, businesses, and other entities are yielding great benefits for engaging young people in STEM fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC04349A4B71142189E1DB2FFFDBEC175"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As interest and momentum grows around STEM programming in afterschool, more and better partnerships across Federal agencies become increasingly important to leverage resources and offer high-quality, hands-on STEM experiences for youth.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HC1521F483CDD411CBDBEA6FA4D880C26"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="H64F6EF16908B4D02A04EB59F04FDC59E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to enhance America’s economic competitiveness by strengthening STEM education through fostering interest and success in STEM subjects among certain student populations in kindergarten through grade 12;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE5099B83E694132B3DDD8470BDC3AA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to engage Federal agencies and foster interagency collaboration in STEM education afterschool program investments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H193314945A7F4482917B1234A3238668"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to recognize the important role that afterschool programs offered by nonprofit and community-based organizations, science centers, museums, libraries, and other such entities, play in STEM education and to support their efforts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89B483FEBBC44F4981990D9CDE976346"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to involve institutions of higher education as partners in such efforts and foster increased collaboration; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B6528BC73B04F36B0A786734B6E5A7C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to inspire young people to study and work in STEM subjects.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HC45A977F4496490B81FE92C9A70A5286"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HED8AB1C323624E5C9E6189EFCAED0ACA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Afterschool or STEM network</header><text>The term <term>afterschool or STEM network</term> means a coalition that fosters partnerships and provides support to afterschool program providers and STEM education providers to develop and sustain quality education programming for children and youth in afterschool programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EBBC22EC4D44642A72E092901A6AC84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Afterschool program</header><text>The term <term>afterschool program</term> means a structured program offered for elementary school, middle school, or secondary school students when school is not in session, such as before or after school, recess time, on the weekend, or during the summer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0B1EB8CA5BD4DD68F9B14DFB3302C23"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CCD52DB4E254EA3AEF592539EFC3D67"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Elementary school</header><text>The term <term>elementary school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D5E0C1408C446B09140D47486A27837"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Middle school</header><text>The term <term>middle school</term> means a nonprofit institutional day or residential school, including a public charter school, that provides middle grades education, as determined under State law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D3B898B8CE24F3EBF8173A0387F04F3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secondary school</header><text>The term <term>secondary school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1546979770F4E2B980AF8FFD1A7081B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05B5A9775F9F4101A0E46A1534BF3D24"><enum>(8)</enum><header>STEM</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, or mathematics, and includes the fields of computer science and robotics.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HA9C69B48F20341DCBD4A73C4E03DFF5F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Afterschool STEM support grant program</header>
 <subsection id="H61CD2A7C48694C24BD7C074B7151B350"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Goals of program</header><text>The goals of the afterschool STEM grant program carried out under this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="H7EB268D7E4694B4CACF2D694B287F6C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support the development and delivery of high-quality STEM education to populations underrepresented in STEM fields;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1837EF360E4541EDA515C1A5B2C39E5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to leverage the expertise and infrastructure available to afterschool programs that include STEM content through afterschool or STEM networks;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC1EBD328C5C461689BDB90890169C8D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to leverage existing Federal STEM education investments, as of the date of enactment of this Act, in order to encourage STEM-focused grant recipients to lend their time and expertise to afterschool programs that include STEM content; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3E5F6B0ECF40A9AFD0E47D2C0128C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide hands-on learning and exposure to STEM research facilities and businesses through in-person or virtual distance-learning experiences.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78C9DCC159CA4F32805939031467386B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H914BF1A378D34D9A9B717642FB0A79EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated to carry out this Act and not reserved under paragraph (4), the Director shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to afterschool or STEM networks—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6CE93400413F40CEBAF663A965884811"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to support afterschool programs that include STEM content through the activities described in subsection (e); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB891E8C45F6F4E95BA368FB58E0E6117"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out the goals described in subsection (a).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70CE4709C6514667A8C86CBD72B0E0EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each grant awarded under this Act shall be for a period of not more than 3 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H385D2E337A2A49218AC8FDF97A3ECCF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text>The Director shall ensure that each grant awarded under this Act is in an amount that is sufficient to carry out the goals described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAD240641B74B4DDAAFF28F05CFC663A3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>From the amounts appropriated for this grant, the Director shall reserve 20 percent of such funds to develop and support new afterschool or STEM networks in States or areas where such networks do not exist.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE39BCD75C9D40E6A8B3D39A985C5130"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="H0A365145D5BF4311B4F3950539A4FDE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An afterschool or STEM network desiring a grant under subsection (b)(1) shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information that the Director may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27142EFBD762422B9420D4D4D2410D06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The application described in paragraph (1) shall, at a minimum, include—</text> <subparagraph id="H8F52E28D8C6347D08DEAEEB33D0C7144"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the status of afterschool STEM programming in the State or area in which the afterschool or STEM network is located, including—</text>
 <clause id="HABD3F16754974E6981A3B3DD93708955"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of afterschool programs in the State or area;</text> </clause><clause id="HDB506BB9D9C4428BB24DF6F74747E031"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of such afterschool programs focused on STEM subjects and activities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB88753D01BF341F1960584507916AAEB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of students served by existing afterschool programs, as of the date of the application, in the State or area;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H254B09A5856444CDB7B7042BF1D8B5C2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of students served by existing afterschool programs that include STEM content in the State or area;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA88067C3CF404DF1A134DDE2DC416327"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the unmet demand for afterschool programs in the State or area; and</text> </clause><clause id="H41675B8030C34132BC32DD4DEC31ED62"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the unmet demand for afterschool programs focused on STEM subjects and activities in the State or area;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AD78D04BC85464B976827BD7DBDAE8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of existing and needed resources that identifies areas and populations most in need of opportunities for high-quality afterschool programs that include STEM content;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8747E39FE3884C0B951068E5869514F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the current and past work carried out by the afterschool or STEM network to support the needs of afterschool program providers in the State or area served by the network;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFED7FE8031DD47AE8E62AA92A0407615"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a detailed plan that describes initiatives that shall be undertaken to—</text> <clause id="HA8DAC89D2DFC4043BBEE44324CA265CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support and grow afterschool programs that include STEM content; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4A361333F0E941AFB4E9D574C5393F04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>leverage existing Federal investments in afterschool programs and STEM education, as of the date of the application;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H46B7ED0678D04A5AB2B50FCDB79E77C2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of financial and other commitments that support expanded afterschool STEM programming in the State or area served by the network; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H62A695E3564042BB998FDA841A30E24E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of any confirmed or potential partners that will work with the afterschool or STEM network to carry out the activities under the grant.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21274DD2829E45749746648970324797"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (b)(1), the Director shall give priority to applications from afterschool or STEM networks that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3A478B07EEDC4E65969AA6BF4A2DC1B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demonstrate a clear understanding of the afterschool programs and settings, and the status of afterschool programs that include STEM content, in the State or area to be served by the grant;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7B0AC926F7142F6BE12348B228F0DE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have established working relationships with afterschool program and STEM education stakeholders in the State or area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE3AEA0527344629BC8BE52F4411698E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are working to advance the availability of high-quality afterschool programs that include STEM content for underserved populations and populations underrepresented in STEM fields, including girls; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H052A97C93C31400886D867AA7793E17E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>are leveraging Federal or other public investments in STEM education or afterschool programming.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H191E023E15C747E18759ECA5BEA4C9EB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text>An afterschool or STEM network that receives a grant under subsection (b)(1) may use grant funds to carry out any of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="H239CF69F86EA4D479A1DE10A51FED701"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Develop quality standards for STEM programming in afterschool programs and provide technical assistance to afterschool programs to implement such standards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1175A26EDA684C03B8F9F2D37EEA443C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Work with State education stakeholders to define and promote appropriate measurable outcomes for afterschool programs that include STEM content.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C5C930C437347F4A6F607C6E6B8596F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Provide technical assistance to afterschool programs to start or grow their afterschool STEM efforts and define appropriate learning outcomes for such efforts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B00977789034CBD97545EA04334EA79"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Coordinate professional development for afterschool program educators by—</text> <subparagraph id="H15B5EFA3B795426D974AA6FDA7801BC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying training programs that are available, as of the time of the identification, for afterschool program educators;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE757FD7D42484AB38B8E857BEB5661E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>working with partners to allow joint professional development with teachers at elementary schools, middle schools, and secondary schools, as appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8885A36A571A408B93458E9B9B34BC22"><enum>(C)</enum><text>partnering with teacher training programs to utilize afterschool programs for practicum experiences, employment placements, and other opportunities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD49F3ABDF62C4964B202AF149BAF6A74"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Help afterschool program providers form strategic partnerships as needed to advance STEM learning in afterschool programs, including partnerships with elementary schools, middle schools, secondary schools, institutions of higher education (including community colleges and programs and schools of education), businesses, research facilities, national laboratories, science centers, and other appropriate entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBC7B04B50824147B186FFEBA8336C19"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Create and disseminate tool kits to afterschool programs wanting to form partnerships and incorporate STEM professionals as mentors and role models that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEE319605EB364487B07B949ED6007BB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide technical assistance and guidance, including assistance in connecting afterschool program providers with STEM researchers and professionals who may be able to assist in STEM-focused activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA0BD8637DF7452393D6A26752D00B80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include—</text> <clause id="H24F5D874E66644AA88338C21C016C059"><enum>(i)</enum><text>examples of strong afterschool programs that have incorporated such partnerships to serve as models;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H75803AA8166E413AB99DDE9B7628C501"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of potential partners that could assist in STEM-focused activities; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6EBC37B9720942ADAC1D064B0712B7F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>guidance on how to engage STEM professionals, mentors, and role models in the program; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EBB8A8C6E4B47788788611B7DF30C2A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify federally supported STEM education programs and research in the State or area served by the grant.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBCD5407318C41489D7ADC9C3095D34C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Provide technical assistance to federally funded STEM researchers and professionals who wish to engage with afterschool programs that, at a minimum, includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H825EA7ED4B844194957DC1F1F5F27BCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>examples of partnerships between afterschool programs and institutions rich in STEM resources;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C52B8A01F4745C1A3B58677966EF557"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a resource that provides a description of the afterschool program setting, the opportunities for engagement in afterschool programs, and the constraints of which the researchers or professionals need to be aware;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF219F8156F484BE08C299F373A07322F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how to find an afterschool program provider with which the researcher or professional would like to engage;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEFC203F820F436685C394B5BAB10B02"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how to ensure an effective and productive partnership with the afterschool provider through mutually beneficial engagement, and engage in a productive conversation with the afterschool provider to determine if the partnership will be productive;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13DA3422657D4E7EB9B81620E31E830A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how to craft a mutually beneficial engagement and partnership; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF1B1A1967DD41D39F4879F6F44B3CA6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>guidance on how to measure appropriate outcomes for afterschool programs and afterschool programs that include STEM content.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB562D0CB64E4A54ADA9278B20BC13CB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any other activity, as proposed in the application and determined appropriate by the Director.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H782687D7BA094C9B912537820D233E63"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Each afterschool or STEM network receiving a grant under subsection (b)(1) shall submit an annual report to the Director regarding the progress of the grant.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HB819280261F243AD982FCD4361B165D0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Federal partnership with afterschool programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall provide information, to each recipient of a STEM research grant under the authority of the Director, on opportunities to engage with students in out-of-school-time programs, such as through mentorships. Such information shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC3733E051C5441C5A75FEEE63CCA2039"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a listing of all afterschool or STEM program networks in the region of the recipient;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA977316702134DB5804EEBF990EFC28A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a toolkit that provides guidance to federally funded STEM researchers on how to engage and partner with afterschool STEM program providers and lend their time and expertise in afterschool programs that include STEM content;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F16D64F1A5749D9AE9E029C88BC53ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information regarding how to create opportunities to have students visit laboratories; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H55872A2E8B8F4D0D9294D97CE9EA304B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>guidance regarding how to create age-appropriate research projects for students.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H38354B8AF17247038518432A3C5931BD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">By not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall prepare and submit to Congress a report on Federal STEM investments in afterschool programs and the best practices for afterschool programs incorporating STEM subjects into their programs.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


