<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1D4AB5E60A1E4F5CAD922CA37D5B780A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1525 IH: Disclosure Modernization and Simplification Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1525</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150323">March 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000548">Mr. Garrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to make certain improvements to form 10–K and
			 regulation S–K, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1232009FF15346BE90FD1CB138429960" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2783ED8AC996421AABE3ABE489AA8B15" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disclosure Modernization and Simplification Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB47E4C8B541D4B9FA5A2B246D1544624"><enum>2.</enum><header>Summary page for form 10–K</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall issue regulations to permit issuers to submit a summary page on form 10–K (17 C.F.R. 249.310), but only if each item on such summary page includes a cross-reference (by electronic link or otherwise) to the material contained in form 10–K to which such item relates.</text>
 </section><section id="HF14D470BFFEC480D90A71C67B9FF9483"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvement of regulation S–K</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall take all such actions to revise regulation S–K (17 C.F.R. 229.10 et seq.)—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB310215CFDA445228CEF7BF0D3A137DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to further scale or eliminate requirements of regulation S–K, in order to reduce the burden on emerging growth companies, accelerated filers, smaller reporting companies, and other smaller issuers, while still providing all material information to investors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBC2E27C218D44C09849657B9261D3B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to eliminate provisions of regulation S–K, required for all issuers, that are duplicative, overlapping, outdated, or unnecessary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2219ACF034B43F9B5C9BF541C99FA2A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which the Commission determines that no further study under section 4 is necessary to determine the efficacy of such revisions to regulation S–K.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HC36866B317804FDF920761A7D53CB4D2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study on modernization and simplification of regulation S–K</header>
 <subsection id="HFA959826B62B4DBA9DB934C66E68038A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Securities and Exchange Commission shall carry out a study of the requirements contained in regulation S–K (17 C.F.R. 229.10 et seq.). Such study shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF28CE32EE53842A190688C84EDED907C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine how best to modernize and simplify such requirements in a manner that reduces the costs and burdens on issuers while still providing all material information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA778AAC97D234AD9A7EA71942CF2A885"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emphasize a company by company approach that allows relevant and material information to be disseminated to investors without boilerplate language or static requirements while preserving completeness and comparability of information across registrants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BF654C2214C420C87AF74847D04919A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate methods of information delivery and presentation and explore methods for discouraging repetition and the disclosure of immaterial information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9F6E0DBE7444FEBBEEC891A01E190C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study required under subsection (a), the Commission shall consult with the Investor Advisory Committee and the Advisory Committee on Small and Emerging Companies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBC13FD7DC31C4EEDA6A93B23A5D21CC6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the end of the 360-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall issue a report to the Congress containing—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCD0F22B155F24D00A67498DB3412E107"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB741D9A65A934AC5B7E37FAE99F25F87"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific and detailed recommendations on modernizing and simplifying the requirements in regulation S–K in a manner that reduces the costs and burdens on companies while still providing all material information; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55019A746D134CC6817B5B985D12B88B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific and detailed recommendations on ways to improve the readability and navigability of disclosure documents and to discourage repetition and the disclosure of immaterial information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AA6644EE0A941ADB46273444BFEB784"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 360-day period beginning on the date that the report is issued to the Congress under subsection (c), the Commission shall issue a proposed rule to implement the recommendations of the report issued under subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC5E15F6C33684F418DBD68F156CA8A00"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Revisions made to regulation S–K by the Commission under section 3 shall not be construed as satisfying the rulemaking requirements under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


