<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1089D87B833C4071ABF3C3860C6F5264" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1597 IH: Agile Acquisition to Retain Technological Edge Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1597</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150325">March 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000238">Mr. Thornberry</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reform the acquisition system of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H504E971EE8284EB2BD1B59D345807D2F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF3C7DDB686A44A01B59A42CA9EEF122B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Agile Acquisition to Retain Technological Edge Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA8B588019B3F4ADB955628EF7768D8FB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="HF3C7DDB686A44A01B59A42CA9EEF122B" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HA8B588019B3F4ADB955628EF7768D8FB" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H3C84ED679800465B98472ED20839F488" level="section">Sec. 3. Sense of Congress on the desired tenets of the defense acquisition system.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H700897A2F97D41328B477ECCBCB13A1A" level="title">Title I—Workforce Development and Related Matters</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1B01CAF8751847209C16CC52D3B4961D" level="section">Sec. 101. Amendments to Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H5E0141D775804C9B82801B0B751C3CCA" level="section">Sec. 102. Dual-track military professionals in operational and acquisition specialities.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H4821E6D8198B4886B3E1274630D3468E" level="section">Sec. 103. Provision of joint duty assignment credit for acquisition duty.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2746E4EE1BB64DE7AE7FABB54B502FCF" level="section">Sec. 104. Requirement for acquisition skills assessment biennial strategic workforce plan.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H260D37666F0944F999106F4D1B6AABB9" level="section">Sec. 105. Mandatory requirement for training related to the conduct of market research.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6E3ACF5C5FAF4CF181841074D935C971" level="section">Sec. 106. Independent study of implementation of defense acquisition workforce improvement efforts.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HBFBFC1EB6233432184D2D687EF35F421" level="title">Title II—Weapon Systems Acquisition and Related Matters</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H5AF35953AA7340DEB2A2461E74F51141" level="section">Sec. 201. Sense of Congress on the desired characteristics for the weapon systems acquisition
			 system.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H8EBD069F33884453AB1C5A1228AD4BC1" level="section">Sec. 202. Revision to duties of the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Developmental Test
			 and Evaluation and the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Systems
			 Engineering.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H8B37F8523A0844329F5739B439BFB250" level="section">Sec. 203. Acquisition strategy required for each major defense acquisition program and major
			 system.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCA0223206E86404097114747B27A7EDB" level="section">Sec. 204. Revision to requirements relating to risk management in development of major defense
			 acquisition programs and major systems.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H77CF1A1EFD00460FAB9A74DD7460BF37" level="section">Sec. 205. Modification to requirements relating to determination of contract type for major defense
			 acquisition programs and major systems.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6B7A0E8ABE7B4E9DA81E119C5D81B048" level="section">Sec. 206. Required determination before Milestone A approval or initiation of major defense
			 acquisition programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H934DB6625C3144DD9E30DD3CF4572FA6" level="section">Sec. 207. Required certification and determination before Milestone B approval of major defense
			 acquisition programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H54683CC9CC824AE78500B668AE7147FC" level="title">Title III—Services Contracting and Related Matters</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H8911589D1E434030AB8C6D9FF5AD8305" level="section">Sec. 301. Examination and guidance relating to oversight and approval of services contracts.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HA3471B9BD1E049CAA84E6E359CE5D5F7" level="title">Title IV—Information Technology Acquisitions and Related Matters</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC97F58B816AA4460A50929AFD63121D5" level="section">Sec. 401. Streamlining of requirements relating to defense business systems.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H97764127ABB84A1993177E5062357983" level="title">Title V—Industrial Base Matters</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7FD90856B78F4D25BBB3DCA646EB3892" level="section">Sec. 501. Codification and amendment of Mentor-Protege Program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF19FBDEC41FF4F5F89A78E6403E7158A" level="section">Sec. 502. Amendments to data quality improvement plan.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H3269E3116229403AA7E70C1E34F3003B" level="section">Sec. 503. Notice of contract consolidation for acquisition strategies.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB1318E168DDA404EA678FBE98C78EB8D" level="section">Sec. 504. Clarification of requirements related to small business contracts for services.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB379CC4C24754EA69BC873BFF1D41789" level="section">Sec. 505. Review of Government access to intellectual property rights of private sector firms.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6695D8679A67426380941E0123C99067" level="section">Sec. 506. Modifications to the Small Business Innovative Research Program and the Small Business
			 Technology Transfer Program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF87463C9B0BF41FFBE7B7C6D579F01E0" level="section">Sec. 507. Extension of defense research and development rapid innovation program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HAF682038F1774335AAD4871E0355A388" level="title">Title VI—Repeal or Revision of Reporting Requirements</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H107516E8F0934FDB89E35CF0B50C81F3" level="section">Sec. 601. Repeal of certain reporting requirements.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H75C06D2109FE4E8B86853581CB1C03EB" level="title">Title VII—Planning, Budgeting, Contracting, Oversight, and Other Related Matters</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H41E091FE950D4E5FAC74C2AF81F947B1" level="section">Sec. 701. Additional responsibility for Director of Operational Test and Evaluation.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H34018AF174CD4CE8A6185218E353B35B" level="section">Sec. 702. Report on linking and streamlining requirements, acquisition, and budget processes within
			 Armed Forces.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HFE5094126F574BA48248CE88D9FB3A38" level="section">Sec. 703. Required review of acquisition-related functions of the Chiefs of Staff of the Armed
			 Forces.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H0ACA188B95D5416DA15911EDC157BE96" level="section">Sec. 704. FAR Council membership for Administrator of Small Business Administration.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2F815DB598404682942419FF0191EBCB" level="section">Sec. 705. Independent study of matters related to bid protests.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HEA74F53D5B264378A3BAE11B89848347" level="section">Sec. 706. Procurement of commercial items.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H59A4AD15B7234868B9B505E75B612DBC" level="section">Sec. 707. Amendment relating to multiyear contract authority for acquisition of property.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H315978E7BCA1463B8C45517FAE5F77BD" level="section">Sec. 708. Use of recent prices paid by the Government in the determination of price reasonableness.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF8969FCDFD6E4BAFA93FE3E85C588902" level="section">Sec. 709. Codification of other transaction authority for certain prototype projects.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HFF17DFABBC4641239B44D2C6411143B8" level="section">Sec. 710. Amendments to certain acquisition thresholds.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H12266E8FB0A94F98AE67C6D8B67FB34A" level="section">Sec. 711. Revision of method of rounding when making inflation adjustment of acquisition-related
			 dollar thresholds.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7A8B74570638410B8A9C34CE313E2140" level="section">Sec. 712. Repeal of requirement for stand-alone manpower estimates for major defense acquisition
			 programs.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
		</section><section id="H3C84ED679800465B98472ED20839F488"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on the desired tenets of the defense acquisition system</header>
 <subsection id="HF75F66712FA54014A60C392E7AF14597"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7B0CF6E7694844FA9FFD673BA3090BD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives held a series of hearings in 2013, 2014, and 2015 gathering testimony from key acquisition leaders and experts. It is clear that the acquisition reform efforts of the last 50 years continue to founder because they fail to address the motivational and environmental factors in which they must be implemented. The acquisition system, though frustrating to all, is in one sense in equilibrium. The acquisition system provides enough benefits to proponents and opponents to continue, with only minor changes, despite its shortcomings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5D64907062B4075A29734CB432A211F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of Defense still has too many defense acquisitions and services chasing too few dollars. Consequently, there remains a vast difference between the budgeting plans of the Department and the reality of the cost of its systems or the services it acquires. To keep programs alive, the Department develops and Congress accepts fragile acquisition strategies that downplay technical issues and assume only successful outcomes from high-risk efforts. As a result, the Department often ends up with too few weapons, with performance that falls short, that are difficult and costly to maintain, delivered late at too high a cost. We have limited insight into the services acquired or what services need to be acquired in the future. Furthermore, the conventional acquisition process is not agile enough for today’s demands. Finally, the Department of Defense continues to struggle with financial management and auditability, affecting its ability to control costs, ensure basic accountability, anticipate future costs and claims on the budget, and measure performance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H640E68A45C43442088AAD839926F1BFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Too often today, all stakeholders in the Department of Defense, Congress, and industry, accept that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD6FCBA9D8EBE4D908AA63496764FBD27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the acquisition process, success is defined as maximizing technical performance or protecting organizational interests, without regard to funding disruptions and delivery delays of needed capability or services to the warfighter; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0EBF3C8F4364134971B7154D5C7EB98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the acquisition process is—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HFCAF433870D0436E9329E3D52212F8F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reactive, meaning issues are addressed late and at great cost only after problems are realized;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H4CBC7C6216BD474EAB7EEC6F3ECD99D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>plodding, meaning the bureaucratic processes are sclerotic and cumbersome;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H523FA9C4087747C18D2CCA0FF067BB24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>opaque, meaning that limiting information is necessary to protect programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD0F269C5EC274ABC8A62BDF36C1C946B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>traditional, meaning that customary approaches and suppliers are preferred over perceived risk of new or unique concepts and vendors.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F94F3B878F14A9289ACAC5AA160D142"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Today, the United States is at a cross-roads, and if changes to the acquisition system are not made soon, the trend of fewer and more costly systems and services that fall short of the needs of the Armed Forces will continue. Congress, the Department of Defense, contractors, and the American people all have a stake in making positive changes. Each plays a role in contributing to the current system. Each gains benefits from that system, but each is frustrated by it as well.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97706F8AF13A40EAB2ED83B0543DE3F9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The acquisition improvement effort of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives proposes a different approach from previous efforts by seeking to improve the environment (i.e., statutes, regulations, processes, and culture) driving acquisition decisions in the Department of Defense, industry, and Congress. The Committee has solicited input from industry and the Department of Defense, as well as others in Congress, and will continue to do so. The Committee recognizes that there are no <quote>silver bullets</quote> that can immediately fix the current acquisition system in a holistic and long-standing manner. Therefore, the reform effort will be an ongoing and iterative process that will result in legislation not only this year, but will be embedded in the Committee’s annual and regular work.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD07930B4095148908CCDAC8D1CBF2838"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress on the tenets of an improved acquisition system</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that all stakeholders in the acquisition system—the Department of Defense, Congress, and industry—should be governed by the following tenets:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA4107F8E2C546F18AE03DA5A5EA484A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Success</header><text>Success in the acquisition system means the timely delivering of affordable and effective military equipment and services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2FF2175C95FC45089CB8EA81E6A96FCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proactive</header><text>The acquisition system should be proactive, meaning—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7DFFB0C95D0040B49E6648DB1264DC60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the system should recognize that development and acquisition problems can occur; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7E15EA914279451EA68FA60BA1825301"><enum>(B)</enum><text>officials at all levels should be empowered to solve problems and reduce risks by surfacing issues early and honestly and taking action to resolve them.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6F038CD943D04576A62F7841D0B94DB2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agile</header><text>The acquisition system should be agile, meaning that needed program adjustments should be proposed and adjudicated quickly.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD51D7D08AAC348BB87D2C417D202295D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transparent</header><text>The acquisition system should be transparent, meaning that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H91E3516FE8F8475D90CCD4E171A1FE8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all decisionmakers should be given useful, relevant, credible, and reliable information when making commitments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5A6DCEFE9019475C9A6177FF95F20854"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Government and industry communication should be clear and open; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD10C00BFC52A49F4864E528C22CE9BF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Defense should produce auditable financial management statements.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H46A910D9CC444EC2B6973062FB446554"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Innovative</header><text>The acquisition system should be innovative, meaning that barriers should be removed that preclude companies from undertaking defense business or officials from proposing new approaches.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><title id="H700897A2F97D41328B477ECCBCB13A1A"><enum>I</enum><header>Workforce Development and Related Matters</header>
			<section id="H1B01CAF8751847209C16CC52D3B4961D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>101.</enum><header>Amendments to Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H39A95A5598134EF0B5B5B14BF00A1A79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permanent extension of fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1705(d)(2) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE4A3C0AFAF26431692C704123B2E7ED4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>of an amount as follows:</quote> and all that follows through the end, and inserting <quote>of an amount of not less than $500,000,000.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB83F5D65F794408599ABE62816457C68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>an amount that is less than</quote> and all that follows through the end, and inserting <quote>an amount that is less than $400,000,000</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2708655867647C6A7C6BCE413D14FAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permanent extension of expedited hiring authority</header><text>Section 1705(g) of such title is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9A872C08DC7044ECA5CB146F245D3109"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6856A22D147B4EEFB0D7C242FE5A106D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Authority.—</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows through <quote>For purposes of</quote> in paragraph (1) and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Authority.—</header-in-text>For purposes of</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91257591DC9E4514B1830295E0A8B2C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>(1)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF61EEDB0E2C54F019B0F4A1405A81EAE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>(2)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F9803476D654057AEB51CDE676EB833"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification of acquisition workforce covered</header><text>Section 1705(g) of such title, as amended by subsection (c), is further amended by striking <quote>acquisition workforce positions</quote> and inserting <quote>of positions in the acquisition workforce, as defined in subsection (h),</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H5E0141D775804C9B82801B0B751C3CCA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum><header>Dual-track military professionals in operational and acquisition specialities</header> <subsection id="H5C08ACE2B1764690B831726F1518ACCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for service chief involvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1722a(a) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <quote>military department)</quote> the following: <quote>, in collaboration with the Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, and the Commandant of the Marine Corps (with respect to the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps, respectively),</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6905FF31A5FA41ED8E2FBE3744F5D915"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dual-Track Career Path</header><text>Section 1722a(b) of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFCC812AB4E834B3A956082A5CEE19E87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2B11412ABFC408FBEB048B1151ECE1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>single-track</quote> before <quote>career path</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H803DBE054C234B2FA45C6AE616B9D1B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph (2):</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75D71A9199614DFAB2C1B95532B8F182" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H9A59E0AD535B43CEAF151CB55EF36D58"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A dual-track career path that attracts the highest quality officers and enlisted personnel and allows them to gain experience in and receive credit for a primary career in combat arms and a functional secondary career in the acquisition field in order to more closely align the military operational, requirements, and acquisition workforces of each armed force.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4821E6D8198B4886B3E1274630D3468E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>103.</enum><header>Provision of joint duty assignment credit for acquisition duty</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 668(a)(1) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF0F9FED52FD74BF59556021554DC42BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (D);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5F0FF9CA887489B8DBB4F80419951B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (E) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H09C3B5A093E8426DA41B21D43611A551"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B94EC144EAF49F19517DC1ECB2E9B42" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="H253E8D7D4E734BE48A8682E827A84DD6" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquisition matters addressed by military personnel and covered under chapter 87 of this title.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="H2746E4EE1BB64DE7AE7FABB54B502FCF"><enum>104.</enum><header>Requirement for acquisition skills assessment biennial strategic workforce plan</header> <subsection id="HC13D7050B2764EE3A5876EB16C098FBA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 115b(b)(1) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8C036D8BC3944360B3BE651C63B22D6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DAD8D5C2AF445BABBF3C23757BE33AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95EBE055517D47009232B4564CD424A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F6E26DE63F3489BB54507502FC87904" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H89F4DD52CB99458DA495C246129870B2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>new or expanded critical skills and competencies needed by the existing civilian employee workforce of the Department to address new acquisition process requirements established by law or policy during the four years preceding the year of submission of the plan; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6574F1F4E6AD42378F966A9F12BC3C4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 115b of such title is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="H498606D9A6D7401784BD202AE4AF7C29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E) of subsection (b)(1), as redesignated by subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>(C)</quote> and inserting <quote>(D)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCABB8F6AECA44B7A2CDDD32CC263640"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) of subsection (b), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>(1)(D)</quote> and inserting <quote>(1)(E)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD6B3290ED904B82B6FFA54C957A8EF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A) of each of subsections (c), (d), and (e), by striking <quote>through (D)</quote> and inserting <quote>through (E)</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H260D37666F0944F999106F4D1B6AABB9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>105.</enum><header>Mandatory requirement for training related to the conduct of market research</header>
 <subsection id="H7F724524818045C288BAF4B066746D59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory market research training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2377 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H1A973CEF547F4371A4C4D9B5E57C277D">
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA77B1D0C2F3B4FB1AE97A2739351DCBE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Market research training required</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall provide mandatory training for members of the armed forces and employees of the Department of Defense responsible for the conduct of market research required under subsection (c). Such mandatory training shall, at a minimum—</text>
 <paragraph id="H63685DE2DA024E048A78022B7AFEAEE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide comprehensive information on the subject of market research and the function of market research in the acquisition of commercial items;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C400120A6C24ADE9E9AC0B577FB5C26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>teach best practices for conducting and documenting market research; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4084A4735CF34E2A93CB60D3A2136252"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide methodologies for establishing standard processes and reports for collecting and sharing market research across the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE39B93E616B84E418E66EE9A0D80422B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Incorporation into management certification training mandate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff shall ensure that the requirements of section 2377(d) of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), are incorporated into the requirements management certification training mandate of the Joint Capabilities Integration Development System.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H6E3ACF5C5FAF4CF181841074D935C971" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>106.</enum><header>Independent study of implementation of defense acquisition workforce improvement efforts</header>
 <subsection id="H18EB6DD8E7DA4EDEAED7E076F230C5FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall enter into a contract with an independent research entity described in subsection (b) to carry out a comprehensive study of the strategic planning of the Department of Defense related to the defense acquisition workforce. The study shall provide a comprehensive examination of the Department’s efforts to recruit, develop, and retain the acquisition workforce with a specific review of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H641DCF8985364FCB849721E0C1A8439E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The implementation of the Defense Acquisition Workforce Improvement Act (including <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/87">chapter 87</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43C3C0247AA042F0987E695E4F29783E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The application of the Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund (as established under section 1705 of title 10, United States Code).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBE94228A8CC438A94077AD9674FEFFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The effectiveness of professional military education programs, including fellowships and exchanges with industry.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0848FA1B90D4305B54F05E353AA8BF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Independent research entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The entity described in this subsection is an independent research entity that is a not-for-profit entity or a federally funded research and development center with appropriate expertise and analytical capability.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H459DD9E76A084614844C24CF47BE3137"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H67A39E89B0FE4B27A7027191DCD02F04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>To Secretary</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the independent research entity shall provide to the Secretary a report containing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBEAC3CBD08CA4D968060901E86CE302C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the study required by subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97D65749D95546F8B2A74C282ED3A1F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations to improve the acquisition workforce as the independent research entity considers to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA107CFB2B5474E3DB49E4886B922554A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>To Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receipt of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall submit such report, together with any additional views or recommendations of the Secretary, to the congressional defense committees.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HBFBFC1EB6233432184D2D687EF35F421"><enum>II</enum><header>Weapon Systems Acquisition and Related Matters</header>
			<section id="H5AF35953AA7340DEB2A2461E74F51141"><enum>201.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on the desired characteristics for the weapon systems acquisition system</header>
 <subsection id="H64B17EC270F3486F9977DA3697058730"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HCF0872F0A8414E47A4C3415A3A24B0A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Current situation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite significant and repeated attempts at acquisition reform, the Department of Defense still experiences case after case of expensive weapon system acquisition failures. The Department of Defense has a track record of too many cancellations, schedule slippages, cost over-runs, and failures to deliver timely solutions to the requirements of the Armed Forces. This situation is unacceptable. For example, according to the Final Report of the 2010 Army Acquisition Review, between 1996 and 2010, the Army expended approximately $1 billion to $3 billion annually on two dozen programs that were eventually cancelled. No military service and no type of weapon acquisition has been immune.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE24744262449C6B8393DCA9F2696DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Problems in all phases of acquisitions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2DC7F5A333304046AE777A64F9C10C20"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite detailed weapon acquisition processes and procedures, there is only limited discipline in starting programs. Many programs begin without a solid foundation. They have too many requirements deemed <quote>critical</quote>, which are driven by too many organizations and individuals. Approved requirements are often set with only a limited understanding of the technical feasibility of achieving them. The resulting compromises of good program management and engineering judgment that allow the programs to proceed are the <quote>spackle</quote> of the acquisition system that covers up the risks and enables the system to operate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBB2FF4BBB7D48D5BE69BEA41F33DB1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As these weapon systems proceed into engineering and manufacturing development, they often encounter development problems leading to cost growth, schedule delay, and performance reductions. Industry and Government officials frequently respond by taking additional development risks to resolve basic performance issues by reducing the time to analyze and assess development results, overlapping key development efforts, and reducing testing. The Department of Defense and Congress disrupt the planned funding of stable programs to find resources for troubled programs or to fund across-the-board spending cuts. Funding instability is the inevitable price that programs pay for survival because funding disruptions actually keep more programs alive.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9222A518ADF54496B473ACDF8B1EC09C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Finally, these weapons are often rushed into production only to encounter production problems, and are fielded with many unknowns or deficiencies leading to significantly reduced quantities and force structure reductions. The warfighter faces the challenge of operating weapons with poor reliability, high maintenance demands, reduced performance, and many capability shortfalls.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14BDEA9AF368410AAD5F63C4BE59BB8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="HDA3BD2BB9D8F4927A3AD8CEB9736FBD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that, in accordance with the tenets described in section 3, to improve weapon system acquisitions, the Department of Defense, Congress, and industry should develop an acquisition system characterized by highly disciplined program initiation coupled with agile program execution and balanced oversight, as described in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0841B883F4345789B3AC7CE529579EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Highly disciplined program initiation</header><text>An acquisition system characterized by highly disciplined program initiation means that programs do not begin engineering development until firm requirements are matched to a flexible acquisition strategy structured to develop militarily useful capability that can be delivered in a relevant period of time with available technologies, funding, and management capacity. Such a highly disciplined program initiation includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7D09A1044D474BD7881AB6AC224C7989"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a workforce with smart requirements setters and expert buyers, with the knowledge, skills, and experience to successfully plan for and execute highly complex acquisitions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75C7CA16BBA54CE199CD75026D28D972"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requirements that are well-defined, technically feasible, and affordable;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45A6B7DF28B84B87BB7172BDDDFF0DEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>acquisition strategies that are designed to minimize time to market of militarily useful capability, with the program concerned being structured so that—</text>
 <clause id="H6F48F363C97F4F61A5722B328985C65C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lower-risk, technically mature capabilities are matched to delivering capability to the warfighter in the near term, while remaining requirements are aligned and resources are programmed to support integration into later increments to meet the requirements of the Armed Forces;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA74912F5B6E943DAA739A3454C449117"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>capabilities are approved for an increment only when their developmental risks have been appropriately reduced; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7029E847C4AF4D8EAAC1BBE3CE2EFEC7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increments are planned to complete engineering and manufacturing development in a reasonable period of time;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDE341A4AB9642918DD736146ACF09F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a science and technology development enterprise that is responsive to the acquisition process before engineering and manufacturing development begins, and sufficiently resourced to reduce risks and enable programs to make smart decisions without losing critical funds; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF99F6A8D0334F43BA8182E8498F5DD0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>redtape reduction in order to free up program and Department officials to focus on their mission of defining an executable program and understanding and addressing risks.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CBC1A04F5D24307A6FAE0EC8A93288E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agile program execution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An acquisition system characterized by agile program execution means a system in which acquisition speed and flexibility to make trade-offs are balanced with the need to achieve desired technical performance. Such agile program execution includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE68427027454A92A2C38EDF0EDE7977"><enum>(A)</enum><text>program managers and program officials who are expert buyers and negotiators who anticipate problems, negotiate solutions, and are empowered to manage;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90E273BAE4DE4CFCBC9568090F58BE3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a preference for fixed price development, with program initiation laying the foundation in which fixed price contracting is the appropriate contract type for product development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FF4E904296744AC89F0AEEFA7B8E71D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>program managers who avoid increasing program risk by resisting the addition of new requirements or the reduction of developmental activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC69E81FEFE24E78B9BE53B5E0FCD571"><enum>(D)</enum><text>empowering program managers and senior decisionmakers to make decisions easily in order to move forward with capabilities that mature quickly, cancel those that encounter greater difficulties than expected, and trade-off or reduce requirements to maintain cost and schedule;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02A1648554AF4B529DE3B29256827543"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enabling program managers to focus on overcoming execution challenges and delivering success rather than concentrating on compliance with reporting, certifications, and other redtape; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D7B2A87447E4C1890DD3B364C1D03CE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>senior decisionmakers who have knowledge of demonstrated performance as programs proceed through development, with robust developmental testing occurring before committing to production for operational use as a basis for decisionmaking.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46A03589CCFD4683A42D45E70A5B75BF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Balanced Oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An acquisition system characterized by balanced oversight means that the focus is on ensuring discipline initiating programs and that appropriate adjustments are made during development, so that programs have the best chance to succeed. Such balanced oversight includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF48E8299794C460E901D7AA736BD3D7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>involvement by decisionmakers early to ensure that an understanding of trade-offs, risks, and needs are considered, resourced, and validated, and that agreement is reached between the executive and legislative branches;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC37474EBFF04351A279C7CD73336232"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acceptance by decisionmakers that complex weapon system developments are inherently risky and require expertise and flexibility to manage effectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C49DE8C7B8F42F1896F6F5E84228403"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conscious decisions by decisionmakers regarding where to accept risk, while ensuring that risk mitigation plans are resourced (with time, funding, alternatives, and competent government and contractor officials);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27BB5CE52AFB4512B121CB972E57CB2D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>measuring and monitoring by decisionmakers of the right factors, such as technology maturation progress and systems engineering during risk reduction, development cost growth during engineering and manufacturing development, and reliability growth during system demonstration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4C556B49023493684B08C3F785B65F0"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work by Congress and the Department of Defense, once a program has begun, to resolve issues by considering trade-offs among cost, schedule, and performance necessary to best support the warfighter; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H211F62DFD7994D4AA0C0551FEC01F71A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">congressional understanding of risks and efforts to mitigate such risks even if they are through non-traditional means or other technological advances.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8EBD069F33884453AB1C5A1228AD4BC1"><enum>202.</enum><header>Revision to duties of the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Developmental Test and
			 Evaluation and the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Systems
 Engineering</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 139b of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF6D55F01BC084F429B4F080813DAE6C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(5)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAC58891E04B342EAAF28CE0B9988396E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>review and approve or disapprove</quote> and inserting <quote>advise in writing the milestone decision authority regarding review and approval of</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C5D76C50D7F47EDABF19DE44AC67112"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>in order to advise relevant technical authorities for such programs on the incorporation of best practices for developmental test from across the Department</quote> after <quote>programs</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C7D9C1B0A1F4EC099C6973C9F1CA659"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(5)—</text> <subparagraph id="H03692C65F7FF43DF8210C7BBE5395FB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>review and approve</quote> and inserting <quote>advise in writing the milestone decision authority regarding review and approval of</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A3860CABAAA4D6CBDD9844D13DD6885"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>in order to advise relevant technical authorities for such programs on the incorporation of best practices for systems engineering from across the Department</quote> after <quote>programs</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H8B37F8523A0844329F5739B439BFB250"><enum>203.</enum><header>Acquisition strategy required for each major defense acquisition program and major system</header>
				<subsection id="HFD1D4C9743784E7A828B91A18F09C872"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consolidation of requirements relating to acquisition strategy</header>
 <paragraph id="H617F56C6A1424D568F07714498E04D61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New title 10 section</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/144">Chapter 144</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2431">section 2431</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H342B7603F5DC4750BC37F47C8F2D747F" style="USC">
							<section id="HB96C038E9B4B4A82ACD07CCA48B41266"><enum>2431a.</enum><header>Acquisition strategy</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C10AEDEC9D54C6E9095F13F97B9B18B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acquisition strategy required</header><text>There shall be an acquisition strategy for each major defense acquisition program and each major system approved by a Milestone Decision Authority.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFBE54ADF3C8242168BA6206A4A24778D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsible official</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each acquisition strategy required by subsection (a), the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics is responsible for issuing and maintaining the requirements for—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA44BA52DA27B4C18850B949668C092D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the content of the strategy; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C66D2B3BFF241E383930196098592AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the review and approval process for the strategy.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5438DCC7B755409DA19442211B837C85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H98D98108BCAA4903A452513DDDF77A7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In issuing requirements for the content of an acquisition strategy for a major defense acquisition program or major system, the Under Secretary shall ensure that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1B65138F67EE423E939705DE82382F3F" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the strategy clearly describes the proposed business and technical management approach for the program or system, in sufficient detail to allow the Milestone Decision Authority to assess the viability of the proposed approach;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1695F99B6E0440FCB52074D5614548E0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the strategy contains a clear explanation of how the strategy is designed to be implemented with available resources, such as time, funding, and management capacity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6E8D5813D914CDE89162154DA14277B" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the strategy considers the items listed in paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EB3825D17084CE1A89888859CDDE0AF" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each strategy shall, at a minimum, consider the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H431409705819424E863331C96EBB76AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An approach that delivers required capability in increments, each depending on available mature technology, and that recognizes up front the need for future capability improvements.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A71E82E91584A6595485E40B63AD233"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Acquisition approach, including industrial base considerations in accordance with section 2440 of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6827E822212D46BEA6BF2F6CCED3D5C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Risk management, including such methods as competitive prototyping at the system, subsystem, or component level, in accordance with section 2431b of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB542141B57DF46B599C93BDE254BAF37"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Business strategy, including measures to ensure competition at the system and subsystem level throughout the life-cycle of the program or system in accordance with section 2337 of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H880C861B5F974AA295F546B7F7444C13"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Contracting strategy, including—</text> <clause id="HBE195D5DBCF6440588AAF17722A61BFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contract type and how the type selected relates to level of program risk in each acquisition phase;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA6DC3D5682E949B48F2EEC2CCCBF8A49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how the plans for the program or system to reduce risk enable the use of fixed-price elements in subsequent contracts and the timing of the use of those fixed price elements;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9FE6D67A704F42F5A612D473D1AF6521"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>market research; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2A0634C076AD4A4FBAA94387BCAF03F9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>consideration of small business participation.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H926CF79F91984033AE5327652538D3DD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Intellectual property strategy in accordance with section 2320 of this title.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFFD97BC8D3A4D8BA91BFB9E81118978"><enum>(G)</enum><text>International involvement, including foreign military sales and cooperative opportunities, in accordance with section 2350a of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8695BBFF1FA74FFB90B3683C88F83624"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Multi-year procurement in accordance with section 2306b of this title.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20A700D4FEAC456AAD85C2A08EC168AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Integration of current intelligence assessments into the acquisition process.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA364023F1714475EBC186C86696FF4A7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H78575700F6734ED2BD4C6B3C9AD055A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics, the Milestone Decision Authority shall review and approve, as appropriate, the acquisition strategy for a major defense acquisition program or major system at each of the following times:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEEEBC723936746AFBA879EF148F2188C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Milestone A approval.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BC9AFB684354BCFAFC059D34E5391B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The decision to release the request for proposals for development of the program or system.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB65B4BC6435649DC83C4EA84F2DDA464"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Milestone B approval.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C9623BCEA0048CEB0A3B348B325824B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Each subsequent milestone.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22AE2EF02DD14A02A9B01346F019D617"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Review of any decision to enter into full-rate production.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E27B45827E6412A8BFF729FB0D7B178"><enum>(F)</enum><text>When there has been—</text>
 <clause id="H5FE57469B10B4CB4AFCF8DEB40426D66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a significant change to the cost of the program or system;</text> </clause><clause id="H6124C9E15CB645D2BE58181CCAB91732"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a critical change to the cost of the program or system;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H99B08E4517664482BE0573B8ECC5C693"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a significant change to the schedule of the program or system; or</text> </clause><clause id="HD41807655911485D850AFA1B4719113F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a significant change to the performance of the program or system.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H542CD4B92A1F4A7BA3D17470FDC4832C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other time considered relevant by the Milestone Decision Authority.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5532912D773749F2A2FF4F76C618619A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Milestone Decision Authority revises an acquisition strategy for a program or system, the Milestone Decision Authority shall provide notice of the revision to the congressional defense committees.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A93319C605A479EB065EBF9DE2E008B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H97D168620EA841C8A30FF8F15BAE860C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>major defense acquisition program</quote> has the meaning provided in section 2430 of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3768939516284C61A8C8F552CD5835C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>major system</quote> has the meaning provided in section 2302(5) of this title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6421376712304CCC9BF0107B66E2C49E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Milestone A approval</quote> means a decision to enter into technology maturation and risk reduction pursuant to guidance prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for the management of Department of Defense acquisition programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEAE0523B3CC41F182155EE2920B6920"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Milestone B approval</quote> has the meaning provided in section 2366(e)(7) of this title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFE9D121506C4750B296A309BB2C861F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>Milestone Decision Authority</quote>, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means the official within the Department of Defense designated with the overall responsibility and authority for acquisition decisions for the program or system, including authority to approve entry of the program or system into the next phase of the acquisition process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AC7C9E3D70F4D87ADBA21162327267E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <quote>management capacity</quote>, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means the capacity to manage the program or system through the use of highly qualified organizations and personnel with appropriate experience, knowledge, and skills.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB6332ADC80C4832AD5BDCB92E4F9504"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <quote>significant change to the cost</quote>, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means a significant cost growth threshold, as that term is defined in section 2433(a)(4) of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EBA7D8174AE42DEA9AB31E328FB653E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <quote>critical change to the cost</quote>, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means a critical cost growth threshold, as that term is defined in section 2433(a)(5) of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6822BCB1543D4CA695580199FF256472"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>significant change to the schedule</quote>, with respect to a major defense acquisition program or major system, means any schedule delay greater than six months in a reported event.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1DD740F2979C4E98AC77E0FA122F772D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Submission to congressional committees</header><text>Upon request by the chairman or ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate or the House of Representatives, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the committee the most recently approved acquisition strategy for a major defense acquisition program or major system. The strategy shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F73A1B63C0D4D64B27803071B6DAE61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2431 the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HDBB3E73DDE3642679566E1B111ACD05B" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">2431a. Acquisition strategy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H604DA6D08C6E46B59C678B3296D2FFB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header> Additional amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H9D4687414FEF493DAE3B09B1C64BC09C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 2350a(e) of such title is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H6BA08AC1D07A4C0D8DEFAE79C68C1883"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Document</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53B0F020D35249F9911A94155141AD4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the Under Secretary of Defense for</quote> and all that follows through <quote>of the Board</quote> and inserting <quote>opportunities for such cooperative research and development shall be addressed in the acquisition strategy for the project</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4B22891AA40472991BE2FB37979A2E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="H8852EBA2096D46288FFE07AC12E96CD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <subclause id="H65F8246BD5EF4DB1AC4CDCEDE1C77DB4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>document</quote> and inserting <quote>discussion</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2B6C489CAC4C4E709C2F848AA6A3A633"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>include</quote> and inserting <quote>consider</quote>;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0C1657A16DCF48D6A4D4407C0F82F7C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>A statement indicating whether</quote> and inserting <quote>Whether</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H2C9799C845B443E6B16A6DB2B6A74739"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text>
 <subclause id="H9ADA7CC7127C4723993A689EBC6AA934"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H89F3F0319EEB48C5B98FB4594EFE8863"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of the United States under consideration by the Department of Defense</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCA10150ED97A4191AD4CE09AECCA4FA5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>The recommendation of the Under Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>A recommendation to the Milestone Decision Authority</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H237785D6659449FEA3E9E1E8322EA1DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 803 of the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/314">Public Law 107–314</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2430">10 U.S.C. 2430</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCA0223206E86404097114747B27A7EDB"><enum>204.</enum><header>Revision to requirements relating to risk management in development of major defense acquisition
			 programs and major systems</header>
				<subsection id="H9C44B54F9AAD40389BA911D20671F370"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Risk management and mitigation requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HC8D9F42380FD490FABCCE014FDFEF31B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/144">Chapter 144</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2431a">section 2431a</external-xref> (as added by section 203) the following new section:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H8267543857D94DBE8F8FA74E8DCA7D7E" style="USC">
							<section commented="no" id="HC84C7B32E8AE429CBEBFE8A4D9403FCF"><enum>2431b.</enum><header>Risk management and mitigation in major defense acquisition programs and major systems</header>
								<subsection commented="no" id="HF6078D8A2C304A4A950B637C4490E5BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H52947F8269944E59A3DBA5CB836D6E2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be a risk management and mitigation strategy for each major defense acquisition program or major system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H52AC97B92A5242C1A1F14E3881AB1E92" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the initial acquisition strategy (required under section 2431a of this title) approved by the Milestone Decision Authority and any subsequent revisions include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDF39391D4AE545B092990523CB9B010C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A comprehensive strategy for managing and mitigating risk (including technical, cost, and schedule risk) during each of the following periods:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H7C973F4F65DB4B76B5FFA43EC2BA3976"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The period preceding engineering manufacturing development, or its equivalent.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1E2B71B755E14337A7160405DA88F040"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The period preceding initial production.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HBFA8568A761F46FB846A2DD236C073D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The period preceding full-rate production.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEFE315C4648741F4A4F11F459E28620C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An identification of the major sources of risk in each of the periods listed in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD6187B5F0CE540148409CD9907743936" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the case of a program or system with separate increments of capabilities that require Milestone Decision Authority approval to begin or proceed, paragraphs (1) and (2) shall apply to each increment.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H54B0C8BFD21A41D3ABA07E7C5B4731DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy To Manage and Mitigate Risks</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0E4989AD718C47D9ACE83CDA3A72ED96"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The comprehensive strategy to manage and mitigate risk included in the acquisition strategy for purposes of subsection (a)(2)(A) shall identify each individual risk and the risk management and mitigation activities to address each risk. For the mitigation activities identified, the strategy shall note whether they require cost and schedule margins and need to be included in funding requests.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC4AB6AF855D24B2CB2BDFFC11A4DFB07" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The comprehensive strategy shall include the role and extent of the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF1A3537DB8F846BEBAE530E6B6F9EBB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Prototyping (including prototyping at the system, subsystem, or component level and competitive prototyping, where appropriate) and, if prototyping at either the system, subsystem, or component level is not used, an explanation of why it is not appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3227FF5D4B84131AB1C8A810152E466"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Modeling and simulation, the areas that modeling and simulation will assess, and identification of the need for development of any new modeling and simulation tools in order to support the comprehensive strategy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC322FBD16AAD4FE59F629CF54B86CC1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technology demonstrations and decision points for disciplined transition of planned technologies into programs or the selection of alternative technologies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H77620B867CFC4FC4AEBFB16729B6AADE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Multiple design approaches.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H27F34BCA021B4EE5A759E3A29657D9DD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Alternative designs, including any designs that meet requirements but do so with reduced performance.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B4F9C57DFAB479B9A502E755F8653D5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Phasing of program activities or related technology development efforts in order to address high risk areas as early as feasible.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5173628F2B8B4E07A1924AA277F1F039"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <quote>major defense acquisition program</quote> and <quote>major system</quote> have the meanings provided in section 2431a of this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FB859C59FB24D4E9E44C9FD3F8010EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2431a, as so added, the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H808BD61FF26C4EEDB4C667A843469459" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">2431b. Risk management and mitigation in major defense acquisition programs and major systems.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10F96FFF56164495AC5103C13CC5B80D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of superseded provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203 of the Weapon Systems Acquisition Reform Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2430">10 U.S.C. 2430</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H77CF1A1EFD00460FAB9A74DD7460BF37"><enum>205.</enum><header>Modification to requirements relating to determination of contract type for major defense acquisition programs and major systems</header> <subsection id="H3C1EC3854A624852A5F6F21F2DFE592D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination of contract type</header><text>Section 2306 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E50810B3F2947A8BFF04F70D610F3E4" style="USC">
						<subsection id="HAA10D012340E4083BC68103CC2F42D32"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Required elements of guidance relating to contract type</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H633919BC26A44F1792573C1AC90AF5B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the guidance of the Department of Defense relating to major defense acquisition programs, major systems, and major automated information systems includes a requirement that the acquisition strategy required under section 2431a of this title for such a program or system includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H444AEC74509741168282B3A0E7B7095B" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a separate identification of the contract type for each acquisition phase of the program or system; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BF12EEA6CC441E7BF2092B0778A1DE4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a justification of the contract type identified.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF01B7DE98A04C619F1F6BC4ED8B2581" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The contract type identified in accordance with paragraph (1)(A) may be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H47883712E2794B92B7419C8E7F095B3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a fixed-price type contract (including a fixed-price incentive contract); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4899DB911AD64BF9AD79CF356C0DEBAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a cost-type contract (including a cost-plus-incentive-fee contract).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FF5D34AA2A94602BE908DB12CE2B02C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The guidance referred to in paragraph (1) shall require that the justification for the contract type selected explain—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H54E88B33C0284DB48B6A6ECA86414FBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the level of program risk in each acquisition phase relates to the contract type selected;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC8E476F9EFF4186A0A38329E2E385BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the use of incentives (especially cost incentives) in the contract, if any, supports the program or system objectives during each acquisition phase; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H011BBACC21A24A2988B9A716EE536732"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the plans for the program or system to reduce risk enable the use of fixed-price elements in subsequent contracts.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B4035174AA240F0B7AD79C8BE591712" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The guidance shall also specify that the use of contracts with target costs, target profits or fees, and profit or fee adjustment formulas can be an appropriate contract type.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H49C7015F21524342A6B914C005D27F59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Section 818 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/364">Public Law 109–364</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2306">10 U.S.C. 2306</external-xref> note) is amended by striking subsections (b), (c), (d), and (e).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H6B7A0E8ABE7B4E9DA81E119C5D81B048" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>206.</enum><header>Required determination before Milestone A approval or initiation of major defense acquisition
			 programs</header>
 <subsection id="H4FCD387CED884FECB07A39D3765A3851"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination rather than certification required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 2366a of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H54D571E762E44E88B5A1CF95F88F08D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Certification</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Written determination required</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H305163C0C9E140FABB8B367153BA38F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>certifies</quote> and inserting <quote>determines, in writing,</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF912612E28F4A8CB2CB74933B97E73F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of written determination to congress</header><text>Subsection (b) of such section is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8667A1928D0D48BA88800FFF2BA44E92" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H33B339B948CE482B89F5047444365C78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of any of the congressional defense committees, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the committee an explanation of the basis for a determination made under subsection (a) with respect to a major defense acquisition program, together with a copy of the written determination. The explanation shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2427D0439A544072A89D81E1420496A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeal of unused definitions</header><text>Subsection (c) of such section is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE2AB162E68D144BCB1F048F992C0614F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (4); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BED9BE6B39E48D9BEC22C078AF3F069"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3), (5), (6), and (7) as paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5), respectively.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC3AEA21A3D944AFA186989EE4F2C253"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H25A9CE81786840F28EE41CE8DB3338EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section heading</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heading of section 2366a of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FF869EFCE2148AB8B83422014B20363" style="USC"> <section id="H9E78C5763E6E4D97A96A144F24BDDF83"><enum>2366a.</enum><header>Major defense acquisition programs: determination required before Milestone A approval</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1198AE020D4ACFAFD2A6A43592A692"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 139 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 2366a and inserting the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H120599B7C7134AC49EF6A935F19ACEDB" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">2366a. Major defense acquisition programs: determination required before Milestone A approval.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H934DB6625C3144DD9E30DD3CF4572FA6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>207.</enum><header>Required certification and determination before Milestone B approval of major defense acquisition
			 programs</header>
 <subsection id="H743060EE2A1B4FFB932F1BC20DD2940A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination required in addition to certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 2366b of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDB621AB2F34A4831B276F7D01FE8571E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Certification</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Certification and determination required</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0431D252F60B41D5A4529FE559CB56B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H368E4FB8367242238340C0CD91101F71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(3) further certifies that—</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1C38F38B5A5402C8A726C4C5B7D6EF0" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HA7A6D7266FD44A80BA51115494808F96"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">further certifies that the technology in the program has been demonstrated in a relevant environment, as determined by the Milestone Decision Authority on the basis of an independent review and assessment by the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, in consultation with the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Developmental Test and Evaluation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63F3AAB011CD4FE0ABFD5BF854F6D1FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines, in writing, that—</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B0BC7857A914D7E9CC732944C18F82E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of written determination to congress</header><text>Subsection (c) of such section is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA99441380E442E4B23B1E13E07BC56D" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H55540F973BA646E9A2CDDEBDB92BEBFC" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of any of the congressional defense committees, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the committee an explanation of the basis for a determination made under subsection (a)(4) with respect to a major defense acquisition program, together with a copy of the written determination. The explanation shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC68811EAEC1347ED83ED5172FC94C16A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text>Subsection (d) of such section is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H43481F74664F4FC0ABC9541B969606F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>certification requirement</quote> and inserting <quote>certification and determination requirements</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H491CCD0EFA40458891C9A66193DC4527"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD9CAF74AAAEB4D2EB6E0A6FA02F757CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) and in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>waiver</quote> before <quote>determination</quote> each place it appears; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87A459ED98E64511A39E3A48F9A689CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>certification components</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>certification and determination components</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F0EF25F57224E7F8895D37E61B67177"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2366b of title 10, United States Code, is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H19DED3D2E6614497913FFE0859D720D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H711ACC85A9B548E6959A6510327F4CB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (a)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DB7B91F8CC94E4A8C5A86060B327334"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)(B), by striking <quote>paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (a)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63CA4E2F195D4EFBA656F790D27C685D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header> <paragraph id="HC8DB3ADBF5BA44E8B187DD5CCE623456"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section heading</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heading of section 2366b of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7E8135B5C9748AC9EC88B67396E98F9" style="USC">
							<section id="H4F5B37DDFFFC4788B7A01C31DCCEEBB3"><enum>2366b.</enum><header>Major defense acquisition programs: certification and determination required before Milestone B
			 approval</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE517C5920ABF444D8C4643B1897ADD8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 139 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 2366b and inserting the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42212C8D14DB4557B9B22EA140D7BF7B" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">2366b. Major defense acquisition programs: certification and determination required before
			 Milestone B approval.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H54683CC9CC824AE78500B668AE7147FC"><enum>III</enum><header>Services Contracting and Related Matters</header>
 <section id="H8911589D1E434030AB8C6D9FF5AD8305" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>301.</enum><header>Examination and guidance relating to oversight and approval of services contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than September 15, 2015, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7F0324DF44BC47989E6438D31680BA2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complete an examination of the decision authority related to acquisition of services; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BAEC5A661674A329DC1D8C47BC675C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and issue guidance to improve capabilities and processes related to requirements development and source selection for, and oversight and management of, services contracts.</text>
				</paragraph></section></title><title id="HA3471B9BD1E049CAA84E6E359CE5D5F7"><enum>IV</enum><header>Information Technology Acquisitions and Related Matters</header>
			<section id="HC97F58B816AA4460A50929AFD63121D5"><enum>401.</enum><header>Streamlining of requirements relating to defense business systems</header>
				<subsection id="H871D31EC685441C187313A231BA989B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H682E114D7F664D30B1E3C72EEC0ACAF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Revision</header><text>Section 2222 of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H343308F08FC6448AA2E45804DABC9C1B" style="USC"> <section id="HBD0FED0AD49549D6841C7E09488ABC87"><enum>2222.</enum><header>Defense business systems: business process reengineering; enterprise architecture; management</header> <subsection id="H3AA214893A0942BAB4C1EF94F2533C66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Defense business systems generally</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each covered defense business system developed, deployed, and operated by the Department of Defense—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC5C1667004DE47FEA807C000D012B459"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports efficient business processes that have been reviewed, and as appropriate revised, through business process reengineering;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0321C497A7DA4A6C90AE1338F2C1E7E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is integrated into a comprehensive defense business enterprise architecture; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FAEEB41F7B149AA9A45E3F4AE2EC022"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is managed in a manner that provides visibility into, and traceability of, expenditures for the system.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA11E15AB7F344C6A1A06928F09696FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuance of guidance</header>
 <paragraph id="H45778D1E0E5445C69E2570F34D0EE66F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary of defense guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall issue guidance to provide for the coordination of, and decisionmaking for, the planning, programming, and control of investments in covered defense business systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4C01E9EEADD41AC8B65EA1D7C3FC829"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supporting guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall direct the Deputy Chief Management Officer of the Department of Defense, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics, the Chief Information Officer, and the Chief Management Officer of each of the military departments to issue and maintain supporting guidance, as appropriate, for the guidance of the Secretary issued under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD86689851610443A9900751C143BC58B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance elements</header><text>The guidance issued under subsection (b)(1) shall include the following elements:</text> <paragraph id="H8BB5EF8DDF0645809CC8EDE25B29EF48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Policy to ensure that the business processes of the Department of Defense are continuously reviewed and revised—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0F62AE1FC09C43BEBBD200C844CB8D64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to implement the most streamlined and efficient business processes practicable; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BC29CEDBEC145CD8A29E2AF665566DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enable the use of commercial off-the-shelf business systems with the fewest changes necessary to accommodate requirements and interfaces that are unique to the Department of Defense.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE45C28742F714765993FB8DAEEDBCBC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A process to establish requirements for covered defense business systems.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBC4EDC063984FF29E6E74761D5ABBD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mechanisms for the planning and control of investments in covered defense business systems, including a process for the collection and review of programming and budgeting information for covered defense business systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4883B3E7A2B64D2892C7C4A7A9235F1E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Policy requiring the periodic review of covered defense business systems that have been fully deployed, by portfolio, to ensure that investments in such portfolios are appropriate.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA69AFD15BBF427489A915A4618EF335"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Defense business enterprise architecture</header>
 <paragraph id="HD65A596821944280BF60787A3C430A06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blueprint</header><text>The Secretary, working through the Deputy Chief Management Officer of the Department of Defense, shall develop and maintain a blueprint to guide the development of integrated business processes within the Department of Defense. Such blueprint shall be known as the <quote>defense business enterprise architecture</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D2B73065F4D404EBF5E6FC7AC09F37D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The defense business enterprise architecture shall be sufficiently defined to effectively guide implementation of interoperable defense business system solutions and shall be consistent with the policies and procedures established by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H794C8623B2E640EEBF9572DA3815856A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The defense business enterprise architecture shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H6367AD5D10EE49AC888AB0A7DF71C8E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include policies, procedures, business data standards, business performance measures, and business information requirements that apply uniformly throughout the Department of Defense; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD47CFD9F886E428FAF956527AB44AABA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enable the Department of Defense to—</text> <clause id="HBA1AB73D7CC642F8BDF776EB9D556AFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>comply with all applicable law, including Federal accounting, financial management, and reporting requirements;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB604105D23504DF8AF111A262063835E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>routinely produce verifiable, timely, accurate, and reliable business and financial information for management purposes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5D27C6B5994C42E5BF8810FE5229D607"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>integrate budget, accounting, and program information and systems.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4B8C6241C0F444DAA9E6A8AEF9335EC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Integration into information technology architecture</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6A023F8A05D84F59BE567A3A4AEC0E24"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The defense business enterprise architecture shall be integrated into the information technology enterprise architecture required under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A99CDCF5DA54C89902D02C632A947D0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense shall develop an information technology enterprise architecture. The architecture shall describe a plan for improving the information technology and computing infrastructure of the Department of Defense, including for each of the major business processes conducted by the Department of Defense.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H873DFE4E927D416A9A30666035BB25CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Defense business council</header>
 <paragraph id="H95BFEE24DF9146A987454F96E5B7DD4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement for council</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a Defense Business Council to provide advice to the Secretary on developing the defense business enterprise architecture, reengineering the Department’s business processes, and requirements for defense business systems. The Council shall be chaired by the Deputy Chief Management Officer and the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H618649223A67472FA4608AC4EBCF7D7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The membership of the Council shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF6B651BFDFF140B8A25244225173852E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Chief Management Officers of the military departments, or their designees.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H911440247D6F469AAD75B53CB45C1F24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The following officials of the Department of Defense, or their designees:</text> <clause id="HCC1F2561DB6846EDB8750BEA62200E8E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics with respect to acquisition, logistics, and installations management processes.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1261AB704B2148C6A543CB07D5F3E660"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) with respect to financial management and planning and budgeting processes.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H258BFFF063A544BCACF8C4C9732AF12A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness with respect to human resources management processes.</text>
											</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37508F4B03DE4575A6F2E995F736A2ED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Approvals required for development</header>
 <paragraph id="H2F6A844F69F8406AAA0EAEB534A075FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial approval required</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that a covered defense business system program cannot proceed into development (or, if no development is required, into production or fielding) unless the appropriate approval official (as specified in paragraph (2)) approves the program by determining that the covered defense business system concerned—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H968D2109A002426D933F144801958179"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supports a business process that has been, or is being as a result of the acquisition program, reengineered to be as streamlined and efficient as practicable consistent with the guidance issued pursuant to subsection (b), including business process mapping;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA07B11D8EC7D4405A83165BD1FC321BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in compliance with the defense business enterprise architecture developed pursuant to subsection (d) or will be in compliance as a result of modifications planned;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03073CD2DAC94F608887871C8E05EF40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has valid, achievable requirements; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A931D3DD50746EEA2ED01FCEA9DFE4F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is in compliance with the Department’s auditability requirements.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFACDAD4030D942B7808882D2CF321D5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate official</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the appropriate approval official with respect to a covered defense business system is the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA345CE988C554DB6A826008B9456125A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of a system of a military department, the Chief Management Officer of that military department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78E8FD58B63B4FC487737DBB8A5E7F28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a system of a Defense Agency or Defense Field Activity or a system that will support the business process of more than one military department or Defense Agency or Defense Field Activity, the Deputy Chief Management Officer of the Department of Defense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9701647F63B24A298F031959C008C015"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In the case of any system, such official other than the applicable official under subparagraph (A) or (B) as the Secretary designates for such purpose.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F854F5ED7604CD69037C85E1DBB7965"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual certification</header><text>For any fiscal year in which funds are expended for development pursuant to a covered defense business system program, the Defense Business Council shall review the system and certify (or decline to certify as the case may be) that it continues to satisfy the requirements of paragraph (1). If the Council determines that certification cannot be granted, the chairman of the Council shall notify the appropriate approval official and the acquisition Milestone Decision Authority for the program and provide a recommendation for corrective action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1C0947DF3B1417AB2F019FAAEEAB2EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Obligation of funds in violation of requirements</header><text>The obligation of Department of Defense funds for a covered defense business system program that has not been certified in accordance with paragraph (3) is a violation of section 1341(a)(1)(A) of title 31.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H612C245BF4914FA2AD3178AB8FEEBC35"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Responsibility of milestone decision authority</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that, as part of the defense acquisition system, the requirements of this section are fully addressed by the Milestone Decision Authority for a covered defense business system program as acquisition process approvals are considered for such system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF1D6A07B358D48EEB74A60EADFA13F18"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than March 15 of each year from 2016 through 2020, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on activities of the Department of Defense pursuant to this section. Each report shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H43E1F4479CC34D1799CE72977D6FE7B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of actions taken and planned with respect to the guidance required by subsection (b) and the defense business enterprise architecture developed pursuant to subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61C9D64918754A3D8AAB0AC3981F3386"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of actions taken and planned for the reengineering of business processes by the Defense Business Council established pursuant to subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2163678F28654928B8986AB0D02E699A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A summary of covered defense business system funding and covered defense business systems approved pursuant to subsection (f).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC62AE91CA607411685A2998FD86A090F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identification of any covered defense business system program that during the preceding fiscal year was reviewed and not approved pursuant to subsection (f) and the reasons for the lack of approval.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21176A52BD3140218F24F979270E0C6E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Identification of any covered defense business system program that during the preceding fiscal year failed to achieve initial operational capability within five years after the date the program received Milestone B approval.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5DA2EFBD3CE48C3A1A945BF1F962714"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For any program identified under paragraph (5), a description of the plan to address the issues that caused the failure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE285CA884F414E5C845E3DC955819021"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A discussion of specific improvements in business operations and cost savings resulting from successful covered defense business systems programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F973A092B714838AFCDBBB1713FA4A7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A copy of the most recent report of the Chief Management Officer of each military department on implementation of business transformation initiatives by such military department in accordance with section 908 of the Duncan Hunter National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/417">Public Law 110–417</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 4569; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2222">10 U.S.C. 2222</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C8E2BEF92A14C059600C6AC63CB094D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H3041A901CF0F4C95B0F3F83C11FA8A1F"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H41A8337194B645DDB078E5B898E2DF04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Defense business system</header><text>The term <quote>defense business system</quote> means an information system that is operated by, for, or on behalf of the Department of Defense, including any of the following:</text>
 <clause id="HF6B99ED9B23543E2A7354C8AF2CA60F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A financial system.</text> </clause><clause id="HF329025507BE4945BA8A81135C616353"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A financial data feeder system.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H07AA5066399948DCB2845268F5EAB3CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A contracting system.</text> </clause><clause id="HD35B4E050E444200A2697625E7ACFE2E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A logistics system.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF6AF7290F374FABBCE03020C4F93F3F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A planning and budgeting system.</text> </clause><clause id="H250BA3B0289845DA9FBED6A4A417B680"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>An installations management system.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H40B645AF60B94655B915710B1BB4EE49"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A human resources management system.</text> </clause><clause id="H9CA4D36327864DB8A3AB90F987F1E752"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>A training and readiness system.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0244129C195D4AB78FCCB2CEA7F53198"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term does not include—</text> <clause id="HAF145436BD184D88BB2AEA275D44761B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a national security system; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H13A404E3E9FE44B893C95935AFB19388"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an information system used exclusively by and within the defense commissary system or the exchange system or other instrumentality of the Department of Defense conducted for the morale, welfare, and recreation of members of the armed forces using nonappropriated funds.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DF2725E65A64B9C84998A0651B82429"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered defense business system</header><text>The term <quote>covered defense business system</quote> means a defense business system that is expected to have a total amount of budget authority, over the period of the current future-years defense program submitted to Congress under section 221 of this title, in excess of the threshold established for the use of special simplified acquisition procedures pursuant to section 2304(g)(1)(B) of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FFD5A5F05DA4F85ADB5487BAF3CAC34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered defense business system program</header><text>The term <quote>covered defense business system program</quote> means a defense acquisition program to develop and field a covered defense business system or an increment of a covered defense business system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46859053D09746DEA850AF5A660522E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enterprise architecture</header><text>The term <quote>enterprise architecture</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 3601(4) of title 44.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8C02A4C7CC94D928BCFB903CC9BF900"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Information system</header><text>The term <quote>information system</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 11101 of title 40.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80BE0FC9867545219CEF224321A9CB1E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>National security system</header><text>The term <quote>national security system</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 3542(b)(2) of title 44.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H672E26AF92F14AC0B340A67DB2164ACC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Milestone decision authority</header><text>The term <quote>Milestone Decision Authority</quote>, with respect to a defense acquisition program, means the individual within the Department of Defense designated with the responsibility to grant milestone approvals for that program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4E023E0D054441383BF63AA46958790"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Business process mapping</header><text>The term <quote>business process mapping</quote> means a procedure in which the steps in a business process are clarified and documented in both written form and in a flow chart.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H105C21B1D9B94145A52C4D24357232E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H50CEEE1158354228B48E399C4F29A12E" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">2222. Defense business systems: business process reengineering; enterprise architecture;
			 management.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17CA71ED7A724F4284C39508EAA8F072"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline for guidance</header><text>The guidance required by subsection (b)(1) of section 2222 of title 10, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a)(1), shall be issued not later than December 31, 2016.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H32622518919548E8AF68F302861D177D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Section 811 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/364">Public Law 109–364</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2222">10 U.S.C. 2222</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H97764127ABB84A1993177E5062357983"><enum>V</enum><header>Industrial Base Matters</header>
			<section id="H7FD90856B78F4D25BBB3DCA646EB3892" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>501.</enum><header>Codification and amendment of Mentor-Protege Program</header>
 <subsection id="HC73C2D2D006F4A49B0CD9007FDC76A9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 831 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/510">Public Law 101–510</external-xref>; 104 Stat. 1607; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2302">10 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref> note) is transferred to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/137">chapter 137</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, inserted so as to appear after section 2323a, redesignated as section 2323b, and amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE909FDEE236D4BDF9033D776C41094A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending the section heading to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H974B6AB8F2354D00BFA6FE86520CB35B" style="USC"> <section id="H92C5FF62301447C595D1E0E5D28BF460"><enum>2323b.</enum><header>Mentor-Protege Program</header></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9255ACD820F94CA597A9B501A6763AD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>pilot</quote> each place such term appears;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB49162027FD2407BAA7B5EC387A48C87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subsection (e)(1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA000BB5EB7F4A6BB4D72F43342A7780" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HA338E442CEDD431AA517DB9ECB6786EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A developmental program for the protege firm, in such detail as may be reasonable, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8499DAF75A684E8A91A0899D9F3E761F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>factors to assess the protege firm's developmental progress under the program; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC218D3E3F454100B4968793290D666A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the anticipated number and type of subcontracts to be awarded to the protege firm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF73801D9696044D99F1D3301BF488770"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2)(B), by striking <quote>under subsection (l)(2)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H775A26937F524D7B9E2EC658FCE8F4F2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(1), by inserting <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>)</quote> after <quote>Small Business Act</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54FF707D8E024AEE80CB4568C9762D06"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by striking subsection (j) and redesignating subsections (k) and (l) as subsections (j) and (k), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9BAF058BF514FB18BBFEB6B61EFEA69"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by amending subsection (j) (as so redesignated) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A984D03344341EA85954AEB3D05BDED" style="USC"> <subsection id="H59DAF3DF371C4B54933F370E944CAF63"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulations implementing the Mentor-Protege Pilot Program established under section 831 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/510">Public Law 101–510</external-xref>; 104 Stat. 1607; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2302">10 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref> note) as in effect on March 25, 2015, shall apply to this section. The Secretary of Defense may revise such regulations or prescribe additional regulations necessary to carry out this section. The Department of Defense policy regarding the Mentor-Protege Program shall be published and maintained as an appendix to the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H60D6FE3FAC3A42EBAA80C545F1AFDE5C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>by striking <quote>prescribed pursuant to subsection (k)</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>described in subsection (j)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H99B4ADDDDB9C4136926C27CA0F9E7340"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subsection (k) (as so redesignated)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0D52552956FD44FABAD292259860CA1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>means a business concern that meets the requirements of section 3(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>) and the regulations promulgated pursuant thereto</quote> and inserting <quote>has the meaning given such term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD6176C24A7840238A2AEB606A5F315D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HC5F16FAA820544E885A4EDA8CDDD8DC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>the severely disabled</quote> and inserting <quote>severely disabled individuals</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4D758199C9264F4CB409A2B8ADBCF717"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by inserting <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(p)</external-xref>)</quote> after <quote>Small Business Act</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46D2CE9CF7984D998F1909C0123F5FCF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>of title 10, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>of this title</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81456742D3E44D5992C8B6767A3163E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (8) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D76A783D8E448DA80BC925CC6F498C6" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H6EA8EE160B5D4C21BE5A86E8981A7B20"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>severely disabled individual</term> means an individual who is blind (as defined in section 8501 of title 41) or a severely disabled individual (as defined in such section).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE57473C8F9464499A10F9B390BF9DD73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2323a the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF22B047AFF1F4B698A14A23DF3CAD4E3" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">2323b. Mentor-Protege Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="HF19FBDEC41FF4F5F89A78E6403E7158A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>502.</enum><header>Amendments to data quality improvement plan</header>
 <subsection id="HF743C3A9192A485DB9D6BF625BAB2BBD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 15(s) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(s)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEA78CA6524514E189878603D9A75ED19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (6); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F40E3D7C70E47899B47DDDCE73A70FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8D857C3F2A04BBFBF16FF466DD6F260" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HAFD908C0BC20458F854BD2369910830A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the first day of fiscal year 2017, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall implement the plan described in this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86AD5C92E32244A79D8E41E33D942615"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall annually provide to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a certification of the accuracy and completeness of data reported on bundled and consolidated contracts.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6045C5D023CB43909D8317ADB107ABE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study</header>
 <paragraph id="H6269D67DB5CF4778BA811E97FACEA417"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than the first day of fiscal year 2018, the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate a study on the effectiveness of the plan described in section 15(s) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(s)</external-xref>) that shall assess whether contracts were accurately labeled as bundled or consolidated.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C8293036E0747369794AF536D044DB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts evaluated</header><text>For the purposes of conducting the study described in paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA9DF971F6B894CCA882D00E1325BAF02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall evaluate, for work in each of sectors 23, 33, 54, and 56 (as defined by the North American Industry Classification System), not fewer than 100 contracts in each sector;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5138DA6D5F848C2872816D287D90716"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall evaluate only those contracts—</text> <clause id="H491895CDDD0643B2914D95B04BD19B04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>awarded by an agency listed in section 901(b) of title 31, United States Code; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA97BE4E0A98849C08A0C5395EF513D6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that have a Base and Exercised Options Value, an Action Obligation, or a Base and All Options Value (as such terms are defined in the Federal procurement data system described in section 1222(a)(4)(A) of title 41, United States Code, or any successor system); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97FF614AC21A4FDAB9310666DA00FFC1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not evaluate contracts that have used any set aside authority.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF52AE1AB917149F5BBBCB71EB1A2C93C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 12 months after initiating the study required by paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate on the results from such study and, if warranted, any recommendations on how to improve the quality of data reported on bundled and consolidated contracts.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3269E3116229403AA7E70C1E34F3003B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>503.</enum><header>Notice of contract consolidation for acquisition strategies</header>
 <subsection id="H05C1CA93A07E4B96A8AB4CB0E4207F84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice requirement for the senior procurement executive or Chief Acquisition Officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44(c)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657q">15 U.S.C. 657q(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1949216AFE0C4001992E643ED65EAD45" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5A7109379AB14BA999C13F7F8B0A4BD5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 days after making a determination that an acquisition strategy involving a consolidation of contract requirements is necessary and justified under subparagraph (A), the senior procurement executive or Chief Acquisition Officer shall publish a notice on a public website that such determination has been made. Any solicitation for a procurement related to the acquisition strategy may not be published earlier than 7 days after such notice is published. Along with the publication of the solicitation, the senior procurement executive or Chief Acquisition Officer shall publish a justification for the determination, which shall include the information in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD054AFBA28104EA1BA1291BC7958493C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice requirement for the head of a contracting agency</header><text>Section 15(e)(3) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(e)(3)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6E6594A47FB4B85A0C6B83BC374465F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2BE7849B546545C0AAFB86455BC916BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Strategy specifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the head of a contracting agency determines that an acquisition plan for a procurement involves a substantial bundling of contract requirements, the head of a contracting agency shall publish a notice on a public website that such determination has been made not later than 7 days after making such determination. Any solicitation for a procurement related to the acquisition plan may not be published earlier than 7 days after such notice is published. Along with the publication of the solicitation, the head of a contracting agency shall publish a justification for the determination, which shall include following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H33D03ACF8F954A2189E04F5E20B846A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The specific benefits anticipated to be derived from the bundling of contract requirements and a determination that such benefits justify the bundling.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE07E98557D584AC39FC734B8A89CEF59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An identification of any alternative contracting approaches that would involve a lesser degree of bundling of contract requirements.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFF6831E15DEB4AB182543D808E59467C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HB646BFE139E94FE9B6B9308DCE76DC48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the specific impediments to participation by small business concerns as prime contractors that result from the bundling of contract requirements; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HAC94F4EBC2D443AF8D319D640F27E5B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the specific actions designed to maximize participation of small business concerns as subcontractors (including suppliers) at various tiers under the contract or contracts that are awarded to meet the requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8770DABBF644426883CC2B9CEAC3CA18"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44(c)(1) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657q">15 U.S.C. 657q(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Subject to paragraph (4), the head</quote> and inserting <quote>The head</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HB1318E168DDA404EA678FBE98C78EB8D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>504.</enum><header>Clarification of requirements related to small business contracts for services</header> <subsection id="H431137490AA24850AB723C081A8314C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Procurement contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(a)(17) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(a)(17)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9CDD63FFDD1143A7A24D575152DDB4D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>any procurement contract</quote> and all that follows through <quote>section 15</quote> and inserting <quote>any procurement contract, which contract has as its principal purpose the supply of a product to be let pursuant to this subsection or subsection (m), or section 15(a), 31, or 36,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C1B440E04104EB8839161DF4054853B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC814D452499E41A689E3FC27689755DD" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H9C3791EBDCC64B33A88C6A23E8E7337C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This paragraph shall not apply to a contract that has as its principal purpose the acquisition of services or construction.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6DA4CA13C284D34BF51AE14E51A1CB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subcontractor contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 46(a)(4) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657s">15 U.S.C. 657s(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>for supplies from a regular dealer in such supplies</quote> and inserting <quote>which is principally for supplies from a regular dealer in such supplies, and which is not a contract principally for services or construction,</quote>.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HB379CC4C24754EA69BC873BFF1D41789" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>505.</enum><header>Review of Government access to intellectual property rights of private sector firms</header>
 <subsection id="H2350DF425C4F4B0DB5C10CAA9BA446BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review required</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall direct the Defense Business Board to conduct a review of Department of Defense regulations and practices, and laws authorizing such regulations and practices, related to Government access to and use of intellectual property rights of private sector firms.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H93BB31B565AF4ED88C465977CF1B2425"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1, 2016, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the findings of the Defense Business Board, along with any actions the Secretary proposes to revise and clarify laws or regulations related to intellectual property rights.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H6695D8679A67426380941E0123C99067" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>506.</enum><header>Modifications to the Small Business Innovative Research Program and the Small Business Technology
 Transfer Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H742D69942155484E93F143097EA296DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6061756F0D1849B3B5526DC473803959"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>development;</quote> and inserting <quote>development, particularly contracts for research and development supporting defense and national security missions and programs;</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE85F0C97CB64327918F408FE0B2CA61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2806DABC8D2D4BC5BFF6C86D40E0F99B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB483ACA6A01041419B769EBD8B15D425"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(C)(i), by inserting <quote>or non-Federal sources of capital</quote> after <quote>funding awards</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0B6F7798407945AEB5DCE164F9BD0DBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (6)(C)(i), by inserting <quote>or non-Federal sources of capital</quote> after <quote>funding awards</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E090B711AB54FB3A7703582FB5C29CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0539698BBE0547728DCF0EB33001458F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (2)(B) and (5)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E5401094C9A46D999058B41B896BBEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AB16EB0582645A5887474A17D06A86D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2D5A03F22A4F4E3FB3D786C8CE40AEE7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Required expenditures for military departments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of each military department shall expend, in connection with SBIR, not less than 2.9 percent and not more than 5 percent of each such military department’s extramural budget for research or research and development for fiscal year 2018 and each subsequent fiscal year.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4687992AC670460EB7A37ACA55E1F980"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(3)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF96527446DDB42769C823533E296E572"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF3C9CA51B904ACCA467541C2FC2DA2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B54F9D0612D4E7AB573D2CDF9A01730"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA6EC555A4674885B504F47C349C348F" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5681D1D30B054AE7ADFCA89196D2084A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Defense and as applied to the Department of Defense and each military department, in the quadrennial defense review (described in section 118 of title 10, United States Code) and other strategies or reports that direct the research and development and acquisition processes of the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFB789C155374FF7B1A1180283CA9FE2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFA5898803CC4D97AF47D9A09D40401E" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD28C8BB0952A4C50A663E8DCB552B62C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Modifications related to military departments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after March 25, 2015, the Administrator shall modify the policy directives issued pursuant to this subsection to establish the authority of each Secretary of a military department to manage and operate the SBIR program funded under subsection (f)(5).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H50B8CDB23FC5495CB4898D1EEE93B8F2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (k)(2)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H47810027CA0149E2BDB085A1D4D504E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (f)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (4) of subsection (f)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H80F4AFCFCB534250BB4B6C5BC2248030"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>subsection (n)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (4) of subsection (n)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA69A599970A14C8892DC799AE53B834A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (m), by inserting <quote>, except as provided in subsections (f)(5) and (n)(4)</quote> after <quote>2017</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H970175312AD64EABAE009744C535596A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in subsection (n)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F3248F5C1ED426FA65219E5E11B8062"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>The percentage</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (4), the percentage</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF816E1C845F49E79CAF82D2E37E3155"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE988BA69FCA4717897DA63FB4B9A1EA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC93B2B7066B64E5E982F7A3BBF7A20D6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Required expenditure for military departments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of each military department shall expend, in connection with STTR, not more than 5 percent of each such military department’s extramural budget for research or research and development for fiscal year 2018 and each subsequent fiscal year.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43DFB9C944D045BB8C0D0F0EBDB51E47"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subsection (o)(3)(B), by striking <quote>Code;</quote> and inserting <quote>Code, and in other reports that direct the research and development and acquisition processes of the Department of Defense;</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EE9E482908343298BE862E04440690A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in subsection (p), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62107B35E74F46E1A53F06B817AC7C76" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB57883B7B729414DAA5D5DBC0D974DD3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Modifications related to military departments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Agile Acquisition to Retain Technological Edge Act</short-title>, the Administrator shall modify the policy directives issued pursuant to this subsection to establish the authority of each Secretary of a military department to manage and operate the STTR program funded under subsection (n)(4).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC0C2F274AA148ACA5A938BCEDBB7867"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in subsection (r)(4), by adding at the end the following sentence: <quote>For the Department of Defense, such Phase III awards shall be made in conformance with defense and national security missions and programs.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AB0C531057C4641B84E27A3F55B90FD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>in subsection (x)(2)(B), by inserting <quote>(or its successor)</quote> before the period at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4798847AF4E64431AA3C26819976B4C8"><enum>(13)</enum><text>in subsection (aa)(4)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5325C045C17F4578B632F626D7898C40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">or project</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">topic</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DE03798838648C68380015B0AD1F3A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or project</quote> after <quote>topic</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD131767898F540389012355AD76F48ED"><enum>(14)</enum><text>in subsection (bb)(1), by striking <quote>another Federal agency</quote> and inserting <quote>one or more other Federal agencies</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H37C7AD6205034CD796C3DE1A0CDC61F9"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (ff)(1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC2E3FBEF0F9B4117AAD188D493DA35CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1 additional Phase II SBIR award or Phase II STTR award</quote> and inserting <quote>one or more additional Phase II SBIR awards or Phase II STTR awards</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2E3C7D1521C45AD8F320461A8AE161E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>from one or more Federal agencies</quote> after <quote>project</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58B75E8CE4474CA294D4FEFDB7BE1B0A"><enum>(16)</enum><text>in subsection (qq)(2), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DE1FF57B22C4907916C338198F558C0" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H872879004AA242C88F63AE1921EE590C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Federal agency shall implement the requirements described under subparagraph (A) not later than December 31, 2017.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF87463C9B0BF41FFBE7B7C6D579F01E0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>507.</enum><header>Extension of defense research and development rapid innovation program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 1073 of the Ike Skeleton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/383">Public Law 111–383</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 4366; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2359">10 U.S.C. 2359</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>through 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>through 2020</quote>.</text>
			</section></title><title id="HAF682038F1774335AAD4871E0355A388"><enum>VI</enum><header>Repeal or Revision of Reporting Requirements</header>
			<section id="H107516E8F0934FDB89E35CF0B50C81F3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>601.</enum><header>Repeal of certain reporting requirements</header>
				<subsection id="H8EC92B69D0B44C1B8C12A227DD902FF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports Related to Military Personnel Issues (Other Than Health Care)</header>
 <paragraph id="HA54D81FB0F3948FBBBBA4201235299FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on voting assistance programs effectiveness and compliance</header><text>Section 1566(c) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C590105690E46048780D6754B922879"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1)</quote> after the subsection heading; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB48EE90C7CB6439DA30F23BDD3089E1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (3).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F90D0A00809477D9D683E8FD35B1F54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on aviation officer retention bonuses</header><text>Section 301b(i) of title 37, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6788C29A9B4240C293899A394A2636D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1)</quote> after the subsection heading; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7FD7353D6844D7BAA6EECF6AA6CD653"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD9D54E2740443589F7729BA30A4873"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on foreign language proficiency incentive pay</header><text>Section 316a of title 37, United States Code, as amended by section 615(5) of this Act, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H22976932A0314193A4467FFED27703DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (f); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97548AF037494246A5075174385DDDB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (f).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCF42D85E69E4FF6AF43FE607E7DC127"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report on use of waiver authority for military service academy appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 553 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/81">Public Law 112–81</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4346">10 U.S.C. 4346</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5C4C251841B1408C8F705DF643B47EFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF584D1C809E2411FAE24C532F31D4514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (e).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57967B5DB6634106AD166E04219808D7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report on increase in Junior Reserve Officers' Training Corps units</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (e) of section 548 of the Duncan Hunter National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/417">Public Law 110–417</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 4466) is repealed.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H6DCEECE915FA4313899E9EAAF43A5DE7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Report on implementation of yellow ribbon reintegration program</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4080ACF08EB949A8BC03529586FEEE86"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 582(e) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/181">Public Law 110–181</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/10101">10 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref> note) is amended by striking paragraph (4).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2759BD39AD3F47C5B1D87B8CD75EE018"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 597 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/10101">10 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63C0E09678784ACE914C041D3556121F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report on local educational agency Assistance related to DOD activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 574 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/364">Public Law 109–364</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7703b">20 U.S.C. 7703b</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2E33ECDD8E394B6FB1AB83272713A343"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC3CB2D2732A451F8E03836D9582804F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H852DD8E62DFF477388EEC06EA23BEB0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports related to health care</header>
					<paragraph id="H5DB53C8820B24C1097806F6360B96CF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports on health protection quality and health assessment data</header>
 <subparagraph id="H997F6CAEC12B4840A0E082884EB2CBF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 1073b of title 10, United States Code, is repealed.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7302250BBD3941D488512B5C22D866BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 1073b.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC8F4F54DB874056A9783CED06EEF199"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on standards of facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1648 of the Wounded Warrior Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1071">10 U.S.C. 1071</external-xref> note) is amended by striking subsection (f).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11DE2812A03144EDBA754A3405DCAAB2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on inspections of facilities</header><text>Section 1662 of the Wounded Warrior Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1071">10 U.S.C. 1071</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H9090BFA25EDC46C49885C0D8FF587D31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Required inspections of facilities</header-in-text>.—</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75DDD5A610A94D3F9354E60606729CAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H500901FBD7E44742A071A2E2B8843C67"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report on inspections of other facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3307 of the U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans’ Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1073">10 U.S.C. 1073</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD5F464011F0C45C2BF1EB3343C808A1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1A5A1140BD7C4F00A326004AC0FA5BE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (d).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5720FF3613F74992BB00747A7B725966"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports related to readiness</header>
 <paragraph id="HAEAE835400DF420E83CFF1BCE2943F69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on Arsenal Support Program Initiative</header><text>Section 323 of the Floyd Spence National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/398">Public Law 106–398</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4551">10 U.S.C. 4551</external-xref> note) is amended by striking subsection (g).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD4FC4B2B37A45FDA7A180E5510E813F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO review of contractor-operated civil engineering supply stores program</header><text>Section 345 of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/26">Public Law 105–26</external-xref>; 112 Stat. 1978) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H33CBAC8FA780431A91C5798EEFE6A111"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEBC7DE7734D400685E584A76134B89C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (d).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF7C986C26A146D2B37708B9DF59EBB2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports related to naval vessels and Merchant Marine</header>
 <paragraph id="HE0A04925B15446C98408CFC14AB18647"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on naming of naval vessels</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7292 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (d).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H966FCB759F174BAAA23494FC5107477D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on transfer of vessels stricken from naval vessel register</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7306 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7EA950942B6C4FB09F853F26C8031B78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H989B8AF3C52F4435B292E3992F7FE681"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) and (f) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B13FCE2EBEC435C947AEB8A9572C9A5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports on mission modules of Littoral Combat Ship</header><text>Section 126 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2C1924F017F54F3BA608DC3DE77E1A27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(b) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Additional Quarterly Reports.—</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H275F7990CAE34293A9D57E91B09BE0FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF5B1B4DAA3548F78AEC548ABB22481C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report on cost estimate of CVN–79</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 122 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/364">Public Law 109–364</external-xref>; 120 Stat. 2104), as most recently amended by section 121 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>), is amended by striking subsection (f).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16BE21EC0C004C069C36A39BFFAE870D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report on assessments of first ship of a shipbuilding program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 124 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 is repealed.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF4CC115CFD354F82A3B7D0852659C5F4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual report of Federal Maritime Commission</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7BCBF610BB174C6DA63039FA46C66D2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 50111 of title 46, United States Code, is repealed.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H22B442F0E56F4D4BB1DF40141A209958"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/501">chapter 501</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 50111.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C8A94EE03584E3A9A6388E5075DF284"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Discretionary reports no longer needed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Navy is not required to submit to the congressional defense committees—</text> <subparagraph id="HD68313AFB6B54B5F9289E3CC4C97DC31"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report, or updates to such a report, on open architecture as described in Senate Report 110–077; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8739FD30DAB14C59A4C1B2C9B5522DD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a monthly report on Ford class aircraft carriers not otherwise required by law.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F1C57E9D44C4BCB909DB687400B4E71"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports related to nuclear, proliferation, and related matters</header> <paragraph id="H7DC7636EECBF4185976F24B6BDAC7A75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on Proliferation Security Initiative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1821(b) of the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2911">50 U.S.C. 2911</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6DDD84034D404B4ABCB1198F0BB21E5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general.—</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3550CABC5A94260899701A40845B5E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (3).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34F5843621534724B2F57B7A4DB2D510"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on warhead life extension options</header><text>The National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>) is amended by repealing section 3118.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF35F331D41F41CA9AE3CAB0248DFAE9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on Nuclear Weapons Council</header><text>Section 179 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (g).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H94986E75FF214F12B81A247A8B46AE1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Briefings on dialogue between United States and Russian Federation on nuclear arms</header><text>Section 1282 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/5951">22 U.S.C. 5951</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H13971D58FCD14C07972850C4BDE1ED0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A1C55A604994805BD0990C2CDF05F36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (a) and (b), respectively.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37F013515EB9463893E4D92375B2610B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Implementation plan for whole-of- government vision prescribed in the national security strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1072 of the National Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3043">50 U.S.C. 3043</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFA0FF3DC7B8A4219A09A6472EDE2D2FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Implementation plan.—</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5F1ADB2D7A84A9DA18BBBDA7AF3A79E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0430AC35F28544BBAE74D5CC4947E7DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (b).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6820104AAE5648F1829C1DD3D2F68DC8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports related to missile defense</header> <paragraph id="H5278954C478C4786BA4257557B568CA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on ground-based midcourse defense program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 234 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/81">Public Law 112–81</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 1340) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA4E2911742DC42A5B698C8547CEEC99C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Sense of Congress.—</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA04FB53712B044289A3AEA22F786F65A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC2D530774DA4E41837306EF279BBBA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on Missile Defense Executive Board activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 232 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/81">Public Law 112–81</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 1339) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCD9AD8A95AEA417F9BC0A5C89B0CAFAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H488497892B4049F9B7981A1DD7F105E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (b).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF34926EC9ECF4FBF8DB32BA2CDDFB7A0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports related to acquisition</header>
 <paragraph id="H7FB9DA49240A456AB7A467F664B3369B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on foreign purchases</header><text>Section 8305 of title 41, United States Code, is repealed.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD00F1AD303714B13ABA0D29FD5884176"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on cost assessment activities</header><text>Section 2334 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1BAA1C60D4F84BB7BDD7F0BB373A4DEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (f); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC6898FF162D48FEBBDAA7C9BD1E5B0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (f).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF9685C40539405C8D4738572BCF91AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on performance assessments and root cause analyses</header><text>Section 2438 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (f).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4E2E6EDD7A84A6B830A62DEF8E341CC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports related to civilian personnel</header> <paragraph id="HF9C9503102704FC5BF1DDFAEA555EA0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on experimental program for scientific and technical personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1101 of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/261">Public Law 105–261</external-xref>; 112 Stat. 2139) is amended by striking subsection (g).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AD446CE190C4A40843C11AABE5CC11C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on pilot program for exchange of information technology personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1110 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 2493) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC606C32AA16048EF92B341E7CA8970C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (i);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H069E5BD3DAF3417F87E22441C615D800"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (j) as subsection (i); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA67E431D02D6488AAF1331C13EA26D1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (i) (as redesignated by subparagraph (B)), by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B124D62FFCD481A8D842007744722CB" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H1D7808C7D53C4776A14B47147A285EE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any employee whose assignment is allowed to continue by virtue of paragraph (1) shall be taken into account for purposes of the numerical limitation under subsection (h).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08C8E8B602A64B20B521411CCF61088A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>GAO report with respect to Department of Defense performance management and workforce incentive
 system</header><text>Section 9902(h) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA2ACE1FA51D4304B108E78789F51E64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>and the Comptroller General,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9E5C3552ACB4D0DB5D5E19A2257CA01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81ABDC9241364EB98DB310845A55AF9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD109611111FE4AC18CEAC9F1FC2F134F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Miscellaneous Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="HC1A56165ABA94C1B9CD232FC91BDD125"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on rewards for combating terrorism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 127b of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H6C9894C90AF84E21BF06D3827A2FFC99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (f); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49E83B7BEF364495ADA922BF274103EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (f).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBA16527AD2F4B7EBBB9A721F34FB118"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on technological maturity and integration risk of critical technologies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 138b of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2E4A919401284CCBA62784030EBB6391"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H497023F42FE34CF8B7BFF1033E67486D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(b)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>(b)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE41C1E9880F142819EEF3D073FA362FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on systems engineering</header><text>Section 139b(d) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H450B36BF02D149848F21E4E6A9E796C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC00B6A4C0DB144D4898C0CB8B3F93C02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5132881163F34DD181FC906E69A1C392"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), as redesignated by subparagraph (B)—</text>
 <clause id="H0B5BB8BD96154E78A1A20E7026C40FFA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (2)</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H16FBEBB686CA46879DC9970DE96B1C70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>systems engineering master plans and</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H553330F799F046D8A24080758A9614E2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>, systems engineering master plans,</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H8D453F8870CE418B892946ED3415331C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>systems engineering, development planning,</quote> and inserting <quote>development planning</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H17EC4EB26DD440499472AEF32E77EB14"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (F);</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEC0BACEE33644439EFF5EE6A125CADD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by transferring subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (4) to paragraph (2), as so redesignated, and redesignating those subparagraphs as subparagraphs (D) and (E), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD97087EAAEF24A3EA86A990F665FEC9B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CA70AEB6F9F4BCBB9C0AFAD2D718580"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report on humanitarian demining assistance authority</header><text>Section 407 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H09D87CA625AA4471A9F44AE439B730A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33A80EC234E7429DAE7CB9442DD28C48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2E460B3F2524D359989D1094730A18F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report on Regional Defense Counterterrorism Fellowship Program</header><text>Section 2249c of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (c).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC213C89497D14B23A239FE27714BF6F3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Report on space science and technology strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2272(a) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraph (5).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H0B457BD4D27E4F2A9F0BA29DC3D5C2DB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report on DARPA</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA26434DCF2FC429DB9D0FD1FAACDC6A8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2352 of title 10, United States Code, is repealed.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79DF7EF1F6C443D8A04E1FD8ED4F9104"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/139">chapter 139</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 2352.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC96F7E22988B41AF9190FF1A517FB172"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Report on airlift requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 112 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 1654) is repealed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73061AEFC4044791A6D58F35061B9F0F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Report on interagency collaboration on unmanned aircraft systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1052(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note) is amended by striking paragraph (4).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7B0F1442D57436BBD83D7D1D53FDF06"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Report on in-kind payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2805 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 2149) is repealed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D3411129ADE4948823C5ED154E13699"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Report on airborne signals intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance capabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 112(b) of the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/383">Public Law 111–383</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 4153) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H391AE056B2E44111BCF50A03007F9990"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA13EC826988942ED8765EC19F2F0EBB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (3).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ECFD35909E041448BCFFB2C994C70F4"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Reports on status of Navy Next Generation Enterprise Networks Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1034 of the Duncan Hunter National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/417">Public Law 110–417</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 4593) is repealed.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H75C06D2109FE4E8B86853581CB1C03EB"><enum>VII</enum><header>Planning, Budgeting, Contracting, Oversight, and Other Related Matters</header>
			<section id="H41E091FE950D4E5FAC74C2AF81F947B1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>701.</enum><header>Additional responsibility for Director of Operational Test and Evaluation</header>
 <subsection id="H9CA0BAA3FDC24F649B86AA18BC67670B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional responsibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 139 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE447F779AA7D41EBBC7F727FC4FD46A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), (j), and (k) as subsections (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), (j), (k), and (l), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFC7B45547414872B7924E5D2E8D6ADD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection (c):</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9A6D708882F49BCAE65F9CE00AB85C7" style="USC"> <subsection id="H2D7AEC2FCF47425493EED9A89ECB1374"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall consider the potential for increases in program cost estimates or delays in schedule estimates in the implementation of policies, procedures, and activities related to operational test and evaluation and shall take appropriate action to ensure that operational test and evaluation activities do not unnecessarily increase program costs or impede program schedules.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF24F862C12124339864DC440861E49DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 196(c)(1)(A)(ii) of such title is amended by striking <quote>section 139(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 139(k)</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H34018AF174CD4CE8A6185218E353B35B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>702.</enum><header>Report on linking and streamlining requirements, acquisition, and budget processes within Armed Forces</header> <subsection id="H300428F98DE1427F9D6E7FE386EA0788"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, and the Commandant of the Marine Corps shall each submit to the congressional defense committees a report on efforts to link and streamline the requirements, acquisition, and budget processes within the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps, respectively.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9190DBF37E36461CBC023F68DC98F21B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>Each report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD0E9FCABA5CD420CBE7E729B7B4256B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A specific description of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H783EB5C51F0E4C85AB5A7DE634B7E9EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the management actions the Chief concerned or the Commandant has taken or plans to take to link and streamline the requirements, acquisition, and budget processes of the Armed Force concerned;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H950B5FC61DD44EA8B1515D67ABC66212"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any reorganization or process changes that will link and streamline the requirements, acquisition, and budget processes of the Armed Force concerned; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7013A632AE304E06AC3ABA3D45E9AD39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any cross-training or professional development initiatives of the Chief concerned or the Commandant.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51A50D9770E6445C9FE72E3C87FECDBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For each description under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5FBC396EE4C9456BB249A211C250B44C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the specific timeline associated with implementation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD25FD1C9D7784726B5A5E127FC541BCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the anticipated outcomes once implemented; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8235637AB20F4F7D99DAC5AD8CD1C325"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how to measure whether or not those outcomes are realized.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC48CA1C490894CA4AA921BBC6BD442CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other matters the Chief concerned or the Commandant considers appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFE5094126F574BA48248CE88D9FB3A38"><enum>703.</enum><header>Required review of acquisition-related functions of the Chiefs of Staff of the Armed Forces</header> <subsection id="HF913EE26A18C41DD85D171E7582A9D52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, and the Commandant of the Marine Corps shall conduct a review of their current individual authorities provided in sections 3033, 5033, 8033, and 5043 of title 10, United States Code, and other relevant statutes and regulations related to defense acquisitions for the purpose of developing such recommendations as the Chief concerned or the Commandant considers necessary to further or advance the role of the Chief concerned or the Commandant in the development of requirements, acquisition processes, and the associated budget practices of the Department of Defense.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD8EBD3F2DAAE42A6B23CA44F1D663B63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than September 15, 2015, the Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, and the Commandant of the Marine Corps shall each submit to the congressional defense committees a report containing, at a minimum, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H705D58761A8D41659749D776379C9A0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recommendations developed by the Chief concerned or the Commandant under subsection (a) and other results of the review conducted under such subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FB5D6E3ABD04089B3D15B7E02A968B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The actions the Chief concerned or the Commandant is taking, if any, within the Chief’s or Commandant’s existing authority to implement such recommendations.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0ACA188B95D5416DA15911EDC157BE96" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>704.</enum><header>FAR Council membership for Administrator of Small Business Administration</header>
				<subsection id="H876992E544F94F8AB0A0A570532E7FC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Addition of Administrator of Small Business Administration to Federal Acquisition Regulatory
 Council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1302(b)(1) of title 41, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDB14C0DCEF994966BA0CC7845544EB97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF175786F40F249F4A8702909EF43ABAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (D); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6C0068AC4D54F5EB2A950BDFD41BFDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB2DBC9A9B8243078EE7C7B5D736B356" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HEF0892E83FAA483992928B6CFB13C535"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7466DE13BFD347A8B83AFE3A9C4AD30C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such title is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H02B371759C844E6D915BBAB317D6B672"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1303(a)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H28BAB36930C34BCBA0A83957F3E42656"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and the Administrator of National Aeronautics and Space,</quote> and inserting <quote>the Administrator of National Aeronautics and Space, and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88152C69E0D742A78316FD8C0FB8DD01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and the National Aeronautics and Space Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2451">42 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.</external-xref>),</quote> and inserting <quote>the National Aeronautics and Space Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2451">42 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>),</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3EAC3D69A9994353A61B98701526CAF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1121(d), by striking <quote>and the General Services Administration</quote> and inserting <quote>the General Services Administration, and the Small Business Administration</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2F815DB598404682942419FF0191EBCB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>705.</enum><header>Independent study of matters related to bid protests</header> <subsection id="HA29F4112FD79480AB27465F3D51928F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall enter into a contract with an independent research entity that is a not-for-profit entity or a federally funded research and development center with appropriate expertise and analytical capability to carry out a comprehensive study of factors leading to the filing of bid protests. The study shall examine issues such as the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H63697D9704A74817B7668F3FDD4A5C6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The variable influences on the net benefit (monetary and non-monetary) to contractors either filing a protest or indicating intent to file a protest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C73439E88724548B5115EF22952A7A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The extent to which protests are filed by incumbent contractors for purposes of extending a contract’s period of performance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E224D2F54C4437E9E73E9DA915F3CC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The extent to which companies file protests even if they do not contest that there was an error in the procurement process.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72B79BB17AC947178334BD8F833F4873"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the independent entity shall provide to the Secretary and the congressional defense committees a report on the results of the study, along with any recommendations it may have.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HEA74F53D5B264378A3BAE11B89848347" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>706.</enum><header>Procurement of commercial items</header>
 <subsection id="HAB38124DBC2A4338B57216CB45564247"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Delegation of Responsibility for Commercial Item Determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2375 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CBD34A5301C401194B7880BF73B2DEF" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HE9AC428BFEDE49BE86EAB1B773C92814"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Delegation of Responsibility Within Department of Defense for Commercial Item Determinations</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H34A10C968A214E3A92E68573AC03592B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall designate an individual within the Department of Defense to be responsible for making determinations that, for the purpose of procurement of an item by a component of the Department of Defense, an item is a commercial item as described in section 103 of title 41. The Secretary shall ensure that the designated individual receives sufficient—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC28F51B55EDF4CCEA5FBCEE45E7D54DF" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>staff and resources so that determinations are made in an expedient manner; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA715C4D1986447A4BC59CBC949368C58" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>staff support or authorities (or both) to provide technical expertise on the functionality of an item subject to determination and expertise in conducting market research related to the item.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEAB01395B34447196A12E0254141E90" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall provide public access to Department of Defense determinations regarding whether an item is a commercial item for the purpose of procurement by a component of the Department of Defense. Each determination shall include a summary explanation of the basis for the determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7A706DB147644B41B56F97FF429CCF4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commercial item exception to submission of cost and pricing data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2306a(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H632607D2BEDC4AC28DAEB162BB2BF7F5" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H4930128399144B7EAC503650404D2BDC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration of determination of commercial item</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying the commercial item exception under paragraph (1)(B) to the required submission of certified cost or pricing data, the contracting officer shall use the determinations made by the individual designated by the Secretary of Defense under section 2375(d) of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H78652FB7F4E2478D94F8D0ED8A7024EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the requirements of sections 2375(d) and 2306a(b)(4) of title 10, United States Code, as added by this section, are implemented not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act to ensure that sufficient capability is available within the Department of Defense to make necessary determinations in a timely manner.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H59A4AD15B7234868B9B505E75B612DBC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>707.</enum><header>Amendment relating to multiyear contract authority for acquisition of property</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 2306b(a) of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75386FBFE82A416F923BEC48E1B089B9" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H355747BE17DE430E97715F7BA32BE083"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That there is a reasonable expectation that the use of such a contract will result in lower total anticipated costs of carrying out the program than if the program were carried out through annual contracts.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H315978E7BCA1463B8C45517FAE5F77BD"><enum>708.</enum><header>Use of recent prices paid by the Government in the determination of price reasonableness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2306a(b) of title 10, United States Code, as amended by section 706, is further amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBCC2DFCA0D524060A5E3DE10E1F3DD90" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HADCEA96E66914E14A5C668D9D6B7D10E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A contracting officer may consider evidence provided by an offeror of recent purchase prices paid by the Government for identical or similar commercial items in establishing price reasonableness on a subsequent purchase if the contracting officer is satisfied that the prices previously paid remain a valid reference for comparison after considering the totality of other relevant factors such as the time elapsed since the prior purchase and any differences in the quantities purchased or applicable terms and conditions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="HF8969FCDFD6E4BAFA93FE3E85C588902" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>709.</enum><header>Codification of other transaction authority for certain prototype projects</header>
 <subsection id="H0D28A4EF27894D229CE45E50B511F81A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 845 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/160">Public Law 103–160</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2371">10 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref> note) is transferred to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/139">chapter 139</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, inserted so as to appear after section 2371a, redesignated as section 2371b, and amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C270A9A472F4B9EBA6BC715F121B34F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending the section heading to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BA2BEE4E6E949489050ABE73997B031" style="USC"> <section id="H5FCEFC5823AE4C7486D66AA8C629C7EC"><enum>2371b.</enum><header>Authority of the Advanced Research Projects Agency to carry out certain prototype projects</header></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FD2B042B4DF4CFB9D983F1C0A4D612F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of title 10, United States Code</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>of this title</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAB2986A8E5B4C0E93DAF10C84EE071B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of title 41, United States Code</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>of title 41</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC751E7581E4C40E3BE6317EF8E23B235"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) of subsection (d)(1) to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5182FCDC6AE64FE4B256B3A8F7D943CF" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="HA384043C20994E9CAE7952B62170D81B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all parties to the transaction other than the Federal Government are innovative small business and nontraditional contractors with unique capabilities relevant to the prototype project.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8564013AE3B448ED83DF65F181F6079B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking subsection (i).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C8D567B2E804B79B8C799678B1C85B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2371a the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3E3E575649A403182D0ADAFCE92060E" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">2371b. Authority of the Advanced Research Projects Agency to carry out certain prototype projects.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="HFF17DFABBC4641239B44D2C6411143B8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>710.</enum><header>Amendments to certain acquisition thresholds</header>
 <subsection id="HABA4CAAA798147A3A56808DEA85F7B66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Simplified acquisition threshold generally</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 134 of title 41, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>$100,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$500,000</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H3E126376F48E4B399CF7AA35265E2BCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Micro-Purchase threshold</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1902(a) of title 41, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>$3,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$5,000</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H36A19B3FA3CB4AE68D5D4E952B11A271"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special emergency procurement authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(b)(2) of title 41, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA6735373CBDC4F7FB0A7C4A7CB0CC3BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>$250,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$750,000</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82EB7A35B2B94138B2045046DC97FD3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>$1,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,500,000</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26D4705F0B1C44639661481A30578033"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Small business concern reservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 15(j)(1) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(j)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$100,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$500,000</quote>.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H12266E8FB0A94F98AE67C6D8B67FB34A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>711.</enum><header>Revision of method of rounding when making inflation adjustment of acquisition-related dollar
 thresholds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1908(e)(2) of title 41, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD31599560E0C4C86B096AD1DEA430851"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>on the day before the adjustment</quote> and inserting <quote>as calculated under paragraph (1)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50DD4E6904EA44EFBC8C25852365C817"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6681A4EA583940F880ADFE335A870B65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (D) and inserting the following new subparagraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23FB75A447FF4D91A63BC4FD2F60E469" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H96BFFAB294084014951DD85298399862"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than $1,000,000, but less than $10,000,000, to the nearest $500,000;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CC1A681CC664EB68AF2D94B302921A2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not less than $10,000,000, but less than $100,000,000, to the nearest $5,000,000;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7995C77D9E214AE2BC7FEB98BFE16E15"><enum>(F)</enum><text>not less than $100,000,000, but less than $1,000,000,000, to the nearest $50,000,000; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71FBB782FDD64C519D948B1C2ABEC69F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>$1,000,000,000 or more, to the nearest $500,000,000.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A8B74570638410B8A9C34CE313E2140" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>712.</enum><header>Repeal of requirement for stand-alone manpower estimates for major defense acquisition programs</header>
 <subsection id="HE0C2F277469940449DC9CC2D4641A5FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of requirement</header><text>Subsection (a)(1) of section 2434 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>and a manpower estimate for the program have</quote> and inserting <quote>has</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H574E46BFE5E347798B6B14762EE9F13D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments relating to regulations</header><text>Subsection (b) of such section is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEBAA8769856642D282232055D9877233"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEAEF07537EA409E82CB299F8CF447B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall require—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>that the independent</quote> and inserting <quote>shall require that the independent</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8753D96B9C949599E041DA07BB95755"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively, and realigning those paragraphs so as to be two ems from the left margin; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H263DD6D4153A414099643DF1E56456A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="H38BCD29E1043451B97FE91BCBEFC95DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and operations and support,</quote> and inserting <quote>operations and support, and manpower to operate, maintain, and support the program upon full operational deployment,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F7EA708B35E4EAE89269DF9EF5E4426"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end and inserting a period.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDBADF7F7D23147DDAC847695F9EAC7DB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header> <paragraph id="HE30C152D488842119E6CB7F223780DCA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section heading</header><text>The heading of such section is amended to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H1D7E6C2B380B4F21A0AAB55FBFD86EC8" style="USC">
							<section id="H2A3E18462E5B4AC2B1115944068C1497"><enum>2434.</enum><header>Independent cost estimates</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8581003173A43F8A83E2478D9C057CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The item relating to such section in the table of sections at the beginning of chapter 144 of such title is amended to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H41D4D711F7F44E47A5689BD0894AF1FD" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">2434. Independent cost estimates.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


