<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4A19E979E0B341EC83F9D7D744F55126" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3204 IH: Tackling Excessive Standardized Testing Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3204</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to reduce the testing requirements for
			 part A of title I of such Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H65F9761FBDF24761816EA4C96B8F6000" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAFBBB30DDA274C5F8D9A836A1FECD8D2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tackling Excessive Standardized Testing Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TEST Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5BF305D475DD43339536B344488F4E45"><enum>2.</enum><header> ESEA amendments</header> <subsection id="H91A8CA5B3FAC478F884840B7B321382F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Academic assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1111(b)(3)(C) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(3)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE9076D3402A0418C9B3871EF15375D69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (v)(I), by striking <quote>clause vii</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (vii) and as otherwise provided under clause (xvi)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA537633B005945A280D89238C2AF7AC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by inserting <quote>except as otherwise provided under clause (xvi),</quote> before <quote>beginning</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H113804308EEC4B44B435E6D004D41BA4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (xiv);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0826D4FFCF5477E95BA28FDE02A0B59"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of clause (xv); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61E64A784DFC41CE9A38DD2498CA7291"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84D4D9E238B3431E8993FDD6830CFF97" style="OLC"> <clause id="HECE9BA86D0CD477A88A1C135B9677707"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning with the first full school year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>TEST Act of 2015</short-title>, in lieu of the requirements of clause (vii)—</text>
 <subclause id="HFC38CA167291438E850EF2108EEE5447"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorize any public elementary school or public secondary school to administer the academic assessments in mathematics required under clause (vii) in each of grades 4, 6, and 8;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H408286CA000F43DE927D7F5D77299D89"><enum>(II)</enum><text>authorize any public elementary school or public secondary school to administer the academic assessments in reading or language arts required under clause (vii) in each of grades 3, 5, and 7;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H773FF5F2E5E945CEB988507FC679D0A7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>authorize a public elementary schools or public secondary school at the 15th percentile or above for mathematics in the State (based on the achievement of students for the preceding school year in each of grades 4, 6, and 8 on the academics assessments in mathematics required under clause (vii)), to, for the school year following the administration of such assessments, administer the academic assessments in mathematics required under clause (vii) in each of grades 4 and 8;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFC67C3D33B81426CAAF58BAAD8A33BE5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorize a public elementary school or public secondary school at the 15th percentile or above for reading or language arts in the State (based on the achievement of students for the preceding school year in each of grades 3, 5, and 7 on the academics assessments in reading or language arts required under clause (vii)), to, for the school year following the administration of such assessments, administer the academic assessments in reading or language arts required under clause (vii) in each of grades 3 and 7;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6212D328B0D54600963836CAB9C634D2"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorize a public elementary school or public secondary school whose students do not meet the academic achievement requirements of subclause (III) of this clause, but which has demonstrated such level of progress with respect to the achievement of students on academic assessments in mathematics required under clause (vii), as determined appropriate by the Secretary to be authorized to administer assessments in mathematics in accordance with subclause (III) of this clause, to administer such assessments in mathematics in accordance with such subclause (III); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD702BB0F58974C92A818BFE4A7C0524B"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorize a public elementary school or public secondary school whose students do not meet the academic achievement requirements of subclause (IV) of this clause, but which has demonstrated such level of progress with respect to the achievement of students on academic assessments in reading or language arts required under clause (vii), as determined appropriate by the Secretary to be authorized to administer assessments in reading or language arts in accordance with subclause (IV) of this clause, to administer such assessments in reading or language arts in accordance with such subclause (IV).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C2DEA72EAFA4F44B5908BCC2E971C9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limited English proficient students</header><text>Section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(v)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter following item (dd), by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>and that the achievement of a student with limited English proficiency shall not be considered for purposes of such definition for the first 12 months that the student is enrolled in a public elementary school or public secondary school</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H29BB90AC86DB4EAD80BA5280AE958E22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application to waivers</header><text>Section 9401 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7861">20 U.S.C. 7861</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC921A442260F46D9AF62EA16A8B278BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H28324CA14A8B4D6C9B228C189B92BA0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (9)(C);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H148CD8E81D2640808BA78A07E572A1B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (10) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F06FAEF61214A719996295DE57DF994"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2DDF7BACAF440EEA3028C37CD28C89C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H04715AD783DC4B8E91F281876B0739D1"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirement under section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v) that a student with limited English proficiency be excluded from the definition of adequate yearly progress for the first 12 months that the student is enrolled in a public elementary school or public secondary school.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44083CACEDC04FCB898564339EF8DCF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB137A5C584654540BDFD704075B8A869" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HCCC4F64A64F647F48FC2230574B255D2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Options for certain academic assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A waiver awarded under this section shall not prohibit a State educational agency from administering academic assessments in accordance with clause (xvi) of section 1111(b)(3)(C) in lieu of the requirements of clause (vii) of section 1111(b)(3)(C).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


