<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9E6A080C8E0A4F228BBA3455F537136F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4208 IH: Authority for the Use of Military Force Against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4208</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151210">December 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000589">Mr. Rigell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the use of the United States Armed Forces against the Islamic State of Iraq and the
			 Levant.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H268E5B9934104D7BA506F58C21B07C50" style="OLC">
 <section id="H13F0D8F6643041E68747F772D345BE35" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Authority for the Use of Military Force Against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4464DF59838A4EC5A97F2625560F360F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H893413E6552E497BA71932A49000CF4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terrorist organization that has referred to itself as the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant and various other names (in this resolution referred to as <quote>ISIL</quote>) poses a grave threat to the people and territorial integrity of Iraq and Syria, regional stability, and the national security interests of the United States and its allies and partners.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD89F1F99F06446E797384A33DE957D6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ISIL holds significant territory in Iraq and Syria and has stated its intention to seize more territory and demonstrated the capability to do so.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF4F4BC9826D4905A82B1BC2B56A7A2A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ISIL leaders have stated that they intend to conduct terrorist attacks internationally, including against the United States, its citizens, and interests.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0862A31AEED4BFAAEF5C57D3B3CF914"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ISIL has committed despicable acts of violence and mass executions against Muslims, regardless of sect, who do not subscribe to ISIL’s depraved, violent, and oppressive ideology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB00B0A1C45364853A8518813BC6ECB32"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ISIL has threatened genocide and committed vicious acts of violence against religious and ethnic minority groups, including Iraqi Christian, Yezidi, and Turkmen populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65762CF578F14350B0171A4F7E606D58"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ISIL has targeted innocent women and girls with horrific acts of violence, including abduction, enslavement, torture, rape, and forced marriage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6142831DB9764FB0AF0CC25875360C11"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ISIL is responsible for the deaths of innocent United States citizens, including James Foley, Steven Sotloff, Abdul-Rahman Peter Kassig, and Kayla Mueller.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H011F3FA77C5541B3873FC042D7C055E9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The United States is working with regional and global allies and partners to degrade and defeat ISIL, to cut off its funding, to stop the flow of foreign fighters to its ranks, and to support local communities as they reject ISIL.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26BAEF3EFD7745E08ECBD1051AB0D9D7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The announcement of the anti-ISIL Coalition on September 5, 2014, during the NATO Summit in Wales, stated that ISIL poses a serious threat and should be countered by a broad international coalition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7435FF4CAB1847CAB36D98E7107A2E3D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The United States calls on its allies and partners, particularly in the Middle East and North Africa, to join the anti-ISIL Coalition and defeat this terrorist threat.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5314F8A7564946A79D13859A35C71194"><enum>(11)</enum><text>President Barack Obama, United States military leaders, and United States allies in the region have made clear that it is more effective to use the unique capabilities of the United States Government to support regional partners instead of large-scale deployments of United States ground forces in this mission.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H29809A66A6414AB08B86CA27E47B164D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization for use of United States Armed Forces</header>
 <subsection id="H391D5FFE50C3434D888B8EE3D5B10AB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The President is authorized to use the Armed Forces of the United States as the President determines necessary and appropriate against ISIL or associated persons or forces as defined in section 6.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6FE15399D89F47A294FC9ED12B676073"><enum>(b)</enum><header>War Powers Resolution requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H6F33B428A6204D09B248BD1B6BE1C826"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Specific statutory authorization</header><text>Consistent with section 8(a)(1) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1547">50 U.S.C. 1547(a)(1)</external-xref>), Congress declares that this section is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1544">50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H664B6A568DB646D0B79B72DB5C20D618"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of other requirements</header><text>Nothing in this Act supersedes any requirements of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE717F5D883ED4275B9FBF0AF9FDEB3DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this authorization is to protect the lives of United States citizens and to provide military support to regional partners in their battle to defeat ISIL. The use of significant United States ground troops in combat against ISIL, except to protect the lives of United States citizens from imminent threat, is not consistent with such purpose.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HAB00A4B9641B4D8F892FABAED9DF338D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duration of authorization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authorization for the use of military force under this Act shall terminate three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, unless reauthorized.</text>
 </section><section id="H9CD4B25CFEDE408B9704476464F4DC4C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall report to Congress at least once every six months on specific actions taken pursuant to this authorization.</text>
 </section><section id="H836B523E9CC243E5B03CDD8E8C15219F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Associated persons or forces defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>associated persons or forces</term>—</text> <paragraph id="H5DACD8DDDFC4489F8C7B8D5090C16BBD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means individuals and organizations fighting for, on behalf of, or alongside ISIL or any closely related successor entity in hostilities against the United States or its coalition partners; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H869FC1A2129D481DB8AEE0F7E9D5B403"><enum>(2)</enum><text>refers to any individual or organization that presents a direct threat to members of the United States Armed Forces, coalition partner forces, or forces trained by the coalition, in their fight against ISIL.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H0842F7861E4344C3A93C728D7F76F206"><enum>7.</enum><header>Repeal of Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/243">Public Law 107–243</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 1498; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</external-xref> note) is hereby repealed.</text>
 </section><section id="HC9B91BBC6ADB45D7A0B7489BC2488B90"><enum>8.</enum><header>Sole statutory authority for military action against ISIL</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This authorization shall constitute the sole statutory authority for United States military action against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant and associated persons or forces, and supersedes any prior authorization for the use of military force involving action against ISIL.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


