<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDFA774950DBE44E9936F0A23C5968EEC" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3654 IH: Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3654</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150930">September 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="">Select Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require a report on United States strategy to combat terrorist use of social media, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H868AF46466D04B809B78D00D0BEA811D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE37BEDF3AC1D4C6088CB503DE9D573B7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H017C0EA586ED4B7385DA600126D9D285"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on strategy to combat terrorist use of social media</header> <subsection id="H0FF96254D24E4C5FAFE7E07262A20A98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on United States strategy to combat terrorists’ and terrorist organizations’ use of social media.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H76DDBE1EE8B346C3B58A306C137525B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9A3DE887B628404289C73FD3C3A14D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An evaluation of what role social media plays in radicalization in the United States and elsewhere.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83FD770B155345328F2CBD9B673A74D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An analysis of how terrorists and terrorist organizations are using social media, including trends.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC1EA0D07B894334BEE427CE641F0D56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A summary of the Federal Government’s efforts to disrupt and counter the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations, an evaluation of the success of such efforts, and recommendations for improvement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4E6616BC4E340A5ADCB1380E84C49FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A classified assessment of the intelligence value of social media posts by terrorists and terrorist organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29EA6FE54CAA40F2A3783BC964F179E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A classified overview of social media training available to law enforcement and intelligence personnel that enables such personnel to understand and combat the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations, as well as recommendations for improving or expanding existing training opportunities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA3A94638145454AB9178823C75619E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) should be submitted in sensitive but unclassified form, and may include a classified annex.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF2EFD15737944F8D8151C3AC6BD70D0F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Policy and comprehensive strategy to counter terrorists’ and terrorist organizations’ use of social
			 media</header>
 <subsection id="H449727D71FC0403DA302757A96592B77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H095E0AB2A2FF4281A83C04A0F3E9106E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A policy that enhances the exchange of information and dialogue between the Federal Government and social media companies as it relates to the use of social media platforms by terrorists.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6774E5F09F7C4131B400D1CDABE3CADD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive strategy to counter terrorists’ and terrorist organizations’ use of social media, as committed to in the President’s 2011 <quote>Strategic Implementation Plan for Empowering Local Partners to Prevent Violent Extremism in the United States</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC367216E32404E1CBF8F2C65FA4E61CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) should be submitted in sensitive but unclassified form, and may include a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H93CFF890ADB5455CA58F7AABEEC43FF4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on the Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


