<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE9EED3FDF1C1450597A37B86527EE3C6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3351 IH: CPI-E Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3351</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for cost-of-living increases for certain Federal benefits programs based on increases in
			 the Consumer Price Index for the elderly.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBA54BBE56BFB440CBD6E89178C79F13A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2A6A01162B894FE7A7330DA196ACC81F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CPI-E Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H822ACA7DA2CA42E0B86E43E841932162"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cost-of-living increases for certain Federal benefits programs based on increases in the Consumer Price Index for the elderly</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever there is an increase in the Consumer Price Index for the elderly, published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, the dollar amounts in effect for the payment of the following benefits, as such amounts were in effect immediately before the increase in the Consumer Price Index for the elderly, shall be increased by the same percentage as such price index was increased:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA7CE61A1222B45219C0F675C3EADB938"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An annuity under the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees Retirement System.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H33A4CC4DF71441CCB8BB7FF07CAAB0E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Department of Veterans Affairs wartime disability compensation under section 1114 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51F9BF31D15F40E38F6127FD2E6D678C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department of Veterans Affairs additional compensation for dependents under section 1115(1) of such title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15BFC60759104CDB845C5041322A1C85"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Veterans Affairs clothing allowance under section 1162 of such title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H75324F2A0E9340A590F81B33AAA7349F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department of Veterans Affairs dependency and indemnity compensation to surviving spouse under subsections (a) through (d) of section 1311 of such title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35CB360015764BAA86D0FDBBA5620CF6"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department of Veterans Affairs dependency and indemnity compensation to children under sections 1313(a) and 1314 of such title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5268D2867A345FDA8CDC9D1CDB11B34"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Military retirement and survivor benefit programs, as defined in section 1461(b) of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H660B2A537B1C4851A891C542D1884D15"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any old-age, survivors, or disability insurance benefit under title II of the Social Security Act.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

