<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDF09F6BE322D495C87820AABE40E7929" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3023 IH: To amend title 5, United States Code, to modify probationary periods with respect to positions within the competitive service and the Senior Executive Service, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3023</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150710">July 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to modify probationary periods with respect to positions
			 within the competitive service and the Senior Executive Service, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5FF2A7D8ED0C4432865269A84C7A1FCC" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9DFD4D9B14A243AFAA1F7035D0C19219" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Extension of probationary period for positions within the competitive service</header>
 <subsection id="H76AB6586EA4145BCA29684FA337150F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3321 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE1911C8455134B3D80103F1AE21E02DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>The President</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsections (c) and (d), the President</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51BC76BA83CC46999F1CA16B443DD720"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (e); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE23B22A0DF284F24989CC9055FEACF56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACB6F43954BB4A51AFD6F4ACB25B7FD9" style="USC">
						<subsection id="H3DE1A552C5A44F378001F13AAC989102"><enum>(c)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8D2A90CD8E64496EACBD76C58B3D35C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the length of a probationary period established under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8CBF167EE1BE441F96E25DB43DF50624" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to any position that requires formal training, a period of 2 years beginning on the date that such formal training is completed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABF219A44ACF412CBA92F3DDA21AC052" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any position that requires a license, a period of 2 years beginning on the date that such license is granted; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F3DC7B5009248F69CE164C34269A4B3" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any position not covered by subparagraph (A) or (B), not less than 2 years.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ADDFF34A8954412B368B7C1DEF8FDAA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The length of a probationary period established under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) in the case of a preference eligible shall be not longer than—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD38A77E28AEC435AAA8218AF1BBB81AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the appointment (as referred to in subsection (a)(1)) or the initial appointment (as referred to in subsection (a)(2)) is to a position that exists on the effective date of this subsection, the length of the probationary period which applies to such position as of such effective date; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3B547CAFC524656BF9E8C6CC5042753"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the appointment (as referred to in subsection (a)(1)) or the initial appointment (as referred to in subsection (a)(2)) is to a position that does not exist on the effective date of this subsection, such length of time as the President may establish, consistent with the purposes of this subparagraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26578BEE768A48DE813190E60AFA779F" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0B43B3A8672F4B88A90DC09F37966E19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>formal training</quote> means, with respect to any position, a training program required by law, rule, or regulation, or otherwise required by the employing agency, to be completed by the employee before the employee is able to successfully execute the duties of the applicable position; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38DD13677E45419F995B6FEF900D4F78"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>license</quote> means a license, certification, or other grant of permission to engage in a particular activity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA20184121BFF482D8496286DB51A268F"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall, in the administration of this section, take appropriate measures to ensure that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H194609ACC70147869F585815E4D2C975"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any announcement of a vacant position within such agency and any offer of appointment made to any individual with respect to any such position shall clearly state the terms and conditions of the probationary period applicable to such position;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87AB3CB5A9AB4EB2AACD3E7A4131A2C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any individual who is required to complete a probationary period under this section shall receive timely notice of the performance and other requirements which must be met in order to successfully complete the probationary period; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD20624D705F741389DC21535A3895932"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon successful completion of a probationary period under this section, certification to that effect shall be made, supported by a brief statement of the basis for that certification, in such form and manner as the President may by regulation prescribe.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0116332DCD24ECFBD3222DB72EF2112"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3321(e) of title 5, United States Code (as so redesignated by subsection (a)(2)) is amended by striking <quote>Subsections (a) and (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>Subsections (a) through (d)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC3FF8CF2F2B4D9596635DA837BA508F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section—</text> <paragraph id="H432A7C5F46C14564A8B3280C2DFD70B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09620EAF9C144E04A061E301EE6B665D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall apply in the case of any appointment (as referred to in section 3321(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code) and any initial appointment (as referred to in section 3321(a)(2) of such title) taking effect on or after the date on which this section takes effect.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H406F4BEFACB948FCA7B147D1CCD904D2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of probationary period for positions within the Senior Executive Service </header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H8CD0417880E44FD98FDB3337BA361746"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3393(d) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>1-year</quote> and inserting <quote>2-year</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H460C5E412A31426185E9546D4FABFE1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 3592(a)(1) of such title is amended by striking <quote>1-year</quote> and inserting <quote>2-year</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H1218F4C96F9D413380BD9F566E0CCB2A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Appeals from adverse actions</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H81B41C8F36EA45D3B22BAA0A72F061BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5</header><text>Section 7501(1) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7EE1D0DA264C4B64A5C07242929E23D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1 year</quote> the first place it appears and inserting <quote>not less than 2 years</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC951E7E536404D8DA5C224E2566C2682"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1 year</quote> the second place it appears and inserting <quote>2 years</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H982758E7A8674EC8BE8052EB726F0D17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5</header><text>Section 7511(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H7E60DE0302324B59A0E9630ED3AB36C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by striking <quote>1 year</quote> the first place it appears and inserting <quote>not less than 2 years</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF20B91515F85467885215739AC4FB876"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), by striking <quote>2 years</quote> the first place it appears and inserting <quote>not less than 2 years</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H02A5FE0F20D149B1B38EA05C8CCD97F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b)—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC3D66E0906A1400AA43336EAEA4160F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB42C91EE356C40F3BDE7B94D464057EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall apply in the case of any individual whose period of continuous service (as referred to in the provision of law amended by paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b), as the case may be) commences on or after the date on which this section takes effect.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


