<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC79A48ABCB904DE7BFEB9D979E448A29" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3273 IH: Prohibiting Assistance to Nuclear Iran Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3273</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000548">Mr. Garrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit assistance to Iran to develop, use, or protect any technology or other assets of Iran’s nuclear program, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H219924E7843B484390670348FE7BA7CE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9AFCA9B3185A47278E38F052C783CE7C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prohibiting Assistance to Nuclear Iran Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HC44C5BB6EBDC4FEABE787E29883C3E17"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on assistance to Iran to develop, use, or protect any technology or other assets of Iran’s nuclear program</header> <subsection id="H949ADBF777944EF09BA4C0A1B450B8D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds available to any Federal department or agency may be used to provide assistance to Iran to develop, use, or protect any technology or other assets of Iran’s nuclear program. For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>assistance</term> shall be deemed to include the use of the Armed Forces of the United States. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E82E37FBE104DD49C88FC7092A37184"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the prohibition on the use of funds to provide assistance to Iran under subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis if—</text> <paragraph id="H294A47B8E27B4B95B57FC04879702206"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President determines and submits to Congress a certification that it is necessary to United States national interests to do so; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80609676ED744ECBBA83D2914F0B0EC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than the end of the 5-day period beginning on the date on which such certification is submitted under paragraph (1), there is enacted a joint resolution stating in substance that Congress approves of such certification of the President.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H29ED9489E490483FAFE571D8A5BB1B8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Computation of period of time</header><text>The period of time described in subsection (b)(2) shall be computed without regard to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H759CB98D681E41478AF4006343ABF0BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the days of which either House of Congress is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain or an adjournment of the Congress sine die; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8AEC1401322424883F01889C11FEB81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any Saturday and Sunday, not excluded under paragraph (1), when either House of the Congress is not in session.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

