<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBBFCB328FDB6486C9F894A2C1E86D05C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2537 IH: College Affordability and Innovation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2537</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for higher education reform.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCF3AFA4007E747898A2659C8461B7715" style="OLC">
 <section id="H36630818EBA04AF294851EA8FA551163" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>College Affordability and Innovation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDAF7D4A526A4494E85FEC276EE997F3B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6CC3CFF06C624C0D9492BEDF343D24A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorizing committees</header><text>The term <term>authorizing committees</term> means the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58EC6CC398554710B38E4C3F8D7CFC28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H0B4C234C734A472F967F5EC5EFC3FB33"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot program to promote innovation in higher education</header> <subsection id="H5EDCBAF41B7748638333A79EFBF9C1F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose; definition</header> <paragraph id="HCE7484FAE8174684B63D33F7F04C2CDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to authorize an evidence-based grant program to promote greater experimentation among institutions of higher education to increase the level of student attainment of postsecondary and graduate certificates and degrees through innovative programs designed to decrease the cost and time required to complete postsecondary and graduate programs while improving the quality and effectiveness of postsecondary education programs, providing accelerated degree or certificate programs, and increasing on-time graduation rates.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H220E0E8CAD27439D9830C4A7B376BDAD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>In this section, the term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE776ECCF7AF41C294E4C2373D1BE719"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Incentive grants for innovative programs that improve quality and affordability</header>
				<paragraph id="H71A45DA08CBA4B2CB7F38C4BDE6C5655"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4865F40FDB71413F814BF3D46F6384F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary shall, for a 5-year award term, award grants to not more than 15 institutions of higher education, through a competitive process described in this section, to enable the institutions to carry out programs designed to graduate students with certificates or degrees at significantly lower costs for students and within shorter time periods than traditional programs while improving the quality and effectiveness of the programs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FCD53D7A15B4630B979E418CB929F41"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good standing requirement</header><text>Only those institutions of higher education that are in good standing with the administration of their student assistance programs under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be eligible to receive grants under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC00C660FF5486DB0CAC3F492B0444E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution of grant funds</header><text>Grant payments shall be awarded with an initial distribution of 20 percent of the total grant amount, followed by a distribution of 10 percent of the total grant amount prior to the second, third, and fourth years of the program, and the remaining 50 percent of the total grant amount after the program receives its final satisfactory annual evaluation by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (f)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90D89E018EC74740B40F66F633BE6F03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Description of innovative programs</header><text>The programs described under paragraph (1) shall include those that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB09387767340418CBFA2D9BD4640EF79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilize online instruction, including distance education (as defined in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>)), or online interaction components, or online instruction integrated with classroom or in-person instruction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1DC10E123AF4029BFA200F325D7BF4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilize direct assessment programs, as described in section 481(b)(4) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088(b)(4)</external-xref>), either within a comprehensive direct assessment program or integrated within another type of academic program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD36574E5802438B8608ED135539FF0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>utilize integration of experiential learning and design of customized programs of study, to promote completion or alignment with medium- and long-term employment needs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EE3E6E9E79B4DD19DEB0F2B898CA09D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allow students to be dually or concurrently enrolled in the postsecondary program and a secondary school, or a postsecondary program and a graduate program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4619A34FC7C4054A9FE6B80DBB7F1B7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>allow students to transfer credits from secondary to postsecondary to graduate programs, such as between associate's and bachelor’s degree programs, without undue burdens, cost, or loss of credit to students to encourage early and on-time completion of a postsecondary degree or certificate; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6982ED61FADD44CFBC2361DB7E670A0F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>utilize any other innovative, evidence-based method of postsecondary education that provides cost-effective, high-quality methods for instruction, student learning, and use of available technology-based resources, including hybrid models incorporating elements of the program types set forth in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), (D), and (E), and adaptive learning technologies.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A2DECEB9F4E4ED59A1D3D93E1F8A271"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header>
 <paragraph id="HEFCCE5082D38468F9317BEF78B11F9A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An institution of higher education that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7F1DB0F09684225B27BF8BB830E6C8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H50A43C052A2641538E6EBF7A733505B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the institution’s quality assurances for the programs to be offered;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4132E5126852481BAD3FEDB95850EFA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the statutory and regulatory requirements for which a waiver is sought under subsection (e) and the reasons for which the waiver is sought;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B89698049154E998957DA788CE094D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the programs to be offered;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EC3CE3700834BE5A0D4B60FC59B29F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the students eligible for the programs offered, including any eligibility limitations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11C26B95452B4910BD4BCB4ABD5D4E2F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an assurance that the institution will fully cooperate with the ongoing evaluations of the programs provided for in this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5034EC0B54894A44A182C5557A273A68"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of how the proposed program will improve the quality of its postsecondary certificates or degrees, reduce tuition and other costs to students, and reduce enrollment time;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2432074A9A6E44DBB20A51EB1A031BFD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of the data (or any other evidence) that indicate that the programs to be offered will likely lead to the outcomes described in subparagraph (F);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D73A5F0A6784DFFA0212DB9DA1FE1DA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a complete listing of the institution’s performance goals and measures regarding assessments of the quality of its postsecondary certificates or degrees, amount of tuition and costs charged to students, and the amount of enrollment time needed by students to complete the postsecondary certificates or degrees; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03F207B287C741A3AF89675BD258E184"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any other information as the Secretary may require.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85F3D50DFFF344FBAEF82FCEE8A81A4F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Awarding of grants</header> <paragraph id="HA768CE3C839149B9A1073A1FAC513713"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under this section to institutions of higher education for new or existing programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E31A5F2EF7B4002ACBC278356A82B2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an institution of higher education that the Secretary determines—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H07FCAB2A943B47309A38E45C8235C850"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is financially responsible, as described in section 498(c)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099c">20 U.S.C. 1099c(c)(1)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C035F46581A42CCB84F87AC85B4F24E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a proven record of graduating students from the other programs of the institution;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26D84BA7C2C5489AB0498FF7F6104277"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has a proven record of graduates from the other programs of the institution securing full-time employment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7519CECE67F84C89871415EA94DA43E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>simultaneously addresses income-related inequalities in remedial education, college access, persistence rates, and graduation rates;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884D360A63F84C40996C7853857F7470"><enum>(E)</enum><text>has support services in place, such as counseling, coaching, mentoring, and outreach, that are designed to assist all students in obtaining information and making decisions regarding financial aid, and degree or certificate likelihood of persistence and completion;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B9C9AF078244C299475FF29E30BE9D1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>will serve low-income students, adult students aged 25 years and older, and part-time students;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92219814BF25488B80DDFB8B71035743"><enum>(G)</enum><text>will support programs that are replicable at a range of institutions of higher education if they are demonstrated to be successful; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54279ED05C1B43999EFB562B0EA3C8A8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>has presented the strongest evidence in support of their likely outcomes, as required under subsection (c)(2)(G).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BCF815AD13B4EA69C1C89DBE53D61BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Diverse populations</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall ensure the participation of diverse student populations, including rural and urban populations, and of a diverse range of institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H346100481E164AF19B59C29B573FCD06"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication of grantees</header><text>The Secretary shall make available to the public and to the authorizing committees a list of the institutions of higher education awarded a grant under this section, including a listing of the specific statutory and regulatory requirements being waived for each institution and a description of the programs and courses to be offered.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73A878EDE1784FCEB8500BFE31DB5CC4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waivers</header>
 <paragraph id="H9F291257845A4487BB9E845C3E21AE9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (2), with respect to institutions of higher education awarded grants under this section, the Secretary may waive—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5E7253AC2AD64975AF76CBD676B9D076"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subsection (a) or (b) of section 481 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088(a)</external-xref> and (b)), as such subsections relate to requirements for a minimum number of weeks of instruction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29A372298CD04BA0AA0891D64D2B22A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 102(a)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(a)(3)(A)</external-xref> and (B));</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9671A70F79AC49858576212D41BF0335"><enum>(C)</enum><text>one or more of the regulations promulgated to carry out part F or G of title IV of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087kk">20 U.S.C. 1087kk et seq.</external-xref> and 1088 et seq.), which inhibit the operation of innovative education programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB71732FD30747599D5C912B76DFB241"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other requirement under title IV of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) that will bias the results of the program, including a requirement related to the award process and disbursement of student financial aid (such as innovative delivery systems for modular or compressed courses or other innovative systems), or other management procedures or processes as determined in the negotiated rulemaking process under section 492 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098a">20 U.S.C. 1098a</external-xref>), or regulations prescribed under such title.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAFA5DAB7DEC408A9590151870091331"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition of waiver</header><text>The Secretary shall not waive, pursuant to paragraph (1), any provision under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) or a regulation promulgated to carry out such Act with respect to award rules (other than an award rule related to an experiment in modular or compressed schedules), grant and loan maximum award amounts, and need analysis requirements, unless the waiver of such provision is authorized by another provision under such Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94066383D884414A9A4D560BC5336BAF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation and reports</header>
 <paragraph id="HAD38E39D62684858BCD86AA5E59BCD65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation and accountability process</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an evaluation and accountability process for the programs authorized under this section and shall administer such process on an annual basis. Such evaluations shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H83255C8B130243589963549CEA8F1D85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which the institution of higher education has met the goals set forth in its application to the Secretary, including the quality of education provided by participating programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD60744679D1A4B0091F1D8F21C8958BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and types of students participating in the programs offered, including the progress of participating students toward recognized certificates or degrees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0AE7374C29E4A31ABA8102E238008B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>issues related to student financial assistance;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA75D1BA9237A4DCE8331554A14E0DA0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which any statutory or regulatory requirements present difficulties for students or institutions in the participating programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9136013145D04761BE6BC67F91EAE93E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an analysis of the program’s progress with each of its objectives, including the number and rate of completion of participating students toward recognized certificates or degrees, prices charged to students, time required to complete the participating programs, on-time completion rates of participating students, and indicators of program quality.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E96CC4F4D88459E8B380F5C4A4DD43F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary shall review policies and identify those policies that present impediments to the development and use of innovative programs and other nontraditional methods of expanding success and access to education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H568E9EA0F1944BC2A53A51216078B71B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Measures</header><text>The Secretary shall establish measures to assess the quality of the education provided by participating programs under this section, including a minimum standard of quality that participating programs shall meet.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F20890DDCB4C09B2EB5C45AA25549C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary shall provide reports to the authorizing committees on an annual basis regarding—</text> <subparagraph id="HAAB80E31A1CC4EF2A471EE907B162225"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the programs authorized under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97806C65DBC94BF2A82143A3F6D6FD5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and types of students receiving assistance under this section for instruction leading to a recognized degree or certificate, including the progress of such students toward recognized certificates and the degree to which participation in such programs leading to such certificates increased.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C2C56C7C9A84049B9EFE27DC2D9DC9B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duties of the secretary</header><text>In conducting the program authorized under this section, the Secretary shall, on a continuing basis—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD75A20BDEE6846D6937264EE0F0115B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure compliance of institutions of higher education with the requirements of this section (other than the sections and regulations that are waived under subsection (e));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAECF57C16C94444894627B867EFB6629"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide technical assistance;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C53E41FFA3E475BBAACD437A21CAAF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitor fluctuations in the student population enrolled in the participating program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1B48BF667284A3B9E99D26669229B74"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assess whether each participating program is improving the quality of postsecondary credentials and meeting the quality control measures set by the Secretary.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H747B1B52611A4CCD8E2F87501215B691"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consumer protection for students</header>
 <paragraph id="HA4AEC45D3B324E808F7F65FAF2E25FEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program termination</header><text>If a program funded under this section terminates on its accord at any point during which the program is receiving funds under this section, or if the Secretary determines that the program does not meet the minimum standard of quality as required under subsection (f)(3)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB21D08DB6E5449368F0986C78317C2CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the institution of higher education administering the program shall provide immediate notice to students enrolled in the program and shall prepare a teach-out plan, as described in section 487(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(f)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A2F88F93A424DBFBFE0EA3AACAE055B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H130A1ABF2ED64C029CD29A1E2DE4E480"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that—</text>
 <subclause id="H97AE1E3CB0C74C9DA08C2FA2DA4F30C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no additional program funds are distributed to the program; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H105F7C5CDD8C40DF80C00E1F7A6EE8BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the institution of higher education administering the program is in compliance with the notice and teach-out requirements under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H616067F3A8CB49B7952C8CB21553630A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assess a fine to an institution of higher education administering the program that is not in compliance with the notice and teach-out requirements under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H726184175FB84CEFB0C88D826CC08D7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice and disclosure for students</header><text>An institution of higher education administering a participating program under this section shall provide notice to all students before they enroll in the participating program that such program is receiving grant funds under this section and may be terminated, as described in paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8359C604B9854529BBA84906D29D7F6E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Final evaluation by third-Party reviewer</header>
 <paragraph id="H902DC94D7F5D402D9A0E5EF697A5EBE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall direct an independent third-party evaluator to review all participating programs and conduct a final evaluation in order to determine the evidence of the effectiveness of each program in achieving its objectives with regard to the quality of the education provided, reducing the cost of the degree or certificate program, and shortening the amount of time needed to complete the degree or certificate program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77CEEA02032448C1A493016EA16D7921"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation methodology</header><text>The independent third-party evaluator shall establish evaluation methodology in carrying out the final evaluation under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50CBAC5043D54BF8BE24C5333619F9A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission to authorizing committees</header><text>The independent third-party evaluator shall publicize the final evaluation and submit such evaluation to the authorizing committees.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95365EB270D04641A17EB8F6A0951EBF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Not more than 1 percent of the total amount appropriated to carry out this section may be used to carry out this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H375603E389F9492D8F81F50734ADD691"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text> <paragraph id="H0D65F89F1B294CF9AF68216DA1B099E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$260,000,000 for fiscal year 2016; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED5425822BA14B58943596790C273E22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as may be necessary for each succeeding fiscal year.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF0AF8BB6DC334ABEA286556D908929CD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Higher education accountability</header> <subsection id="HD8DE030870AE4A319626D653E17409F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose; definition</header> <paragraph id="HFFDDC6D741E54CC5A0DB252F5A818845"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The purpose of this section is to establish minimum institutional accountability standards that will be required of all institutions of higher education that receive funds or whose students receive funds pursuant to title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) programs. The standards shall focus on affordability, accessibility for low- and middle-income students, and value.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE0D1AB0A638415A97BA2A5220DA9F4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="HAAD2850E9E594C61BD04B887BAF498E9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> means an institution of higher education described in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>), except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C3D695598CC48B98931941EF076914D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> does not include institutions that solely offer graduate or professional degree programs of study.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE7D5B407C0D4DC6B18A39314381F44E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Institutions</header><text>To the extent an institution offers undergraduate programs of study and graduate or professional degree programs of study, for purposes of this section, the term <term>institution of higher education</term> with respect to such institutions shall only include the undergraduate programs of study.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2D0CCFD164E4FBB941B8184760AF615"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission on higher education accountability standards</header>
 <paragraph id="H6F1A8EA226D24B19841817460165B5EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, there shall be established a Commission on Higher Education Accountability Standards (referred to in this section as the <quote>Commission</quote>) to make recommendations on a set of minimum accountability standards and the measures for assessing compliance with such standards for institutions of higher education that shall focus on affordability, access for low- and middle-income students, and value.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HFEA6267D0C98486DA5646F6F539FE34D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition of the Commission</header>
 <subparagraph id="H078B795A10A644EC9ECB5BC5943C31EA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Members of the Commission shall be appointed as follows:</text> <clause id="H573BE0C92A514463A72AD61B71BF3C85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate, with the concurrence of the Minority Leader of the Senate on 2 of such members.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFD974FB27E834D0F86DCE537740D6CF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the House of Representatives, with the concurrence of the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives on 2 of such members.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2547E882C9E248479F40561B3F3C764B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed by the Secretary, including at least 1 member from the National Center for Education Statistics and 1 member from the Federal Student Aid Office of the Department of Education.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B925ADD59204AD2923373B8B02FD150"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>In the event that any member of the Commission has not been appointed during the 90-day period after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall appoint the remaining member in order to establish the Commission.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2B98402F7DC44A683C20B67909CF090"><enum>(B)</enum><header>General qualifications</header><text>Members of the Commission shall be appointed on the basis of the individuals’—</text> <clause id="H1BE46FBE2A5D49BFB58CC5C53B7EFC6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>experience, integrity, impartiality, and good judgment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H27CFCDAEBA9444A2B22BA0E4C265AB18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>except with respect to the undergraduate students, technical qualifications and professional standing.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D915596ADA2493BBC240BFCF928A8B0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Members of the commission</header><text>Members appointed under subparagraph (A) shall be comprised of the following relevant stakeholders:</text> <clause id="HC4CAE82316CE4491B959B179DF40376F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>2 undergraduate student leaders from different types of institutions of higher education.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9EA167D5AA7E4846A1ADAFF0E756BC47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>2 members of national or regional student advocacy organizations with a track record of engagement and expertise on issues related to college costs and student debt.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H98241FADA8424962BE3EB8A2D850BBA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>1 consumer advocate or consumer protection expert with demonstrated knowledge of consumer protection issues related to undergraduate students.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H69E1A497DFB046F7BFA435BCD695A1F7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>2 representatives of faculty groups or associations with expertise related to higher education finance or governance.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H48A6709B1820419A8D9B383DE9761689"><enum>(v)</enum><text>1 State government official with demonstrated knowledge of State budgeting and higher education funding.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87CDB667A5BD45E882721A6072A5EA54"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>3 administrative officers from various types of institutions of higher education, including at least 1 from a minority-serving institution.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAACA30F9BC424415943708FF6F833088"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>1 higher education researcher.</text> </clause><clause id="H1128901F629F429FB784D1BC16C8700A"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>1 State postsecondary education data system director.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H435EF144925145648608A5F228265148"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>1 member from the National Center for Education Statistics.</text> </clause><clause id="HD98053E4234E4E368E22678DA9BEDD52"><enum>(x)</enum><text>1 member from the Federal Student Aid Office of the Department of Education.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD82D26645CB432AAC6E8203268647F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE888D3CDF5054A06BDF7E289F63FB590"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall make recommendations on a set of minimum accountability standards that institutions of higher education must meet with respect to affordability, accessibility, and value in order to receive funds or that the students of such institutions may receive funds pursuant to title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) programs. The Commission shall also recommend measures and acceptable levels of performance on those measures to assess compliance with the minimum accountability standards. If the Commission cannot issue its recommendations by consensus, it shall issue its recommendations based on the views of a majority of the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61593EA5037E4733A0A26E83ECEEA066"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required measures</header><text>The Commission shall include, at a minimum, the following measures as part of the minimum accountability standards it shall recommend:</text>
 <clause id="H450F80B52D2D471DBBBE7176766A7915"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Affordability</header><text>The average or mean cost of tuition and other costs required for attendance after all institutional, Federal, and State grant aid is taken into account.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H72A22E3A088F4999BE4353117D965A65"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text>The percentage of the total number of enrolled students who are recipients of a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C9417AF25734FA3959DCFD725CB4C5B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Value</header><text>Student loan repayment rates.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H521B9C790CE14F6292B12788E896D6AF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other measures</header><text>The Commission shall make recommendations on additional measures to comprise the minimum accountability standards, including the following:</text>
 <clause id="HBCF1751E71A94F2E8F518D6B8022521F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Affordability</header><text>The Commission shall make recommendations on additional higher education affordability measures, including the appropriateness of the following:</text>
 <subclause id="H28BE89A242E7475FA89CE7072E12ED21"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The cost of tuition relative to the cost to the institution of educating a student and the institution’s administrative costs.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H68036D413FB546CFA616E0712ACEFC52"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The percentage of institutional aid that is awarded on the basis of need, as opposed to merit.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H1E543A3558414678A67F0FDBB7A2CDC3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Annual increases in tuition after taking into account all public subsidies.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCBD6785974044A509519361BBE0A52CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text>The Commission shall make recommendations on higher education accessibility measures, including the appropriateness of the following:</text>
 <subclause id="H537108F264C94D8ABCD7C5AB3914C7D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Enrollment of low- and middle-income, underrepresented minorities, and adult students aged 25 and older.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA22F4318AF5B48FD86578B4F7A9DD413"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Whether institutional policies on credit transfers meet industry standards by type of receiving institution.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H34B175F0AE1F42AC83589B9E72C9EFC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Value</header><text>The Commission shall make recommendations on measures of higher education value, including the appropriateness of the following:</text>
 <subclause id="HDB5CD32280384562A98C162673CDF2CA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Student progress toward completion of a postsecondary degree or certificate.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H29719799FABD480CAF02DC3AFD99593F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Student completion of a postsecondary degree or certificate, including for transfer and part-time students, or where applicable, transfer rates to 4-year degree programs.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8AE4B3A7BD5C431AA3FA95E2C9E761A3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Student retention rates.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB44DD79D726D4660A47389190C8CEA1C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Full-time employment and graduate degree enrollment rates after graduation.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H449A092C03A2476CB2286EFB3E97993D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Commission shall take into account the differences in missions of institutions of higher education and ensure that institutions are held to standards that are appropriate for their mission.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H48364872A65945C5B3D905C090E4525E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hearings and report</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2E1FFEC063854436A24C0392C76E4380"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the appointment of the final member of the Commission, the Commission shall hold public field hearings in all regions of the United States. The Commission shall hold not fewer than 8 hearings.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H676E7A390E6146A989AA586F70693F71"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the appointment of the final member of the Commission, the Commission shall prepare a report on the recommendations under paragraph (3) and submit the report to the Secretary and the authorizing committees. The report shall include the following:</text>
 <clause id="HE853E2A22A564D9092DC00BBA80E4282"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Recommendations for minimum accountability standards and the measures for assessing compliance with those standards for every institution of higher education that receives funds or whose students receive funds pursuant to title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) programs. The standards shall focus on affordability, access for low- and middle-income students, and value. The Commission shall recommend standards that are in accordance with the types of information that institutions of higher education are authorized to collect and report under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6D7BC1C9107A4505B5EE0EDDC3862628"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Recommendations for applying the standards to institutions of higher education with different academic missions.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H84CC309989B544D39DA8E79F59A8F8D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Recommendations for periodic reevaluation of the standards and their efficacy by the Secretary.</text> </clause><clause id="H8F6104B153964F25917523855C589101"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Recommendations for sharing institutions’ performance with respect to the standards with prospective students and conducting complementary consumer education for students.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H774639E64BCA4317AEE7630633F0B727"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Recommendations for the criteria the Secretary should use to reward institutions of higher education that meet and exceed the minimum accountability standards.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4E121ED2A0734A788800AD7482FD8C2C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Recommendations to Congress on reforms to statutory or regulatory limitations on the collection and availability of data that would improve the Secretary’s ability to assess institutions’ compliance with minimum standards of affordability, accessibility, and value.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33F9EAFE73D140EAADB76CD6A7FC3AC1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Securing information</header><text>The Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out its duties under this section. The Commission may request the head of any State or local department or agency to furnish such information to the Commission.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HDE800581EFBF4218A94477973D0C5238"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Final standards</header>
 <subparagraph id="H447962DE5E414CE4890C77E7F260EB72"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving the report under paragraph (5), the Secretary shall publish a final rule on institutional accountability standards. The standards shall be determined by the Secretary after giving due consideration to the recommended standards provided by the Commission. The Secretary shall set forth in writing the reasons for any deviation from the Commission’s recommendations for any standard or measure and shall submit the written statement to the authorizing committees.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0D662EDF5854E25BB87A70B8A3E749D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required measures to be included</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall include the measures described in paragraph (3)(B) that the Commission is required to include as part of its minimum accountability standards.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88D798FCBC5640EFADCBB1F22767873B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The Secretary shall annually assess compliance with the institutional accountability standards. On September 30 of the year following the publication of the final rule as required under paragraph (7) and every year thereafter, the Secretary shall publish a list of each institution of higher education that participates in title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) and the institution's level of compliance with the accountability standards. The list shall be made easily accessible to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB343ED80B69E4CC49F3AA21A035AE627"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures to implement this subsection, including procedures for effectively applying this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD664011538674E21A354FE549872C4F7"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate 60 days after the date on which the Commission submits the report under paragraph (5).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H832C8BE2C6A342B088EDA17EB7114408"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incentivize improvement for below-Standard institutions</header>
 <paragraph id="HC90B957F386C42078B2606DD8960701A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An institution of higher education that participates in title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) programs and that does not meet the institutional accountability standards adopted under subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFAFB0D834159426DBF0129C95E9725A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be deemed to be in probationary status; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CCE0209743B4FAEBE92E807E2B6F80F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall work with the Secretary to develop a plan for how the institution will achieve compliance not later than 5 years after the date of the determination of noncompliance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE844E2EF41E4BB19E4008BED22D0C95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuous improvement</header><text>For each year following a determination that an institution of higher education does not meet the institutional accountability standards adopted under subsection (b), the institution shall demonstrate to the Secretary continuous improvement in following its plan to achieve compliance.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9BB687B3AC214A8CB2515FE3FBC81F71"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Failure to make continuous improvement</header>
					<subparagraph id="HA1BBBF6462B74976A2E95E6766B3E78E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <clause id="HFF501AC8D32C4BE68672B322D287218C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>2 years out</header><text>If an institution of higher education does not show continuous improvement 2 years after a determination that it does not meet the institutional accountability standards adopted under subsection (b), the institution shall pay to the Secretary an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of funds made available under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) to students in attendance with an undergraduate enrollment status at the institution during the prior academic year, to be deposited into the fund described in subparagraph (C).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8688B75697F64AC79ED2B754578309A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>3 years out</header><text>If an institution of higher education does not show continuous improvement 3 years after a determination that it does not meet the institutional accountability standards adopted under subsection (b), the institution shall pay to the Secretary an amount equal to 20 percent of the total amount of funds made available under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) to students in attendance with an undergraduate enrollment status at the institution during the prior academic year, to be deposited into the fund described in subparagraph (C).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H30701D13E2E941DB9EE77E1041BCD222"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>4 years out</header><text>If an institution of higher education does not show continuous improvement 4 years after a determination that it does not meet the institutional accountability standards adopted under subsection (b), the institution shall pay to the Secretary an amount equal to 30 percent of the total amount of funds made available under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) to students in attendance with an undergraduate enrollment status at the institution during the prior academic year, to be deposited into the fund described in subparagraph (C).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC666BB5EFD1D48E49E73029DEA91ACE5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver and payment plan</header>
 <clause id="H3AF2EC731AFE450B9D5629507CE65A27"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive a requirement of an institution of higher education paying the amount owed pursuant to subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines such a waiver is necessary to avoid extreme hardship for the students enrolled at such institution.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H70BBF967F31E4783A62EB2B419D7301E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Payment plan</header><text>The Secretary may allow an institution of higher education that owes an amount under subparagraph (A) to enter into a payment plan to pay such amount.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD53B1155D414A2ABDC1020980F93C5F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>There shall be established a special fund in which amounts refunded by an institution of higher education under this paragraph shall be placed to be used pursuant to subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2A9FDA2DE61454DB7E4BCF3C9B0C6C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Noncompliance five years out</header><text>If an institution of higher education fails to achieve compliance by not later than the date that is 5 years after the date of the determination that the institution does not meet the institutional accountability standards, the institution—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H47FF9F7EE55849F19D86327DCB34F8D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be eligible to receive funds under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) for the academic year following the date that is 5 years after the date of the determination;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA08409106AFD498CB2B78658513300B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be required to submit a teach-out plan, as described in section 487(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(f)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H844BD1A9635841EDAEF0511D2CBACA0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall be eligible to receive funds under such title IV when the institution is able to demonstrate compliance with the institutional accountability standards.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9C971F6ABD64D2AB2277581E8EE86A1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of reward grant program</header>
 <paragraph id="HE727D06C192948AE85D91C370D065D79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts available in the fund established pursuant to subsection (c)(3)(C), the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education that meet or exceed the institutional accountability standards adopted under subsection (b). In determining the criteria for awarding grants, the Secretary shall give due consideration to the recommendations of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46104FFD533A450A914F28C5C0023084"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use for financial aid</header><text>An institution of higher education awarded a grant under paragraph (1) shall use the grant funds for need-based aid to students who are eligible for Federal Pell Grants under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


