<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6CB17294F3A6417BADD4A20A4C09AADA" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3783 IH: Community-Based Gang Intervention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3783</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151021">October 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide definitions of terms and services related to community-based gang intervention to ensure
			 that funding for such intervention is utilized in a cost-effective manner
			 and that community-based agencies are held accountable for providing
			 holistic, integrated intervention services, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE8EE874B165A45D9914610C9A8384825" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBEC6301BB416406F987749B213712A7E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community-Based Gang Intervention Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H70021ECE7CDE4C45B4962860DB4E4CB9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H9B7E1FE525854C9489080474C179A9FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H57A566ADABF646FA8C424B179226842B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the first time in the history of the United States, more than one in every 100 adults is incarcerated.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80E54A747CDD48F4ADB78AF847D1F2D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States incarcerates more people than any other country in the world, with more than 2,200,000 people behind bars and another 5,000,000 people on probation or parole.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A2C905B15D34D60964FF7DDEB26E595"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States has only 5 percent of the world’s population, but 25 percent of the world’s prisoners.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB3171B8629D42B7995E5F24494BE6F1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2007, the Federal Government spent $19,617,000,000 on police protection, corrections, and judicial and legal services, representing a 286-percent increase since 1982. This included a 475-percent increase for corrections and a 287-percent increase for police protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9FCC83547174FE2994BCBB72EBEACA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The growing prison system is also impacting State budgets, with total State spending on incarceration topping $53,000,000,000 in 2012, up from $10,000,000,000 in 1987.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF79B7F1717F94F4EB9FE131E752661EE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>With increased prison costs, vital social programs and services such as education, job creation, housing, and healthcare are being cut or eliminated to maintain the prison industry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0941072A84434D6C8039C89F152237B0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Between 1987 and 2007, the amount States spent on corrections increased 127 percent, while the increase in higher education spending was only 21 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H201F1EA33FE14661B8722DEA10F88686"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Over the past 10 years, the State of California’s general fund expenditures for higher education have fallen 9 percent, while general fund expenditures for corrections and rehabilitation have increased 26 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6871964422E24DD38EA180F3F4B22943"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The State of California has the second largest prison population in the Nation with 165,062 prisoners under the jurisdiction of State or Federal correctional authorities in 2010.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H699D1ACB104B4DBC8140A19DABAD9589"><enum>(10)</enum><text>According to one study, there are now 6 times as many gangs and at least twice the number of gang members in Los Angeles since the start of the 30-year <term>war on gangs</term>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8B32692C4524E4D8B9D2EADE2F39692"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The city and county of Los Angeles have been dubbed the <term>gang capital</term> of the Nation with an estimated 463 gangs and 38,974 gang members in the city, and more than 1,300 gangs and 150,000 gang members in the county.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69AF812E36264ABB960F6EA393711987"><enum>(12)</enum><text>According to the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, allowing 1 youth to leave school for a life of crime and drug abuse costs society between $1,700,000 and $2,300,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA22CE5AADDF4BAEBF7177D452CF1F7C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In the State of California, the average annual cost per inmate is $47,421 for an adult inmate, and $218,000 for a youth inmate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5ABEA16FF8634296BC1ACC6AD736FE24"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The most recent data on overall State spending on juvenile justice programs reveals that in 1998, States spent nearly $4,200,000,000 on juvenile justice related programs, which was a 65-percent increase from fiscal year 1994. Of those expenditures, 67 percent went towards residential placements, while only 8.4 percent went towards delinquency prevention.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09191C18438341119BB003CFEA880E9F"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Gang and youth violence substantially decreases when governments address the root causes of gang violence and adequately fund community-based programs and practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70A4317FA7EA41378679DE222DA7B00A"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Studies continue to prove that community-based gang intervention provides long-lasting, cost-effective results and opportunities for the youth and families most susceptible to gang violence.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H814FCE76A2644571A2F7210372BFFC2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that, in developing a comprehensive violence reduction strategy, the United States should acknowledge and address larger, entrenched social conditions and issues such as poverty, homelessness, inadequate educational systems, and limited economic opportunities that give rise to gangs and gang violence.</text>
			</subsection></section><title id="HAC09873C71A140DF923F19D90469E704"><enum>I</enum><header>COMMUNITY-BASED GANG INTERVENTION AGENCIES</header>
 <section id="HBDDBAE375F3B4FE29DBCC949E51F4AA2"><enum>101.</enum><header>Community-based gang intervention agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5601">42 U.S.C. 5601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new title:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38D633D2C8B84C35854D3B71105FF979" style="OLC">
					<title id="H014C8E692E0D4B3398B7768AF70E0E28"><enum>VI</enum><header>COMMUNITY-BASED GANG INTERVENTION GRANTS</header>
 <section id="H45655749F68141F98687059954E42318"><enum>601.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this title is to offer holistic and comprehensive support for the variety of community-based gang intervention activities that focus on and engage active and former gang members, their close associates, and gang members in and returning from confinement. Gang-involved youth and their families require specialized intensive and comprehensive services that address the unique issues encountered by youth when they become involved with gangs. Community-based gang intervention involves proactive and reactive responses to gang activities on several levels, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H665FA9B23B0643E6925D2A3BA9FB6877"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the regional level, to promote and coordinate peace truces and cease-fires between groups;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H098526A12F3C46FAA91D54972D0165B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State and local level, including community and the juvenile halls, camps, Division of Juvenile Justice facilities, county jails, and State prisons; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E381CD61C7241608D3599C997B9294C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the neighborhood and street level, including with active gang members individually.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H2A57784D65094659AFAB4E947CD1A4C6"><enum>602.</enum><header>Support of community-based gang intervention agencies</header> <subsection id="HC34AF5B6FA9A4EC99557F409E693766E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Support of community-Based gang intervention agencies</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall award grants to eligible entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8AEC5D6F88A341729C8379857112235F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>For the purposes of this section, an <term>eligible entity</term> means a community-based gang intervention agency that is a nonprofit organization with a proven track record and expertise in providing community-based gang intervention activities through a community-based gang intervention model.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E255223FEC94D3F987EB23A7516D819"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant activities</header><text>Each entity awarded a grant under this section shall carry out the following activities:</text> <paragraph id="HE50F06762B8445FC89BB3568474537EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conduct street mediation by working with gang members and persons with influence over such member to defuse and de-escalate potential and actual violence internally between gang members and between rival gangs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD6E5FB9081C49C694AAA73569E2CABC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Develop local and regional truces by creating cease-fires or nonaggression agreements between rival gangs and neighborhoods.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56A810A0A74A47649BB05F54E2AE9D53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Serve as conduits who facilitate constant dialogue and maintenance between gangs and neighborhoods.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB57A7D98EF57410D8F531BBB10C61922"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provide services that respond to the high levels of anxiety experienced by gang members to decompress critical situations due to traumatic events.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3EA5CCA71A7431D95B95D47508FCF41"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Provide 24-hour, 7-day-a-week crisis intervention services by responding to requests for violence prevention services made by gang members, the families of gang members, school officials, intervention workers, social service agencies, or law enforcement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4EF1FDE44D04EC7BF4E124FC6403292"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Provide targeted training and technical assistance to violence-plagued communities after a major gang-related incident.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA719A3B0AE1481E900899669F68A87F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Facilitate the development of a community response plan, including training protocols, situational scene scenarios, and emergency response.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDFDAFB3B5A24BD295A8DABF1C367955"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Make a reasonable effort to prevent gang-related rumors from intensifying tension between gangs or igniting violent responses by gangs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FB465135299497AB62A7FB87D9539B0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Establish relationships with community stakeholders to inform and engage them in quality-of-life activities that enhance intervention activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B29E5E42FCC42DEBF7D162CAF45EF73"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Serve as intervention representatives in communities by attending local meetings involving nonprofit organizations, schools, faith-based organizations, and other entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C0FA69DA3A2449491A0AF0876EB9B5D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Develop conflict resolution skills and techniques to address and resolve community concerns related to gang activity in order to improve the quality of life within neighborhoods.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H869E27886157468EAF45BA9AFB037C87"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Work with schools to respond to gang-related issues and crises both in and outside of school.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H180A3D768A8843209D92407A225C1DFF"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Provide support services for youth and families affected by gang violence and other victims of gang violence (including any individual who is physically, emotionally, financially, or otherwise harmed by criminal activity, and those affected by harm done to or by a family member), which may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2A8B37DA0D094288B297482188DFBD24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advocating for public sector and private sector assistance and services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B6FEC803C18496F82D701307B2E84C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grief counseling; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC8F1048443842FFB6AB24F929818C7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>referrals to treatment and rehabilitation for cognitive, mental, emotional, physical, or financial injury, loss, or suffering.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H971A647EDD7D4F29ADAC4CBD4F0A37DD"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Provide comprehensive mental health services to youth and families affected by gang violence or involvement, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6727D5409CC44B7FB76F8B49868E6316"><enum>(A)</enum><text>integrated services comprised of individual, family, and group therapy modalities, and psychological education provided through youth and parent training programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CB0D23011F940F18A70B9980D2091A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>gang-responsive services including skills training, assessing and servicing youth with developmental disabilities, behavioral modification, and services to address substance use and abuse, anger management, emotional regulation, traumatic stress, family violence, depression, suicide, anxiety, and educational problems.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5D2FBED33F249578EC0676EDF0F50B4"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Provide public and private sector career job training, development, and placement, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H2B1A98093111471B941E4F8C3BEA633D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>job-finding and job-maintaining skills, including skills related to resume writing, interviewing, workplace decorum, interpersonal communication, and problem-solving;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8A8EA672D3F452598DB7E7D239A0CC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information about legal rights in the workplace; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3FE0E5E675C4C56A919841B004D4B6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial literacy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED8F243A47144E7A96A64D60B89C0BC1"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Assist with substance use and abuse treatment, domestic violence victims, and voluntary tattoo removal of markings on the body related to gang involvement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2FF42F68D18F4FA2B5EABC147520BC0B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of victims assistance</header><text>An entity awarded a grant under this section that provides victim assistance under paragraph (13) of subsection (c) shall not discriminate in the provision of such assistance to an individual based on race, ethnicity, gender, sexual orientation, socioeconomic level, or past record.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDDE27DDDE7384CD38D4238877596BAB1"><enum>603.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H93ED0FFCD7EA49A0BCE6E2A27B2B50F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community</header><text>Notwithstanding the definition of <term>community based</term> in section 103, the term <term>community</term> means a unit of local government or an Indian Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H23475FA2449942729EDBF3882AAED5FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community-based gang intervention agency</header><text>The term <term>community-based gang intervention agency</term> means a community-based organization, association, or other entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC7A6883C18474A7B9BF60FD0188FB474"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promotes public safety, with the specific objective of reducing and stopping gang-related and gang-motivated violence and crime; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75407FF8E8E041508F5B6B97D78C4579"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a history of, or experience or specific training in, effectively working with gang-involved youth and their families.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23A7BC10D274424EA2E55DB81E349232"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community-based gang intervention model</header><text>The term <term>community-based gang intervention model</term> means a holistic and comprehensive approach to reducing gang violence that utilizes the two-prong approach of community-based intervention and an integrated approach of providing rehabilitative service delivery to gang-involved youth that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8441E851400D4CD7A0BD19A4F0C06A8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deploys specialists in community-based gang intervention who are trained to utilize the two-prong approach of community-based gang intervention and who intercede, interact, and participate with and in the community to quell rumors, prevent and mediate conflicts, and respond to crises related to gang activity and violence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF97B0500B4C24B52934984B6E2FCE853"><enum>(B)</enum><text>delivers rehabilitative services to gang-involved individuals and families; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE209BD1740D7403E842023E1EFB1ACEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>addresses the barriers that gang-involved youth and their families encounter and the societal factors that promote gang violence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81DEC20E3F554AC99A7E9AEAA17AAE74"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text>The term <term>evidence-based</term>, when used with respect to a practice relating to gang activity prevention and intervention (including community-based gang intervention), means a practice (including a service, program, or strategy) that has statistically significant outcomes that include a reduction in gang-related violence and an increased number of youth in job development, recreation, arts-based activities, or faith-based activities. Such outcomes may be determined by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB42964C534B94610BBCA4BB5C8FD58BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an experimental trial, in which participants are randomly assigned to participate in the practice that is the subject of the trial; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD857C4DAC10D47C0BBB3D832F7D7EC13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a quasi-experimental trial, in which the outcomes for participants are compared with outcomes for a control group that is made up of individuals who are similar to such participants.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H460CE15C87D24CBCB17C575C84DF2E5B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gang</header><text>The term <term>gang</term> means a group of individuals—</text> <subparagraph id="H0665C801D6C04794AEAB636E601D54F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>organized by geography, culture, or activity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA397E92C30404878B9528D5F42F7F9F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that have a group name, and may have other identifying characteristics of the group such as colors and nicknames; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF51FD57537D54E4EA2E7AB08525258CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who engage in the use of violence to defend the members or territory of the group.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF03994D504C248E3A1C1628BFFDA0C25"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Promising</header><text>The term <term>promising</term>, when used with respect to a practice relating to community-based gang intervention, means a practice that is not evidence-based, but—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0BFCB4D9BE79487080A948A3B7C37955"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that has outcomes from an evaluation that demonstrate that such practice reduces gang-related violence and crime; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H272B6C73A2EB4935A810586FE54658AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>about which a study is being conducted to determine if such practice is evidence-based.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H646FA3247B7743F49CD71C43C7630308"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Youth</header><text>The term <term>youth</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H66BC0C7E2EB14569BAF61DEC4450C313"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is 18 years of age or younger; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5408E86604734F96AA0B2FCDC208E448"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in any State in which the maximum age at which the juvenile justice system of such State has jurisdiction over individuals exceeds 18 years of age, an individual who is such maximum age or younger.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H531C18DEE50C4743BDB04AB514874765"><enum>II</enum><header>AMENDMENTS TO THE OFFICE OF JUVENILE JUSTICE AND DELINQUENCY PREVENTION</header>
 <section id="HA291635ECE2F4EE6A5748F3C8EDDFDE7"><enum>201.</enum><header>Definition of community-based gang intervention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103 of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5603">42 U.S.C. 5603</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF33279C24E0D43B1A49DE907342D9C32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>except when used in title VI,</quote> before <quote>the term</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DFF0E78870F41F79AFCBCD58C6C21AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (28), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H460DB840AD224892BBFBC041702D07FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (29), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H930201D19B234937947B1FA6EED0883B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H79D89A5817FC4BF29D87758AE42E86E1" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H20DBF09D5A8142349E650F645057A9B8"><enum>(30)</enum><text>except when used as part of the term <term>community-based gang intervention agency</term> or <term>community-based gang intervention model</term>, the term <term>community-based gang intervention</term> means a two-prong approach to reducing gang violence that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA5DC698AC6D4F558EFB476373377611"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides specialized, gang-specific mediation and mitigation to stop or prevent violence by, within, and between gangs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H839BD9F95B314C3E869E1532A99254C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides the redirection of individual gang members and their families through proactive efforts that increase peace and safety for gang members, their families, and their communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H81D9DB656C984755AA61B5DF17FC94BB"><enum>202.</enum><header>Community-based gang intervention representative to State advisory boards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 223(a)(3)(ii) of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5633">42 U.S.C. 5633(a)(3)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE946FE84F9E9468E834C36A536398775"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (III), by inserting <quote>, or community-based gang intervention</quote> after <quote>delinquency prevention or treatment</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEC47F93F9FC4C1B8E14FAA3C902929E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subclause (IV), by inserting <quote>community-based gang intervention,</quote> after <quote>prevention and treatment,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H372E438E1BAC4CD8A8CE521C4ABA673E"><enum>203.</enum><header>Grants for delinquency prevention programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 504 of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5783">42 U.S.C. 5783</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB900728EE55A486389368B838CF7BD95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDCDA08DD5954390912B5BF3EC3BC3F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (7) and (8) as paragraphs (8) and (9), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAD11814EBBF4EF3B4BED48BDC31C7E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H07650E3A89D345CA8CE2AC48D7602609" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H1CE954FF2DCA42D59846A316ADE7BEC6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>community-based gang intervention and gang prevention activities;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0560EA57E4A48DCAE654A894767BAEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2), by inserting <quote>and community-based gang intervention</quote> before <quote>activities;</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></title></legis-body> </bill> 

