<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0FEA6051F293454687049A4B136EE4B2" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 787 IH: Payer State Transparency Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 787</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150205">February 5, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000548">Mr. Garrett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To assess the State by State impact of Federal taxation and spending.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0F573B3F860A431EA2FB26C80F82D8C3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H96E2201F14FE41A4BF439FD7E0BA6038" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Payer State Transparency Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAA05BD45899645318989ABABAE023F5B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Calculation of Federal Tax Burdens and Outlays</header> <subsection id="H58257A048C3A43A99BEA9A8C6F88D904"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State by State Calculation of Federal tax burdens</header> <paragraph id="H18FFD239ED9B42B6AD6A129547842185"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Economic Analysis, shall calculate the Federal tax burden of each State for each calendar year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3189E5268363453D9504D6279B939509"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Calculation of Federal tax burden</header><text>For purposes of calculating the Federal tax burden of each State under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H633D1BF04AA0407784140A461C84AECB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>treat Federal taxes paid by an individual as a burden on the State in which such individual resides; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H95164AB862344455A10ADFC20C28FEC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>treat Federal taxes paid by a legal business entity as a burden on each State in which economic activity of such entity is performed in the same proportion that the economic activity of such entity in such State bears to the economic activity of such entity in all the States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFF422FFB0E424D438CA9E2B496C5B17B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State by State Calculation of Federal Outlays</header> <paragraph id="HA22608639FCA4ECAB75D1CA6E67BCAE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in coordination with the Council of Economic Advisers and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall calculate the total amount of Federal outlays received by each State in each fiscal year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC82093B526184430B9A923DD717A4D65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of Contract Awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of calculating the amount of Federal outlays received by a State under paragraph (1), a Federal contract award shall be treated as a Federal outlay received by each State in which performance under the award takes place in the same proportion that such performance in such State bears to such performance in all the States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H92BA199B371C437487703457E8A62306"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State Defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section the term <term>State</term> means each of the several States.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA346F526DB224681A663C53DF084C8B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Joint Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 180 days after the beginning of each calendar year, the Secretary of Commerce and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEE05369CF89342D68268389FD0E7149A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>jointly submit to Congress a report containing the results of the calculations described in section 2 with respect to such calendar year; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3AE4A32A59F43768F7D02DAC1D3E006"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish the report on a publicly accessible website of the Bureau of Economic Analysis.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

