<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H14216A181E6F4E65BB8F9BA18311581C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2769 IH: Risk-Based Capital Study Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2769</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150615">June 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000458">Mr. Fincher</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck of Washington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the National Credit Union Administration to conduct a study of the appropriate capital
			 requirements for credit unions, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD000856553A64A61A40C52D8CAD60CD5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5436E3D91AFD4238BD88719CDE7206E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Risk-Based Capital Study Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H80152AAEC00D4B4BB58242C72388B636"><enum>2.</enum><header>NCUA Study</header> <subsection id="HA21AD6CAF1EA4DFFA21DD1017733A7AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Credit Union Administration shall conduct a study of the appropriate capital requirements for Federal credit unions and State credit unions (as such terms are defined, respectively, under section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>) (hereinafter referred to as <quote>credit unions</quote>)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBF1FFE764D3B4F5FB5E0BAB2100DBF1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issues To be studied</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H6B88FD89444F47D3BF6753CD6530EBD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of whether or not the National Credit Union Administration has the clear legal authority to prescribe separate risk-based capital thresholds for both <quote>adequately capitalized</quote> and <quote>well capitalized</quote> credit unions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BD02BA1001848349F1FB7E7253898CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a discussion of the differences between credit unions and other types of depository institutions and reasons why they should have similar or different risk-weights for their capital requirements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H336A1CCA24074DC6A3B45E00E5953E14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a discussion of the rationale behind the risk-weights assigned in the proposed rule of the National Credit Union Administration titled <quote>Risk-Based Capital</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 4340; January 27, 2015); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEEB9E3252CC451B9467A8F002B38FEE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of the impact the proposed rule described in paragraph (3) would have on excess capital above the minimum level for a credit union to be <quote>well capitalized</quote> (a credit union’s <quote>capital cushion</quote>) including the impact it could have on credit union lending and credit union examinations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D6FABFEC92B4082BCA7C88005980100"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Voluntary participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any credit union may voluntarily provide information for the study required under subsection (a) upon the request of the National Credit Union Administration, but may not be required to provide such information.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3543E97FDE3B438381619B437A124CED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the National Credit Union Administration shall issue a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives containing—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1314553B8647457D844C3E478991883A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E5448FE04944ACE88E9390D5B9479D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any legislative recommendations of the National Credit Union Administration to improve the capital system for credit unions or establish a risk-based capital system for credit unions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5E1E9C76F44D484A9D981C67C3D0C4A7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Delay of rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the National Credit Union Administration may not issue or implement any final rule or regulation with respect to risk-based capital for credit unions, including the proposed rule described under section 2(b)(3), before the end of the 120-day period beginning on the date the National Credit Union Administration issues the report required under section 2(d).</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


