<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD17636B66D434E8389D55082E20D4497" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1438 IH: Oregon Coastal Lands Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1438</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require that certain Federal lands be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H14DE8158DCC943229F43CA6FAFD3314E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD6A7B89A03AA4F98889F830FDD3AB49D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oregon Coastal Lands Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H8DD64C54DCCE48C98665E47D06044165"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2804FAE61E634D9598B424C1528E322E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Confederated tribes</header><text>The term <term>Confederated Tribes</term> means the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7415B7A9C4F14A0E9F9D37854202ABEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oregon coastal land</header><text>The term <term>Oregon Coastal land</term> means the approximately 14,408 acres of land, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Oregon Coastal Land Conveyance</quote> and dated March 27, 2013.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H127D562F794F4FD2A889CD4D86FF75B3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="HC7B9355DCE2949C5B623F3AE991FE0F4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conveyance</header> <subsection id="HCC58600F1F2B4847B0861334A7BA7F65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, including rights-of-way, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Oregon Coastal land, including any improvements located on the land, appurtenances to the land, and minerals on or in the land, including oil and gas, shall be—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC3FD63EDFB74ECF807802DDF74ED850"><enum>(1)</enum><text>held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Confederated Tribes; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAE66FA3FE7649C2BCCA0639EF7DA0D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>part of the reservation of the Confederated Tribes.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2AC2C10EBD17450AA431772ABFFA4CFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall complete a survey of the boundary lines to establish the boundaries of the land taken into trust under subsection (a).</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HAECF69604C984E2B9870F07A6240F3A8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Map and legal description</header> <subsection id="H14DF7973C46745179AF81AD0C451EDC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and legal description of the Oregon Coastal land with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3188A39F6F2D42F6A5D9EAA2A2E1FC41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE09C7A1E9CE54093B08E4BDBC7A28CA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF071377229D24D1D9AAC2BD94D9649DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text>The map and legal description filed under subsection (a) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical or typographical errors in the map or legal description.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H3012852738EF4F218259845DC5BC7C0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description filed under subsection (a) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Secretary.</text> </subsection></section> 
<section id="HA703AC89A2BD4002AE89F333B42B0ADD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administration</header> 
<subsection id="HC8B44958292249DFACE6DC1008339E8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Unless expressly provided in this Act, nothing in this Act affects any right or claim of the Confederated Tribes existing on the date of enactment of this Act to any land or interest in land.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HFE53D26994E543E995B445BCB3F96D70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header> <paragraph id="H700D2C51B1334252B17D604AECC9187F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exports of unprocessed logs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal law (including regulations) relating to the export of unprocessed logs harvested from Federal land shall apply to any unprocessed logs that are harvested from the Oregon Coastal land taken into trust under section 3.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77427A179AFA449AB57A9951BF0572EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-permissible use of land</header><text>Any real property taken into trust under section 3 shall not be eligible, or used, for any gaming activity carried out under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/497">Public Law 100–497</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H416FF9E46B10428EA8B101251BB2C0C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Laws applicable to commercial forestry activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any commercial forestry activity that is carried out on the Oregon Coastal land taken into trust under section 3 shall be managed in accordance with all applicable Federal laws.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7AC062A636EE44678343F3FFAA4AC383"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Confederated Tribes shall consult with the Secretary and other parties as necessary to develop agreements to provide for access to the Oregon Coastal land taken into trust under section 3 that provide for—</text> <paragraph id="H7C086DC1F4244F7C89276F8CEFFB77F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honoring existing reciprocal right-of-way agreements;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5525EB8305BF435B95A71A198D4668F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>administrative access by the Bureau of Land Management; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H612EEF6D14B74BC4B13EBBC0F4566FF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">management of the Oregon Coastal lands that are acquired or developed under the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460l-4">16 U.S.C. 460l–4 et seq.</external-xref>), consistent with section 8(f)(3) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/162/460l-8">162 U.S.C. 460l–8(f)(3)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBC4B9E1C6CBD4A538BE2F6E112F4541D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Land use planning requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), once the Oregon Coastal land is taken into trust under section 3, the land shall not be subject to the land use planning requirements of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Act of August 28, 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1181a">43 U.S.C. 1181a et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HFC2B64982BDA481D98C9B05F5AB5666C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Land reclassification</header> <subsection id="HD86745C47AAF463EA529055541B6E07A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of Oregon and California railroad grant land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary shall identify any Oregon and California Railroad grant land that is held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Confederated Tribes under section 3.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE549AD2929744C4D93E947AF4A4D078E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of public domain land</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall identify public domain land in the State of Oregon that—</text> <paragraph id="H8F114DEA87A741BB94EB5569ADF2E442"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is approximately equal in acreage and condition as the Oregon and California Railroad grant land identified under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F6FA83CFB72404397071887481C7BC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located in the vicinity of the Oregon and California Railroad grant land.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H213C6BA547054C8C9855A55B452C21D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maps</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress and publish in the Federal Register one or more maps depicting the land identified in subsections (a) and (b).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H624E429AE8DB4AB9B9E1B1427DFDF6B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reclassification</header> 
<paragraph id="HB7BF8A2E084D41CC8D8ED3A353FAC7AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After providing an opportunity for public comment, the Secretary shall reclassify the land identified in subsection (b) as Oregon and California Railroad grant land.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H676E341C86C0416D89AF38BFD08C4567"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The Act of August 28, 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1181a">43 U.S.C. 1181a et seq.</external-xref>), shall apply to land reclassified as Oregon and California Railroad grant land under paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


