<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3335174E52034BF48361095576BAF686" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4295 IH: To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to increase the rest periods of flight attendants to the same rest periods of pilots.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4295</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to increase the rest periods of
			 flight attendants to the same rest periods of pilots.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3C454537821A48F9888DCBAF60DFC8F3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2F53259CED4842A8A41837821A9C2EC9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Rest periods for flight attendants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall increase the rest periods described in section 121.467(b) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to ensure that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H584EECE511B34741A4C07ECB31B9C024"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a flight attendant scheduled to a duty period of 14 hours or less as provided under paragraph (b)(1) of such section must be given a scheduled rest period of at least 10 consecutive hours; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C3E5D1CE45E496193C98C52B4087D64"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the scheduled duty period may be reduced to a period of not less than 9 consecutive hours, if the flight attendant is provided a subsequent rest period of at least 11 consecutive hours and the subsequent rest period is scheduled to begin not later than 24 hours after the beginning of the reduced rest period and must occur between the completion of the scheduled duty period and the commencement of the subsequent duty period.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


