<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDDD218353099489E89996EB4EE809BD3" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 977 IH: MEND Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 977</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150213">February 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001179">Mr. Schock</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To enable hospital-based nursing programs that are affiliated with a hospital to maintain payments
			 under the Medicare program to hospitals for the costs of such programs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H75D9F623CBC34C3AB0BD72ECF58AEFCF" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE60CE3A008DD4EDAB6B32E6D35251FDD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making the Education of Nurses Dependable for Schools Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>MEND Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF750BDF0CC9F4C56AF1BFC64ED216457"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enabling hospital-based nursing programs that are affiliated with a hospital to maintain Medicare payments for the costs of such programs</header> <subsection id="H30598BE3DE5A427F8CAFE565462F1378"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clarifying the methodology for payment under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act to providers for the costs of nursing and allied health education activities for cost reporting periods beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall apply section 413.85 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations—</text>
 <paragraph id="H29E0DC36BC5E4277BFBF4496CF2D5347"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by treating a provider as meeting all of the requirements described in paragraph (f)(1) of such section if the provider or a wholly owned subsidiary educational institution of such provider singly or collectively meets all of such requirements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC6DB163DA7240F5B1FC70503CF9FDD6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a provider that would meet the requirements of paragraph (g)(3) of such section, with respect to a nursing or allied health education program, except that the transfer described in such paragraph of such a program to a wholly owned subsidiary educational institution in order to meet accreditation standards occurred after October 1, 2003, by treating such provider as meeting the requirements of such paragraph (and eligible for payments under such paragraph) with respect to such program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H526F504BC6C04D768BB786FEE5808D5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of a provider or wholly owned subsidiary educational institution of such provider that has been in continuous operation since October 1, 2003, by treating such provider, beginning as of such date with respect to such program, as described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3BCB6984F634BBC8222A5DDB7ED0CE4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by defining the term <term>wholly owned subsidiary educational institution</term>, as referenced in such section, as such term is defined under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA16F370E6A6B493A9A769E9F192B47C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD49F265CA71243D0A81D3EE1D537BCD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>provider</term> has the meaning given such term in section 400.202 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2408FFF711F84CE4B5DBF3820760940B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wholly owned subsidiary educational institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>wholly owned subsidiary educational institution</term> means, with respect to a provider, an educational institution that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H05DADC03C0EF4D4CB8529C8EABA8FF49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is organized as a legal entity distinct from the provider;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA604ABDB60E545F5B7006F717C858329"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the provider as its sole owner or sole member; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEB460E2E4F14788904D31DC0E1563AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is organized in the same State in which the provider is organized or registered to do business.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

