<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6B51ABC12C9347C08C7DFACE5C732D94" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1615 RH: DHS FOIA Efficiency Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 106</calendar>
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1615</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 114–148]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150325">March 25, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000819">Mr. Walker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20150611">June 11, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="M001150">Mrs. Miller of Michigan</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20150611">June 11, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 25, 2015</action-instruction>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Chief FOIA Officer of the Department of Homeland Security to make certain improvements in the implementation of section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Freedom of Information Act), and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HHM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HDFD1E021CBAA40E9BCA49DC4C875D941">
<section id="H3B64A402673E41C8965094B6B970088F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS FOIA Efficiency Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB6794CA279794418A5A065F373B1F066"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security Freedom of Information Act implementation</header> <subsection id="H0DD17AF2E456401E85374A7FD12BCE78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deadline for updating regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief FOIA Officer of the Department of Homeland Security, as appointed pursuant to section 552(j) of title 5, United States Code, shall finalize and issue an updated regulation implementing section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Freedom of Information Act), which shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="H3525B1CC2D6A4CF2A296659D1902F095"><enum>(1)</enum><text>public guidance on procedures to be followed when making requests under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6C60A7522384B6683B5B079711AC0AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>updated guidance to the components of the Department responsible for processing such requests, which may include information on how to adopt automated processing of requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), or (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H866D297BB1154553A6DE98E66BC3314C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detailed information on fees and costs associated with such requests; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC69F1ACEA6EB456C9697DE715440CFBC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>detailed information on the appeals process for such requests.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5F7291C60DF14D85A89BA420F0239B7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of costs</header>
<paragraph id="H871A61ABFA4C46B79282AE525BDEFC81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief FOIA Officer, in coordination with the Chief Financial Officer of the Department and the heads of each of the relevant components of the Department, shall identify the total annual cost to the Department of implementing section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEB19724DCC24AD6A6DF47081FB4051F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Chief FOIA Officer shall develop guidance on reporting standards related to the direct and indirect costs to the Department associated with the processing of requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD746B6A4E56B4620BFE8764230A4186B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost savings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief FOIA Officer, in collaboration with the heads of each of the relevant components of the Department, shall—</text> <paragraph id="HABF8050C99674298A6D7214436AEA388"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify unnecessary and duplicative actions taken by the Department in the course of processing requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code, by not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFADD832D578943E5B9DD8D19E5E11D02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>eliminate unnecessary and duplicative actions taken by the Department in the course of processing requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code, by not later than 12 months after the identification of such action under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H31F28B86FC4B4ECABB9CCC24489F189C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>FOIA tracking systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief FOIA Officer shall develop a plan to automate the processing of requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code to the Department. Such plan shall take into account the specific needs of each of the components of the Department responsible for processing such requests and address required and recommended technology capabilities and elements. Such plan shall include an assessment of the costs and benefits associated with establishing and using electronic processing systems to process requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF0A87D11F33E492989BCC38C55805A39"><enum>(e)</enum><header>FOIA backlog</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief Privacy Officer of the Department, in consultation with the Chief FOIA Officer, shall update and issue guidance to the heads of each of the relevant components of the Department regarding the goal of reducing the backlog in processing requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code, by 50 percent between fiscal year 2015 and fiscal year 2018.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H21F227306CEE4DF2BE3BA01A6AA6BE28"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H2B965FC634754AFDACE20BC9EB755433"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Semiannual privacy report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief FOIA Officer shall include in each semiannual privacy report submitted under section 1062(f) of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ee-1">42 U.S.C. 2000ee–1(f)</external-xref>) each of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H929B2C37604648C6A5084A784B3F602A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The total costs to the Department of meeting the requirements of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, for the period covered by the report.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85DC42EA76C34458B0A98F37D971B1AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of progress made toward meeting the backlog goals pursuant to subsection (e) during the period covered by the report and the periods covered by the two preceding reports.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2383FE755D054EFE9ECABACB276D99E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of whether the Department has adequate staffing and other resources to address the backlog goals pursuant to subsection (e) for processing requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB29AD48AE1AE45CABF9F9B0925917A44"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of the progress made towards automating the processing of requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code, during the period covered by the report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H35D983E8E345401BB06E85EDFF1AFA39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2016 requirements</header><text>The Chief FOIA Officer shall include in the second semiannual privacy report for fiscal year 2016 each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H72350DC535A34DCC984A506375DC4AA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of any cost savings identified under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5C378971242A450AB43FA79525F3CACE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The plan developed under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCBF4E619B48F45EDAEDDC910D9F4C143"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Duplicative action defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>duplicative actions</quote> means actions carried out by two or more components or programs that are engaged in the same activities or provide the same services related to the processing of FOIA requests to the same beneficiaries.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H8B32732103914A5EA8DF7346FDEFAFFB" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Progress on automation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon completion of the plan to automate the processing of requests made under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code, the Chief FOIA Officer shall provide the plan to the heads of the components of the Department and seek written feedback from each head of a component agency regarding the extent to which that component will adopt the plan, the associated costs, and the projected timelines.</text></section> </legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20150611">June 11, 2015</action-date> <action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

