<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H5C1A8B06461542F1B67F03F300BDE87E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2200 RH: CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 120</calendar>
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2200</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 114–164]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150501">May 1, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20150617">June 17, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20150617">June 17, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 1, 2015</action-instruction>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing functions of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security and to require dissemination of information analyzed by the Department to entities with responsibilities relating to homeland security, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HHM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HF1453E758E0241988FC54D57781F31C4">
<section id="HAFC7C7D6794546558991EAD6708498E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC1735F5874AC4EF5BDD18FB1FE0B001B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing</header> <subsection id="H4B7B7A90E4D14C62BC3C45724A7E6F7B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33D5EF9ADF0F4DAA87758845092FEB6D" style="OLC">
<section id="HF3DECAC1BB934CBE92E586B88180AF57"><enum>210G.</enum><header>Chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing</header>
<subsection id="H5BE6A37C00134A919874B9377FCFA78D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security shall—</text> <paragraph id="H69699D7B48CD41E6ADD81D1A0574B197"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support homeland security-focused intelligence analysis of terrorist actors, their claims, and their plans to conduct attacks involving chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials against the Nation;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0455C6978BA4458BB9FF64F223F162C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support homeland security-focused intelligence analysis of global infectious disease, public health, food, agricultural, and veterinary issues;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44F0CEEDB9884A9CB45200EFA5A59E7A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support homeland security-focused risk analysis and risk assessments of the homeland security hazards described in paragraphs (1) and (2), including the transportation of chemical, biological, nuclear, and radiological materials, by providing relevant quantitative and nonquantitative threat information;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1CB22B56C9E6441C9E8F3EB08426061B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>leverage existing and emerging homeland security intelligence capabilities and structures to enhance prevention, protection, response, and recovery efforts with respect to a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear attack;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8D88CDED1174E40912474FD395249F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>share information and provide tailored analytical support on these threats to State, local, and tribal authorities as well as other national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders and other Federal agencies, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H12C98F9A10834389837737DA816FBA99"><enum>(6)</enum><text>perform other responsibilities, as assigned by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE90A131B9FAE4D188BCD338ED2D1234C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Where appropriate, the Office of Intelligence and Analysis shall coordinate with other relevant Department components, including the National Biosurveillance Integration Center, others in the Intelligence Community, including the National Counter Proliferation Center, and other Federal, State, local, and tribal authorities, including officials from high-threat areas, State and major urban area fusion centers, and local public health departments, as appropriate, and enable such entities to provide recommendations on optimal information sharing mechanisms, including expeditious sharing of classified information, and on how they can provide information to the Department.</text></subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC432865D26694B7B8230162B7A36C8C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H288D85A67C9E4AE0970E48E93F0F02CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and any committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate having legislative jurisdiction under the rules of the House of Representatives or Senate, respectively, over the matter concerned.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC45EEAE9F38847F7B9A641FC1F5D5D52"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Intelligence Community</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/401a">50 U.S.C. 401a(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32203838F8BD41BC8B67064A97CC3BB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders</term> means officials from the Federal, State, local, and tribal authorities and individuals from the private sector who are involved in efforts to prevent, protect against, respond to, and recover from a biological attack or other phenomena that may have serious health consequences for the United States, including infectious disease outbreaks.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H328F0FAAE657403E93C56050E17E0888"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to such subtitle the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CD58810253B4AFE8A92545DEE1324C2" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 210G. Chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H539F86B981BD4630A71DB7518208623E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H1A283DFDC759461396F92C9747DB71B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall report to the appropriate congressional committees on—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF843F9F4B94B418A962907CCDA75FC47"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the intelligence and information sharing activities under subsection (a) and of all relevant entities within the Department of Homeland Security to counter the threat from attacks using chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF01155F380641839374C7B5B63FD0B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department’s activities in accordance with relevant intelligence strategies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H025AE19680A34E128BEC4EC08E694B82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment of implementation</header><text>The report shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HF41AD84EE0E84CA48FC7403F4CCB9058"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of methods established to assess progress of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis in implementing the amendment made by subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B6752E190B24644A40218EC642FA9E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such assessment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77D2FF48C3884EB886CBBA7DB7F63953"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This subsection shall have no force or effect after the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FCF77DEF656450DBDB7C2F69F3BCF7E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Dissemination of information analyzed by the Department to State, local, tribal, and private entities with responsibilities relating to homeland security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201(d)(8) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121(d)(8)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and to agencies of State</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>to State, local, tribal, and private entities with such responsibilities, and, as appropriate, to the public, in order to assist in preventing, deterring, or responding to acts of terrorism against the United States.</quote>.</text></section> </legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20150617">June 17, 2015</action-date> <action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

