<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7D41B1EDA3354ACEB8552E883F75D5A5" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3711 IH: Chicano Park Preservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3711</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of Chicano Park,
			 located
			 in San Diego, California, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H910F39805CB24EAFA8C9ADB80597A639" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0AB3408CCBDE480F9DD4D287833CA708" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chicano Park Preservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF784CE490688423691C0CEB6C258CE0B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special resource study</header> <subsection id="H9803F6E1C4214630A92787C060618755"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall conduct a special resource study of Chicano Park and its murals located in San Diego, California.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDBCD74054A82417FABD0884D64349ADA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H29C3B595734B4D69AB3BEB065BDEB5A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the national significance of the site;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H827D7538B13F400091C13022B02CF6A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the site as a National Historic Landmark or Affiliated Area of the National Park System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC8C122A01464C5288750CD0E00E8B4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider other alternatives for preservation, protection, and interpretation of Chicano Park and its murals by Federal, State, or local governmental entities, or private and nonprofit organizations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C9C3BDBBCCB4CA79D5A9C8BA2CCA7CA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with interested Federal, State, or local governmental entities, private and nonprofit organizations or any other interested individuals; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83C6EE0F3AC44B339827C15B867FFEF2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify cost estimates for any development, interpretation, operation, and maintenance associated with the alternatives.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23B24F1D454F439BBC3D2CD19EE5885C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEE3BAF5E8E41441B86DAC5CF96D9E035"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be conducted in accordance with section 100507 of title 54, United States Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECA73BAD9BCC450BBE9C73636CCB9407"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not withstanding section 2(c)(1), not consider any options that involve Federal acquisition of lands, interests in lands, or any other property related to the Chicano Park and its murals.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE71B4C918CA4519A99BA13F52105194"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date on which funds are first made available for the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report containing the results of the study and any conclusions and recommendations of the Secretary.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


