<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0693C5483EF4F6CBCC94BA1A9AA77F5" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1041 IH: Jamiel Shaw, II Memorial Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1041</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150224">February 24, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To make payments by the Department of Homeland Security to a State contingent on a State providing the Federal Bureau of Investigation with certain statistics, to require Federal agencies, departments, and courts to provide such statistics to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and to require the Federal Bureau of Investigation to publish such statistics.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0D4A13D6907A4F608D06DF7D89FB6032" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9848F3160A474634AA1AD20AA53215FE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jamiel Shaw, II Memorial Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3B7B9189F4D445A8ABCD97BFC36C0DD4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Payments by the Department of Homeland Security contingent on State immigration reporting</header> <subsection id="HD3CD9C8E25D94264BF819EA7F18344E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or any political subdivision thereof may not receive funds under any program or activity administered by the Department of Homeland Security unless the State—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFCBA5CE008F140308A2378055289FD7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for each person who is arrested, charged with a crime, convicted of a crime, or incarcerated after being convicted of a crime by the State or any political subdivision thereof, compiles statistics on such person, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D31D5AA013B4E8BB3E5BF4E89B17D1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the immigration status of such person;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE842A31FE0047C8AB86159B508F4253"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the country of origin of such person; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8F6194577D74B40ADBB84887B171114"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the crime associated with such arrest, charge, conviction, or incarceration after conviction;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AC8DCBF5F254CE79E2943752814C423"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reports such statistics monthly to the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1400E75EE8B0494B97A7B49624BCA08D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>monthly certifies compliance with paragraphs (1) and (2) to the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD0BD52C95B844ECBE710C88BE8ADDF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect with respect to funds made available under a program or activity administered by the Department of Homeland Security for fiscal years beginning on or after October 1, 2015.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1D6032D57E9D44EA82C27D2A754F1BE6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal immigration reporting requirement</header> <subsection id="H36849B6FB4A84E3F862CB84C5F7C6E0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal agency and department shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2902366AEC7E45CB84BBFE2902C1EF90"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any person such agency or department arrests, charges with a crime, prosecutes to conviction of a crime, or incarcerates after conviction of a crime, compile statistics on such person, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HD167C83D15BC4F9492809E31C0CE947D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the immigration status of such person;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3445EC3DCA604377A3CB58AC7D2D2441"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the country of origin of such person; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E66A39A21D34F82969753F0F442DDBF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the crime associated with such arrest, charge, conviction, or incarceration after conviction; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BA40F2E94C24BDBAC030AAC0E06D996"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report such statistics monthly to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H25773B2A658E4A41946083C051B1B979"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect with respect to any person arrested, charged with a crime, prosecuted to conviction of a crime, or incarcerated after conviction of a crime by a Federal agency or department on or after October 1, 2015.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5B7B971ECE8547A3BC8C6768895AE1C6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statistics to be published</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Bureau of Investigation shall annually publish all statistics reported under this Act as a separate data collection of the Uniform Crime Reports issued by such Bureau.</text></section> <section id="H1F7A3A02EB334149A0905E5EAD85812C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>crime</term> means an offense listed in Table 4 of the Uniform Crime Report of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, issued pursuant to section 534(a) of title 28, United States Code.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

