<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8867784075AF430A91A93A33884B2531" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1915 IH: David’s Sling Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1915</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150421">April 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Defense to carry out activities relating to the research,
			 development, test, and evaluation and procurement of the David’s Sling
			 weapons program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA186111973BE410BA852CFF063A3A544" style="OLC">
 <section id="H55484CC195104766A3C59CFE1A5B600B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>David’s Sling Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H728075B5A50146B48838A1C176F242AC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H07B67D44C5D94E359859DBC60D469124"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Israel is threatened by missiles and rockets from adversaries in the region.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H954BC9BB911745F1B12A9F990C812D4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Over the past several years, with the assistance of the governments of the Islamic Republic of Iran and Syria, Hezbollah and Hamas have increased their stockpile of rockets and missiles, which are ready to be fired at Israel. The Lebanon conflict in 2006 proved that Large Caliber Artillery Rockets (LCARs) and Short Range Ballistic Missiles (SRBMs) have become an immediate mortal threat to the Israeli civilian population and are in the possession of Hezbollah and Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF466380D45546628B91DF803D52B3F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2014, Hezbollah took possession of advanced guided-missile systems from Syria, representing a major upgrade from the tens of thousands unguided rockets in Hezbollah’s possession.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBAF01500AEB4BC0B458FE38EA2E441F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hamas militants recently acquired long-range M–302 rockets and fired them deeper into Israel than they ever had before.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4B456DB24A24BF08622AA0C72508CB9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2008, the United States and Israel signed a project agreement to co-develop the David’s Sling system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4602A86E73941648C0F8BA1C8844F65"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The David’s Sling system will provide Israel an effective and affordable defense against the threat of LCAR, Tactical Ballistic Missiles (TBM) and against the emerging Cruise Missile and similar representative threats, currently proliferating in the region.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33D20BCB3DC54A3B84F0E3256BDEDE82"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Israeli Ballistic Missile Defense (BMD) multi-tier architecture is comprised of the Upper Tier (Arrow Weapon System with Arrow 2 and Arrow 3 interceptors) and Lower Tier (David's Sling and Iron Dome systems). Arrow 2 and Iron Dome are operational, while David's Sling is expected to reach its initial operational capability shortly, followed by Arrow 3 in near future.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3622576CF87F497BA534892C513AB058"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each system is designed to optimally encounter its own range of threats, with a limited planned overlap between them. David's Sling is designed to provide a regionally versatile defense in a range between Iron Dome and Arrow 2 systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C07EAA6714E4DB9BCB7A5C59B81A3A0"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The missile and rocket threat to Israel is immediate. Rapid development and deployment of the David's Sling system is crucial to provide an enhanced defense to the State of Israel and its people.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF722A4A768A542F5AE1CCCD9EB6B978D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The fiscal year 2016 requirement for maintaining the cost and schedule for the Arrow II, Arrow III, David’s Sling, and Iron Dome programs is $475,200,000 to support research, testing, development, and procurement of these systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAB09E071E3746198A6326B254B52CB4"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the $475,200,000, $136,900,000 is required in fiscal year 2016 for completion of research and development and $150,000,000 is required for the procurement of David’s Sling system components.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E52EEFBC0B349DBBD815758915DFF71"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The United States-Israel Enhanced Security Cooperation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/150">Public Law 112–150</external-xref>) reaffirmed the commitment of the United States to the security of Israel as a Jewish State and to assist in the defense of Israel and to protect United States interests.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD06D66E2D5E4808927AA567AFC16D6B"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United States-Israel Strategic Partnership Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/296">Public Law 113–296</external-xref>) designated Israel as a Major Strategic Partner of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H68BB4EE37AEE48C9865EAEAAE92CA33F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Development and production of David’s Sling weapons program</header>
 <subsection id="H287AF457BA364DA9BEE33EF7FF04B32C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may carry out activities relating to the research, development, test, and evaluation and procurement of the David’s Sling weapons program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H286F60AA928F47599E80ABF19FFB0CFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Defense for fiscal year 2016, to carry out this section there is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2016—</text>
 <paragraph id="H23AA2491796B4C678189D6B5F993C742"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for procurement, Defense-wide, $150,000,000; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E688A92F2F84CB4A9786F08B2FD5B32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for research, development, test, and evaluation, Defense-wide, $136,900,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6740B7B2D27246709A5DF9D1C2C5D20C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress on coproduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the Sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H02AE8A0A15FA46A9AFD37C4108118848"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States and the Government of Israel should enter into a production agreement that specifies the terms of coproduction, program schedule, and an itemization of costs with respect to the David’s Sling weapons program production activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70B080FEBBCD460E84192C12DCFDC276"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such production agreement should strive for coproduction of the David’s Sling components to the most optimal level and schedule; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32A2340FD61448E9BDCC6C2433242D91"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaching such a bilateral production agreement, to include funds disbursement policy, should be a priority, as has been done in other missile defense programs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


