<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB484CB41A4EA4E0682B0A358F94CA6DF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 567 IH: Revolving Door Pension Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 567</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide that a former Member of Congress receiving compensation as a highly-paid lobbyist shall
			 be ineligible to receive certain Federal retirement benefits, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA58CCD03CE0C4E1095B2D7248F92BAE0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H76B303B891104DA6870EF54C94C0DAEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Revolving Door Pension Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H86E40C155A6A415EB00EF496935F0410"><enum>2.</enum><header>Forfeiture of benefits for any former Member of Congress who becomes a highly-paid lobbyist</header> <subsection id="H97A5B11625FF4FED93EA75F100C46C95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a former Member of Congress may not be paid any covered benefit if such former Member is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2F07C55109064B579F9C8585FE27CCD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a registered lobbyist; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF987EE0FF846FB8B2CA9EA6FE23691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>receives in any year annual compensation equal to or greater than $1,000,000 as a direct result of lobbying activities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC991A073A9CD4CD987CEB8FC9DCA5B50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Former Member of Congress</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>former Member of Congress</quote> means any Member of Congress who becomes a former Member of Congress after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C4A77A28670465FAE0EB100594BBF65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>covered benefits</quote>, as used with respect to a former Member of Congress, means any payment or other benefit which is payable, by virtue of service performed by such former Member, under any of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HAE6385A240BD4870AC5C0C7EC05C642C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Civil Service Retirement System, including the Thrift Savings Plan.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BF6E45342C3422ABEC549DE22FC230A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Employees Retirement System, including the Thrift Savings Plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9EA6DE85CCBE4F84BE3240D6BBA4773B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, including enhanced dental benefits and enhanced vision benefits under chapters 89A and 89B, respectively, of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02670CB2A40D4FF4ADF0154E5B55C531"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be considered to prevent the payment of—</text> <paragraph id="H6DB87AB09AA9427A8D99405423806571"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any lump-sum credit, as defined by section 8331(8) or 8401(19) of title 5, United States Code, to which a former Member of Congress subject to subsection (a) is entitled;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA688AFD3A96A4B5ABE40B3BDDB8BB355"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any contributions in the account of a former Member of Congress subject to subsection (a) in the Thrift Savings Fund which, as of the date on which subsection (a) applies to a former Member, is nonforfeitable; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72D5039651DA44719C31330E6271A53C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any annuity payments with respect to an annuity of a former Member of Congress subject to subsection (a) to a former spouse or survivor who is entitled to such payments.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H007813DFAFDF460380BE93282101ED72"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any forfeiture of an annuity under subsection (a) shall be effective on January 1 of the year immediately following any year, beginning in 2016, in which the former Member of Congress receives annual compensation equal to or greater than $1,000,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFCAEE4589D5F480E80693D6F1146523F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any regulations necessary to carry out this section may be prescribed by—</text> <paragraph id="H5C57EA696B4C433B89EA430366EA4E5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in paragraph (2), the Director of the Office of Personnel Management; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9CF10ABFBC94ED39EB7099BD720F8CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent that this Act relates to the Thrift Savings Plan, by the Executive Director (as defined by section 8401(13) of title 5, United States Code).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H355C4509B6D04890AA779E0C3221E2CA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H90BD0B4FFFE44EAAB64762ADE6CAD564"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <quote>agency</quote>, <quote>client</quote>, <quote>covered executive branch official</quote>, <quote>covered legislative branch official</quote>, <quote>lobbyist</quote>, <quote>lobbying activities</quote>, and <quote>lobbying contact</quote>, have the meaning given such terms in section 3 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E9DBD23972045A28DAB6501177F512D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>Member of Congress</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2106 of title 5, United States Code; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3110A98B18DA466596CFCE19F9B0465D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>registered lobbyist</quote> means a lobbyist registered or required to register, or on whose behalf a registration is filed or required to be filed, under section 4 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


