<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD5C4A62AC65D4B14A3BA7FAAE07D639A" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3405 IH: To prohibit the Department of Health and Human Services from obligating or expending any funds for grants for developing or evaluating a video game to train parents in food parenting practices, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3405</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit the Department of Health and Human Services from obligating or expending any funds for grants for developing or evaluating a video game to train parents in food parenting practices, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCF6BFE6F50EB4946B2148EEB3006593F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H581D7EF5DAE546E79ED49A8A69A1A0B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibiting grant funds for <quote>Kiddio: Food Fight—Training Vegetable Parenting Practices</quote></header> 
<subsection id="HBF2EDDC8DCDF4EE4B76C964DA3D9A527"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Department of Health and Human Services may not obligate or expend any funds for—</text> <paragraph id="H0561C5BD653D4215AB717F532E52AD3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grant project # 4R44HD075521–02 of the National Institutes of Health (<quote>Kiddio: Food Fight—Training Vegetable Parenting Practices</quote>; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECBFBAC9655045E09F82F9BE232FD601"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for developing or evaluating a video game to train parents in food parenting practices.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE11CF252852D456E95969407C0FD02A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unobligated balances</header><text>Of the amounts made available for any grant, contract, or cooperative agreement of the Department of Health and Human Services described in paragraph (1), the unobligated balances of such amounts are hereby rescinded.</text></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

