<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H462DB2FAEDF84B91922E25DC901E3E83" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2469 IH: Columbia River Basin Restoration Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2469</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish within the Environmental Protection Agency a Columbia River Basin Restoration Program.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HBA97D6F38890491589FD3523034409C3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD9E3E4F35C114EE8B3634F91BE3D41D1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Columbia River Basin Restoration Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB5C313979A9B475388DCC8204FB7F698"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H38E52B8142EA41789222398D875385A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Columbia River is the largest river in the Pacific Northwest by volume;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H563578ECFA2B4110A7A3D3851F6F748B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the river is 1,243 miles long, with a drainage basin that includes 259,000 square miles, extending to 7 States and British Columbia, Canada, and including all or part of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H09130234E7134D04BBCF56BB9808EB2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>multiple national parks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D12BEE0439B47A3A91FBDCBB29D1D4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>components of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6BF1C6BCD52541BEAA8486FD9FE69B04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>national monuments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H458CBEF421144D8EBCF835EABF317711"><enum>(D)</enum><text>national scenic areas;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E4D3D9849374394854D219965E1FF5C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>national recreation areas;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H590A97AC583642E2A052816969C04591"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other areas managed for conservation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6C92329FA0C4709B9ACD435774463A1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>multiple tribal reservations and over 45,000,000 acres of tribally comanaged land;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB20FB6DD78814A8796D09DD50D6C0431"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Columbia River Basin and associated tributaries (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Basin</quote>) provide significant ecological and economic benefits to the Pacific Northwest and the entire United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H929A25411B394E5891C9838DBD618717"><enum>(4)</enum><text>traditionally, the Basin includes more than 6,000,000 acres of irrigated agricultural land and produces more hydroelectric power than any other North American river;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89652303C5E14B6DAF7A259277B52ECA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>significant commerce takes place on the federally authorized Columbia Snake River System navigation channel, which is 465 miles in length, from the mouth of the Columbia River to Lewiston, Idaho;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A1FA5AD5A634E39AF06618DB486857F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Basin—</text> <subparagraph id="H0ECC7A3730114AA89ECAA63DE515C726"><enum>(A)</enum><text>historically constituted the largest salmon-producing river system in the world, with annual returns peaking at as many as 16,000,000 fish; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE603714132EC45A9B92D73BDA02F7951"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <clause id="H9665DFB0687C446AA8216D8BABC98578"><enum>(i)</enum><text>supports economically important commercial and recreational fisheries;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA04C48C39AC34A4EA3F8733A31BD02A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supports treaty tribal fisheries;</text></clause> <clause id="H50587E8EBF4C4440B50BF348D881A916"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is home to numerous species of salmonids, including steelhead, bull trout, and Kootenai white sturgeon, that are listed as threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA55494C7BF4D40FFBF7902FCBBC889D7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is a cultural and historical resource and provides sports and recreation opportunities for millions annually;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEC69565AFA04A74AE183C90DA128BD2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>toxics are present throughout the Columbia River Basin that are harmful to humans, fish, and wildlife;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B556A515BE140FA8B9EF8061DEE7EB2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>studies have shown that Columbia River fish contain a wide array of contaminants;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64227A7DB0CB46D9A6770CBD9B8B6AD3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a fish consumption survey in the Columbia River Basin showed that tribal members were eating 6 to 11 times more fish than the estimated national average;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FDA1972825B42AAB2158078930BB070"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in 2013, the States of Oregon and Washington issued a fish advisories warning against consumption of resident fish between Bonneville Dam to McNary Dam because of toxic contamination;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1ACB9D993EE44D1AA3973DB86E0CD21B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in 1995, the lower river and estuary was designated an <quote>estuary of national significance</quote> in accordance with section 320 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1330">33 U.S.C. 1330</external-xref>), because of degradation and contamination in the lower river, lack of structure to coordinate programs and policies, significance of the lower river to survival of species throughout the basin, and the importance of the lower river to the economic viability of the region; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03E1EEAE77A64184AFBDC2D53E8FE9E8"><enum>(12)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6942EFB6006E45CBA1926D3B11D1C3B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in 2006, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency named the Columbia River Basin 1 of the 10 large aquatic ecosystems in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD31B68D67D084509A3A1BDC6F3C88E52" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Columbia River Basin is the only large aquatic ecosystem in the United States that does not receive dedicated appropriations as a large aquatic ecosystem; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H50D4B52601F843328479F942706C2000" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the other 9 large aquatic ecosystems receive appropriations through the Geographic Programs program area of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H72711BBA41E74D089F65547DCB5E38F0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Columbia River Basin restoration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE27C938D4E984C59AC062C9771A3FDA9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H02D9077D94C944F88D380C61E3FF02DB"><enum>123.</enum><header>Columbia river basin restoration</header> 
<subsection id="H85ADEEF6873B47CCA3B67F6C3B620718"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<paragraph id="H2E541A96272843A5AFAC86E339531439"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Action plan</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7D6522130D2A4FF9940453D1193A4167"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Action Plan</term> means the Columbia River Basin Toxics Reduction Plan developed by the Environmental Protection Agency and the Columbia River Toxics Reduction Working Group in 2010.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H010D150BC1BD4996AACBF7E489F8CB34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>Action Plan</term> includes any amendments to the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC616E40237744141BDA4BDD23460C3F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Columbia River Basin</header><text>The term <term>Columbia River Basin</term> means the entire United States portion of the Columbia River watershed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FB8CD23D6084D1EB5F0A861E9E68C40"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Estuary Partnership</header><text>The term <term>Estuary Partnership</term> means the Lower Columbia River Estuary Partnership, an entity created by the States of Oregon and Washington and the Environmental Protection Agency under section 320.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB471C783AD24EDE8F7BF2C06DBDD313"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Estuary plan</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2A6985A942CE4712964ABDC6103916B5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Estuary Plan</term> means the Estuary Partnership Comprehensive Conservation and Management Plan adopted by the Environmental Protection Agency and the Governors of Oregon and Washington on October 20, 1999, under section 320.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1D7AF8A565A4E29845D9B5B3993DF1E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>Estuary Plan</term> includes any amendments to the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6AD6219E6DD4CA387992FFC5B7EC5AC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lower Columbia River Estuary</header><text>The term <term>Lower Columbia River Estuary</term> means the mainstem Columbia River from the Bonneville Dam to the Pacific Ocean and tidally influenced portions of tributaries to the Columbia River in that region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2716EA658824EEEADF2D12CA5F88F9B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Middle and Upper Columbia River Basin</header><text>The term <term>Middle and Upper Columbia River Basin</term> means the region consisting of the United States portion of the Columbia River Basin above Bonneville Dam.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H923A1F77AC234658A4091C8083137A56"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Columbia River Basin Restoration Program established under subsection (b)(1)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H015EF46922594C94BFA57533E61F3BC6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Working Group</header><text>The term <term>Working Group</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H46B14FBACF4B428E96978BAAAA9B056F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Columbia River Basin Toxics Reduction Working Group established under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE260A9F35194F808ADA6C3AFB84DF72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the Lower Columbia River Estuary, the Estuary Partnership.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H30CE0EB3FABA4209A34FA690BAFD7FC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Columbia River Basin restoration program</header> 
<paragraph id="H4317F344E7CA4D7490FE651BAA3651EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5247B21E169B4058BEEEEF1CD7FD9146"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish within the Environmental Protection Agency a Columbia River Basin Restoration Program for the purposes of reducing toxic contamination and cleaning up contaminated sites throughout the Columbia River Basin.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H751340B61AB84E4C922ED1EFA249CFC5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No effect on existing authority</header><text>The Program shall not modify any legal or regulatory authority or program in effect as of the date of enactment of this section, including the roles of Federal agencies in the Columbia River Basin.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDA5488083014E2CB564260B3A4538D8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Relationship to existing activities</header><text>The Program shall—</text> <clause id="H9B75A5F5B878400F8E83E64BEBF41680"><enum>(i)</enum><text>build on the work and collaborative structure of the existing Columbia River Toxics Reduction Working Group representing the Federal Government, State, tribal, and local governments, industry, and nongovernmental organizations, which was convened in 2005 to develop a collaborative toxic contamination reduction approach for the Columbia River Basin;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF8536CB8FACD47139C2D5E9FD93CCFE8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the Lower Columbia River Basin and Estuary, build on the work and collaborative structure of the Estuary Partnership;</text></clause> <clause id="H8DC520653CA3498FBA75B191E1CBFD4E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordinate with other efforts, including activities of other Federal agencies in the Columbia River Basin, to avoid duplicating activities or functions; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H83271A88774A43BCBBD2B5632AEE3957"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>not impede implementation of existing agreements or other recovery and mitigation programs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD096887B6C24D499F9C1B514391DF57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of program</header><text>The Program shall consist of a collaborative stakeholder-based program for reducing toxic contamination throughout the Columbia River Basin.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD9C51A41C334CEEBC769FAB1C1E19FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HFEF3A1E0CA044E6BA00AE96959F1B3C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess trends in water quality and toxic contamination or toxics reduction, including trends that affect uses of the water of the Columbia River Basin;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H406E55B3A2FA47D2BF9CD692E96ABEA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collect, characterize, and assess data on toxics and water quality to identify possible causes of environmental problems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9382A4D4C08845E0A0EF4291F77DB9F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide the Working Group with data, analysis, reports, or other information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D960C2B08FE4F44954047650C28745D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to the Working Group, and to State governments, tribal governments, and local governments participating in the Working Group, to assist those agencies and entities in—</text> <clause id="HDE1666F044DB415A9825D6C9A59307CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>developing updates to the Action Plan;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3F900E24A0E34951BDFE253EB0FC33B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommending and prioritizing projects and actions for the Action Plan; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5C1547B3874E4C80B1301996A5A4BAFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reviewing progress and effectiveness of projects and actions implemented, as well as cumulative progress toward the goals of this section, and the Action Plan;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9BD79E6BFB84E659141D860175BB4EB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>periodically update the Action Plan and the Estuary Plan as required by counsel, and ensure that those plans, when considered together and in light of relevant plans developed by other Federal or State agencies, form a coherent toxic contamination reduction strategy for the Columbia River Basin;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22E50C008B6C4B1D889A047A635911BE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>track progress toward meeting the identified goals and objectives of the Action Plan by coordinating and reporting environmental data related to the Action Plan and the Estuary Plan and making the data and reports on the data available to the public; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A39F673992D4FE98D20C19DDFFE67E3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provide grants in accordance with subsection (d) for projects that—</text> <clause id="H4853E0C9782C41C4BB1E62FF0A3FE033"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assist in—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H795061EF5B984A068E75446E7054EA07"><enum>(I)</enum><text>eliminating or reducing pollution;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H37A1384C034043CD8E807336C2065B8B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cleaning up contaminated sites;</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H0B495D3718F34E47AF68669AF0705B74"><enum>(III)</enum><text>improving water quality;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H1BF50E419008492EB3BB50739FA2BD14"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>monitoring to evaluate trends;</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H35E2036BCAD044218D7BEA850336FD82"><enum>(V)</enum><text>reducing runoff;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H1B980ED66EF14090B19A931EEBD65B38"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>protecting habitat; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H7A334E1719F340E887B6F38AA66F105B"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>promoting citizen engagement or knowledge;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H455A1DD929B64663A76C1BD8DA0DDDF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>address the goals, tasks, or action items in the Action Plan or the Estuary Plan; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE71FB804F81E46B8A6D9B3A5F1CC3D7D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are recommended by the Working Group to implement the Estuary Plan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE5F62CA153514A3898C9C10353C0B629"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stakeholder working group</header> <paragraph id="H13004863E575485B9E6C2EDE845578EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a Columbia River Basin Toxics Reduction Working Group.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46BED08D371A4A06994338314D6A3D9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDFDB4706F88D4E2BBF416347683AD670"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Membership in the Working Group shall be on a voluntary basis and any person invited by the Administrator under this subsection may decline membership.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4587216B57984AE2BF3BD5FA50F263F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Invited representatives</header><text>The Administrator shall invite, at a minimum, representatives of—</text> 
<clause id="H6E591B2E8DFB407AA672A5692BA5BC4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each State located in whole or in part within the Columbia River Basin;</text></clause> <clause id="HA4C9DB08F7B84132BBACA44679C87F86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Governors of each State located in whole or in part with the Columbia River Basin;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4333979CB3AC48EA83D98CB629B1EA60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each federally recognized Indian tribe in the Columbia River Basin;</text></clause> <clause id="H9ABFC6727FB1471EBD57902284763817"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>local governments located in the Columbia River Basin;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H210DB174072A4DFC891703A36B6EF142"><enum>(v)</enum><text>industries operating in the Columbia River Basin that affect or could affect water quality;</text></clause> <clause id="HD830C881C7344E3B8443F35B1EB48855"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>electric, water, and wastewater utilities operating in the Columba River Basin;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE9C173708CA44D039B502DFAD98FD81C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>private landowners in the Columbia River Basin;</text></clause> <clause id="H817FAD3978F945628A97FD9216FC8CAF"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>soil and water conservation districts in the Columbia River Basin;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4E3CEFFF91D34A48A5783C5DD092BF1B"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations that have a presence in the Columbia River Basin;</text></clause> <clause id="HF77D8CDEA4B84E87B2B7294E29220208"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the general public in the Columbia River Basin; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE660BB02982C43ED98162CE85C7F4564"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the Estuary Partnership.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6345762B5304EACB8137AB9B079157E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Geographic representation</header><text>The Working Group shall include representatives from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3D041F539FA840F39629EB094202B875"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40903EA3B4A14757B4356F9BAF0D6BE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each of the Lower, Middle, and Upper Basins of the Columbia River.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD143278BC43A4B4EBAFCB701D51AFA69"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties and responsibilities</header><text>The Working Group shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9EDB3A7C65CE42BB9451458F4B3F3C40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participate in developing updates to the Action Plan, including by providing comments on the updates;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0EDF8B0838BB453A9688A6593FA05B07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommend and prioritize projects and actions for the Action Plan; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9966191A193D4F8E81C0AA6F5D4AC17A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>review the progress and effectiveness of projects and actions implemented, as well as cumulative progress toward the goals of this section, and the Action Plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33069D46EF87448C95EE9776F97F9605"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lower Columbia River Estuary</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3163409324014049AEDE205509E889A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Estuary Partnership</header> 
<clause id="H111FFD0DE015434890AFFF0F5475D16E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Estuary Partnership shall perform the duties and fulfill the responsibilities of the Working Group described in paragraph (4) as those duties and responsibilities relate to the Lower Columbia River Estuary for such time as the Estuary Partnership is the management conference for the Lower Columbia River National Estuary Program under section 320.</text></clause> <clause id="H983BC36C7A9048C0A3B9FAD34391C61B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>If the Estuary Partnership ceases to be the management conference for the Lower Columbia River National Estuary Program under section 320, the Administrator may designate the new management conference to assume the duties and responsibilities of the Working Group described in paragraph (4) as those duties and responsibilities relate to the Lower Columbia River Estuary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F33FE79DA6F49C6A1FD26E3EB682893"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Estuary plan</header> 
<clause id="H3AB34AC82F2F4F9AA4C16543C082EB8A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Estuary Plan shall function as the Action Plan for the Lower Columbia River Estuary for such time as there is an Estuary Plan in place pursuant to section 320.</text></clause> <clause id="H15FF8CBD7B0743A5800FB6ECA8055232"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Incorporation</header><text>If the Estuary Partnership is removed from the National Estuary Program, the duties and responsibilities for the lower 146 miles of the Columbia River pursuant to this Act shall be incorporated into the duties of the Working Group.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAFDFE088AE2044CC8A42A0373B67F336"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants</header> 
<paragraph id="H9AE090A8C9BC494987DF2139B12D01AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a voluntary, competitive Columbia River Basin toxics program to provide grants to State governments, tribal governments, regional water pollution control agencies and entities, local government entities, nongovernmental entities, or soil and water conservation districts to develop or implement projects authorized under this section for the purpose of implementing the Action Plan and the Estuary Plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53875C4AD7A548BB9E6CD77AB0A44F4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal share</header> <subparagraph id="HDD6E71FD189D406983347E198315474F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Federal share of the cost of any project or activity carried out using funds from a grant provided to any person (including a State, tribal, or local government or interstate or regional agency) under this subsection for a fiscal year—</text> 
<clause id="H5873E1CC02F9499EAF3939F8B29E399A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not exceed 75 percent of the total cost of the project or activity; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2C6FF12E76DA40B2A3DBBA22D96421BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be made on condition that the non-Federal share of that total cost shall be provided from non-Federal sources.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5668525ECE74A7F9A8B79152B29748E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>With respect to cost-sharing for a grant provided under this subsection—</text> <clause id="H23223FCFC7F04849AA2DA3410057F12B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a tribal government may use Federal funds for the non-Federal share; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7FB3E26401A943DDB31E0F5825F03C74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator may increase the Federal share under such circumstances as the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H068C4263056D42C6B3C2D449797B9E1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>In making grants using funds appropriated to carry out this section, the Administrator shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDD64EFC474C64C379651D1B522FF701B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide not less than 25 percent of the funds to make grants for projects, programs, and studies in the Lower Columbia River Estuary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5EB9CC714F0D4FF99D233B50D101BAE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide not less than 25 percent of the funds to make grants for projects, programs, and studies in the Middle and Upper Columbia River Basin, which includes the Snake River Basin; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7AC4F37E32A24D1A8D4C070100454A41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>retain for Environmental Protection Agency not more than 5 percent of the funds for purposes of implementing this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H939E7C170FE3446F8A742C3C01436D9A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H54F828DB95C64086A170F73BC02C509E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each grant recipient under this subsection shall submit to the Administrator reports on progress being made in achieving the purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H361C0172418E44B4A170E84C41B353ED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Administrator shall establish requirements and timelines for recipients of grants under this section to report on progress made in achieving the purposes of this section and the goals of the Action Plan and the Estuary Plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC54DE861320D4E6D94A389038168D6BD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relationship to other funding</header> <subparagraph id="H65D4D4ECBE224AB283223BCCD582A07E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section limits the eligibility of the Estuary Partnership to receive funding under section 320(g).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C40C02E60D14525AAC33C91DFAC3039"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>None of the funds made available under this subsection may be used for the administration of a management conference under section 320.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1E22173595CE419480C1AC26E8EEA639"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual budget plan</header><text>The President, as part of the annual budget submission of the President to Congress under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, shall submit information regarding each Federal agency involved in protection and restoration of the Columbia River Basin, including an interagency crosscut budget that displays for each Federal agency—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5161B14635F24CF2BF600EFA03344594"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amounts obligated for the preceding fiscal year for protection and restoration projects, programs, and studies relating to the Columbia River Basin;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D93B428430D4AECAC1EAF2019573033"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the estimated budget for the current fiscal year for protection and restoration projects, programs, and studies relating to the Columbia River Basin; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3C565C30CC745FC8AA5FD7902F6898F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the proposed budget for protection and restoration projects, programs, and studies relating to the Columbia River Basin.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3590575274AF478E96D978D14C2D0DE4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


