<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5394EEAD397D4CF182D2BAD24752F270" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 433 IH: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 523 East Railroad Street in Knox, Pennsylvania, as the “Specialist Ross A. McGinnis Memorial Post Office”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 433</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150121">January 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001193">Mr. MacArthur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001154">Mr. Shuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000372">Mr. Frelinghuysen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 523 East Railroad Street in Knox, Pennsylvania, as the <quote>Specialist Ross A. McGinnis Memorial Post Office</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H08A96A7B42BB485BACD68C7733B3C6F4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE83B937D2DC64FD3A57E37A747C12AB2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H28B260F5DEC741BD9DF878267F0378C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ross Andrew McGinnis was born and raised in Knox, Pennsylvania, the son of Tom and Romayne McGinnis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58BE8918564A45B3B279CEF42EFCFC93"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specialist McGinnis joined the Army in 2004 and following his training, was assigned to 1st Platoon, C Company, 1st Battalion, 26th Infantry Regiment, 2nd Brigade Combat Team, 1st Infantry Division.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A5C5B93C44A447DA675A71554FBA078"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On December 4, 2006, McGinnis was killed in action while serving in Iraq. For his actions that day, he was awarded the Congressional Medal of Honor by President George W. Bush on June 2, 2008.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H819FF84BC70F4A7BB6823B06F46C744F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the official Medal of Honor Army Citation:</text> <subparagraph id="H343D6A1FF45C4FE9966F0C649785E95D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Private First Class Ross A. McGinnis, United States Army. For conspicuous gallantry and intrepidity at the risk of his life above and beyond the call of duty.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H902292C54F7D4115A75686A5B0B4EA68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Private First Class Ross A. McGinnis distinguished himself by acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving as an M2 .50-caliber Machine Gunner, 1st Platoon, C Company, 1st Battalion, 26th Infantry Regiment, in connection with combat operations against an armed enemy in Adhamiyah, Northeast Baghdad, Iraq, on 4 December 2006.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0995D6283C6341E88764EE536EA736DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That afternoon his platoon was conducting combat control operations in an effort to reduce and control sectarian violence in the area. While Private McGinnis was manning the M2 .50-caliber Machine Gun, a fragmentation grenade thrown by an insurgent fell through the gunner's hatch into the vehicle. Reacting quickly, he yelled <quote>grenade,</quote> allowing all four members of his crew to prepare for the grenade's blast. Then, rather than leaping from the gunner's hatch to safety, Private McGinnis made the courageous decision to protect his crew. In a selfless act of bravery, in which he was mortally wounded, Private McGinnis covered the live grenade, pinning it between his body and the vehicle and absorbing most of the explosion. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1596B7841E50430EA6FF8B46621ABC0A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Private McGinnis' gallant action directly saved four men from certain serious injury or death. Private First Class McGinnis' extraordinary heroism and selflessness at the cost of his own life, above and beyond the call of duty, are in keeping with the highest traditions of the military service and reflect great credit upon himself, his unit, and the United States Army.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H2841694805CE4FF7B0227CA5F5A0F9CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Specialist Ross A. McGinnis Memorial Post Office</header> <subsection id="HF2894F086D794D1EA74CC75352B60950"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 523 East Railroad Street in Knox, Pennsylvania, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Specialist Ross A. McGinnis Memorial Post Office</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4CB282FFBA50494E828A3FAC586DE1B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Specialist Ross A. McGinnis Memorial Post Office</quote>.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

