<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H63FBE25FF6C84383AAB857A2E4F5D224" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4205 IH: Christmas Tree Tax Exemption Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4205</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151209">December 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To permit producers of <quote>Choose and Cut</quote> Christmas trees to opt out of the Christmas tree promotion, research, and information order.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1380853EA36D474981378CB976CF1B51" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA07A082438BF4D828ED046B3287E6DC9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Christmas Tree Tax Exemption Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H529DECB9659C49D8887FEB4748C48FB5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority of <quote>Choose and Cut</quote> Christmas tree producers to opt out of the Christmas tree promotion, research, and information order</header> <subsection id="HCA63543CBC8F4810AB8E08746666E22A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority of producers To opt out</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall permit a Choose and Cut Christmas tree producer to opt out of the Christmas tree promotion, research, and information order contained in part 1214 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, and issued by the Secretary pursuant to the Commodity Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7411">7 U.S.C. 7411 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to Christmas trees produced by the producer and sold directly to final consumers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBA9AD3354D2F41B6AD8806A5C4EFB766"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H17F488133EF44C8BAE6990A0FAFB440B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Choose and Cut Christmas tree producer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Choose and Cut Christmas tree producer</quote> means a producer who produces Christmas trees in the United States, allows consumers to select a Christmas tree for purchase before the Christmas tree is severed or cut from its roots, and sells that Christmas tree directly to the final consumer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F50C955378A4DCA89A39FEA0DEB3C81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Christmas tree</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Christmas tree</quote> means any tree of the coniferous species that is severed or cut from its roots and marketed as a Christmas tree for holiday use.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CD2FD484D5D4364ADBC9BFD36FE95D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Producer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>producer</quote> means any person who is engaged in the production of Christmas trees in the United States, and who owns, or shares the ownership and risk of loss of the production of Christmas trees or a person who is engaged in the business of producing, or causing to be domestically produced, Christmas trees beyond personal use and having value at first point of sale.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


