<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3B4446854F2B4001B82A56FD6A0A6A76" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1122 IH: Strengthening Homeland Security, Intelligence, and Essential Law Enforcement Departments Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1122</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prioritize the payment of pay and allowances to members of the Armed Forces and Federal law
			 enforcement officers in the event the debt ceiling is reached or there is
			 a funding gap.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H32F8CB20F27848DEBB05F152A65BD01C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H524DBB9A567E45419DA194175B159D8E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Homeland Security, Intelligence, and Essential Law Enforcement Departments Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SHIELD Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="HC4A0AB8B29F644C6BBDE2A76BA1FF0D0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE637A1438A374FBC92536FBDA7975C0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Armed Forces represent the finest fighting force in the world.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8AF8F64C1034A27BD5D65E27847A89C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An interruption in compensation could affect morale and cause hardship which would threaten United States security and the safety of our troops.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E5778A59403490DAF0443B9F39FC26A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It is a vital national interest that the United States Armed Forces, including reserve components, can operate with the assurance that they will continue to receive pay and allowances for their service if a funding gap occurs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE38647FDE21D48E0B10E3D7C9775835F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Federal law enforcement officers are highly trained and dedicated men and women, committed to protecting liberty, public safety, and the security of our Nation from both foreign and domestic threats.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD06E8C9982054089955A2B34AECB6735"><enum>(5)</enum><text>They have no equal in the private sector, and perform a role that is both unique and vital to the continuing operation of the Federal Government and commerce during times of crisis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H297B73D021AF4088AB9FCBE8406BE491"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Each and every day, Federal law enforcement officers are engaged around the clock in activities that include, but are not limited to, dignitary protection, criminal investigation, homeland security, border security, intelligence gathering, and fighting waste, fraud and abuse.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABA4429674EE476EB61DC5C0074752F6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>These critical Government functions cannot be interrupted due to an absence of Congressional appropriations or during periods of a Government shutdown, nor can we expect that the threats posed by violent criminals, terrorists and America’s enemies will lessen during such periods of fiscal uncertainty.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HDAFED59C6CFA427986CDBA78D4F88F4C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Priority payments if the debt ceiling is reached for defense and Federal law enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the event that the total public debt reaches the public debt limit, as established under section 3101 of title 31, United States Code, the following payments on obligations incurred by the Government of the United States shall be made:</text>
 <paragraph id="H829C020FD81648C9AD8924D5460145F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The pay and allowances of members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components thereof, who perform active service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H838BCD34FB0A4959A4D3E3A7B11F2F25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The pay and allowances of critical law enforcement officers who are employed by Federal agencies.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H90D5641B865F48C6B12929B937596507"><enum>4.</enum><header>Emergency appropriations of funds for defense and Federal law enforcement during a funding gap</header> <subsection id="HB8A2CAE3DF3E418C99938E6A3E38D36C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriation of funds for military pay and allowances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period of lapsed appropriations for the Armed Forces, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the Secretary of Defense (and the Secretary of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard), out of any amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as the Secretary of Defense (and the Secretary of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard) determines to be necessary to continue to provide pay and allowances (without interruption) to members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components thereof, who perform active service during the period of lapsed appropriations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBF2C33EB0C42475FA94A2156F5D43784"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriation of funds for Federal law enforcement officer pay and allowances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period of lapsed appropriations for a federal agency that employs critical law enforcement officers, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the head of such agency, out of any amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as the heads of such agencies determine to be necessary to continue to provide pay and allowances (without interruption) to such critical law enforcement officers during the period of lapsed appropriations.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H443508EDBA784AFE80BBCF7B73312998"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE2D79A9BDD514F9CA33832E82D98D1CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>critical law enforcement officer</term> means an employee—</text>
 <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51B6D400731C4B02B53E24C811976CDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who has statutory authority to make arrests or apprehensions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEA829274F3A4213B4D433C0083E95EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is authorized by the agency of the employee to carry firearms; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA71FDA149A5F4E7AB70877CEEFF52EE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose duties include performing emergency work involving the safety of human life or the protection of property.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9386C0CB86D457B87917F5B88AB1DCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of lapsed appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>period of lapsed appropriations</term> means any period during which appropriations are not available due to the absence of the timely enactment of any Act or joint resolution (including any Act or joint resolution making continuing appropriations) appropriating funds for the payment of the pay and allowances.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H792B0E7AB8C64EE6A79A2C9EDA4D7018"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Total public debt</header><text>The term <quote>total public debt</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3130 of title 31, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

