<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H35864F28591A422DAEFC277CC00F8287" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1344 RH: To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize a program for early detection, diagnosis, and treatment regarding deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, and young children.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 182</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1344</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 114–241]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150310">March 10, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20150908">September 8, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="P000596">Mr. Pierluisi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000589">Mr. Rigell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action> 
<action-date date="20150908">September 8, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 10, 2015</action-instruction> 
</action> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize a program for early detection, diagnosis, and treatment regarding deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, and young children.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HIF00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H46F7B6935DE24C40A1EE92193DAC4648"> 
<section id="HCF66A65F94B74335928E14D57C9DA354" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may cited as the <quote>Early Hearing Detection and Intervention Act of 2015</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H09D826BD5B26404F9F40727BC79B7344"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7FD5062915024D5DA1C651576241C9E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, toddlers, and young children require access to specialized early intervention providers and programs in order to help them meet their linguistic and cognitive potential.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4861EBA7F1804887840F38E5E8F5B0CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Families of deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, toddlers, and young children benefit from comprehensive early intervention programs that assist them in supporting their child’s development in all domains.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E5D50D82EA0466F8D8E2E5BBEB61E86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Best practices principles for early intervention for deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, toddlers, and young children have been identified in a range of areas including listening and spoken language and visual and signed language acquisition, family-to-family support, support from individuals who are deaf or hard-of-hearing, progress monitoring, and others.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB2C4CBE95224F97B4CC90194A6B6D84"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Effective hearing screening and early intervention programs must be in place to identify hearing levels in deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, toddlers, and young children so that they may access appropriate early intervention programs in a timely manner.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBD47A1D933244A038E82F28213E6AE42"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reauthorization of program for early detection, diagnosis, and treatment regarding deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, and young children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 399M of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g-1">42 U.S.C. 280g–1</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H95C2D24E9E6D4F248E7FF25D292EFAA1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HE09545C91D5A44DC9B84EA50AEFBFB9C"><enum>399M.</enum><header>Early Detection, Diagnosis, and Treatment Regarding Deaf and Hard-of-Hearing Newborns, Infants, and Young Children</header> <subsection id="HD526E193DFE8470FA2AB83A9067CF648"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Health Resources and Services Administration</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall make awards of grants or cooperative agreements to develop statewide newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening, diagnosis, evaluation, and intervention programs and systems, and to assist in the recruitment, retention, education, and training of qualified personnel and health care providers for the following purposes:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE9320BA3805B461785C7946529BF1584"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To develop and monitor the efficacy of statewide programs and systems for hearing screening of newborns, infants, and young children, prompt evaluation and diagnosis of children referred from screening programs, and appropriate educational, audiological, and medical interventions for children confirmed to be deaf or hard-of-hearing, consistent with the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H9EC2C576E7394675A829C1F4E996E0B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Early intervention includes referral to and delivery of information and services by organizations such as schools and agencies (including community, consumer, and parent-based agencies), pediatric medical homes, and other programs mandated by part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, which offer programs specifically designed to meet the unique language and communication needs of deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, and young children.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H885E6ACE7EB24D5A8C428025473C9B14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information provided to parents must be accurate, comprehensive, and, where appropriate, evidence-based, allowing families to make important decisions for their child in a timely way, including decisions relating to all possible assistive hearing technologies (such as hearing aids, cochlear implants, and osseointegrated devices) and communication options (such as visual and sign language, listening and spoken language, or both).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD383365B15C4642B08FAE7511DEB6B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Programs and systems under this paragraph shall offer mechanisms that foster family-to-family and deaf and hard-of-hearing consumer-to-family supports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86357E88186543C59A23BDED8985E929"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop efficient models (both educational and medical) to ensure that newborns, infants, and young children who are identified through hearing screening receive followup by qualified early intervention providers, qualified health care providers, or pediatric medical homes (including by encouraging State agencies to adopt such models). </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7216F39DDEFA46EAB6464DF8DCA6C9EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To provide for a technical resource center in conjunction with the Maternal and Child Health Bureau of the Health Resources and Services Administration—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H112266862B214EA4BA95D083CF8410C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide technical support and education for States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB6379939934449D8AC050519173F8BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to continue development and enhancement of State early hearing detection and intervention programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0440332E0BA348C3A2D12ACAFF2E125D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance, data management, and applied research</header> 
<paragraph id="H270FCB9D793C49829B89EE36EC8D5F80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall make awards of grants or cooperative agreements to State agencies or their designated entities for development, maintenance, and improvement of data tracking and surveillance systems on newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screenings, audiologic evaluations, medical evaluations, and intervention services; to conduct applied research related to services and outcomes, and provide technical assistance related to newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening, evaluation, and intervention programs, and information systems; to ensure high-quality monitoring of hearing screening, evaluation, and intervention programs and systems for newborns, infants, and young children; and to coordinate developing standardized procedures for data management and assessing program and cost effectiveness. The awards under the preceding sentence may be used—</text> <subparagraph id="H95592B90DB554E30A76BAB35F04108EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance on data collection and management;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C2A74DF1F4D4EBCAFAA80C54B60EA1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to study and report on the costs and effectiveness of newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening, evaluation, diagnosis, intervention programs, and systems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H75961F6B63CD4B98BA9EC2CE700C164D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to collect data and report on newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening, evaluation, diagnosis, and intervention programs and systems that can be used—</text> 
<clause id="H0E3D32E35C3B466B85979FB9A835D490"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for applied research, program evaluation, and policy development; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB3CD535C183542ABA99F793310BD38EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to answer issues of importance to State and national policymakers;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H214C56F260E14977809958F62E874F54"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to identify the causes and risk factors for congenital hearing loss;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20469C4958744EBCA7691D4207FFA45A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to study the effectiveness of newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening, audiologic evaluations, medical evaluations, and intervention programs and systems by assessing the health, intellectual and social developmental, cognitive, and hearing status of these children at school age; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9985581745264368BCEE0E5351B4171E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to promote the integration, linkage, and interoperability of data regarding early hearing loss and multiple sources to increase information exchanges between clinical care and public health including the ability of States and territories to exchange and share data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A1FE0D3634B4416BF5ACEF3E6CD1DCB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Institutes of Health</header><text>The Director of the National Institutes of Health, acting through the Director of the National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders, shall, for purposes of this section, continue a program of research and development related to early hearing detection and intervention, including development of technologies and clinical studies of screening methods, efficacy of interventions, and related research.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7EFB030D8FEE4ADC965F3201EDB96FBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination and collaboration</header> 
<paragraph id="HF3EB3C014F464E12842B570EF65DC0BF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out programs under this section, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall collaborate and consult with—</text> <subparagraph id="HF21C5F560C9A455CAB7E8E131EC130C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFBC75135172D4FCDB90515040225BF5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State and local agencies, including those responsible for early intervention services pursuant to title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) (Medicaid Early and Periodic Screening, Diagnosis and Treatment Program); title XXI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>) (State Children’s Health Insurance Program); title V of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/701">42 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>) (Maternal and Child Health Block Grant Program); and part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1431">20 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1BBBF92A692404F9AA0E3421AC12C3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consumer groups of and that serve individuals who are deaf and hard-of-hearing and their families;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA2A1D7C6A204DD687C3035D7227A2F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>appropriate national medical and other health and education specialty organizations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA31E90D58614A608CF497D8C1DD737E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>persons who are deaf and hard-of-hearing and their families;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD95FF00175E0444A96A19EE0C828355B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other qualified professional personnel who are proficient in deaf or hard-of-hearing children’s language and who possess the specialized knowledge, skills, and attributes needed to serve deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, toddlers, children, and their families;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H248B8CB371EC4B878D32B0899B4DB4CD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>third-party payers and managed-care organizations; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE4847D3209D4FA6BB219113EFD511C7"><enum>(H)</enum><text>related commercial industries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4F71A06A7BA4F60ABAA2A49CAED6574"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Policy development</header><text>The Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall coordinate and collaborate on recommendations for policy development at the Federal and State levels and with the private sector, including consumer, medical, and other health and education professional-based organizations, with respect to newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening, evaluation, diagnosis, and intervention programs and systems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD31822626E8D491CB4C2901A226ED3CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State early detection, diagnosis, and intervention programs and systems; data collection</header><text>The Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall coordinate and collaborate in assisting States—</text> <subparagraph id="HE5B63C37DE904FF29FB12A219C0D5EB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening, evaluation, diagnosis, and intervention programs and systems under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA63F6F37DB4402BACA3B14E639320B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop a data collection system under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5DC067B704C447308AE60CD438A01DC9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction; religious accommodation</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt or prohibit any State law, including State laws which do not require the screening for hearing loss of newborns, infants, or young children of parents who object to the screening on the grounds that such screening conflicts with the parents’ religious beliefs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0757250C8334BDC9DB08D124487DEA2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1DCE8B9127D543CC816154ADEE3AB224" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>audiologic</term>, when used in connection with evaluation, refers to procedures—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF7F6C780671441DF90D3DC6D1E75A790"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to assess the status of the auditory system;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D92902CC5774E799E31534AB691784A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to establish the site of the auditory disorder, the type and degree of hearing loss, and the potential effects of hearing loss on communication; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCFB96E0CD5384E8684BCB2E299B3300D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to identify appropriate treatment and referral options, including—</text> <clause id="H98BF4DC896AB4551BBA3CA63DE884683"><enum>(i)</enum><text>linkage to State coordinating agencies under part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1431">20 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</external-xref>) or other appropriate agencies;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H544B61880DED4926B9BD1416FA42E51E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>medical evaluation;</text></clause> <clause id="HF328C022A09E45F5827934F26FD6BCA8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>hearing aid/sensory aid assessment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6140ECDABAEB44DBA93BDFB65A4A1B3C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>audiologic rehabilitation treatment; and</text></clause> <clause id="H841EBA1FF3134521B504B95C9BBDCB03"><enum>(v)</enum><text>referral to national and local consumer, self-help, parent, and education organizations, and other family-centered services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4917434F6E846619280F0E2A1BEABBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>early intervention</term> refers to—</text> <subparagraph id="HD9CEACCC876D4EC58A16EDE68AB43ACD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing appropriate services for the child who is deaf or hard of hearing, including nonmedical services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC06D06001F744C758CFB653FD4624B80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring the family of the child is—</text> <clause id="H170F4E96F4714E02930FA88068016612"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provided comprehensive, consumer-oriented information about the full range of family support, training, information services, and language and communication options; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H96B92BBADB3346A9B1A34615B4693D3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>given the opportunity to consider and obtain the full range of such appropriate services, educational and program placements, and other options for their child from highly qualified providers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB50DA0068BA490D915AEE9940C0D298"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>medical evaluation</term> refers to key components performed by a physician, including history, examination, and medical decisionmaking focused on symptomatic and related body systems for the purpose of diagnosing the etiology of hearing loss and related physical conditions, and for identifying appropriate treatment and referral options.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H213C99C66658488BAFC37808179492A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>medical intervention</term> refers to the process by which a physician provides medical diagnosis and direction for medical or surgical treatment options for hearing loss or related medical disorders.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H012110D949B44E3F9863FA5A208AFD2E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening</term> refers to objective physiologic procedures to detect possible hearing loss and to identify newborns, infants, and young children who require further audiologic evaluations and medical evaluations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFFCF8315CEA64034A5D74050C8429A06"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<paragraph id="H9C9D9840CB79446D9A8F503B7DEE0C77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Statewide newborn, infant, and young childhood hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out subsection (a), there is authorized to be appropriated to the Health Resources and Services Administration $17,800,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H316B2972378E44C58FBEE1E5B99C65E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance, data management, and applied research; centers for disease control and prevention</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out subsection (b)(1), there is authorized to be appropriated to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention $10,800,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EDCC828858B42B6A0F1292EC0C68055"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical assistance, data management, and applied research; national institute on deafness and other communication disorders</header><text>No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out subsection (b)(2). Such subsection shall be carried out using funds which are otherwise authorized (under section 402A or other provisions of law) to be appropriated for such purpose.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20150908">September 8, 2015</action-date> <action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

