<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAD0C4389C90B45C6A0D774A4519E5BF1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2681 IH: Training Highly Skilled Americans Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2681</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150604">June 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish the STEM Education and Training Account
			 in order to enhance the economic competitiveness of the United States by
			 providing funding for STEM education and training, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H164DD80610AB46338BBC90019B84828A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H316B3821B1154D73AF709B51D8FEA196" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Training Highly Skilled Americans Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF4E3F8F396A748B6B50AA90126B1BCD0"><enum>2.</enum><header>STEM education and training</header> <subsection id="HADAFA4CA329445CFA33C5CAC9F951F6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fee</header><text>Section 212(a)(5)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H97D600820A2442DC8E1C92581F67DEE3" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H0FDFFB7D125E4CC585C51164562D0349"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Fee</header><text>An employer shall submit, along with an application for a certification under this subparagraph, a fee of $1,000, which shall be deposited in the STEM Education and Training Account established under section 286(w).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7C5D5DDB123D47B69E4001480517FEC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>H–1B nonimmigrant petitioner account</header><text>Section 286(s) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(s)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraphs (3) and (4) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H933905BA944E4386AD0016F4447E4672" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H6F1CE235A4244AF6B38A8FCF8BAD4027"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Low-income stem scholarship program</header>
 <subparagraph id="H66A807C9AC0B4D4EB16B2C340600DAB1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Thirty percent of the amounts deposited into the H–1B Nonimmigrant Petitioner Account shall remain available to the Director of the National Science Foundation until expended for scholarships described in section 414(d) of the American Competitiveness and Workforce Improvement Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1869c">42 U.S.C. 1869c</external-xref>) for low-income students enrolled in a program of study leading to a degree in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5185060F2D5A4DC6BEF0D46F2EEA52DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Stem education for underrepresented</header><text>The Director shall work in consultation with, or direct scholarship funds through, national nonprofit organizations that primarily focus on science, technology, engineering, or mathematics education for underrepresented groups, such as women and minorities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FF35D629E864AE8945571F662C61C58"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Loan forgiveness</header><text>The Director may expend funds from the Account for purposes of loan forgiveness or repayment of student loans which led to a low-income student obtaining a degree in science, technology, engineering, mathematics, or other high demand fields.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8144BEBF279842D0BD544E6403263FBE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National science foundation grant program for K–12 science, technology, engineering, and
			 mathematics education</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEA7D900BD2A34FBCBF7740F6C8F3DAF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Ten percent of the amounts deposited into the H–1B Nonimmigrant Petitioner Account shall remain available to the Director of the National Science Foundation until expended to carry out a direct or matching grant program to support improvement in K–12 education, including through private-public partnerships. Grants awarded pursuant to this paragraph shall include formula-based grants that target lower income populations with a focus on reaching women and minorities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H371F66ED2A3E49B49946128DCDB200E9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Types of programs covered</header><text>The Director shall award grants to programs that—</text> <clause id="H61428B28E1C4408192F2CB10C3CE91FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support the development and implementation of standards-based instructional materials models and related student assessments that enable K–12 students to acquire an understanding of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, and to develop critical thinking skills;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCEB9574854714F6998471DDC89B1AF46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide systemic improvement in training K–12 teachers and education for students in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, including by supporting efforts to promote gender-equality among students receiving such instruction;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5849D7E225F5489ABBFDCBCD722D78E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>support the professional development of K–12 science, technology, engineering, and mathematics teachers in the use of technology in the classroom;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H463E16DCE53D4C0796D53988FFC6595F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>stimulate systemwide K–12 reform of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics in urban, rural, and economically disadvantaged regions of the United States;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H84305E24A3CF421BB64E7392B3CE9534"><enum>(v)</enum><text>provide externships and other opportunities for students to increase their appreciation and understanding of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (including summer institutes sponsored by an institution of higher education for students in grades 7 through 12 that provide instruction in such fields);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC47075E43B9D41A4892B5E8BC3F01FBD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>involve partnerships of industry, educational institutions, and national or regional community-based organizations with demonstrated experience addressing the educational needs of disadvantaged communities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2FBC1CE2D4AE4ED58F2491A9EC3679AD"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>provide college preparatory support to expose and prepare students for careers in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8E304ABE4DD14546B29EAA0230C924FF"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>provide for carrying out systemic reform activities under section 3(a)(1) of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1862">42 U.S.C. 1862(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA88621AB2E7140798A98F943DBADC657"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of fee</header><text>Section 286 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HFEC01C2632AD4CB19236DAB80A9003A8" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HEDAC60B756234FFEB0456232994974D4"><enum>(w)</enum><header>Stem education and training account</header>
 <paragraph id="HF5F8AC8411884D5D8E1DF370B4CFD53B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the general fund of the Treasury a separate account, which shall be known as the <term>STEM Education and Training Account</term>. Notwithstanding any other section of this title, there shall be deposited as offsetting receipts into the Account all of the fees collected under section 212(a)(5)(A)(v).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H38AC00D4347D4934AB786C0DE499146A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC56FF00E2E424028B02277AF23EEF6CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The purposes of the STEM Education and Training Account are to enhance the economic competitiveness of the United States by—</text>
 <clause id="H1DE8A70B96EC49CC93026B2B6728E7D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>strengthening STEM education, including in computer science, at all levels;</text> </clause><clause id="H00AFADA80B80422C8F8F8E65B3F09DD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring that schools have access to well-trained and effective STEM teachers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H92E9D6522F174DDE99DB4EE96E6BD625"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>supporting efforts to strengthen the elementary and secondary curriculum, including efforts to make courses in computer science more broadly available; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD31D49520B764C2B8984B8A822F15377"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>helping colleges and universities produce more graduates in fields needed by American employers.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE007EF15A21A4B6BB4DC94C43822A1EF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>STEM education</term> means instruction in a field of science, technology, engineering, or math included in the Department of Education’s Classification of Instructional Programs taxonomy within the summary groups of computer and information sciences and support services, engineering, mathematics and statistics, biological and biomedical sciences, and physical sciences.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA31DE8B1D6C348CDBDAFC42B57537474"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allocations to States and territories</header>
 <subparagraph id="H998E61AFE32A4939A4A49DEB5A0F058D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary of Education shall proportionately allocate 70 percent of the amounts deposited into the STEM Education and Training Account each fiscal year to the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands in an amount that bears the same relationship as the proportion the State, district, or territory received under subpart 2 of part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6331">20 U.S.C. 6331 et seq.</external-xref>) for the preceding fiscal year bears to the amount all States and territories received under that subpart for the preceding fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD2FA86982144C33BA5520E52A3B01A7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum allocations</header><text>No State or territory shall receive less than an amount equal to 0.5 percent of the total amount made available to all States from the STEM Education and Training Account. If a State or territory does not request an allocation from the Account for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reallocate the State’s allocation to the remaining States and territories in accordance with this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H022B4C7972BC4035939C3D063CB1FBBE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts allocated pursuant to this paragraph may be used for the activities described in section 2(d) of the Training Highly Skilled Americans Act of 2015.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC104D69F7E1A4A0BAF86E221172ECD40"><enum>(4)</enum><header>STEM capacity building at minority-serving institutions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H095E5A48B48144C281D500B6EE4C7141"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall allocate 20 percent of the amounts deposited into the STEM Education and Training Account to establish or expand programs to award grants to institutions described in subparagraph (C)—</text>
 <clause id="HBA55E03501EC4398AC59C7CDA8974368"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to enhance the quality of undergraduate science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education at such institutions; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8C1D5D6251B940908EA746BFC959FC0E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to increase the retention and graduation rates of students pursuing degrees in such fields at such institutions.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H120B8777091348D887C8EF98B2D44145"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Types of programs covered</header><text>Grants awarded under this paragraph shall be awarded to—</text> <clause id="H6B0D921254CD4564AE48E9078326AB98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>minority-serving institutions of higher education for—</text>
 <subclause id="HFBBA44294C7241CA83E9BA03AE77D95C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>activities to improve courses and curriculum in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA2A19E15D0CC493BA50CE1A94E657D17"><enum>(II)</enum><text>efforts to promote gender equality among students enrolled in such courses;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD68B15E55C0F472C835074CD52416C8E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>faculty development;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFA510731AA8F43A7A5CF50AB719CE977"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>stipends for undergraduate students participating in research; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5E02FAAC37764E97BA69177DF19F87E9"><enum>(V)</enum><text>other activities consistent with subparagraph (A), as determined by the Secretary of Education; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H92722D0581B149789A20946F4335FD28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to other institutions of higher education to partner with the institutions described in clause (i) for—</text>
 <subclause id="HFE4B8772589B45F5A815700D03B99A68"><enum>(I)</enum><text>faculty and student development and exchange;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H25F15667630645899BCCB32351F05F72"><enum>(II)</enum><text>research infrastructure development;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H39E07771C15E4A4FB717D59F185F780C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>joint research projects; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF0A2D7733BAF4490B43120AF336E848E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>identification and development of minority and low-income candidates for graduate studies in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics degree programs.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H846B7073CC1A4D019C74B29611CC3217"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Institutions included</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>institutions</term> shall include—</text> <clause id="HFD9BEBD7A7C449059D5AEE8C502F1CC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>colleges eligible to receive funds under the Act of August 30, 1890 (7 U.S.C. 321–326a and 328), including Tuskegee University;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H680E468822434BF9BA87352FEE0B12E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1994 Institutions, as defined in section 532 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/301">7 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H880BAA1DB67848FC9C0EF475BB3E300C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>part B institutions (as defined in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>)); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBEBEC49D9B6944D0AE0B88DDB6EA3D26"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Hispanic-serving institutions, as defined in section 502(a)(5) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)(5)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CD8A91F839F413681FE9EAABD54F069"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Granting of bonding authority</header><text>A recipient of a grant awarded under this paragraph is authorized to utilize such funds for the issuance of bonds to fund research infrastructure development.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB03EF70D0864A38A0EA75F3B7B603B6"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Loan forgiveness</header><text>The Director may expend funds from the allocation under this paragraph for purposes of loan forgiveness or repayment of student loans which led to a low-income student obtaining a degree in science, technology, engineering, mathematics, or other high demand fields.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H378F64E8CC09492BBD6E51B100FAED9A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Workforce investment</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall allocate 5 percent of the amounts deposited into the STEM Education and Training Account to the Secretary of Labor until expended for statewide workforce investment activities that may also benefit veterans and their spouses, including youth activities and statewide employment and training and activities for adults and dislocated workers described in section 128(a) of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2853">29 U.S.C. 2853(a)</external-xref>), and the development of licensing and credentialing programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA86185D13F56429FAF72760D40CB81C8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>American dream accounts</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall allocate 3 percent of the amounts deposited into the STEM Education and Training Account to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities to establish and administer American Dream Accounts under section 2(e) of the Training Highly Skilled Americans Act of 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDF86EBE7A2A40F6899B071176836229"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Administration expenses</header><text>The Secretary of Education may expend up to 2 percent of the amounts deposited into the STEM Education and Training Account for administrative expenses, including conducting an annual evaluation of the implementation and impact of the activities funded by the STEM Education and Training Account as required under section 2(d)(3) of the Training Highly Skilled Americans Act of 2015.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCBB74E768CBA4FF0B7CA74E780FF5AE3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Stem education grants</header>
				<paragraph id="H7ADB7E7DFEC44CDDACDC36F732DB9132"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application process</header>
 <subparagraph id="HACAA90B530B9462F94B39AB0741BB7CD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Governor and Chief State School Officer desiring an allocation from the STEM Education and Training Account under section 286(w)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by subsection (c), shall jointly submit a plan, including a proposed budget, signed by the Governor and Chief State School Officer, to the Secretary of Education at such time, in such form, and including such information as the Secretary of Education may prescribe pursuant to subparagraph (B). The plan shall describe how the State plans to improve STEM education to meet the needs of students and employers in the State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BB72B0CC07041A0A5EB5E2FC0480E51"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall issue a rule, through a rulemaking procedure that complies with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, prescribing the information that should be included in the State plans submitted under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D3F56A13D30403490C9E08D01C292E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowable activities</header><text>A State, district, or territory that receives funding from the STEM Education and Training Account may use such funding to develop and implement science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) activities to serve students, including students of underrepresented groups such as minorities, economically disadvantaged, and females by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8DB5EB8529AD47D693150CFA3B465AAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strengthening the State’s STEM academic achievement standards;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B4CA28501014696B18E898C376A249E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implementing strategies for the recruitment, training, placement, and retention of teachers in STEM fields, including computer science;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF92ABD1F11B42A3B744AC73DE308A99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>carrying out initiatives designed to assist students in succeeding and graduating from postsecondary STEM programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BD5892A28544FB2A4985FC8EFA13BB1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improving the availability and access to STEM-related worker training programs, including community college courses and programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0A9562882874C42A66C86935AFE4EE3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>forming partnerships with higher education, economic development, workforce, industry, and local educational agencies; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD85356D42ADD4669B733B254C7B6D868"><enum>(F)</enum><text>engaging in other activities, as determined by the State, in consultation with businesses and State agencies, to improve STEM education.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H598D5FF7DA3342EFB2FC85A7C977C65F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National evaluation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H162BE7587E314F08907BF392E11A4077"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Using amounts allocated under section 286(w)(7) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by subsection (c), the Secretary of Education shall conduct, directly or through a grant or contract, an annual evaluation of the implementation and impact of the activities funded by the STEM Education and Training Account.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96D7C3C415E242A1B96A489DADA7DAE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report describing the results of each evaluation conducted under subparagraph (A) to—</text>
 <clause id="H57BFBD764124485EB733A55D63E91B5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the President;</text> </clause><clause id="H9303A52C1AB54B52A2B2E369E863FC98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB0075FFC410C4855A5F8834454014D49"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text> </clause><clause id="H560C9116D0C94956BEF5802E548DC007"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA7D95F4E1C9B47288E0366F239B01B84"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8313F94D2454FAB8CF13E7E9E85C6F2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>The Secretary shall make the findings of the evaluation widely available to educators, the business community, and the public.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06E38CCE843B4C5289BD8802D0B5063A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to permit the Secretary of Education or any other Federal official to approve the content or academic achievement standards of a State.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9DC7051C300D4D48970F73C63F66366F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>American dream accounts</header>
 <paragraph id="H8B2DB6878C234BDAACA57D99259CFEF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H48023BDDEB594A849A3559FAA0B862D8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>American dream account</header><text>The term <term>American Dream Account</term> means a personal online account for low-income students that monitors higher education readiness and includes a college savings account.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC49AADE345104FE0A561A1E2F2F192E3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <clause id="HCFE54F840E5247C28669F71C9223B00E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9DDD6339935C490E9AEED88BBD9439C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text> </clause><clause id="HF67647026B4D4C3FA04CF6DEC44D2C67"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7657165DD0514985AB52D3033F48DF68"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives;</text> </clause><clause id="H6FB6E120817D49D69D285C6BFEF414B1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6B361D720C314F88805568F4E02951FC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text> </clause><clause id="H69D4D1F38CBB4EF4B0A1D8366393B178"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other committee of the Senate or House of Representatives that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49FCDFDA7B474151A932A4DB0EAA7862"><enum>(C)</enum><header>College savings account</header><text>The term <term>college savings account</term> means a savings account that—</text> <clause id="HB8CF55AD0004432984D4673B48B70B72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides some tax-preferred accumulation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HACDBB2FF3928489CA50CBBC78B9C43B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is widely available (such as Qualified Tuition Programs under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">section 529</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or Coverdell Education Savings Accounts under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/530">section 530</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA13941E37BA54203876EF9C63C8D7672"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>contains funds that may be used only for the costs associated with attending an institution of higher education, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H8E8A76CF5AED43FE86E88DA94A4A5F28"><enum>(I)</enum><text>tuition and fees;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5B292151D3BD485CA459E62F1FF702B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>room and board;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFADFC61C25AE4751A29535C2BE2F7736"><enum>(III)</enum><text>textbooks;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC121DB9661184A47BF2727349D16C145"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>supplies and equipment; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H600C126187794708BD3532A0109EE5D0"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Internet access.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9554F2CA4C04A6E961800655945A67E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Dual enrollment program</header><text>The term <term>dual enrollment program</term> means an academic program through which a secondary school student is able simultaneously to earn credit toward a secondary school diploma and a postsecondary degree or credential.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54596FB13F5A4EC6B6ADB9407B2AE744"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <clause id="H52C8A8721A19403F879018FA219209D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State educational agency;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0840E49B486C4FA99979BC3B6F275438"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text> </clause><clause id="H5B087457ABC44265A7B296F836D30271"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a charter school or charter management organization;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5758D74372CB4706A6DA428A40CE21BE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an institution of higher education;</text> </clause><clause id="H90161045BFEE4B07A98E0B9188D4E4C4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8AC3091A548943508A241D358C21294F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>an entity with demonstrated experience in educational savings or in assisting low-income students to prepare for, and attend, an institution of higher education; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H30723C0C3BAE4D20A290E2F853E35AFB"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a consortium of 2 or more of the entities described in clauses (i) through (vi).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ED1F3D6905F4116989FCB4CCFF45A8B"><enum>(F)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>parent</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>) and the term <term>charter school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5210 of such Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD12E6CEAB514157B58C9E2BC3EFBB47"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8022719FEF20490591531EA4AD485613"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Low-income student</header><text>The term <term>low-income student</term> means a student who is eligible to receive a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65F700CD3F944FB398644F85BCFC7F00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant program</header>
 <subparagraph id="H86D69B544C67482AA4F71F72EDAAE554"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary of Education is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities to establish and administer American Dream Accounts for a group of low-income students.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H828C6C7B56D246FC9AEC4EF14AF83185"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount made available each fiscal year to carry out this section under section 286(w)(6) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by subsection (c), the Secretary of Education shall reserve not more than 5 percent of such amount to carry out the evaluation activities described in paragraph (5)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H959868D7B99048CFB24011059D327A7F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection shall be for a period of not more than 3 years. The Secretary of Education may extend such grant for an additional 2-year period if the Secretary of Education determines that the eligible entity has demonstrated significant progress, based on the factors described in paragraph (3)(B)(xi).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC62159E57AA14923BC104D08C197ECB9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications; priority</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5443E93A2CF242A6B34C190D4920EC3C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible entity desiring a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Secretary of Education at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary of Education may require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H847B895AE1CA43579C2E3C6EFD176505"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The application described in subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> <clause id="H660962D27D5B4C819D2D8FBB500CCD64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the characteristics of a group of not less than 30 low-income public school students who—</text>
 <subclause id="H7077D2C015FD43AE87B88DACD3020868"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are, at the time of the application, attending a grade not higher than grade 9; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC8288524B88143B4B8E5D306429972D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will, under the grant, receive an American Dream Account;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAEEF87FDD9B9463FBAF8E3E07C6CCBB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will engage, and provide support (such as tutoring and mentoring for students, and training for teachers and other stakeholders) either online or in person, to—</text>
 <subclause id="HCA26F83EC3C143AF9108FE36B5BC756E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the students in the group described in clause (I);</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5FA1231E039F4DB39147AB218E757B84"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the family members and teachers of such students; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H262A28D6BBE04FA8AEE5C427608826B8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>other stakeholders such as school administrators and school counselors;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H1D5B25DBA4694BBA9D955DC014B63144"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an identification of partners who will assist the eligible entity in establishing and sustaining American Dream Accounts;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF138E80AF877416DA37B645674F91C7E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of what experience the eligible entity or the eligible entity’s partners have in managing college savings accounts, preparing low-income students for postsecondary education, managing online systems, and teaching financial literacy;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HADCA576CBF3347ACADEBF902F4407E07"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will help increase the value of the college savings account portion of each American Dream Account, such as by providing matching funds or incentives for academic achievement;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9942B838FF234529996BDB74D8B6CCFD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will notify each participating student in the group described in subparagraph (A), on a semiannual basis, of the current balance and status of the student’s college savings account portion of the student’s American Dream Account;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H73BA6269DF214F2BA05AE138338520D5"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a plan that describes how the eligible entity will monitor participating students in the group described in clause (i) to ensure that each student’s American Dream Account will be maintained if a student in such group changes schools before graduating from secondary school;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF466F2B21DEB4961845574C3DD6FF9D3"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a plan that describes how the American Dream Accounts will be managed for not less than 1 year after a majority of the students in the group described in clause (i) graduate from secondary school;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H95935BDD02F84B9298CD53594E2B5F66"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will encourage students in the group described in clause (i) who fail to graduate from secondary school to continue their education;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAA9F48B119BA43CC9CCBF055AC7E8EDE"><enum>(x)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will evaluate the grant program, including by collecting, as applicable, data about the students in the group described in clause (i) during the grant period, and, if sufficient grant funds are available, after the grant period, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HECC5CC91BFD04827A898407749B1055E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>attendance rates;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC6089159B8004DD38D9B9A86EF1CD027"><enum>(II)</enum><text>progress reports;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7D08BC0A3B6344F6A0D50DE384C7644F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>grades and course selections;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFCE873E278C64BBBBD09D2BE77A5E35B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the student graduation rate (as defined in section 1111 (b)(2)(C)(vi) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(vi)</external-xref>));</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5A7649DCF0CB4B1E9CC7EFFA15715A58"><enum>(V)</enum><text>rates of student completion of the Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1090">20 U.S.C. 1090</external-xref>);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB010277578B2474AA87FA25001313B55"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>rates of enrollment in an institution of higher education; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H896FEB1A91F4468EAD79F6535085EEE1"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>rates of completion at an institution of higher education;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD6CF9983F70B4A9589DA6EB8E93D0AF2"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>a description of what will happen to the funds in the college savings account portion of the American Dream Accounts that are dedicated to participating students described in clause (i) who have not matriculated at an institution of higher education at the time of the conclusion of the period of American Dream Account management described in clause (viii);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB062693224EA4F8DBF9DC2D7FF25037C"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will ensure that funds in the college savings account portion of the American Dream Accounts will not make families ineligible for public assistance; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7C0DB94540894960A1C8DBF57D6B3162"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will ensure that participating students described in clause (i) will have access to the Internet.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45903D7DC3C1479FAC6FAA10495F258F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary of Education shall give priority to applications from eligible entities that—</text>
 <clause id="H76B9930D89EE4CD4AA4F8C3710BC9C71"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are described in paragraph (1)(E)(vii);</text> </clause><clause id="HF84EC46D364841B09336DCD188338C94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serve the largest number of low-income students;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H54858F04976447AB8EE24075995FC4E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>emphasize preparing students to pursue careers in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3546725968D84EDDA4A68C3F2C1A4F7C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity described in clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (1)(E), provide opportunities for participating students described in clause (i) to participate in a dual enrollment program at no cost to the student.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B40F9B2CA8E4880A73997864A5BC784"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC75EC7217CFC47DDA9ED1AE44FEF0F44"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall use such grant funds to establish an American Dream Account for each participating student described in paragraph (3)(B)(i), which will be used to—</text>
 <clause id="HA3DB0E5805624C26BCA94B0C3286ABD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>open a college savings account for such student;</text> </clause><clause id="HF8169B668E3544B9987311F7327FE563"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>monitor the progress of such student online, which—</text>
 <subclause id="H395E5C0D4021451EBC3B798681DF89EE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall include monitoring student data relating to—</text> <item id="H1E4DA7D2C0B041FC879F1C7D28F6C56D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>grades and course selections;</text>
 </item><item id="HBDB3BB2FAC3C434CBBAA075A307EEB33"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>progress reports; and</text> </item><item id="HBBDAE83C19D84719BC9B9E661FA623EA"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>attendance and disciplinary records; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H990A90151E0B4C96BFDEE656EF2615BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may also include monitoring student data relating to a broad range of information, provided by teachers and family members, related to postsecondary education readiness, access, and completion;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HEF081EC911A64EFF9D58FF938E0EEDDF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide opportunities for such students, either online or in person, to learn about financial literacy, including by—</text>
 <subclause id="H95A3CA368BC94D4B978DD7F65E413424"><enum>(I)</enum><text>assisting such students in financial planning for enrollment in an institution of higher education; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H40D20726162641CDBBBE5A247FBAB50A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>assisting such students in identifying and applying for financial aid (such as loans, grants, and scholarships) for an institution of higher education;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HBFEB19B3515C4BAAA55BE04B97F3403A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide opportunities for such students, either online or in person, to learn about preparing for enrollment in an institution of higher education, including by providing instruction to students about—</text>
 <subclause id="H95458C074D7142A99E7AA22AA96FFFB1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>choosing the appropriate courses to prepare for postsecondary education;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8CA8AAEEE1B7460386D1A06EBDA52A75"><enum>(II)</enum><text>applying to an institution of higher education;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1FA6128193494D45B69A806998CDE1D8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>building a student portfolio, which may be used when applying to an institution of higher education;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDA8D40F7BE104315A26A1BB7D3A5754F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>selecting an institution of higher education;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4280EA98788740A0B87A2C65715B9059"><enum>(V)</enum><text>choosing a major for the student’s postsecondary program of education or a career path, including specific instruction on pursuing science, technology, engineering, and mathematics majors; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H613272EAFAB0495B87DACC450E94DA2B"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>adapting to life at an institution of higher education; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HC31519BA09704FD89B09F87AB0133006"><enum>(v)</enum><text>provide opportunities for such students, either online or in person, to identify skills or interests, including career interests.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14F719B72BDC41C7BDB4256323455D8F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Access to American dream account</header>
 <clause id="H703A04364A95402298CD6B73CF9ABFED"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clauses (iii) and (iv), and in accordance with applicable Federal laws and regulations relating to privacy of information and the privacy of children, an eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall allow vested stakeholders described in clause (ii), to have secure access, through the Internet, to an American Dream Account.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5067BA6448E348E68A7AEE197B661684"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Vested stakeholders</header><text>The vested stakeholders that an eligible entity shall permit to access an American Dream Account are individuals (such as the student’s teachers, school counselors, counselors at an institution of higher education, school administrators, or other individuals) that are designated, in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>), by the parent of a participating student in whose name such American Dream Account is held, as having permission to access the account. A student’s parent may withdraw such designation from an individual at any time.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3784B8CA63E040649739E7667DE09E23"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception for college savings account</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall not be required to give vested stakeholders described in clause (ii), access to the college savings account portion of a student’s American Dream Account.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA51592E42EA45308183B2A9F65A0518"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Adult students</header><text>Notwithstanding clauses (i) through (iii), if a participating student is age 18 or older, an eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall not provide access to such participating student’s American Dream Account without the student’s consent, in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7351C7802FDE4576B08A9311B5F7C52C"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Input of student information</header><text>Student data collected pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) may only be entered into an American Dream Account by a school administrator or such administrator’s designee.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8CBA07DACB74B0F83AFB47BC5A9230A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of student information</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection may not use any student-level information or data for the purpose of soliciting, advertising, or marketing any financial or nonfinancial consumer product or service that is offered by such eligible entity, or on behalf of any other person.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3139203DE588476EABC1FB9E73A92F16"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on the use of grant funds</header><text>An eligible entity shall not use more than 25 percent of the grant funds provided under this subsection to provide the initial deposit into a college savings account portion of a student’s American Dream Account.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0D67BA9B33341E1AF670F108F3358B7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports and evaluations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3F75FA8EEF664CD4BD83900ECC9DEB7F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the Secretary of Education has disbursed grants under this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Education shall prepare and submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress that includes an evaluation of the effectiveness of the grant program established under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84DCC5FC7A8D423287FDEA96CF6F4A65"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report described in subparagraph (A) shall—</text> <clause id="HAC5A9C2B76E64F01A2576A34862FDD8B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>list the grants that have been awarded under paragraph (2)(A);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H11A13F5EADC94920988A2C39CB0AEA56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include the number of students who have an American Dream Account established through a grant awarded under paragraph (2)(A);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDA1863199E3947C982ADBE070A19D356"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide data (including the interest accrued on college savings accounts that are part of an American Dream Account) in the aggregate, regarding students who have an American Dream Account established through a grant awarded under paragraph (2)(A), as compared to similarly situated students who do not have an American Dream Account;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9C95CE174B2A4D188C2949D60148F73A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>identify best practices developed by the eligible entities receiving grants under this subsection;</text> </clause><clause id="H7D13F04BD97F46E9856ADE67AF83C1E8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>identify any issues related to student privacy and stakeholder accessibility to American Dream Accounts;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAAB1F735610E4FD9A5E24AA825D87432"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>provide feedback from participating students and the parents of such students about the grant program, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H2886163B5B2B450E969A8C33BB199D44"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the impact of the program;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HBEF0A72D4D3D40618A1CD0F715CAAACE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>aspects of the program that are successful;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEBC8629E543A4205902A777CE4C41BAE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>aspects of the program that are not successful; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H6D05F07A12C440ABA0A02A07358EB189"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any other data required by the Secretary of Education; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HBC02E3D692CB4068A9682E251ED4F6F7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>provide recommendations for expanding the American Dream Accounts program.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BB5505FA8AA4EB186689AD28D1339ED"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligibility to receive federal student financial aid</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any funds that are in the college savings account portion of a student’s American Dream Account shall not affect such student’s eligibility to receive Federal student financial aid, including any Federal student financial aid under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>), and shall not be considered in determining the amount of any such Federal student aid.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2647D4F4F72C4097AFF0958B5A4206D6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 480(j) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087vv">20 U.S.C. 1087vv(j)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H5D5950E370DC42739073B4DC1C884873" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HDCE2E1E055D1451FA652B55D29951FCA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), amounts made available under the college savings account portion of an American Dream Account under section 2(e)(4) of the Training Highly Skilled Americans Act of 2015 shall not be treated as estimated financial assistance for purposes of section 471(3).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


