<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1EB46917E4B247BB9101D033F12FA02E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2899 IH: CVE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2899</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Office for Countering Violent
			 Extremism.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7A3A9F3ECE6F492F8A58B6C5ACD1BC97" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1FAB3E44015B45AF960DC4CF44F3F29D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Violent Extremism Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>CVE Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA4382E3705444A5885A4BCDBF456A140"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of the Office for Countering Violent Extremism of the Department of Homeland Security</header> <subsection id="H008138F64E464572B9008D842AE12849"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CAE57CEC3024BCFB4A0D6724D5DE9CA" style="OLC">
					<section id="H96EA0C6C60B344DA844493B791C3FA53"><enum>104.</enum><header>Office for Countering Violent Extremism</header>
 <subsection id="HD8CEAABDF232429EBCB1CE0B22463B65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in the Department an Office for Countering Violent Extremism. The head of the Office shall be the Assistant Secretary for Countering Violent Extremism, who shall be appointed by the Secretary. The Secretary shall also appoint a career Deputy Assistant Secretary for Countering Violent Extremism.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA61AA652A03C402C872401BA2AAB8C8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assignment of personnel</header><text>The Secretary shall assign or hire, as appropriate, permanent staff to the Office for Countering Violent Extremism. In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, seek to assign to or hire for the Office an individual who has a demonstrated background in technical matters, on and offline media, or marketing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3055F53EE16443A3BC077063D9AB6005"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint within each appropriate component and office of the Department, including at a minimum, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, the Office of Privacy, the National Protection and Programs Directorate, the Office of Civil Rights and Civil Liberties, and the Science and Technology Directorate, an individual to serve as liaison to the Office for Countering Violent Extremism.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD8AF4FC4D5254F25B1741F3F6E8193C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Countering Violent Extremism shall be responsible for the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC51F662A63E94EB58D6B659142348D33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Coordinating the Department’s efforts to counter violent extremism across all the components and offices of the Department that conduct strategic and supportive efforts to counter violent extremism. Such efforts shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF2EB7F8EC3854D6482F6839261E6F7BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying risk factors that contribute to violent extremism in communities in the United States and potential remedies for Government and non-government institutions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H191F087C91B647BD9F1E3E7A4065C899"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identifying populations targeted by violent extremist propaganda, messaging, or recruitment.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1A695CDF37F44539A5D759607F0136E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Managing the outreach and engagement efforts of the Department directed toward communities at risk for radicalization and recruitment for violent extremist activities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11A67E826135487BA0B894549A356ADD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ensuring relevant information, research, and products inform efforts to counter violent extremism.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC799A04152E2416CBE842E8DAEF7E4D6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Developing and maintaining a Department-wide strategy guiding policies and programs to counter violent extremism. Such strategy shall, at a minimum, address each of the following:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HA8012A076C9B4BC29731AF4B822C6FC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Department’s counter-messaging program pursuant to paragraph (2), including a plan to leverage new and existing Internet and other technologies and social media platforms to counter violent extremism, as well as the best practices and lessons learned of other Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, and foreign partners engaged in similar counter-messaging efforts.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H90A5264E43ED44BF965A4B1E845F4E56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Department’s countering violent extremism-related engagement efforts.</text> </clause><clause id="H65EC011F34C14530B8F6A0D544639EBB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The use of cooperative agreements with State, local, tribal, territorial, and other Federal departments and agencies responsible for efforts relating to countering violent extremism.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB81D0F72416D4C1498F4D8DB658AFF9F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Ensuring all activities related to countering violent extremism fully respect the privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties of all Americans.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB963A0404BF942D58F19F8D915A2B423"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying and recommending new research and analysis requirements in coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology and the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis and ensure the dissemination of information and methods for Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial countering violent extremism practitioners, officials, law enforcement, and non-governmental partners to utilize such research and analysis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE06909761D8F48C6958D303B763FCAAF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Assessing the methods used by violent extremists to disseminate propaganda and messaging to communities at risk for radicalization and recruitment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H61B9609D4E054C83BE92FDB2CEE2F506"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establishing a counter-messaging program to craft strategic counter-messages to the propaganda and messaging referred to in subparagraph (G) of paragraph (1) which shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6FD5FB5DEBC34747BA603B6AF8E17418"><enum>(A)</enum><text>explore ways to utilize relevant Internet and other technologies and social media platforms; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A8B2E4D8B3A480B9FF8282BB6BB69C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maximize other resources available to the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EBAB701B4BF4FA6BF6089CBDA624505"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Serving as the primary representative of the Department in coordinating countering violent extremism efforts with other Federal departments and agencies and non-governmental organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4E7339567614D939BA04D12FF549813"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Serving as the primary Department-level representative in coordinating with the Department of State on international countering violent extremism issues.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF15E53CD436462381D9EF7946AFF93E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, providing guidance regarding the use of grants made to State, local, and tribal governments under sections 2003 and 2004 under the allowable uses guidelines related to countering violent extremism.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8CA6E78618B643F4A69603DFC8EBEDD2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Countering Violent Extremism shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency outlining the roles of the Assistant Secretary and the Administrator with respect to the administration of grants under sections 2003 and 2004 related to countering violent extremism.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13C2103F3E0D4486BBA64F97A388F06E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Countering Violent Extremism shall submit to Congress an annual report for each of the next five fiscal years (beginning in the fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this section) on the Office for Countering Violent Extremism. Each such report shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9C0EB17B1371429F8DBE44E53AA52464"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the status of the programs and policies of the Department for countering violent extremism in the United States, including the budget of the Department for countering violent extremism and the number of full-time employees dedicated to countering violent extremism programs, as well as the number of part-time employees supporting countering violent extremism programs. Each such budget shall include an accounting of all funding amounts for all departmental programs, initiatives, and personnel related to countering violent extremism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD347762FD2E94A47AE019C0F2ABDA25E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the efforts of the Office to cooperate with and provide assistance to other departments and agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H457561CB756D47FEACBA493DD1C2CBB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Qualitative and quantitative metrics for evaluating the success of such programs and policies and the steps taken to evaluate the success of such programs and policies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4A3AB93876D434B9EF3B638520A781F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A detailed summary of the organizations with which the Department conducted outreach to discuss countering violent extremism, an accounting of grants awarded by the Department to counter violent extremism, and an accounting of all training specifically aimed at countering violent extremism sponsored by the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF919D381BDB744C09EE572F84991EB01"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Details of the optimal level of personnel and funding for the Office.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74AA5204493444698967F3A2583081D7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Violent extremism defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>violent extremism</quote> means ideologically motivated terrorist activities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDE64F0A1084D41A3B9024EE795EC78EA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of funding</header><text>Out of funds made available to the Office of the Secretary, $10,000,000 is authorized for the Office for Countering Violent Extremism for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB42496614ECF47BFA6C8D8484D6CC3BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 103 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9333C48A60B4C95896084ACB030EDA9" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 104. Office for Countering Violent Extremism.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


