<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H322907E849D0400EA46AA41665D3DBAF" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2927 IH: To authorize Hispanic-serving institutions receiving grants under part A of title V of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to use such grant amounts to assist students in entering medical schools, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2927</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001055">Mr. Heck of Nevada</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize Hispanic-serving institutions receiving grants under part A of title V of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to use such grant amounts to assist students in entering medical schools, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H4C1666C4EB334359B4C27FD5E8F247D3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H216CF363A10D4DC59D18E51C5E0DEDE9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authorized grant activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 503 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101b">20 U.S.C. 1101b(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC6BE9A9E6B514D3997F5C1D6C6BBFEF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by inserting before the period at the end the following; <quote>and student support programs designed to facilitate the successful advancement from four-year institutions to an allopathic or osteopathic medical school accredited by a nationally recognized accrediting agency or association recognized by the Secretary pursuant to part H of title IV</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4AD912AC89847ED9ECD054FCC3FE43F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (16) and paragraph (17); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BAD6571FC074ED4AA0AA2E33A94D182"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (15) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1C80FAFA3437475490306C35A60E13AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HABF1B369E16E48E9A76B09961D072A4C"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing counseling, mentoring, and other support services for underrepresented students studying in pre-medical or other health and science fields designed to facilitate their successful application to an allopathic or osteopathic medical school accredited by a nationally recognized accrediting agency or association recognized by the Secretary pursuant to part H of title IV.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

