<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H43968B2C5096498CA0AE8D6BC6749C12" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2589 IH: To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission to publish on its Internet website changes to the rules of the Commission not later than 24 hours after adoption.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2589</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150601">June 1, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission to publish on its Internet website changes to the rules of the Commission not later than 24 hours after adoption.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H1344A302282F474180F77D96DC4F9B41" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB8A3674F791F4F6F82892BA1CC6E1672" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Timely availability of changes to rules of the Commission</header> 
<subsection id="H61588BA01C324E489D9DECF69CD94C44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/154">47 U.S.C. 154</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H55CF2DC0CC394BF4B28CF78D11AD76E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HFC329FFFF84641FCAFF6BCA182418FEB"><enum>(p)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 hours after adopting a provision that will appear in the Code of Federal Regulations, or an amendment to or repeal of a provision that appears in the Code of Federal Regulations, the Commission shall publish on the Internet website of the Commission the text of the provision adopted or repealed, or the text indicating how the provision is being amended, as the case may be. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H41E7C63F9C1B4C17982F3C104F1297F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to a provision, or an amendment to or repeal of a provision, that is adopted after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

