<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H510B469CE2524E6BB8ED2146215220C1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 895 IH: Native Hawaiian Education Reauthorization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 895</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150211">February 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000473">Mr. Takai</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding Native Hawaiian education.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7066789A01F644A98759C52DF16DCCDE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3D78D529760D4EE5AFA0F58FE2B174E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Native Hawaiian Education Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H28706BDADDD5497F8ED02D95C43BAD05"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7202 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7512">20 U.S.C. 7512</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A7559C4496848FDBCC0D55F031E22D5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4A6AF841C35742EBA47059E28195E01D"><enum>7202.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H913A69A2E6974ED2B7F132E6EFB9D48E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Native Hawaiians are a distinct and unique indigenous people with a historical continuity to the original inhabitants of the Hawaiian archipelago, whose society was organized as a nation and internationally recognized as a nation by the United States, the United Kingdom, France, and Japan, as evidenced by treaties governing friendship, commerce, and navigation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEF3C2DCF9604925A632639E412896D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States has recognized and reaffirmed that—</text> <subparagraph id="H9730486805284729824D145E9B4A103B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Native Hawaiians have a cultural, historic, and land-based link to the indigenous people who exercised sovereignty over the Hawaiian Islands, and that group has never relinquished its claims to sovereignty or its sovereign lands;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H350CA02749AA4E0F9B84BFE4FDE7A956"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States furnishes services to Native Hawaiians because of their unique status as the indigenous people of a once sovereign nation with whom the United States has established a trust relationship;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79C2CA2E87DA4AC18CFAD9CF502CBD88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Congress has also delegated broad authority to administer a portion of the Federal trust responsibility to the State of Hawaii;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18D22F7CDC9B450684A0E5A771862B01"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the political status of Native Hawaiians is comparable to that of American Indians and Alaska Natives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2E28A1E4F3D4B32BADF0E05C5853D8F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the aboriginal, indigenous people of the United States have—</text> <clause id="H5876C6FE5F3545CEB5B109EDF6A53636"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a continuing right to autonomy in their internal affairs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H21B5B6A95E90402C82BA23DFEF86D921"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an ongoing right of self-determination and self-governance that has never been extinguished.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BDF7CBA77354A1FA48CB8CB5202B3C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The political relationship between the United States and the Native Hawaiian people has been recognized and reaffirmed by the United States, as evidenced by the inclusion of Native Hawaiians in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D10D3A3686D44BB88258F4E6E76E998"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2991">42 U.S.C. 2991 et seq.</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09889296857E4553B0EE53401DA02FF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Public Law 95–341 (commonly known as the <term>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</term> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0A9255707F04995B9D9D97EB6E5B26F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Museum of the American Indian Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/80q">20 U.S.C. 80q et seq.</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAACF69DCE5F54EBDAF2A0398F13103FE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDFFAC5200874B40930E6995AAF38F62"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the National Historic Preservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/470">16 U.S.C. 470 et seq.</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36F88CF2768F4BD2A283D77504A37650"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2901">25 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA721026746EF422BB510AFBB8EC70E5B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian Culture and Art Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/4401">20 U.S.C. 4401 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C9D08695F564A748F5E6BA5E2516CAF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/128">Public Law 113–128</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF6F746C7E294A8C853F61AB86FCB99C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3001">42 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H850A916F4BBA4D9DACB2359F75DA10D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 1993, 2005, 2009, and 2014, the Kamehameha Schools Bishop Estate released the findings of the Native Hawaiian Educational Assessment Project, which found that despite the successes of the programs established under title IV of the Augustus F. Hawkins-Robert T. Stafford Elementary and Secondary School Improvement Amendments of 1988, many of the same educational needs still existed for Native Hawaiians. Subsequent reports by the Kamehameha Schools Bishop Estate and other organizations have found—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H56F0FD3947F340B2A4197CBAACA95991"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Native Hawaiian students continue to begin their school experience lagging behind other students in terms of readiness factors such as vocabulary test scores;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAB3D3723E54436F919D05EF4EE5E975"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Native Hawaiian students continue to score below the State average and national norms on standardized education achievement tests at all grade levels, despite gradually increasing Native Hawaiian achievement scores and a narrowing of gaps between Native Hawaiian and non-Native Hawaiian students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E8B13AAA0B540D2A5C382299CFA2A07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lower percentages of Native Hawaiian students are represented in the uppermost achievement levels and in gifted and talented programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD8F7338E49041E49B76653BA8ED34B0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Native Hawaiian students continue to be overrepresented among students qualifying for special education programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5E460761ED84FDF8DF02CAAD3DC8987"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Native Hawaiians continue to be underrepresented in institutions of higher education and among adults who have completed 4 or more years of college; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H795E55CACB9E47408FA5CA2DD53F5FF6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Native Hawaiians continue to be disproportionately represented in many negative social and physical statistics indicative of special educational needs, such as student absence rates and family poverty rates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE6CCF4E33D24BB299A93E207FDADF1C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of Native Hawaiian students served by the State of Hawaii Department of Education has risen from 20 percent in 1980 to 28 percent in 2011, and there are, and will continue to be, geographically rural, isolated areas with a high Native Hawaiian population density.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF088172D675B45A5BDB219398F1D9832"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Despite the consequences of more than 100 years of nonindigenous influence, the Native Hawaiian people are determined to preserve, develop, and transmit to future generations their ancestral territory and their cultural identity, in accordance with their own spiritual and traditional beliefs, customs, practices, language, and social institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8F2A090E20C44B3B85D4C2812DC7BB6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The State of Hawaii, in the constitution and statutes of the State of Hawaii—</text> <subparagraph id="H0EC7CE91E2F24F8F81ADACBF7F5E2736"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reaffirms and protects the unique right of the Native Hawaiian people to practice and perpetuate their culture and religious customs, beliefs, practices, and language;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF9B7EBCA86E4F30B3A2825B4A5EB2C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recognizes the traditional language of the Native Hawaiian people as an official language of the State of Hawaii, which may be used as the language of instruction for all subjects and grades in the public school system; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB843659440C148539C44296F5A55EBAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promotes the study of the Hawaiian culture, language, and history by providing a Hawaiian education program and using community expertise as a suitable and essential means to further the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H5BDB18A604E246718E47CADC71166B69"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7203 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7513">20 U.S.C. 7513</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD972665691AD48D288C4C3AAC69758C3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H99B1290E58004184B61B5E87F086735C"><enum>7203.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this part are—</text> <paragraph id="H35CC1775C6BB402AA6AB37FB0F8CBDE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to authorize, develop, implement, assess, and evaluate innovative educational programs, Native Hawaiian language medium programs, Native Hawaiian culture-based education programs, and other education programs to improve the academic achievement of Native Hawaiian students by meeting their unique cultural and language needs in order to help such students meet challenging State student academic achievement standards;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F83E27C9E854B89BB32537963872AD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide guidance to appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies to more effectively and efficiently focus resources, including resources made available under this part, on the development and implementation of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H206D04CC270A423B917BC0A3D17B5C45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>innovative educational programs for Native Hawaiians;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE98EC165BD1C48E19C8808CE3C50CDB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rigorous and substantive Native Hawaiian language programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H355E46E88AD54A7ABAEE1A24D9C07EA9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Native Hawaiian culture-based educational programs; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C19EAFF6A444A3B5206D3A91B273BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to create a system by which information from programs funded under this part will be collected, analyzed, evaluated, reported, and used in decisionmaking activities regarding the types of grants awarded under this part.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HD9918F4FA0974B5F868344AA70311CEA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Native Hawaiian Education Council grant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7204 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7514">20 U.S.C. 7514</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EC5CE17C432403BA331AB8709BB1D35" style="OLC">
				<section id="H10C3E97320524738923719A401F130B4"><enum>7204.</enum><header>Native Hawaiian Education Council grant</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HBD4066C401F44B3CB1617BE3DE462384"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant Authorized</header><text>In order to better effectuate the purposes of this part through the coordination of educational and related services and programs available to Native Hawaiians, including those programs that receive funding under this part, the Secretary shall award a grant to an education council, as described under subsection (b).</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HE59A97C9E08E4C14902CEF2745AED629"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Education Council</header>
 <paragraph id="H7FB74C92A33F4D379F2E56824683FE3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive the grant under subsection (a), the council shall be an education council (referred to in this section as the <term>Education Council</term>) that meets the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6716C146D7F44E284BEC1BB481B5443"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Education Council shall consist of 15 members of whom—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FBF54B44BF74CD7BE3F111C524436AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 shall be the President of the University of Hawaii (or a designee);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB99CEFAF2A044189870D7C6809284EFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 shall be the Governor of the State of Hawaii (or a designee);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0AF71C531C545BBBEB4561C243DEA2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 shall be the Superintendent of the State of Hawaii Department of Education (or a designee);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8865800B74114A5BB14FA92FA1B5D233"><enum>(D)</enum><text>1 shall be the chairperson of the Office of Hawaiian Affairs (or a designee);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69B4A1C3C30F4FC3A28CC23A57F24393"><enum>(E)</enum><text>1 shall be the executive director of Hawaii’s Charter School Network (or a designee);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ED28439B4A94E3397116630ABDAD56A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>1 shall be the chief executive officer of the Kamehameha Schools (or a designee);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A2F0BDAC56F47E6BEE0818969EB0DD6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>1 shall be the Chief Executive Officer of the Queen Liliuokalani Trust (or a designee);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H898ECE8C4207498285F8CF6BA95DF227"><enum>(H)</enum><text>1 shall be a member, selected by the other members of the Education Council, who represents a private grant-making entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01CF49AB8C6045AEBDE2C4E96E10AA88"><enum>(I)</enum><text>1 shall be the Mayor of the County of Hawaii (or a designee);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF834ABE7798A44E7B3E9EFEEAE08BF6B"><enum>(J)</enum><text>1 shall be the Mayor of Maui County (or a designee from the Island of Maui);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F47D35688AA4B0081CC6939E0765921"><enum>(K)</enum><text>1 shall be the Mayor of the County of Kauai (or a designee);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAF9189CE15A4189A76DFD50CFB9A221"><enum>(L)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the Mayor of Maui County from the Island of either Molokai or Lanai;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CBDEAEDC9C64C819527CE6EF4DA199D"><enum>(M)</enum><text>1 shall be the Mayor of the City and County of Honolulu (or a designee);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BEA4FD0BE574BB0973056E6F1CF7E39"><enum>(N)</enum><text>1 shall be the chairperson of the Hawaiian Homes Commission (or a designee); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9CC8EF176CF4FF79164E2F7B82F1F03"><enum>(O)</enum><text>1 shall be the chairperson of the Hawaii Workforce Development Council (or a designee representing the private sector).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB4A6EE66579347EE94B653D71625DCBD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Any designee serving on the Education Council shall demonstrate, as determined by the individual who appointed such designee with input from the Native Hawaiian community, not less than 5 years of experience as a consumer or provider of Native Hawaiian education or cultural activities, with traditional cultural experience given due consideration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE694F28B32E344EF976DF21E360D65AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A member (including a designee), while serving on the Education Council, shall not be a recipient of grant funds that are awarded under this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6642CE3442924BF59CD0B927E4437B5E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Term of members</header><text>A member who is a designee shall serve for a term of not more than 4 years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F8C971B0C3B45DC9E9531408166D233"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Chair, vice chair</header> <subparagraph id="H3C4E3A220AA646AA97DE10BC33F3237A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Education Council shall select a Chair and a Vice Chair from among the members of the Education Council.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2362F0068BD94817B1DF6F97B2370359"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term limits</header><text>The Chair and Vice Chair shall each serve for a 2-year term.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9455EE443920434C8FBEA0DDA0D6FEE8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Administrative provisions relating to education council</header><text>The Education Council shall meet at the call of the Chair of the Council, or upon request by a majority of the members of the Education Council, but in any event not less often than every 120 days.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB31C45C98BC43C7BAEF1B309D61909D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>No compensation</header><text>None of the funds made available through the grant may be used to provide compensation to any member of the Education Council or member of a working group established by the Education Council, for functions described in this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H502E694A011E453B8880C5C9F5422114"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of Funds for Coordination Activities</header><text>The Education Council shall use funds made available through the grant to carry out each of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C6D2C3E14D948AA936D3ACEC5F01137"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Providing advice about the coordination, and serving as a clearinghouse for, the educational and related services and programs available to Native Hawaiians, including the programs assisted under this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H282113F35D6D47E986801AB638257C17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assessing the extent to which such services and programs meet the needs of Native Hawaiians, and collecting data on the status of Native Hawaiian education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H803226A23B4A4D429A931A92A48D9F14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing direction and guidance, through the issuance of reports and recommendations, to appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies in order to focus and improve the use of resources, including resources made available under this part, relating to Native Hawaiian education, and serving, where appropriate, in an advisory capacity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H62A9E5B173F947FE9308A57267686E84"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Awarding grants, if such grants enable the Education Council to carry out the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C02F286C3A9467AA12BB58982B9C048"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Hiring an executive director who shall assist in executing the duties and powers of the Education Council, as described in subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9F47D0835484F13B1FB756E2A6877A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of Funds for Technical Assistance</header><text>The Education Council shall use funds made available through the grant to—</text> <paragraph id="H7637F371D46741729B3F6CB82EA0DDD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to Native Hawaiian organizations that are grantees or potential grantees under this part;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2818A231CE841B28853FF0179E614CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>obtain from such grantees information and data regarding grants awarded under this part, including information and data about—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H51468DEC4E5C4F6F96C4D30BB240465E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of such grantees in meeting the educational priorities established by the Education Council, as described in paragraph (6)(D), using metrics related to these priorities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H269D52744E194FBC9CAD9D254B113E91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effectiveness of such grantees in carrying out any of the activities described in section 7205(c) that are related to the specific goals and purposes of each grantee’s grant project, using metrics related to these priorities;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F813FFD997146A08FDD759C7E927079"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess and define the educational needs of Native Hawaiians;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CA547CFAA4349998398B99ADF457C06"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assess the programs and services available to address the educational needs of Native Hawaiians;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB18F3DD30394DA0831F4641C62F8E40"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess and evaluate the individual and aggregate impact achieved by grantees under this part in improving Native Hawaiian educational performance and meeting the goals of this part, using metrics related to these goals; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC725FB123F2A4F269012B1B2A9F57830"><enum>(6)</enum><text>prepare and submit to the Secretary, at the end of each calendar year, an annual report that contains—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBA8F03C380294AB6A62F1770F3C363AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the activities of the Education Council during the calendar year;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9879E1A34FE3405AB0A85900C806A94A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of significant barriers to achieving the goals of this part;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC50160707C4F4E5C84E8FE7E94FFCD7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a summary of each community consultation session described in subsection (e); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD01EE3B239E84CC8A423CFBB1B762884"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations to establish priorities for funding under this part, based on an assessment of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HC37B76DE3C64425CA1F289A27009E248"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the educational needs of Native Hawaiians;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H4523234949AF4E9CB075286EA6D4974A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>programs and services available to address such needs;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H84BF7CD608B643E7B118F8537BCABE60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of programs in improving the educational performance of Native Hawaiian students to help such students meet challenging State student academic achievement standards; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5D866913D5114D788BCC0B9FECD43B2A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>priorities for funding in specific geographic communities.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H134E5509E7214AAE8E0ACBB840593905"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of Funds for Community consultations</header><text>The Education Council shall use funds made available though the grant under subsection (a) to hold not less than 1 community consultation each year on each of the islands of Hawaii, Maui, Molokai, Lanai, Oahu, and Kauai, at which—</text>
 <paragraph id="H30DB2650585B4310B5FB2252E73101CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than 3 members of the Education Council shall be in attendance;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H50E2141326534A8684639D86344048FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Education Council shall gather community input regarding—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD48480ABD15A412E944011E69E5A8A3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>current grantees under this part, as of the date of the consultation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H498699B174764192AFDA086D72963305"><enum>(B)</enum><text>priorities and needs of Native Hawaiians; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D71E25AAC2D42B2ABCD575C02642B09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other Native Hawaiian education issues; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB90787BE3D7E4B7B90654DB9EAC3E6BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Education Council shall report to the community on the outcomes of the activities supported by grants awarded under this part.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27EBB077701240DFA35A2F512E17CF89"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>For each fiscal year, the Secretary shall use the amount described in section 7206(d)(2), to make a payment under the grant. Funds made available through the grant shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA0D943431EE4958B5DC4E68BF4AE568"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Beginning not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Native Hawaiian Education Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title>, and for each subsequent year, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Indian Affairs and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H05A302436EFE42FCB701927F67CA3B43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes the annual reports of the Education Council;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A3C6A85632C4356BEBEE65BDD432C4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the allocation and use of funds under this part and the information gathered since the first annual report submitted by the Education Council to the Secretary under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F0682C6B62C4605ACC091F169FDE1A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contains recommendations for changes in Federal, State, and local policy to advance the purposes of this part.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H53086C66B6E14D148C6A231ECB4A939D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7205 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7515">20 U.S.C. 7515</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BE6038529DB4C76980B69F0B92227DD" style="OLC">
				<section id="H1FC954034FD14F50969CF4012E1E5BA9"><enum>7205.</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header>
 <subsection id="HBFC2334083D647EFA13CF29ACF3F0DBD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants and contracts</header><text>In order to carry out programs that meet the purposes of this part, the Secretary is authorized to award grants to, or enter into contracts with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H39BC2A3A28D14ED39740A41076E1286B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Native Hawaiian educational organizations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H25CE22E481B4423CA12CEBAAD00ABD2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Native Hawaiian community-based organizations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE221E5DBFE42434C9F5C19D0945E39F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>public and private nonprofit organizations, agencies, and institutions with experience in developing or operating Native Hawaiian education and workforce development programs or programs of instruction in the Native Hawaiian language;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF28F1975597546FABFC852030F450E88"><enum>(4)</enum><text>charter schools; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC130AE2D19FA4198A36748F549578741"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consortia of the organizations, agencies, and institutions described in paragraphs (1) through (4).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H639CDD681A0A4CB0A7AA6BB2894086F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants and entering into contracts under this part, the Secretary shall give priority to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H94B5834787FB42199D47F561E45AC4B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>programs that meet the educational priority recommendations of the Education Council, as described under section 7204(d)(6)(D);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8954715E158A4457885F80CD580D17B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the repair and renovation of public schools that serve high concentrations of Native Hawaiian students;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE73C2D6C82F4D83A0F6BA0A884A69DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>programs designed to improve the academic achievement of Native Hawaiian students by meeting their unique cultural and language needs in order to help such students meet challenging State student academic achievement standards, including activities relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBC90F370C7284B51871DFED555CE9ABE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>achieving competence in reading, literacy, mathematics, and science for students in preschool through grade 3;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B99478C42A84FDD90082203BFD9C8F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the educational needs of at-risk children and youth;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67A2FC9CADFC457BAD85F60E581B29D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>professional development for teachers and administrators;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12FE5C7255F0471EB54BFA25616B479D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the use of Native Hawaiian language and preservation or reclamation of Native Hawaiian culture-based educational practices;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8B981A95E1F482488D262D3884C0682"><enum>(E)</enum><text>preparation for employment in fields in which Native Hawaiians are underemployed or underrepresented; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H870CBB8B3FC84743BB54C4219233AA2F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other programs relating to the activities described in this part; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2FB301D1659475B88AA580C22F58187"><enum>(4)</enum><text>programs in which a State educational agency, local educational agency, institution of higher education, or a State educational agency or local educational agency in partnership with an institution of higher education applies for a grant or contract under this part as part of a partnership or consortium.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5854949017E24148B5A2A2D4938E0F0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>Activities provided through programs carried out under this part may include—</text> <paragraph id="HCEAB5D26CBDE4F2AA28A6A1411736154"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development and maintenance of a statewide Native Hawaiian early education and care system to provide a continuum of high-quality early learning services for Native Hawaiian children from the prenatal period through the age of kindergarten entry;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F39A605A04244D88405CF44B967D3BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the operation of family-based education centers that provide such services as—</text> <subparagraph id="H387FE2CC6EFD4C109639F5FAD3058F3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>programs for Native Hawaiian parents and infants from the prenatal period through age 3;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78F586AB37664928A3F7C91AE6FDB35B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>early care and education programs for Native Hawaiians; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA49C1F42CE04305A6B1A2DC4EFA95ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>research on, and development and assessment of, family-based, early childhood, and preschool programs for Native Hawaiians;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E1A27F1FE6B4E78BCF0BBD330E1D8C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>activities that enhance beginning reading and literacy in either the Hawaiian or the English language among Native Hawaiian students in kindergarten through grade 3 and assistance in addressing the distinct features of combined English and Hawaiian literacy for Hawaiian speakers in grades 5 and 6;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA77DF407DDBC469CAA4FDB5BE1ED96EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>activities to meet the special needs of Native Hawaiian students with disabilities, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4FA9EFB0FBD4E69B883087A72894AF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the identification of such students and their needs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD4E1C4E35CF4F6DB86B74F21C2F33A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of support services to the families of such students; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E66FD5065D2419EB693C217A80DDA79"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other activities consistent with the requirements of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32858DA2EF1B44E78584828BB12E3183"><enum>(5)</enum><text>activities that address the special needs of Native Hawaiian students who are gifted and talented, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H965A15F7644D4C46BC9A15DAF0CDA75D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educational, psychological, and developmental activities designed to assist in the educational progress of such students; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0580496AFF4430487F0A36DC8FB7D50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>activities that involve the parents of such students in a manner designed to assist in the educational progress of such students;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H475A20C1CEB5438F9D7E7AC9E38A0F3D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the development of academic and vocational curricula to address the needs of Native Hawaiian children and adults, including curricula materials in the Hawaiian language and mathematics and science curricula that incorporate Native Hawaiian tradition and culture;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C611800067A455F956367D01FCD371E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>professional development activities for educators, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H6A6DC50AE51D43E1ADEDB695C447FD39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of programs to prepare prospective teachers to address the unique needs of Native Hawaiian students within the context of Native Hawaiian culture, language, and traditions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE930F512F7A4F7E90A7C451BF9FAEE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in-service programs to improve the ability of teachers who teach in schools with high concentrations of Native Hawaiian students to meet the unique needs of such students; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDBC129D66EF4A80A814C47027D95EE7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the recruitment and preparation of Native Hawaiians, and other individuals who live in communities with a high concentration of Native Hawaiians, to become teachers;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H837899C49E5B4B72A8864C18A9EDCA11"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the operation of community-based learning centers that address the needs of Native Hawaiian families and communities through the coordination of public and private programs and services, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC6BE655342644B19E0F8B8D3F2E305B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>early care and education programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF90FBED928814B80857C11AE2C1BDFBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before- and after-school programs and weekend academies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3528383C9BAB4AAEB4583C61F420E054"><enum>(C)</enum><text>career and technical and adult education programs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C1E9B76A99B4A2E9175ED0A19EE9403"><enum>(D)</enum><text>programs that recognize and support the unique cultural and educational needs of Native Hawaiian children, and incorporate appropriately qualified Native Hawaiian elders and seniors;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB249818D00954730A39EFC9741BAD22A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>activities, including program co-location, to enable Native Hawaiians to enter and complete programs of postsecondary education, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFA600913440A497EAE6D148A4952DA03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to subsection (f), the provision of full or partial scholarships for undergraduate or graduate study that are awarded to students based on their academic promise and financial need, with a priority, at the graduate level, given to students entering professions in which Native Hawaiians are underrepresented;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB510ABD19F09431787492AC32573088E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family literacy services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72950B4D3F6849408F7B7E08974804CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>counseling and support services for students receiving scholarship assistance;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCF9674AEA944656B7256864776C29D2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>counseling and guidance for Native Hawaiian secondary school students who have the potential to receive scholarships;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8F7183B17D047638A05ABD7B00FA6D1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assistance with completing the college admissions and financial aid application processes; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA33C9E1C1BF54568B14C501F8054E9E1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>faculty development activities designed to promote the matriculation of Native Hawaiian students;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C5BFF73AB2E493A8A237C6803FFAD56"><enum>(10)</enum><text>research and data collection activities to determine the educational status and needs of Native Hawaiian children and adults;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67598AD03EB74A8990986B8E908D6676"><enum>(11)</enum><text>other research and evaluation activities related to programs carried out under this part; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8925AFCC2F6460D8A673137237D034B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>other activities, consistent with the purposes of this part, to meet the educational needs of Native Hawaiian children and adults.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC02853D0C75243D6A14998F55A5CFE9C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional activities</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, funds made available to carry out this section as of the day before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Native Hawaiian Education Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title> shall remain available until expended. The Secretary shall use such funds to support the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB85933A625AE4E9A99EF59A01E8D0D07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The development of a body of Native Hawaiian law.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF0FBAF7F5674DF3BF9B75158C4C8590"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The repair and renovation of public schools that serve high concentrations of Native Hawaiian students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H679763B778D2463B99B557BA360C04FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The perpetuation of, and expansion of access to, Hawaiian culture and history through digital archives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4D95BA9CF3374607AA04692D40961232"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Informal education programs that connect traditional Hawaiian knowledge, science, astronomy, and the environment through State museums or learning centers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF0AC400B38D64251AB8D041C7A4F600D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Public charter schools serving high concentrations of Native Hawaiian students.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34C546D86046482AAED8292D041870CE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header> <paragraph id="HA76D0838F8F74F3D8D77D3A94A645332"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), not more than 5 percent of funds provided to a recipient of a grant or contract under this section for any fiscal year may be used for administrative purposes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADF85E7EF72647BCBAF048B9379F1488"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary may waive the requirement of paragraph (1) for a nonprofit entity that receives funding under this section and allow not more than 10 percent of funds provided to such nonprofit entity under this section for any fiscal year to be used for administrative purposes.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA39F220816834FAE9510BE5F1D47882E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Scholarship rule and conditions</header>
 <paragraph id="HF79ED51525F646118A98E7B107A0F3D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scholarship conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall establish conditions for receipt of a scholarship awarded under subsection (c)(9)(A). The conditions shall require that an individual seeking such a scholarship enter into a contract to provide professional services to the Native Hawaiian community, either during the scholarship period or upon completion of a program of postsecondary education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB08021DE5094B9ABED31EF73ED2CD90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institutions outside Hawaii</header><text>The Secretary shall not establish a policy under this section that prevents a Native Hawaiian student enrolled at a 2- or 4-year degree-granting institution of higher education outside of the State of Hawaii from receiving a scholarship pursuant to subsection (c)(9)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HC33C4DC0B30D420CAAD9C2BD0668654D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Administrative provisions; authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7206 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7516">20 U.S.C. 7516</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49951A74885C434B9A872876801B5C98" style="OLC">
				<section id="H6C2FDB9ACC964576880809E4CE6201D5"><enum>7206.</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header>
 <subsection id="HDE1805F57C7B4CC1B5689CD8A2DAA4DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application required</header><text>No grant may be made under this part, and no contract may be entered into under this part, unless the entity seeking the grant or contract submits an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may determine to be necessary to carry out the provisions of this part.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4D333E9E3F1D44DFB90127DED6B7A0A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direct grant applications</header><text>The Secretary shall provide a copy of all direct grant applications to the Education Council.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HE3A550370C0B4F26B837DBF8D08B08EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header> <paragraph id="HE723893EA6F443A38F4C2FD81D0041E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), funds made available under this part shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, any State or local funds used to achieve the purposes of this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB1D5936CFF740789EFA08D9184C7FC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any nonprofit entity or Native Hawaiian community-based organization that receives a grant or other funds under this part.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H110126072CAA4D22956AA1B563242F99"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8823204DE8D34D149A3FAFFE54F5D7CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, and sections 7204 and 7205, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2016 and each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H423C35D9098748CE913AE4DF31FA8BB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>Of the funds appropriated under this subsection, the Secretary shall reserve, for each fiscal year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Native Hawaiian Education Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title> not less than $500,000 for the grant to the Education Council under section 7204.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5A7122E2C1C4238A7F83591DA9A00AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Funds appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="H1DEA269F83844EA9AF727C51587A211C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7207 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7517">20 U.S.C. 7517</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCA761BA8DA024FFD9F8168DD95F8329A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (6) as paragraphs (2) through (7), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF4D8EEF1B44445FB6B7B04CC80C8D16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) (as redesignated by paragraph (1)) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H337F4765ACCC48C884B720E6A8E39163" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H12BEFA74036F48D1BE7A644288F556D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community consultation</header><text>The term <term>community consultation</term> means a public gathering—</text> <subparagraph id="H9B6C88E0AF9847ABBA2725A38F88FB90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to discuss Native Hawaiian education concerns; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CD81F1029554AC8AD35B484875D6FD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>about which the public has been given not less than 30 days notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

