<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1029B9542A2645A38F3FF8446AAD422B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2557 IH: Promoting New Manufacturing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2557</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001176">Mr. Scalise</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To promote new manufacturing in the United States by providing for greater transparency and
			 timeliness in obtaining necessary permits, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBB20B52352B04DB8A62806F5F59B0C7C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H69B83E1849C54F1ABBFC2140E84F3589" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting New Manufacturing Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H824F05FD23CE4347AC8693EF07ACAFA4"><enum>2.</enum><header> Building and Manufacturing Projects Dashboard</header> <subsection id="H446FEBFB19B144E48A879EEE525D6FE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall, with respect to fiscal year 2008 and each subsequent fiscal year, publish in a readily accessible location on the Environmental Protection Agency’s public Website the Agency’s estimate of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA5E5DBA67DD74C46AC7AE56957A411A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total number of preconstruction permits issued during the fiscal year.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H90A0840024DD4B13BF1332A32773E2E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The percentage of such preconstruction permits issued within one year after the date of filing of a completed application.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF4368476D414D6DBCB2E09FA9F270E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The average length of time for the Agency’s Environmental Appeals Board to issue a final decision on petitions appealing decisions to grant or deny a preconstruction permit application.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB8847789BD04119A3B0F6B5AFD0DECB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial publication; updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8BFF15646A42479EBAB1759E71F50E8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make the publication required by subsection (a) for fiscal years 2008 through 2014 not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4A3AADCAAD341F987CCA6BA2A73D1E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update such publication not less than annually.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7428BEC42E2642A990586C6A6133B952"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sources of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF28282DE1DF84F55AA3E025E78937429"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to information to be published for fiscal years 2008 through 2014, the Environmental Protection Agency’s estimates shall be based on information that is in the Agency’s possession as of the date of enactment of this Act, including information in the RACT/BACT/LAER Clearinghouse database.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93288645E77D4C0F87B4A81D7BD48FB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to information to be published for any fiscal year, nothing in the section compels the Environmental Protection Agency to seek or collect any information in addition to the information that is voluntarily provided by States and local air agencies for the RACT/BACT/LAER Clearinghouse database.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H49E22243C6DC433BAFD26891FD8A40BE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Timely issuance of regulations and guidance to address new or revised national ambient air quality
			 standards in preconstruction permitting</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H00530D57FCA1462585288127A278EC8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In publishing any final rule establishing or revising a national ambient air quality standard, the Administrator shall, as the Administrator determines necessary and appropriate to assist States, permitting authorities, and permit applicants, concurrently publish regulations and guidance for implementing the standard, including information relating to submission and consideration of a preconstruction permit application under the new or revised standard.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H01FEE08C3C534C26B35E1BFBA0C75425"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of standard to pre­con­struc­tion permitting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator fails to publish final regulations and guidance that include information relating to submission and consideration of a preconstruction permit application under a new or revised national ambient air quality standard concurrently with such standard, then such standard shall not apply to the review and disposition of a preconstruction permit application until the Agency has published such final regulations and guidance.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8591E997EC6547F4B50DCFE0C6E675FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header>
 <paragraph id="H613B5404F3BF446C8A298BEDB4189D7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>After publishing regulations and guidance for implementing national ambient air quality standards under subsection (a), nothing in this section shall preclude the Environmental Protection Agency from issuing subsequent regulations or guidance to assist States and facilities in implementing such standards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AE23637256943319D5F378ADAE45F6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to eliminate the obligation of a preconstruction permit applicant to install best available control technology and lowest achievable emissions rate technology, as applicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC68D27086334F4B9354EDE22B1AEFD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of a State, local, or tribal permitting authority to impose more stringent emissions requirements pursuant to State, local, or tribal law than Federal national ambient air quality standards established by the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEA03DE07E78C4E898AC827F970A85D89"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress on actions to expedite review of preconstruction permits</header>
 <subsection id="H2B6172A684994C54B3D73C524058CC1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFEB703D1E79B4B54AF489C0083CFBE43"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying the activities being undertaken by the Environmental Protection Agency to increase the efficiency of the preconstruction permitting process;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC6C190C41774985AD4CA78B7398A2BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying the specific reasons for delays in issuing—</text> <subparagraph id="H82D2054A63C74F9A944A4DA9A190A2AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preconstruction permits required under part C of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7470">42 U.S.C. 7470 et seq.</external-xref>) beyond the one-year statutory deadline mandated by section 165(c) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7475">42 U.S.C. 7475(c)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F752900F47E461A93A8DFD15F6B4D68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preconstruction permits required under part D of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7501">42 U.S.C. 7501 et seq.</external-xref>) beyond the one-year period beginning on the date on which the permit application is determined to be complete;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H87AC8196D08F4B36A29F4D59BF5B093D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describing how the Agency is resolving delays in making completeness determinations for preconstruction permit applications;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98728D8F3D5B4D4DB18B37B9CBC305C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describing how the Agency is resolving processing delays for preconstruction permits, including any increases in communication with State and local permitting authorities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FD75A64A43F4E539748FA7D4D9BBE1C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>summarizing and responding to public comments concerning the report received under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H190FC8EE3471455D82F5C857934C04C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before submitting each report required by subsection (a), the Administrator shall publish a draft report on the Website of the Environmental Protection Agency and provide the public with a period of at least 30 days to submit comments on the draft report.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H06E35738DB5C49C9A6BB580C0D567412"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sources of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section compels the Environmental Protection Agency to seek or collect any information in addition to the information that is voluntarily provided by States and local air agencies for the RACT/BACT/LAER Clearinghouse database.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0EE5495F04E84C10AA9C90EF1517A3CB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H454C9B2433444ABEAC84F4D0D189BAEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF132EC00E0F4557A721AF4016475B99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Best available control technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>best available control technology</term> has the meaning given to that term in section 169(3) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7479">42 U.S.C. 7479(3)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF12E940E83740D8911327820C625420"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lowest achievable emissions rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lowest achievable emissions rate</term> has the meaning given to that term in section 171(3) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7501">42 U.S.C. 7501(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2478C40AD1445078D2934B98F019526"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Major emitting facility; major stationary source</header><text>The terms <term>major emitting facility</term> and <term>major stationary source</term> have the meaning given to those terms in section 302(j) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7602">42 U.S.C. 7602(j)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H71FCDA6C3A524D34B658F2AD36EB49B6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>National ambient air quality standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national ambient air quality standard</term> means a national ambient air quality standard for an air pollutant under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>) that is finalized on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49C594B2251E47018D4BDE41D15B70D0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Preconstruction permit</header><text>The term <term>preconstruction permit</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4EB48DC4C2C493CB74BD5AD84CF6E99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a permit that is required under part C or D of title I of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7470">42 U.S.C. 7470 et seq.</external-xref>) for the construction or modification of a major emitting facility or major stationary source; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00EB94C68DFC413E9738DBBE7BAAF77E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any such permit issued by the Environmental Protection Agency or a State, local, or tribal permitting authority.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84BCAF6B4BE44E7C8AEEEEC0B6EC8735"><enum>(7)</enum><header>RACT/BACT/LAER Clearinghouse database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>RACT/BACT/LAER Clearinghouse database</term> means the central database of air pollution technology information that is posted on the Environmental Protection Agency’s Website.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


