<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6EC102B8B65A441082C8FD3B93AB36D0" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1280 IH: Skills Connection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1280</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Labor to create a searchable database containing a credentials registry, a skills database, and a jobs bank.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H154D79EA96A340ED9B46364524086195" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1C0032E0E5024BE4BA6325151968AA0E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Skills Connection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H39926BF549A24DE79AFDB639E6CBAD6C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Creation of searchable database</header> <subsection id="HD83BF8D572314853B94D4F3DCD4E4ED9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall create a publicly available, easily navigable, and searchable database containing the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC5A8C779EE4442DA94239ABEBD77212A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A registry of credentials (which may be certificates), for purposes of enabling programs that lead to such a credential to receive priority under a covered provision.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30E5900753E141359C19A41EA89C2C5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A skills database, for purposes of enabling programs that lead to such a credential to receive priority under a covered provision.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H698C44352C9E4B4FAB08AFE72A89EB64"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A jobs bank.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H870E932E326244268F019F865699A716"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credentials registry</header><text>In creating a registry of credentials, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF0205896EE8140F498137908BDD595F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>list the credential in the registry if the credential is required by Federal or State law for an occupation (such as a credential required by a State law regarding qualifications for a health care occupation);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA81461B6751E452B8C622BDB6BFA7436"><enum>(2)</enum><text>list the credential, and list an updated credential, in the registry if the credential involved is an industry-recognized, nationally portable credential that is consistent with the Secretary's established industry competency models and is consistently updated through third party validation to reflect changing industry competencies; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HF108A3508707450C9C2124D85357359D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each credential listed in the registry, provide an assessment of which skills listed in the skills database created under subsection (c) align with or are related to the requirements of the credential.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H821DAA84EBA04D2989FA40D4DCC78F94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Skills database</header><text>In creating a skills database, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H33223A71C8DD4A80A1CC47E187CBAA0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">list identifiable skills that are required for employment in the manufacturing sector, as determined by the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="H2B76D77807C04E72A4737CCDEA7597F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by using the Manufacturing Institute-endorsed Skills Certification System or similar resource; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA832030AB6D04DC8B0D0E81F3C8B4755"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by consulting with an organization similar to the Manufacturing Institute;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6F4EE09A4F3484D885940CB7DADC108"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after consultation with the Manufacturing Institute or similar organization and representatives of the Armed Forces list identifiable skills developed through service in the Armed Forces; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H085D0EE9D22D44E78F696615CCC654FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for each skill listed under paragraphs (1) and (2), include information about how that skill aligns with or is related to the requirements for the credentials listed under the credentials registry created under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H22AF78EEC677416D9488C4F45B280BC8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Jobs bank</header><text>In creating a jobs bank, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8434428DD00F4393A5F06076A87F7C3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enable job seekers to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF193B9E21E9D48988167FD6168706F4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter basic information through the statewide employment statistics system established under section 15 of the Wagner-Peyser Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/49l-2">29 U.S.C. 49l–2</external-xref>) for their State of residence about their skills, experience, credentials, and preferred area of employment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H039E92FF3CE7403D80B89BC7DCF5E6AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">browse job listings submitted by employers to such jobs bank that match the credentials, experience, or other qualifications entered under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F166EF73B4643E2822595C42937FC30"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">automatically match available jobs with job seekers who have matching qualifications; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4040A2E1B5A40FB992929F1CB25E366"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enable information relating to shortages in certain skills or credentials available to be utilized by State workforce investment board established under section 101 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</external-xref>) and others to inform decisions about how to allocate workforce development resources.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDEFD8EB4E8244BEEACFB33669049B2DE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> 
<paragraph id="H422A7415B7B94C5CA89E83D3570B83D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require an entity with responsibility for selecting or approving an education, training, or workforce investment activities program with regard to a covered provision, to select a program with a credential listed in the registry described in subsection (b); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD46C52F6235B433489937AD1F07B7ED5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to be an endorsement of a skill listed under the skills database described in subsection (c) by the Secretary of Labor or the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA17A79BA46B94A27A08CC86D16970DE8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>For each fiscal year, funds shall be available from the amount appropriated for each such fiscal year for the Workforce Innovation Fund established under section 1801(a)(3) of title VIII of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/10">Public Law 112–10</external-xref> for the costs of carrying out the provisions of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAE221A5A49C045FD95FD58548CA74C2D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H780D5CD94B5C4402AD1104C457D7DB10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Armed Forces</term> means the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4D0B0561FBC4C50A2FF6C2C87E3841B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered provision</header><text>The term <term>covered provision</term> means any of sections 129 and 134 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3164">29 U.S.C. 3164</external-xref>, 3174), section 122(c)(1)(B) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2342">20 U.S.C. 2342(c)(1)(B)</external-xref>), and section 236 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2296">19 U.S.C. 2296</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H533A4F9CCACC4427A465BEB322DEEDBC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Industry recognized credential</header><text>The term <term>industry-recognized</term>, used with respect to a credential, means a credential that—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AD1B15A2754405893673EA2A5FBB6E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is sought or accepted by companies within the industry sector involved as recognized, preferred, or required for recruitment, screening, or hiring; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3906D93E6084C22B37A40557A7B00F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is endorsed by a nationally recognized trade association or organization representing a significant part of the industry sector.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DD99BA506EF4FB18D7B041EF7F9F8E7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nationally portable</header><text>The term <term>nationally portable</term>, used with respect to a credential, means a credential that is sought or accepted by companies within the industry sector involved, across multiple States, as recognized, preferred, or required for recruitment, screening, or hiring.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE33BD1E8481D496DA238BD1DA40D321C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56E0BF5036B8406296CDA345CBFBEBC1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Workforce investment activities</header><text>The term <term>workforce investment activities</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


