<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0BA45E70C2EE4933B6ED7DAC3D0FD691" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 290 IH: Creating Access to Rehabilitation for Every Senior (CARES) Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 290</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001055">Mr. Heck of Nevada</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to eliminate the 3-day prior hospitalization
			 requirement for Medicare coverage of skilled nursing facility services in
			 qualified skilled nursing facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H33BFD2EFCFF94EFB94C7976A2556311F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAAAF6C78232A4B3D936D94A3F5D9DB6D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating Access to Rehabilitation for Every Senior (CARES) Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3BD1254BDDCF421E9E5ACB53ED343C9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elimination of Medicare 3-day prior hospitalization requirement for coverage of skilled nursing facility services in qualified skilled nursing facilities</header> <subsection id="H04A24401EE3141A880085A2902010DF5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (f) of section 1812 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395d">42 U.S.C. 1395d</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3567BA72C2948E5AE85F1B36587AD94" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H0E377DE071A143A3997D2703295CEAD8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coverage of extended care services without a 3-Day prior hospitalization for qualified skilled
			 nursing facility</header>
 <paragraph id="H945261E2611E4777B5FA77979DF0B21D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective for extended care services furnished pursuant to an admission to a skilled nursing facility that occurs more than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Creating Access to Rehabilitation for Every Senior (CARES) Act of 2015</short-title>, coverage shall be provided under this part for an individual for such services in a qualified skilled nursing facility that are not post-hospital extended care services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58736E6ECF7E4F0CAB966867AE7A6377"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continued application of certification and other requirements and provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of the following provisions shall apply to extended care services provided under paragraph (1) in the same manner as they apply to post-hospital extended care services:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB42DC7AE9EAD42FBA5DD051D5EC9681F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Paragraphs (2) and (6) of section 1814(a), except that the requirement of paragraph (2)(B) of such section shall not apply insofar as it relates to any required prior receipt of inpatient hospital services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95EEB06ABAC242A2BB9CEEF9510B2BD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subsections (b)(2) and (e) of this section.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96968EC0A80A4F109CB69E81401F2026"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Paragraphs (1)(G)(i), (2)(A), and (3) of section 1861(v).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8B98960CF054C69982A729EC1D2FD5C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 1861(y).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11A474C08E6C4C58A21A73D23FCDB885"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 1862(a)(18).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2ABCE7EF9BA4514897479E50CCDBA5D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 1866(a)(1)(H)(ii)(I).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC96DB0F3CAFE4B0793FB680FEE25A0E9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Subsections (d) and (f) of section 1883.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0773CC3A196E4BC196E0670CC0B7CAE2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Section 1888(e).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B8B326DE4B94629A9833ED32AEBD0D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified skilled nursing facility defined</header> <subparagraph id="HC2B9E710661947CDAB597DC161DCCD91"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>qualified skilled nursing facility</term> means a skilled nursing facility that the Secretary determines—</text>
 <clause id="H2D658D81BD3E44CDA54414C722CA10AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), based upon the most recent ratings under the system established for purposes of rating skilled nursing facilities under the Medicare Nursing Home Compare program, has an overall rating of 3 or more stars or a score of 4 stars or higher on the individual quality domain or on the staffing quality domain; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0F552CAD1A374BB9B2A2881348501A42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not subject to a quality-of-care corporate integrity agreement (relating to one or more programs under this Act) that is in effect with the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services and that requires the facility to retain an independent quality monitor.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The Secretary may make a determination under clause (ii) based upon the most current information
 contained in the website of the Inspector General.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6640D5DF865C445396A15A4A614470AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver of ratings to ensure access</header><text>The Secretary may, upon application, waive the requirement of subparagraph (A)(i) for a skilled nursing facility in order to ensure access to extended care services that are not post-hospital extended care services in particular underserved geographic areas.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE3F821C4EBE42B3A2C1EE368070438B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Grace period for correction of ratings</header><text>In the case of a skilled nursing facility that qualifies as a qualified skilled nursing facility for a period and that would be disqualified under subparagraph (A)(i) because of a decline in its star rating, before disqualifying the facility the Secretary shall provide the facility with a grace period of 1 year during which the facility seeks to improve its ratings based on a plan of correction approved by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83B2040A02C84E998C2BCD2D779DD56C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Holding beneficiaries harmless in case of disqualification of a facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a skilled nursing facility that qualifies as a qualified skilled nursing facility for a period and that is disqualified under subparagraph (A), such disqualification shall not apply to or affect individuals who are admitted to the facility at the time of the disqualification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9A887C419BCF43AF9D369C31CD416EEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>MedPAC study of cost of implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall conduct a study of, and submit a report to Congress and the Secretary of Health and Human Services on, the cost of impact of the amendment made by subsection (a), no later than June 1, 2018.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


