<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDB01B864FBA447B78A827BDF57A83B2F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4109 IH: Protecting Financial Aid for Students and Taxpayers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4109</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151119">November 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Higher Education Opportunity Act to restrict institutions of higher education from
			 using revenues derived from Federal educational assistance funds for
			 advertising, marketing, or recruiting purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H28FD68BC0F18470FBBFB114B083F8ABB" style="OLC">
		<section id="H93B7842C0E4749368F5B46763A0B0312" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; findings</header>
 <subsection id="H60CB3B28448148DEAA6BAFC69AE9EBAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Financial Aid for Students and Taxpayers Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H5EF8E450B3564072A644A1791496FF12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7AE33FF40BF8492E89817718F383DE12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>From 1998 to 2013, enrollment in for-profit institutions of higher education increased by 314 percent, from 498,176 students to 2,064,920 students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DFE2F39945C4B6F9E56CCF806932218"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the 2012–2013 academic year, students who enrolled at for-profit institutions of higher education received $26,469,028,523 in Federal Pell Grants and student loans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3323C3744711461F80E538B9A3F59DF5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Eight out of the 10 top recipients of Post- 9/11 Educational Assistance funds are for-profit institutions of higher education. These 8 companies have received $2,900,000,000 in taxpayer funds to enroll veterans from 2009 to 2013.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03F84955FDC648B5BF8E3B20496CEA0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An analysis of 15 publicly traded companies that operate institutions of higher education shows that, on average, such companies spend 28 percent of expenditures on advertising, marketing, and recruiting.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H36E5AC73D1A44181B654E915E912A2CE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restrictions on sources of funds for recruiting and marketing activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 119 of the Higher Education Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011m">20 U.S.C. 1011m</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H038CADE354F64CBDBA4EFE5BC23A4D8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and Restrictions on Sources of Funds for Recruiting and Marketing Activities</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Funds</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDED7303BB0494793B63460B18409945F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>subsections (a) through (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (a), (b), (c), and (e)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE3570B9584C49D5863E3F1D8F8CC741"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14FE75908E5E4668A7CFF2FAD0002FDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68BE2A42A43E42739AC44530CB7615D2" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H3D8CE604208D41DD9B3A0DFB82C1CAED"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Restrictions on sources of funds for recruiting and marketing activities</header> <paragraph id="HE3AA0CDA66FB4ECF80748DBB129B9AD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An institution of higher education, or other postsecondary educational institution, may not use revenues derived from Federal educational assistance funds for recruiting or marketing activities described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E2DDE3736934306A9386807A65182C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered activities</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the recruiting and marketing activities subject to paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H57ECED07E5A249B098C5E0FF7E465879"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Advertising and promotion activities, including paid announcements in newspapers, magazines, radio, television, billboards, electronic media, naming rights, or any other public medium of communication, including paying for displays or promotions at job fairs, military installations, or college recruiting events.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H961D99AE72744D66B92DBBF227B96CB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Efforts to identify and attract prospective students, either directly or through a contractor or other third party, including contact concerning a prospective student’s potential enrollment or application for grant, loan, or work assistance under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) or participation in preadmission or advising activities, including—</text>
 <clause id="HCF5AA60952C84244BC3DF2A64B570BD6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paying employees responsible for overseeing enrollment and for contacting potential students in-person, by phone, by email, or by other internet communications regarding enrollment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF4E3E21DC0D545B4B8606FAF94364DA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>soliciting an individual to provide contact information to an institution of higher education, including websites established for such purpose and funds paid to third parties for such purpose.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H245176AC173743D1B1A97B091DBA8D40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such other activities as the Secretary of Education may prescribe, including paying for promotion or sponsorship of education or military-related associations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC528E3909A214AD78CEB1B33ED555EAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Any activity that is required as a condition of receipt of funds by an institution under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>), is specifically authorized under such title, or is otherwise specified by the Secretary of Education shall not be considered to be a covered activity under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB55948239242436AA592871CAF793E4F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal educational assistance funds</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>Federal educational assistance funds</quote> means funds provided directly to an institution or to a student attending such institution under any of the following provisions of law:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA0014DEFE008468B80142BD2052CD474"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H432493A53BF94893BC59653EDD61259D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Chapter 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, or 35 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BC6DC5F74AE4962B42EF679FCD2621D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Chapter 101, 105, 106A, 1606, 1607, or 1608 of title 10, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9ADE7BEEC894F81B0E0F4E0B3C1C3BD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 1784a, 2005, or 2007 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B1910333BAC46B59D04D2DFB594A776"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3111">29 U.S.C. 3111 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE791EAF930FF4874BE4C3317A1261F94"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Adult Education and Family Literacy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3271">29 U.S.C. 3271 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD23BC0B2B44723B75FDD21225E660C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as a limitation on the use by an institution of revenues derived from sources other than Federal educational assistance funds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD96B8C96B72C411BB173969983EBF7B1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each institution of higher education, or other postsecondary educational institution, that receives revenues derived from Federal educational assistance funds shall report annually to the Secretary and to Congress the institution's expenditures on advertising, marketing, and recruiting.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


