<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H34D8D62745A549BD858C4D1C46E4C90C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2073 IH: Home Owner Managing Energy Savings Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2073</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the establishment of a Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF9D33A4A1A224C559F916D27587132E9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H431CAD18318D470C9D6D5CC0DE980A4D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Home Owner Managing Energy Savings Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HOMES Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9BE7AC7FB1B34F769A616E84833FA684"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA66062B16FB64C6D96F0C32EA51F88BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>BPI</header><text>The term <quote>BPI</quote> means the Building Performance Institute.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H883DF65692A64E07838BBDB1FCCF26CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy audit</header><text>The term <quote>energy audit</quote> means an inspection, survey, and analysis of energy flows for energy conservation in a building, process, or system to reduce the amount of energy input into the system without negatively affecting the output. An energy audit is the first step in identifying opportunities to reduce energy expense and carbon footprints.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF4F0745FE744C01B7FA4F2D0063A511"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electric utility</header><text>The term <quote>electric utility</quote> means any company, person, cooperative, State, or Indian tribe agency that delivers or sells electric energy at retail, including nonregulated utilities, utilities that are subject to State or Indian tribe rate regulation, and Federal power marketing administrations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C6090CCBFDE428DB2B1E07A9AF62A98"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal rebate processing system</header><text>The term <quote>Federal Rebate Processing System</quote> means the Federal Rebate Processing System established under section 3(b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF7AD6A41549422DA45A8449100B591C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Home</header><text>The term <quote>home</quote> means a residential dwelling unit in a building with no more than 4 dwelling units that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC18689DE647E405D95A5603D64FE3408"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located in the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H378B953F01FF407AA6CEDA29FFDD667B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was constructed before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31A207A9530142FB87BDBE5512FA3CEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is occupied at least six months out of the year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBB2CF07F42341B5B0A29974049AB6D2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Home energy savings retrofit rebate program</header><text>The term <quote>Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program</quote> means the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program established under section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A5C4D624906473994014ECC04A33D53"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Homeowner</header><text>The term <quote>homeowner</quote> means the owner of an owner-occupied home or a tenant-occupied home.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H09F8DAE7537341F5B5668389EB61CD96"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <quote>Indian tribe</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CA100EA8911441EBA9DEA9A2BBFF864"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Natural gas utility</header><text>The term <quote>natural gas utility</quote> means any company, person, cooperative, State or local governmental agency or instrumentality, or Indian tribe that transports, distributes, or sells natural gas at retail.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6AFFBF6654846479498001C29398A9C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Qualified contractor</header><text>The term <quote>qualified contractor</quote> means a residential energy efficiency contractor that meets minimum applicable requirements established under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B6370A9685E4A79814A092619DD6CED"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Qualified home energy efficiency retrofit</header><text>The term <quote>qualified home energy efficiency retrofit</quote> means a retrofit described in section 8(d).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H494A5E5ABD55439E8C8614298826F15B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Quality assurance program</header><text>The term <quote>quality assurance program</quote> means a program established under this Act, or recognized by the Secretary under this Act, to oversee the delivery of home efficiency retrofit programs to ensure that work is performed in accordance with standards and criteria established under this Act. Delivery of retrofit programs includes delivery of quality assurance reviews of rebate applications and field inspections. Individuals performing quality assurance work under a quality assurance program must be certified under an ANSI accredited quality control inspection certification designation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB258EA4B0AA14CEDB87379234E288CCF"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Quality assurance provider</header><text>The term <quote>quality assurance provider</quote> means any entity that meets the minimum applicable requirements established under section 6(b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H69E6801943734DCFA50749BED3793CAB"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Rebate aggregator</header><text>The term <quote>rebate aggregator</quote> means an entity that meets the requirements of section 5.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF79D4A83E2B74C9C84B86253B203AD92"><enum>(15)</enum><header>RESNET</header><text>The term <quote>RESNET</quote> means the Residential Energy Services Network, which is a nonprofit certification and standard setting organization for home energy raters that evaluate the energy performance of a home and Energy Smart Contractors that make energy improvements to the home.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05B92A55EFCA420B861FACEDE750D14F"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC5F7D7865564E83A344AE65A475A817"><enum>(17)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF7DE8C26DB9749EB9F3366E773B17101"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82F490705C744768BDDC60935D40C257"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB31E79E12074182AB7C2AAC8472AD99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0EBC29292AE43C6823ABF0BAF31E4A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Guam;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE945C4BC8F184E4E8E3B403B6244AF30"><enum>(E)</enum><text>American Samoa;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C06D2732C874EF5B89DC6D95B67EFD1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE89454E03DB44A859A1ABEA8BEDB5059"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the United States Virgin Islands; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A160CAEE55D4D21915E456078CF4BB4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H5C1C90391AC04032877C4D5138E46B39"><enum>3.</enum><header>Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program</header>
 <subsection id="HF498F218F42C4C1183AAD42A9524CD58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H15C07A111C514DCB8B0F93080D7005D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal rebate processing system</header> <paragraph id="H04E374742F824EDB9F1E7F0DDFF2A036"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD14EE2BF09AC48DB9D083F6DB7F32118"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a Federal Rebate Processing System which shall serve as a database and information technology system that will allow rebate aggregators to submit claims for reimbursement using standard data protocols;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE6A9F5B4DA74CFA8E61EA9CE6B349FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a national retrofit Web site that provides information on the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program, including—</text>
 <clause id="HA95D5A4F83C3479098EFD18F0D9F7403"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how to determine whether particular efficiency measures are eligible for rebates; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE30A5844A44A45D18F4154FA30053D21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how to participate in the program; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5809A5640C0E4B30A623EE37D2BF922C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make available model forms for demonstrating compliance with all applicable requirements of this Act, which shall be required to be submitted by—</text>
 <clause id="HFF157B2E27CB48EF8703479BC72BC616"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each qualified contractor on completion of an eligible home energy retrofit; and</text> </clause><clause id="H89425F7CA83E4563814902E6F601DB32"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each quality assurance provider on completion of field verification.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD9C09908E044C9E8495F34181805153"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Model forms</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1)(C), the Secretary shall convene a group of stakeholders that are directly and materially affected by the Program to develop the final forms.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H158A2E8C20384869BCE91177DB0294E8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Contractors</header>
 <subsection id="H646946654E284610825360057E8B0C76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contractor qualifications</header><text>A contractor may perform retrofit work under the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program in a State if the contractor—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0FC627F4894F445396D8A34B8FDB4C17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>meets all applicable contractor licensing requirements established by the State;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H06FC65D2D5F642108C60EFBF39136D28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC129B7878B454A0F9E2E1F00DF867B78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accredited by—</text> <clause id="H7D478873C323444B9B2FF856C72D0139"><enum>(i)</enum><text>BPI as a BPI GoldStar Contractor;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC3D669B1876947C2B89B6AD8AD12FCD5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>RESNET as an Energy Smart Home Performance Team;</text> </clause><clause id="H7E836C9DC0454B739DEA4D02AD730CD2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ACCA as a QA Home Performance Contractor;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD637B62B1A9041A0A9EE585498F6273C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a State-based certification program established to carry out State energy, clean air, or environmental programs; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA539E6F0C6CF49158DDAD676CDC2F70D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an equivalent accreditation program approved by the Secretary for this purpose; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H870D79FFCC35417790F035E2EFC915B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the general contractor, and—</text>
 <clause id="H333486A98ACB42718709504332A3F9D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subjects the energy efficiency retrofit to a third-party review by a party approved by the Secretary and a quality assurance inspection authorized by the Secretary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H62762468E47C4A42A381892A16148E8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>employs, or utilizes subcontractors who employ, individuals to complete individual or comprehensive scopes of work related to the energy efficiency retrofit who are certified by—</text>
 <subclause id="HE358987EFA40449BA093F8D202F50C29"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">BPI;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8239F65612DE475BA877F508092319A1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>RESNET;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA835158D7D1943468959D7F759DAA745"><enum>(III)</enum><text>NATE;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD3B48E56532F41918BA9AF1045792B89"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>ACCA;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H646901EB85CB4BD8A7E3A2922F219F6A"><enum>(V)</enum><text>LIUNA;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H65AE4B3B35BB4CB7A160DAB708811A31"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the Regional and State Department of Energy Weatherization Training Centers; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H54BC8123512F43798D29BAA777343FC8"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>other contractor or worker certification programs approved by the Secretary;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE57A1EC9BBC347BEB14A83DDD3ACAC34"><enum>(3)</enum><text>holds insurance coverage of at least $1,000,000 for general liability, and for such other purposes and in such other amounts as required by the State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DB7C159501F422CA38ED7AF5661ADFA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides warranties to the homeowner that completed work will—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D9A6E189EA043A3BA35FC3B6A849CCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be free of significant defects;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91824A1D7A7D4C7799AD9F226CEC5F30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be installed in accordance with the specifications of the manufacturer, and all applicable State and local codes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5F589B159BA4229AB39AB621899FCB3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>perform properly for a period of at least 1 year after the date of completion of the work; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF862B82837B41138E9231A61EC3E615"><enum>(5)</enum><text>completes an energy audit to determine the impact of the proposed energy efficiency measures in accordance with an ANSI accredited energy auditing standard.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H351805050E544555A8D7EDBC98E4924A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreement between contractor and home owner</header><text>A contractor who performs retrofit work under the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program must sign a written or electronic contract with the homeowner that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H721005D5F1944C7BA8D2A4B82A7AB31C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an agreement to not increase the cost of the home improvement as a result of the rebates received under this Act with respect to physical improvements made to the home;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E0A890AFAF34F0FB49B4ACB51EEFEB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the contractor and homeowner choose the transferable rebate option authorized under section 7, an agreement to provide the homeowner, before a contract is executed between the contractor and the homeowner covering the eligible work, a notice of the rebate amount the contractor intends to apply for with respect to eligible work under this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD932A2D7B7034D40BEF32F59F5969DB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a notice that the homeowner acknowledges that they—</text> <subparagraph id="H239A124DD56B413FAD61CD4F857C4EA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reviewed the national retrofit Web site for the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EA5FA7490F343E3AF18D4EE373D45A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>understand the scope of work intended to be completed and that such work may be eligible for a rebate under the program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H739B7366997E49D5B077486341793F92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>understand that the rebate funds are fully subject to availability from the Department or Rebate Aggregator and not within the control of the contractor.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5A1083C83CFF47A7AED2972F72D03289"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rebate aggregators</header>
 <subsection id="HE48695A83BF741B09D8F78DAF1B0B312"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a network of rebate aggregators or a national rebate aggregator that can facilitate the delivery of rebates to participating homeowners or contractors by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H609399A1A6C9488BBE1A2F939CBA8390"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reviewing the proposed rebate application for completeness and accuracy;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H93E458D92CA24008A0086E4815F31701"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reviewing measures for eligibility in accordance with this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58BD6BF8DF2B4352A59FC19BBF02E227"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing data to the Federal Rebate Processing System consistent with data protocols established by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2A5436960B94D09A30811732E4D6C62"><enum>(4)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of receipt, distributing funds received from the Department of Energy to homeowners or contractors.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2F25463353549EEA98BAFA1D2000B82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to apply to the Secretary for approval as a rebate aggregator, an entity shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H84C0D797CC4848B88487AD34014B3103"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Home Performance with Energy Star program sponsor;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD285124B81754BD488A7443F949EFF98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an entity administering a residential or building energy efficiency retrofit program, solar program, or other such program impacting energy efficiency in homes established or approved by a State or local government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97186539EC454C1A9B554ABADE240E5D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a Federal power marketing administration, an electric utility, or a natural gas utility that has—</text> <subparagraph id="HA01B425630FB4A338C51534F3B606D9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a residential energy efficiency retrofit program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78AC16DDE7874B298D829D2FC32503FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a quality assurance provider or provider network; or</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEECC8209F9B04D2C9BC00765C72D6A6F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an entity that demonstrates to the Secretary that the entity can perform the functions of a rebate aggregator, without disrupting existing residential retrofits in the States that are incorporating the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program, including demonstration of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H98C259DB78FB4655B4CBB7B8D41E722B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the capability to provide electronic data to the Federal Rebate Processing System;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59992E5533614F25AC0B7485B920FC09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a financial system that is capable of tracking the distribution of rebates to participating contractors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2584D8DF5844ECC9C47FA601961AC4A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordination and cooperation by the entity with the appropriate State energy office regarding participation in the existing energy efficiency programs that will be delivering the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5EB748928A434193AD0BFC4CA402F771"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public utility commission efficiency targets</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2E88785860724DE9B335D3CFBC88B25C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop guidelines for States and local governments to use to allow utilities participating as rebate aggregators to count the energy savings from the participation of the utilities toward State and local level energy savings targets; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CEE32A9DEA342A8BFDFCE8B9D93AE7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>work with States and local governments to assist in the adoption of those guidelines for the purposes and duration of the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5244730CC3CC413D9B49B9C3980E56BE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Quality assurance providers</header>
 <subsection id="H0544C47D4E7F4095BF046E87523F9DCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>An entity shall be considered a quality assurance provider under this Act only if the entity is qualified through—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C999FB21F2545EFBCEF63369047D61C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the BPI;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE66AF9DE068643DBACD42FD213ECFDBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>RESNET; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDBDD8EB286244F9B779119B74C623C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other entity designated by the Secretary such as a State, local government, or State-approved or local government-approved residential energy efficiency retrofit program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF476AF27B202494DBEA920A757E28A77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>A quality assurance provider shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6E96B2E50C334BD1A9F340904F099364"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be independent of the contractor;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF001C8766C3B40489D24A4C84DB988E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>confirm that contractors or installers of home energy efficiency retrofits meet the qualification requirements of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63B3544471744E538EC25D5120655061"><enum>(3)</enum><text>perform field inspections to confirm the compliance of the retrofit work and the simulated energy savings under the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2BCC59E5823D4D858FEBFB3B60837EF3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Transferability of home energy savings rebate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A homeowner may transfer the rebate provided under the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program to the contractor performing the retrofit work if the contractor completes a form that accompanies the rebate form developed under section 3(b). This form, to be made publically available by the Secretary 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, must be approved by paper signature or electronically by the homeowner and include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBBEB71ECBCDD424A8BF3D8B7021F2BF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount of the rebate the contractor will submit for disbursement to the contractor;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8BFA912C53147B0B48FAAC400BC86CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the level of energy use reduction of the home retrofit certified under section 8(e)(4), and assurance that the contractor will provide the certificate to the homeowner within 30 days of receipt from the Department of Energy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2ED2BD5381F4FC880D19A41DFDAFB69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a documentation report of the retrofit performed and paid by the homeowner; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC85525473FB04EAEA66311ECC520DBB3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>confirmation from the homeowner that they understand they have the right to submit directly for the rebate and have chosen to transfer the credit in full to the contractor.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HF31CA050328D4CB5B1642D8BC3F0EF57"><enum>8.</enum><header>Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate program</header>
 <subsection id="H464CC83535A441199D90D8B331802E13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a qualified home energy efficiency retrofit of a home is carried out after the date of enactment of this Act by a qualified contractor in accordance with this section, rebates shall be awarded for retrofits that achieve home energy savings in accordance with this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6FFA61FDB6F64C2EA606884646F87FEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of rebates</header>
 <paragraph id="H5F0AC40FAD4B41329F8C84D59FBE11DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (e), the amount of a rebate provided to the owner of a home or a designee of the owner under this section shall be determined in accordance with the following formula:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE931D7FF24274D28AB130954D351058C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Retrofits that are projected to save at least 20 percent of energy use (Home Performance Retrofits) shall receive a rebate of $2,500.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEF0959788AF4D8990B8D84E6BCC232D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Retrofits that are projected to save at least 40 percent of energy use (Deep Home Performance Retrofits) shall receive a rebate of $5,000.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H68BF13761CF546BB839FB202123EB0C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rebate payment</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAD09C500316340ABB618F35B230B4C5A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The rebate shall be paid, based on energy savings as calculated under subsection (e), within 60 days after—</text>
 <clause id="H22497998785C41F0B4D7340F7AD1C4B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submission of the required rebate forms; and</text> </clause><clause id="HB0A9E07837D34C82ADC50EA2D6B6C5CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the completion of any quality assurance assessment required under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0CB28E858864FC29CA1697A2A956502"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Quality assurance assessments</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a schedule of required quality assurance assessments. In the first year of the program, the first 10 homes retrofit by each contractor and then 60 percent of all future homes shall be required to have a quality assurance assessment. The Secretary shall establish a cost effective schedule of required quality assurance assessments for subsequent years based on performance under the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F7419C3C2474206BC06837309FF108E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Bonus incentive</header><text>Recipients of grants under section 9 and rebate aggregators are encouraged to present a proposal to the Secretary for an incentive bonus for contractors who have delivered services to consumers and who have achieved a 70 percent or greater realization rate for predicted gross energy cost savings achieved by their portfolio of participating customers. Bonus incentives under such a proposal may be up to 20 percent of the rebate paid to the homeowner.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4E4C75831724420AD0145A898D26A35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In no event shall the amount of rebates under this subsection exceed—</text> <subparagraph id="HE338B74C4C3F42198D68655293011CBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000 with respect to any individual; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA52B294E6C4E436BB53708AE909E2D93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>50 percent of the qualified home energy efficiency expenditures paid or incurred by the homeowner under subsection (c).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01946646F8044374AB1FBDC0A7C5C5A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified home energy efficiency expenditures</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified home energy efficiency expenditures</quote>—</text> <paragraph id="H478FDC7ECBE2482D92D83298A02E9527"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means any amount paid or incurred by a homeowner for a qualified home energy efficiency retrofit, including the cost of diagnostic procedures, labor, reporting, and modeling; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE9071235D56484B83C4D8DAE51BF3A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2631631D5CF45458515304F4F10A10B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improvements to swimming pools or hot tubs; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2570D91F0B148469133C94D1BA7930B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any amount paid or incurred to purchase or install a biomass, wood, or wood pellet furnace, boiler, or stove, unless the system—</text>
 <clause id="H12153985990C4554A64EFEB5FD396A2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is designed to meet at least 70 percent of the heating demands of the home;</text> </clause><clause id="HAE4BF8C19D1641D684A72AD0F5DE170B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of woodstoves, is certified by the Environmental Protection Agency;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5EAEB21AC762412FA896A34D8A81DBC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a wood stove replacement, replaces an existing wood stove with a stove that is certified by the Environmental Protection Agency, if a voucher is provided by the installer or other responsible party certifying that the old stove has been removed and made inoperable;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF084BCFB9244D7BB384B8E0D89A3308"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of a furnace or boiler, is in a home with a distribution system (such as piping, ducts, vents, blowers, or affixed fans) that allows heat from the furnace or boiler to reach all or most parts of the home; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4424A90A1F08441F83600BDFB418C3BC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is certified by an independent test laboratory approved by the Secretary as having—</text> <subclause id="H0AAE1F9EA1514BDBA6B75DAB38385349"><enum>(I)</enum><text>thermal efficiency (with a high heating value) of at least 75 percent for stoves and 80 percent for furnaces and boilers;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H83CA5E42D5E84AD9B90E4BC380B2F9CB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>particulate emissions of less than 3.0 grams per hour for wood stoves or pellet stoves; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HAF6674B9CBD4454FB7F9306D712A9DCB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>less than 0.07 lbs per million BTU for outdoor boilers and furnaces.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B66409F9A6747F3828824B7AEF99C74"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualified home energy efficiency retrofit</header>
 <paragraph id="HF25938AA1BAC41FEB92C2395182115FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified home energy efficiency retrofit is a retrofit that implements measures, during a rebate-eligible year in the existing principal residence of the homeowner which is located in the United States, intended to reduce the energy use of such residence. A qualified home energy efficiency retrofit shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8B5CCBBC555C4872874F4C584A4E82D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be implemented and installed by a qualified contractor;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A0118011FA545DD908F45D629D98F8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>install a set of measures modeled to achieve a reduction in home energy use of 20 percent or more from the baseline established under subparagraph (C), using computer modeling software approved under paragraph (2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF84E698659AB4B06BE7C6272E23F3BC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish the baseline energy use as provided in subsection (e)(1)(C);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63584241FC264843B197DFD7AADA3068"><enum>(D)</enum><text>implement a test-out procedure, following guidelines of the applicable accrediting program described in section 4(a)(2) (A), (B), or (C), or equivalent guidelines approved by the Secretary for this purpose, to ensure—</text>
 <clause id="H76E4A627E2424628B72291E584C3AC05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the safe operation of all systems post retrofit; and</text> </clause><clause id="H51A5AF8A721B4512B72786D1B36FC18C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that, except as provided in paragraph (3), all improvements are included in, and have been installed according to—</text>
 <subclause id="H272D86B2774D4FBC8B9EA57887AD1EC0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>standards of the applicable accrediting program described in section 4(a)(2) (A), (B), or (C);</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4447153FB7DD456FAB4E03D0440D9922"><enum>(II)</enum><text>manufacturers installation specifications; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6B7D1FD270E04B0E904560B956020BDF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>all applicable State and local codes or equivalent standards approved by the Secretary for this purpose;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34AD71D9AFB94C1A9C2221FDDB6C4CAD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include only measures that have an average estimated life of 5 years or more as determined by the Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H436E18046B8E4FC09F27FA5F0A8D929A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>not include any amount which is paid or incurred in connection with any expansion of the square footage of the residence; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47B88D13709D4C468BE0FF055DE4949E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>not include improvements to swimming pools or hot tubs or any other expenditure specifically excluded by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H499B22E251F94807A2AE53DCFA290235"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approved modeling software</header><text>The contractor shall use modeling software certified by RESNET as following the software verification test suites in section 4.2.1 of RESNET Publication No. 13–001, or under equivalent standards approved by the Secretary for this purpose, and shall have the ability at a minimum to assess the savings associated with all the measures for Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D5B422A03F04E159D8B380A4F7AE319"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(D)(ii), installation of gas-fired appliances shall comply with requirements of the National Fuel Gas Code (ANSI Z223.1/NFPA 54) and applicable installation requirements in lieu of performance of combustion tests outside those required by the National Fuel Gas Code (2012 Edition) and the International Fuel Gas Code (2012 Edition).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H837E78529AB74DE2962F1673FE7BC68E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Energy use reduction</header>
				<paragraph id="H3CECFEB8476A41269E93257DF0AD9036"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of energy use reduction</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC16F1F9F68EB45CC99FB18BB894157CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The reduction in energy use for any residence shall be determined by modeling the annual predicted percentage reduction in total energy consumption or costs for heating, cooling, hot water, and permanent lighting. It shall be modeled using computer modeling software approved under subsection (d)(2) and calibrated according to subparagraph (C) of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52D2A8A36EA94171BCDCF9F577B80B04"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Energy costs</header><text>For the purposes of subparagraph (A), the energy cost per unit of fuel for each fuel type shall be determined by dividing the total actual energy bill (subtracting taxes and fees) for the residence for that fuel type for the most recent available 12-month period by the total energy units of that fuel type used over the same period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31C3F3F2190D467F9864613AD376B825"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Baseline energy use</header><text>For the purposes of subparagraph (A), the software model that establishes the baseline energy use and predicted energy savings shall be calibrated according to the procedures set forth in sections 3 and 4 of ANSI/BPI Standard BPI–2400–S–2012: Standard Practice for Standardized Qualification of Whole-House Energy Savings Predictions by Calibration to Energy Use History, or an equivalent standard approved by the Secretary for this purpose.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02B542188B354D5EAA01B7431D062154"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>The percent improvement in energy consumption calculated under this section shall be documented through modeling software described in subsection (d)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FCCA1ABB02047B4A82E50E9233F69BA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>The Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="H2065E58232874FED848A6DF864055DB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall periodically evaluate the software packages used for determining rebates under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB8618A09A9B4CAAB591C5088BDCC9EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall monitor and compare the predictions to the real energy data, and based on the results, create performance criteria to allow or disallow the software; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB5A9BDBBB1B4D309984F11D4D939925"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may disallow the use of software programs that improperly assess energy savings.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE9830A106734AB0816E69DBFE7CB94D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certificate of retrofit performance</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a system for distribution of a certificate of performance in accordance with BPI–2101–S–2013: Standard Requirements for a Certificate of Completion for Residential Energy Efficiency Upgrades with the issuance of a rebate that certifies the predicted level of energy use reduction achieved by the retrofit. The certificate shall be provided to the rebate recipient. If the recipient is the contractor under the terms of section 7, the contractor shall remit the certificate to the homeowner, to be delivered or postmarked not later than 30 days after the contractor’s receipt of the certificate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE1A159C96E240899183F69AFD6CC128"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary shall not utilize the authority provided under this Act to—</text> <subparagraph id="H863ECF9CB18C45258C0D5745C2EFBD9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop, adopt, or implement a public labeling system that rates and compares the energy performance of one home with another; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75EFBEAED00942F3B545AC3473995310"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require the public disclosure of an energy performance evaluation or rating developed for any specific home.</text>
					</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Nothing in this paragraph shall preclude the computation, collection, or use, by the Secretary,
			 rebate aggregators, or quality assurance providers, or the States or
			 Indian tribes, for the purposes of gathering information on the rating and
			 comparison of the energy performance of homes with and without energy
 efficiency retrofits.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5817DFD2DD349D3B4B15D6A809C60F4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualification for rebate</header><text>On submission of a claim for a retrofit rebate by a rebate aggregator to the system established under section 5, the Secretary shall provide reimbursement to the rebate aggregator, if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2F9BA06C9CBB42FD8DD2C0C080C7C128"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the retrofit is a qualified home energy efficiency retrofit;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H36B4DEE91CA14FF1B22085AEB1AEEECA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of the reimbursement is not more than the amount described in subsection (b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28450E9D3FAD4AF69878BFCD25ABC789"><enum>(3)</enum><text>documentation required to verify the claim is transmitted with the claim; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3211C1D9EA0441319FEA7A1ED6E6F882"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any quality assurance assessment required by the Secretary or the rebate aggregator has been completed.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE5C3EDDB3944B4D9451082BB065AD52"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Audits</header>
 <paragraph id="HCAF4919CF6C0480D95BF77656F2F5D6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On making payment for a submission under this section, the Secretary shall review rebate requests to determine whether program requirements were met in all respects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C1659FF3E49491EACB716B41591F9BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incorrect payment</header><text>On a determination of the Secretary under paragraph (1) that a payment was made incorrectly to a party, not later than 3 years after the payment was provided the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H61075FBCDB684B0592A991C2B26E98FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recoup the amount of the incorrect payment; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB17995802E64821886E35D1E39119F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>withhold the amount of the incorrect payment from the next payment made to the party pursuant to a subsequent request.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCFED2BC2B9046FF80BB9B73633D1925"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Incentives</header><text>The amount of incentives that the Secretary may provide to quality assurance providers and rebate aggregators under this Act shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="HED3CA88602D946F5B727D25ECC976CE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$50 for each rebate review and submission provided under the program;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E34C140200842DA929DEE4D9F12BA3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$250 for each field inspection conducted under the program; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA923BFB354C46C5B881415330BD6AAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such other amounts as the Secretary considers necessary to carry out the quality assurance provisions of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4CF6D945608D41F6A7956B59CDAC43D5"><enum>9.</enum><header>Grants to States and Indian Tribes</header>
 <subsection id="HC2DF0B7C3C86439786766DCA4C8B2222"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or Indian tribe that receives a grant under subsection (d) shall be permitted to use the grant for—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0F34DBC44F4741C9A9734D306C2B2E39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>administrative costs;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H58971EA9785B4EEAAD31CCC1014EEF5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oversight of quality assurance plans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD7030065991407B9F17994D680D756F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>development of a quality assurance program;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H92F3AA2766444B9ABE9F9CB2E51E5BCE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishment and delivery of financing pilots in accordance with this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76AB199896A74AF7BE91B30C220811F0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordination with existing residential retrofit programs and infrastructure development to assist deployment of the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B24A2A1355245A982C7DD1D6BEE6AB9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the costs of carrying out the responsibilities of the State or Indian tribe under the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8127E115B59146D8BFD5ABE02718C0C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial grants</header><text>Not later than 60 days after receipt of a completed application for a grant under this section, the Secretary shall either make the grant or provide to the applicant an explanation for denying the grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1022C51B8C7D4BE79254106488EE4322"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Indian tribes</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve an appropriate amount of funding to be made available to carry out this section for each fiscal year to make grants available to Indian tribes under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H43F50DFF313F425A847EA8F15ABCBF16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State allotments</header><text>From the amounts made available to carry out this section for each fiscal year remaining after the reservation required under subsection (c), the Secretary shall make grants available to States in accordance with section 15.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE856EE8985A345B4B5BDF11B0A305CDB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Quality assurance programs</header>
 <paragraph id="HDB62282E444845FB829C19415FAAAE39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or Indian tribe may use a grant made under this section to carry out a quality assurance program that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H657C9C88D12C4BBF851FBC00A17132FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operated as part of a State or local government approved energy conservation plan established under part D of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6321">42 U.S.C. 6321 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAF0D83388384F99A946AFBB208B7EC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>managed by the office or the designee of the office that is—</text> <clause id="H64BFA840B5CD4714BEF84DB3040943A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>responsible for the development of the plan under section 362 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6322">42 U.S.C. 6322</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H956DF5D164DF4D3E9994CD287752D739"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable conducting an existing energy efficiency program; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB059D0926344FCCBA0BCADE7114E2C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a grant made to an Indian tribe, managed by an entity designated by the Indian tribe to carry out a quality assurance program or a national quality assurance program manager.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A5C9FBB5BC149B68347F2E87D630D20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a State or Indian tribe has not provided or cannot provide adequate oversight over a quality assurance program to ensure compliance with this Act, the Secretary may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9082C840D5BC4695A9E89BEFC2FD88DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withhold further quality assurance funds from the State or Indian tribe; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H818B3E0F6D0B4B3C8F4BF6EE5B557E8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require that quality assurance providers operating in the State or by the Indian tribe be overseen by a national quality assurance program manager selected by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0572A6C696424A79919F1436CC7CECB0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>A State or Indian tribe that receives a grant under this section may implement a quality assurance program through the State, the Indian tribe, or a third party designated by the State or Indian tribe, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7B4F5B61A1EC40BB9B4C5CAB86474FEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an energy service company;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B96FC11AD0B4A7C9D9C7B081D3C3B21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an electric utility;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52EA9BD6C1934C07A5E605D808478999"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a natural gas utility;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE860D81A07C843CDB1508564F291DDF0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a third-party administrator designated by the State or Indian tribe; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA16CF92C56A460CAB6FD548F8B32DE3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a unit of local government.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50F3662E6B9240659EA14E0EDF757763"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public-Private partnerships</header><text>A State or Indian tribe that receives a grant under this section is encouraged to form partnerships with utilities, energy service companies, and other entities—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA937CBF402BB4969AA19C85AA8B428DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to assist in marketing a program;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H89FB5386EA2F4C0AB719E17AEF17782F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to facilitate consumer financing;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12C04196E8C24483B49E0A4631709127"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to assist in implementation of the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program, including installation of qualified home energy efficiency retrofits; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H397EC78C9E0D4E95B9DE1CE7D19AAA27"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to assist in implementing quality assurance programs.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5DCDE5E739D43A7B03F49409C187D43"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Coordination of rebate and existing state-Sponsored programs</header> <paragraph id="H6E43F3E2D3C04B1EA084E0CB58B54781"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or Indian tribe shall, to the maximum extent practicable, prevent duplication through coordination of a program authorized under this Act with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H53525423CC624234AD0587BB8BF90A71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Energy Star appliance rebates program authorized under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 115); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2524807F168482F97247636CD2875E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comparable programs planned or operated by States, political subdivisions, electric and natural gas utilities, Federal power marketing administrations, and Indian tribes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C2233BA87D48E48252613FB0076CC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing programs</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, a State or Indian tribe shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD131ACDAA617474CB4BAA4214CBB5451"><enum>(A)</enum><text>give priority to—</text>
 <clause id="H0839174A3F594E7FB8C4BD3FBFCC4CF3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>comprehensive retrofit programs in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, including programs under the supervision of State utility regulators; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD8F530C01C4F4669A446EE7977A72625"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>using funds made available under this Act to enhance and extend existing programs; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56AC025692B8407A93B0351573998A5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to enhance and extend existing programs by coordinating with administrators of the programs.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H13DE00F5791149EBB12A7044B53637F2"><enum>10.</enum><header>Quality assurance program</header>
 <subsection id="HB2B0CDA7443C445CB4D8DAC754A475EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>As part of a grant application described in section 9(b), a State or Indian tribe shall submit to the Secretary a plan to implement a quality assurance program that covers all federally assisted residential efficiency retrofit work administered, supervised, or sponsored by the State or Indian tribe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9257EC4E31AD446AAFC05C2C19445A69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The State or Indian tribe shall—</text> <paragraph id="H88630405B002469191196103D89D89AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a quality assurance program in consultation with industry stakeholders, including representatives of efficiency program managers, contractors, and environmental, energy efficiency, and labor organizations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E358AC8BCD9498D8D41CD8FA2A31F10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement the quality assurance program not later than 180 days after receipt of a grant under section 9.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AA337605E3F45F4B9816B24EB00F83C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The quality assurance program established under this section shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H2D9BB408E6264BA9A70E66FC88D9DDEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintenance of a list of qualified contractors authorized to perform such retrofit work as described in section 4; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FDE6D0A5B0C43188665969A3F43E40C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>nonbinding targets and realistic plans for—</text> <subparagraph id="H08CEBC7E9C4049078D70392A77768303"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the recruitment of small minority-owned or women-owned business enterprises; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23ABE5E3FD0D4998A86173ABA2D4798E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the employment of graduates of training programs that primarily serve low-income populations with a median income that is below 200 percent of the poverty line (as defined in section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>), including any revision required by that section) by participating contractors.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC52B35B83CC74DCEBC31935156C515A8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a State or Indian tribe has not taken the steps required under this section, the Secretary shall provide to the State or Indian tribe a period of at least 90 days to comply before suspending the participation of the State or Indian tribe in the program.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA9E05240EBD6475C8CBF0D204FEEF392"><enum>11.</enum><header>Evaluation report to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H4884C441E2534139AA432CDFF29040E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter until the termination of the program under this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the use of funds under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3B146BC9DDD64972B75611141F256350"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall evaluate—</text> <paragraph id="H3F7C534EB6F44E5E9A2C0099CEF38076"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how many eligible participants have participated in the program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H108E17AE94A84ECF8973D727185D2558"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how many jobs have been created through the program, directly and indirectly;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H069CF44B274B46A2BA3C8AD5A8ACF36B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>what steps could be taken to promote further deployment of energy efficiency and renewable energy retrofits;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2BBA50ABBD64E38BEAADDC2EF3D33DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the quantity of verifiable energy savings, homeowner energy bill savings, and other benefits of the program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC860F33683B45169F6C404FC0426FAE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any waste, fraud, or abuse with respect to such funds; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF7A0EAC0EE648DAA4188627A537433E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91338FA87C984335BC3811748B57DC9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>The Secretary shall require rebate aggregators, States, and Indian tribes to provide the information required to enable the Secretary to carry out this section. If the Secretary determines that a rebate aggregator, State, or Indian tribe has not provided such information on a timely basis, the Secretary shall provide to the rebate aggregator, State, or Indian tribe a period of at least 90 days to provide any necessary information, subject to withholding of funds or reduction of future grant amounts, or decertification of rebate aggregators.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA47F0375354F4BB3B2AD2114E199CF46"><enum>12.</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <subsection id="H21125B3FD5D6465298B10A6AB317CB21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to section 15(b), not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide such administrative and technical support to rebate aggregators, States, and Indian tribes as is necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAA3C83C25A6947FBAEC3B2CDDA639D67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment of personnel</header><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service and General Schedule classifications and pay rates, the Secretary may appoint such professional and administrative personnel as the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H176B66E3661B42F48FF6F8CE968DC2D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rate of pay</header><text>The rate of pay for a person appointed under subsection (b) shall not exceed the maximum rate payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD24891ACA4AF4C67A6C861961564A36D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultants</header><text>Notwithstanding section 303 of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/253">41 U.S.C. 253</external-xref>), the Secretary may retain such consultants on a noncompetitive basis as the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAE0EC8DE3EEE4DF581015085E2B01C4C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contracting</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary may waive all or part of any provision of the Competition in Contracting Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/369">Public Law 98–369</external-xref>; 98 Stat. 1175), an amendment made by that Act, or the Federal Acquisition Regulation on a determination that circumstances make compliance with the provisions contrary to the public interest.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9D208C6B557C4D1591358D5AABC9B988"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Information collection</header><text>The Secretary shall establish, and make available to a homeowner, or the homeowner’s designated representative, seeking a rebate under this Act, release forms authorizing access by the Secretary, or a designated third-party representative to information in the utility bills of the homeowner. The form shall not include personal identifying information such as name, address, social security number or other identifying information as defined by the Secretary.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HEA1CE9D82F924A9AB57C11287A457B6D"><enum>13.</enum><header>Treatment of rebates</header>
 <subsection id="H6F041B82E671461899790D6DFE6B9B8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, rebates received for a qualified home energy efficiency retrofit under this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H291BC11ECD9C4CC1A8D5B4FF6A818AD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not be considered taxable income to a homeowner; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8958F1BF2DAF4A8A9B21AA4F3E6FE727"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall prohibit the consumer from applying for a tax credit allowed under section 25C or 25D of that Code for the same retrofit work performed in the home of the homeowner. If the work is additional, and not included in the rebate baseline, a homeowner may claim the credit.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61CE9FDB82244B96B315628DEA9DBFEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <paragraph id="H16B531085D4D4625985C164C7075892E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A participating contractor shall provide notice to a homeowner of the provisions of subsection (a) before eligible work is performed in the home of the homeowner.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71E7023FDC594943A39BF71ECF9EA05C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice in rebate form</header><text>A homeowner shall be notified of the provisions of subsection (a) in the appropriate rebate form developed by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3A2FFC592BE94F229FE70486D226CDD8"><enum>14.</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <subsection id="H05E9A7F3F367441BACE0D4136A7C0358"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to violate this Act (including any regulation issued under this Act), other than a violation as the result of a clerical error.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3FA3708938EB4BC497709BDE541FF9EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>In addition to any penalty applicable under other Federal law for fraud or other crimes, any person who commits a violation of this Act shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty in an amount that is not more than the higher of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6FDB872961464F628C46B542664151C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$15,000 for each violation; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4460E8F557A74BFEBA2D7A102335DE20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>3 times the value of any associated rebate under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34B0514E870544A9BC78049D25EE8280"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="H99C8376ABA534522807C0FEA00052EEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess and compromise a penalty imposed under subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAEEC5F25E2B41C99E4C25701D71696E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require from any entity the records and inspections necessary to enforce this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC365FFD99AE84EBE8666E32039ED77EC"><enum>15.</enum><header>Funding</header> <subsection id="HF8377D0022514A129855683B4D5736CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph id="H1DC7ED7942354CAAA6FD39874EFDD533"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $250,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2019, to remain available until expended.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H844A37B52DF44AD38CB99B51020127D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maintenance of funding</header><text>Funds provided under this section shall supplement and not supplant any Federal and State funding provided to carry out energy efficiency programs in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCC7B354405A48EC928B711AB952C8F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants to states</header>
 <paragraph id="HD445C75C95F9480DA471DE9A79B43176"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the amounts provided under subsection (a), not more than 6 percent shall be used to carry out section 9.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DEF4DB08E4B4F7CBCBEBE0CD43A3E8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution to state energy offices</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall determine a formula to provide funds described in paragraph (1) to State energy offices, in accordance with the allocation formula for State energy conservation plans established under part D of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6321">42 U.S.C. 6321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E753440E8F147B8B3A89B0AA82DC4CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tracking of rebates and expenditures</header><text>Of the amount provided under subsection (a), not more than 2.5 percent are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to be used for costs associated with tracking rebates and expenditures through the Federal Rebate Processing System under this Act, technical assistance to States, and related administrative costs incurred by the Secretary.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF207DC17DF98407F9EB8308B86A76A5C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program review and backstop funding</header>
 <paragraph id="H64D9AFB8B53A4A4D82376FE6C191CFDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall perform a State-by-State analysis and review the distribution of Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebates under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E31D67741364D7AB3218A1FF7CB8C05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text>The Secretary may allocate technical assistance funding to assist States that have not sufficiently benefitted from the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5AFB56C36CFC4F3F8E3CCD0E5949C5C4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Return of undisbursed funds</header><text>If the Secretary has not disbursed all the funds available for rebates under the Home Energy Savings Retrofit Rebate Program by September 30, 2019, any undisbursed funds shall be returned to the Treasury.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H44BAF31968A14A65898960BD4F8693E3"><enum>16.</enum><header>Pilot program</header>
 <subsection id="HFE52E758281F4D0187C6E87B6C34CB33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a Residential Energy Efficiency Pay for Performance pilot program for States to encourage the use of measured energy savings, and financial payments for those energy savings, in the operation of residential energy efficiency programs. Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide common measurement criteria, developed with the input from home performance industry stakeholders, to ensure comparability among programs but allow flexibility in program design. The Secretary shall establish a competitive program with grants to be provided to no less than 5 State energy offices with a total authorization of appropriations of $100,000,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C65AA81BDA449E6AD44A6B2C407C739"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>State energy office</quote> means the office or agency of a State responsible for developing the State energy plan for the State under section 362 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6322">42 U.S.C. 6322</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


