<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H55BD9C18969F4D6094C66AFF10B95E47" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3875 EH: Department of Homeland Security CBRNE Defense Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3875</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish within the Department of Homeland Security a Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HF455E0A83C684078A8E70B98AABC859C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9B46D1133E9F426596B0222B92FBAB8F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; Table of contents</header>
<subsection id="H291A72435FDE4446BECFDF82466CF843"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security CBRNE Defense Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E506C2BDADC49BBB1E777675BD12F4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="H9B46D1133E9F426596B0222B92FBAB8F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; Table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H580BD868BC734CFA95AA80686F95E140" level="section">Sec. 2. CBRNE Office.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HBDAFF19DD4B942AC887C0FACC65E7616" level="section">Sec. 3. Chemical Division.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HC222731AB6CF43DB8403A6F04E105F39" level="section">Sec. 4. Biological Division.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HF57077F3B5DE45979561C85ED26053AB" level="section">Sec. 5. Nuclear Division.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD0C2D818984145BEAD0209748052D244" level="section">Sec. 6. Explosives Division.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H64326527AF4B43EDB1DD3EEBFE36A8F2" level="section">Sec. 7. Savings provisions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H65F704695BBA47039135CEB1B218234F" level="section">Sec. 8. Clerical amendments.</toc-entry>
</toc></subsection></section>
<section id="H580BD868BC734CFA95AA80686F95E140"><enum>2.</enum><header>CBRNE Office</header>
<subsection id="HB41B38EBBB0F48B6A825D8D97799AF2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by adding at the end the following new title:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD9ADDB5F5A74AB79FA4666C4B708F89" style="OLC"> <title id="H9E8D850B347C4B9DA6A98DC39623F0C8"><enum>XXII</enum><header>CBRNE Office</header> <subtitle id="H2D60783186E6464FA313525D8AE531B0"><enum>A</enum><header>Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office</header> <section id="H0141BEEC244147679FF182210409B87D"><enum>2201.</enum><header>Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office</header> <subsection id="H94F8FC856AAC4E24B452B885BB6875C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department a Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office (referred to in this title as the <quote>CBRNE Office</quote>). The CBRNE Office shall be comprised of the Chemical Division, the Biological Division, the Nuclear Division, and the Explosives Division. The CBRNE Office may include a Health Division.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H742C4416E4A5401B8A8F9AD8CD593FB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission of Office</header><text>The mission of the CBRNE Office is to coordinate, strengthen, and provide chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives (CBRNE) capabilities in support of homeland security.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD586A66F4EDA48F78FD00ED5D120F008"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The Office shall be headed by an Assistant Secretary for the Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office (referred to in this title as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>), who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1851295A43924B2BBB003016BE44F50A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H1C5DEF44E1B946A1919B0DC4F5C36A71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop, coordinate, and maintain overall CBRNE strategy and policy for the Department;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H93EF32FA01AE4789AF9DDC4E49583AC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop, coordinate, and maintain for the Department periodic CBRNE risk assessments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF34BD7F0876443F843FEFD71D1F0638"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serve as the primary Department representative for coordinating CBRNE activities with other Federal departments and agencies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0FA4501A5B204CB4AB6AF4C0B5585922"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide oversight for the Department’s preparedness for CBRNE threats;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DE85730087B4421BDCD5F92314EA12E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide support for operations during CBRNE threats or incidents; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFE726D5A2F274E3C8051A013D5BD8249"><enum>(6)</enum><text>carry out such other responsibilities as the Secretary determines appropriate, consistent with this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1592E85FF21D4F19AC414FC88A259EAB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Other officers</header><text>The Director of the Chemical Division, the Director of the Biological Division, the Director of the Nuclear Division, and the Director of the Explosives Division shall report directly to the Assistant Secretary.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H33E4760C1FB7457682EDCCD3F26C10E8"><enum>2202.</enum><header>Composition of the CBRNE Office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall transfer to the CBRNE Office, the functions, personnel, budget authority, and assets of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H4DAF128C90F840F9A5175D091DEBD3DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Office of Health Affairs as in existence on the day before the date of the enactment of this title, including the Chief Medical Officer authorized under section 516, and the National Biosurveillance Integration Center authorized under section 316.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H89121EB06592445480391831E52764BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Domestic Nuclear Detection Office authorized under title XIX, as in existence on the date before the date of the enactment of this title (and redesignated as the Nuclear Division).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16314421148C4A2DB2A656ED1D584578"><enum>(3)</enum><text>CBRNE threat awareness and risk assessment activities of the Science and Technology Directorate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB2471C22153B4752808437FD844F700C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The CBRNE functions of the Office of Policy and the Office of Operations Coordination.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H646A0DE2522D46569E5031D2AC5E2699"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Office for Bombing Prevention of the National Protection and Programs Directorate, as in existence on the day before the date of the enactment of this title.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HDCCC14E6EDD541718523260019F1D81C"><enum>2203.</enum><header>Hiring authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In hiring personnel for the CBRNE Office, the Secretary shall have the hiring and management authorities provided in section 1101 of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3104">5 U.S.C. 3104</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/261">Public Law 105–261</external-xref>), except that the term of appointments for employees under subsection (c)(1) of such section may not exceed 5 years before granting any extension under subsection (c)(2) of such section.</text></section> <section id="H2F781E05913F42CE8F87DA73FE52DEF5"><enum>2204.</enum><header>Grants, cooperative agreements, and other transactions and contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, in carrying out the responsibilities under this title, may distribute funds through grants, cooperative agreements, and other transactions and contracts.</text></section>
<section id="H077292B0829E49D78649E1AA370E40DB"><enum>2205.</enum><header>Terrorism risk assessments</header>
<subsection id="HD8EFBE2C405B484AAF233FF4737A8BF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Terrorism risk assessments</header>
<paragraph id="H72DDEA978AA94CF59046A0AD1E333D4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall, in coordination with relevant Department components and other appropriate Federal departments and agencies, develop, coordinate, and update periodically terrorism risk assessments of chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear threats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2677BEB75C5847D0BCACF6B3E0CD4377"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comparison</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall develop, coordinate, and update periodically an integrated terrorism risk assessment that assesses all of the threats referred to in paragraph (1) and, as appropriate, explosives threats, and compares each such threat against one another according to their relative risk.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7F5AAB946FB14E588927B68728F7557F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion in assessment</header><text>Each terrorism risk assessment under this subsection shall include a description of the methodology used for each such assessment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H948197A8EF6E4236AD7746240B709155"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Each terrorism risk assessment under this subsection shall be updated not less often than once every 2 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H89005BD31FAE438280F94CC505A932B4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Provision to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall provide a copy of each risk assessment under this subsection to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate not later than 30 days after completion of each such assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC62B2D3970A48EF87EAC59C676EF32F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text>In developing the terrorism risk assessments under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with appropriate Federal departments and agencies, shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H3D62669DBCBF4042AFE73E3348F9F217"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the proposed methodology to be used for such assessments; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H52EF31C35ED140F4A60E8BC876D9E6FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the evolving threat to the United States as indicated by the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFE84E8ADBC3B4DD68BF78CCED8E1E890"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Usage</header><text>The terrorism risk assessments required under subsection (a) shall be used to inform and guide allocation of resources for chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear threat activities of the Department.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE359BB0A529A49D9AE37FEA39A7F42AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Input and sharing</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall, for each terrorism risk assessment under subsection (a)—</text>
<paragraph id="H3F06113017FE49DFA4005986E644A4CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek input from national stakeholders and other Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial officials involved in efforts to counter chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear threats;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAF0E37D4C6C4DBD941D0703E88931F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that written procedures are in place to guide the development of such assessments, including for input, review, and implementation purposes, among relevant Federal partners;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65840A343CBD4FC8BC1145AE84C0A088"><enum>(3)</enum><text>share such assessments with Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial officials with appropriate security clearances and a need for the information in the classified versions of such assessments; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H708DBF404EEC42BA84F3D798B1BBA6CE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, make available an unclassified version of such assessments for Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial officials involved in prevention and preparedness for chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear events.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H64B23273C54F44E3BC1B9A95F67A0C52"><enum>2206.</enum><header>CBRNE communications and public messaging</header>
<subsection id="HE9F504DBFB524F199ACF7251975CA4D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary, shall develop an overarching risk communication strategy for terrorist attacks and other high consequence events utilizing chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear agents or explosives that pose a high risk to homeland security, and shall—</text> <paragraph id="HAED29C363B6541799233E1E7CAEEE357"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop threat-specific risk communication plans, in coordination with appropriate Federal departments and agencies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFEB4688179B84B74B96EE79A1E0FDB32"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop risk communication messages, including pre-scripted messaging to the extent practicable;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F82AB59C8234E30ABC20AB96CC4673E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop clearly defined interagency processes and protocols to assure coordinated risk and incident communications and information sharing during incident response;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEAF56F969562462BB33613CB6EFBB078"><enum>(4)</enum><text>engage private and nongovernmental entities in communications planning, as appropriate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BDF1758AF4847A1A127460A681B4F38"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify ways to educate and engage the public about CBRNE threats and consequences;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3FDEF271959B456598CC17E39B7D1E5F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop strategies for communicating using social and new media; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB72EA19262EB4EB4B26AE18A8367971C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide guidance on risk and incident communications for CBRNE events to State, local, tribal, and territorial governments, and other stakeholders, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H716430F576AC4F35827980CFD520FC47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Communication during response</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide appropriate timely, accurate information to the public, governmental partners, the private sector, and other appropriate stakeholders in the event of a suspected or confirmed terrorist attack or other high consequence event utilizing chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear agents or explosives that pose a high risk to homeland security.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF076372151504260A9A3AC4F4E62321E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H1A8E1240DE4C43249ABD5D8CAD5694AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development efforts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this title, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on current and future efforts of the Department to develop the communication strategy required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2205796CADE648B6BFA000BE7645F45B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Finalization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date the report required under paragraph (1) is submitted, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate the communication strategy required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H935528E107824857BB9685B0B7FDBFC8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2207.</enum><header> Chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives intelligence and information sharing</header> <subsection id="H73BC0095502B450FA3A9C20F411C75CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H39DAD3E5A2F14F70AAB68152FF6B755F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support homeland security-focused intelligence analysis of terrorist actors, their claims, and their plans to conduct attacks involving chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear materials or explosives against the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D2A3FEA9BD94184A6091700A6CF7CA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support homeland security-focused intelligence analysis of global infectious diseases, public health, food, agricultural, and veterinary issues;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8D0FB46771774986B4690078F0705234"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support homeland security-focused risk analysis and risk assessments of the homeland security hazards described in paragraphs (1) and (2) by providing relevant quantitative and nonquantitative threat information;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FE4FBDB731D401DAD258323695BCA01"><enum>(4)</enum><text>leverage existing and emerging homeland security intelligence capabilities and structures to enhance prevention, protection, response, and recovery efforts with respect to a chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, or explosives attack;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2D42A5663D91440DB4107447FAD3C64A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>share appropriate information regarding such threats to appropriate State, local, tribal, and territorial authorities, as well as other national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC095E14B018544A78834EC4238CF79F2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>perform other responsibilities, as assigned by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H991F27C778C342659A17BE6BD255A217"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>Where appropriate, the Under Secretary of Intelligence and Analysis shall coordinate with the heads of other relevant Department components, including the Assistant Secretary, members of the intelligence community, including the National Counter Proliferation Center and the National Counterterrorism Center, and other Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial authorities, including officials from high-threat areas, to enable such entities to provide recommendations on optimal information sharing mechanisms, including expeditious sharing of classified information, and on how such entities can provide information to the Department.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A5C67D2F20647FB93299A4298D52E71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="HA7E3605B90754201851EB1986EC0A581"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4DD9686152FC4536ACE5497D8D6CC470"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the intelligence and information sharing activities under subsections (a) and (b) and of all relevant entities within the Department to prevent, protect against, prepare for, respond to, mitigate, and recover from terrorist attacks and other high consequence events utilizing chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear agents or explosives that pose a high risk to homeland security; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51DB07AB9E16408E9D67D1BA442F28E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department’s activities in accordance with relevant intelligence strategies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3F2575841F9413BA8B8B35CA899F074"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment of implementation</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall also include—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0708C43A43E41EA9B6AA1F8ABC06057"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of methods established to assess progress of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis in implementing this section; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5FF5502331514BA095912DDFB5B205E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such assessment of such progress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAF992A96C43B410485B77BF57C10AAFA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H81EB8378A93441D48DC52176B93CC074"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BE8EADC92E8431B9F0E20BFC29B856B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders</header><text>The term <term>national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders</term> means officials from Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial authorities and individuals from the private sector who are involved in efforts to prevent, protect against, prepare for, respond to, mitigate, and recover from a biological attack or other phenomena that may have serious health consequences for the United States, including infectious disease outbreaks.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H082EA1CB14BF44699CB8F5DC0CD44638"><enum>(b)</enum><header>After action and efficiencies review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Assistant Secretary for the Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office of the Department of Homeland Security (established pursuant to section 2201 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a) of this section), shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that—</text> <paragraph id="H5F122F03B488485B9AD19F958D525EEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reviews the functions and responsibilities of the Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office of the Department (established pursuant to section 2201 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a) of this section) to identify and eliminate areas of unnecessary duplication;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H67DD48795F6247F394CBC39A0C2CB56E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides a detailed accounting of the management and administrative expenditures and activities of the Office, including expenditures related to the establishment of the CBRNE Office, such as expenditures associated with the utilization of the Secretary’s authority to award retention bonuses pursuant to Federal law;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA564052520664C7FBE6BC4846DBF7E34"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies any potential cost savings and efficiencies within the CBRNE Office or its divisions; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H374E87ABD67248A1A3B7FA677DD8D6C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifies opportunities to enhance the effectiveness of the management and administration of the CBRNE Office to improve operational impact and enhance efficiencies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H189DDF2768764206B1B5D3FAE07B40F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB306B5B23F8D4365927A8E48C04DA179"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall assess the organizational structure of the management and execution of the Department of Homeland Security’s chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities, and shall develop and submit to the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate at the time the President submits the budget under section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, for the fiscal year that follows the issuance of the Comptroller General review required pursuant to subsection (d) a proposed organizational structure for the management and execution of such chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD86CBE98969F4C768E02AC23CE56D1EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organizational justification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall include in the assessment required under paragraph (1) a thorough justification and rationalization for the proposed organizational structure for management and execution of chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H6D81AFC8FA1149EA8E409AC6CAA6AAA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A discussion of the methodology for determining such proposed organizational structure.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE5B077B0EFAE49DEB6E0B28715C82C16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A comprehensive inventory of chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities of the Department of Homeland Security and where each such activity will be located within or outside such proposed organizational structure.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB93B424821B40EBA97647373F1DA0CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Information relating to how such proposed organizational structure will facilitate and promote coordination and requirements generation with customers.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H57BFD433A64848A8BCCC18BCFFF34EF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to how such proposed organizational structure will support the development of chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development priorities across the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H54FAC92C133A4CEFB5E9C933417ACCC1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>If the chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities of the Department are not co-located in such proposed organizational structure, a justification for such separation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4B88D54C454C49728827374C37CE7100"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The strategy for coordination between the Under Secretary for Science and Technology and the Assistant Secretary for the Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office on chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFEF12B120D80430194905698890E3311"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Recommendations for necessary statutory changes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H96E214DE569A4CA1A54E5C2B137C0515"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may not take any action to reorganize the structure referred to in paragraph (1) unless the Secretary receives prior authorization from the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate permitting any such action.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4172B068C7CD403FAC9CBF96984D4261"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office review of chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities</header> <paragraph id="H1107340768064C60BC1CA1AAE0C3E1C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the organizational structure of the Department of Homeland Security’s management and execution of chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE49CB9B887F64F499E3E44A30D657F77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The review required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H7AC9572DD1A745C5A78DEFD4B1B53866"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the organizational structure for the management and execution of chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities of the Department of Homeland Security, including identification of any overlap or duplication of effort.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC12ED82174C94E7B970F22775003FD67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recommendations to streamline and improve the organizational structure of the Department’s management and execution of chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives research and development activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FE43E0E89DA450BB7F8B2FB8F6FAA08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the review required under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCD321E0DDE4041A6B89F02AF03EC4958"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Dissemination of information analyzed by the Department of Homeland Security to State, local, tribal, and private entities with responsibilities relating to homeland security</header><text>Paragraph (8) of section 201(d) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and to agencies of State</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>to State, local, tribal, territorial, and appropriate private entities with such responsibilities, and, as appropriate, to the public, in order to assist in preventing, protecting against, preparing for, responding to, mitigating, and recovering from terrorist attacks against the United States.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6A48BB609A894567A94B9306FDE121FE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HC4A908EF736A4A91AD340C14EB961252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) of section 103(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/113">6 U.S.C. 113(a)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Assistant Secretary for Health Affairs, the Assistant Secretary for Legislative Affairs, or the Assistant Secretary for Public Affairs,</quote> and inserting <quote>Assistant Secretary for Legislative Affairs or the Assistant Secretary for Public Affairs,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE5873CCDA214408A8D5818C61B6EDC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 302 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/182">6 U.S.C. 182</external-xref>)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA2C0FC41C0EE480AA705AAE7D07049C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (13) and (14) as paragraphs (14) and (15), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACD032ABFE664C548FFB90F293698853"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (12) the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B9014296FA14F358DC5053D5E00E5DE" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HA6415715FF0B41F0ADCB9BC52E50D50F"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborating with the Assistant Secretary for the Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office on all chemical, biological, and explosives research and development activities;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9A078A92D61427690096008707D67DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b) of section 307 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/187">6 U.S.C. 187</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block id="H3532EC9F80B241828FEA476597A19F81" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H91E6675FFCE54A0FAFD1B2853B7FF0A4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>CBRNE defense</header><text>The Director shall coordinate with the Assistant Secretary for the Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office on all chemical, biological, and explosives research and development activities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD83FD2F74B4544139731B906EA441019"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c) of section 516 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321e">6 U.S.C. 321e</external-xref>)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H475A2D000CBD4CF9B27CD2991E459D69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, including the health impacts of chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear agents and explosives</quote> after <quote>natural disasters</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32B9A909DA554E26BE9D2A3323602BE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7CB35C279A2465A86D6C95B6D7C3E7D" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H1AD1805B8AEC43D5A5E3CEDBCAA27E36"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating the Department’s policy, strategy, and preparedness for pandemics and emerging infectious diseases;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C61616C6F834F2E95EAD406F02C0E54"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>Under Secretary for Science and Technology</quote> and inserting <quote>Assistant Secretary for the Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HBDAFF19DD4B942AC887C0FACC65E7616"><enum>3.</enum><header>Chemical Division</header>
<subsection id="HE37BF4D0CD1E4843BC17E80D036AA2C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 2 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D6949D0B6AD4F2B91F86BB429FC5787" style="OLC"> <subtitle id="H1AA95C14B9EA4FBABC8B485774208B18"><enum>B</enum><header>Chemical Division</header> <section id="HA1D66DC38B064D068246648B28F18545"><enum>2211.</enum><header>Chemical Division</header> <subsection id="H334914878BC5453F9CBF5F386223EA03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the CBRNE Office a Chemical Division, headed by a Director of the Chemical Division (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDFC2A056805846238E2F69F059229162"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission and responsibilities</header><text>The Director shall be responsible for coordinating departmental strategy and policy relating to terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing chemical agents that pose a high risk to homeland security, including the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9C59AFF29EA0414E99A65FD0B898CE63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing and maintaining the Department’s strategy against chemical threats.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H36C9D068E1C9495E80390D8FD765B548"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Serving as the Department representative for chemical threats and related activities with other Federal departments and agencies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H246B9CF2F9974C94897D427E9536F589"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing oversight of the Department’s preparedness, including operational requirements, for chemical threats.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF050A5FC58CD4F0CB5A7DBD82628D18F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Enhancing the capabilities of Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial governments, and private entities as appropriate, against chemical threats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FA2458ACC2D456F8E53069545DA9C84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Evaluating and providing guidance to Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial governments, and private entities as appropriate, on detection and communication technology that could be effective in terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing chemical agents.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1B056BB82F904F089D3AA13757AA808F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Supporting and enhancing the effective sharing and use of appropriate information generated by the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>)), law enforcement agencies, other Federal, State, local tribal, and territorial governments, and foreign governments, on chemical threats.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HDE5B32F10FC744349C384F709D872A94"><enum>2212.</enum><header>Demonstration projects</header> <subsection id="HCA3D03FC22914CAAB48E3AA9365FA945"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may, subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, partner with high-risk urban areas or facilities to conduct demonstration projects to enhance, through Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial governments, and private entities, capabilities of the United States to counter terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing chemical agents that pose a high risk to homeland security.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H67F78A9941CC41449D952D4C898E811E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The Director may provide guidance and evaluations for all situations and venues at risk of terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing chemical agents, such as at ports, areas of mass gathering, and transit facilities, and may—</text> <paragraph id="HFFE06374E5534167883728CA1B7F4B92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure all high-risk situations and venues are studied; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H896056F538284889B54E20DC18130118"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure key findings and best practices are made available to State, local, tribal, and territorial governments and the private sector.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8A02B3EA7E424A66A1660FB1395DD6F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>The Director shall notify the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate not later than 30 days before initiating a new demonstration project.</text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HE631F7F18CDC46CDAFD28C0996531A7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate an assessment of the Department of Homeland Security’s programs and activities related to terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing chemical agents that pose a high risk to homeland security.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC222731AB6CF43DB8403A6F04E105F39"><enum>4.</enum><header>Biological Division</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 2 of this Act and as amended by section 3 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text>
<quoted-block id="H5668E1F85CFF4E15941C11BA52C35087" style="OLC">
<subtitle id="H286CE77EAAEF4631A11C3C1275524F17"><enum>C</enum><header>Biological Division</header>
<section id="H329797FD31B5494CBAD0FC2FFAF29C10"><enum>2221.</enum><header>Biological Division</header>
<subsection id="H53BAB4F08C9F48A2814F2EA64F138084"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the CBRNE Office a Biological Division, headed by a Director of the Biological Division (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0660DA6B4B7E49EF939B14740CD66D2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission and responsibilities</header><text>The Office shall be responsible for coordinating departmental strategy and policy relating to terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing biological agents that pose a high risk to homeland security, including the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H1F4B1B69260A4463BD6F703FD92A7C3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing and maintaining the Department’s strategy against biological threats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3AD1EFE5D4B84A139216B0DC6A5C89CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Serving as the Department representative for biological threats and related activities with other Federal departments and agencies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H78293A05BAD647A1B0CF9E41C85A4AA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing oversight for the Department’s preparedness, including operational requirements, for biological threats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5D3613B9FC3439FA2B2B7EA0717551F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhancing the capabilities of Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial governments, and private entities as appropriate, against biological threats.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H491529E231684EF4AF3A4A532AFFBFC5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supporting and enhancing the effective sharing and use of appropriate information generated by the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>)), law enforcement agencies, other Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial governments, and foreign governments, on biological threats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2794D7F3F2F456282C0A575348A29AB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Achieving a biological detection program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F60EED6C24F45CC8EA2CD557F4A6150"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Maintaining the National Biosurveillance Integration Center, authorized under section 316.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HF57077F3B5DE45979561C85ED26053AB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Nuclear Division</header> <subsection id="H98EF2350BF3542B2B2C8166B595C1F0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 2 of this Act and as amended by sections 3 and 4 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H259CB1A97FF44558A5C3CC785200BA38" style="OLC">
<subtitle id="H11EB6BDD30C1465D8911F143F4F16CE6"><enum>D</enum><header>Nuclear Division</header>
<section id="HCF69CA40C1CE4EF88E056FADC19486BE"><enum>2231.</enum><header>Nuclear Division</header>
<subsection commented="no" id="HEE166D1FC0EE4C8DB29AFC1C025AE04F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall include within the CBRNE Office the Nuclear Division under title XIX, headed by the Director of the Nuclear Division (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) pursuant to section 1901.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE99C896EED6F45A1AAA759B9D018CA85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission and responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities specified in title XIX, the Director shall also be responsible for coordinating departmental strategy and policy relating to terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing nuclear or other radiological materials, and for coordinating Federal efforts to detect and protect against the unauthorized importation, possession, storage, transportation, development, or use of a nuclear explosive device, fissile material, or radiological material in the United States, and to protect against an attack using such devices or materials against the people, territory, or interests of the United States, in accordance with title XIX.</text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H8F9831D3F29F4675BFE7FD28C09A3344"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Title XIX of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2686E6A156BA4861965F71F2E4430F6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the title heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="title" style="OLC">Domestic Nuclear Detection Office</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="title" style="OLC">Nuclear Division</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE6C3BFF029414877A8082873F1B2796A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1901 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/591">6 U.S.C. 591</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1BE8140C2F7B45CB9A1A00BD30B42562"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Domestic Nuclear Detection Office</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Nuclear Division</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEA2B9DD55EF1476D9FEB6BE566E03B7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>There shall be established in the Department a Domestic Nuclear Detection Office</quote> and inserting <quote>There is in the Department a Nuclear Division, located in the CBRNE Office</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H519638184F2844CEB24ECD8A86BBB983"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>Director for Domestic Nuclear Detection, who shall be appointed by the President</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Nuclear Division</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H560B2149525144FD81C12DE6F3E4E22A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (a) of section 1902 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/592">6 U.S.C. 592</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C088F206F1D4D46A943DE148E4B5926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text>
<clause id="H9AE6A49B729046D782AF4D2B9E6A11B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>responsible for</quote> the following: <quote>coordinating departmental strategy and policy relating to terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing nuclear or other radiological materials, and for</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAA99D0149969411CADB9727D84D78335"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>to protect</quote> and inserting <quote>protecting</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4D30248A4E164D2EA4569A920EDAAC04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Domestic Nuclear Detection Office</quote> and inserting <quote>Nuclear Division</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2D1EE34795F4EEDB30B64E96CC0B2B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by repealing section 1903 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/593">6 U.S.C. 593</external-xref>);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2A81A1A0CC6049BC9E072B5796C2AE6A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 1906 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/596">6 U.S.C. 596</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6F56599B53BB4CBCA73E55AC0164838C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text>
<clause id="H4B5F65D6E3844C7FB4D773156721045C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Domestic Nuclear Detection</quote> and inserting <quote>the Nuclear Division</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE78323A133F24CD5A9D2FC8AB938247C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>paragraphs (6) and (7) of</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9A060DD567FD424FAFE662B968F7E113"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>paragraphs (6) and (7) of</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E657E63E7A74E6282D45756269EAB89"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 1907 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/596a">6 U.S.C. 596a</external-xref>)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2DCB5A5FBA6C4E298D8A89B3FB31FC9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Annual</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Biennial</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3BAED98BF984BDBAC1EA8BCE4C45B36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>each year</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>every 2 years</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4158F35FA07A46C68C1B30262EE9264E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>previous year</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>previous 2 years</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H525D2796B5CC4F62A010C31FEB2CD469"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading of subsection (a), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Annual</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Biennial</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1785F78AB60544FDBD790E1B29070826"><enum>(E)</enum><text>subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="H3A963B18D06545D385BFF9F56611FFC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Annual</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Biennial</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause>
<clause id="HFFF11B7C00334F3EAA506B208958269D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>odd-numbered</quote> after <quote>each</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7726C61407584A77AF4E3D6D43A35C67"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>annual</quote> and inserting <quote>biennial</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDC2F120123BD469BB4D73E393A041CEF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B99D4495CA04BF08B6B6A2E1709B222" style="OLC"> <section id="H4E904FB9DD364EA6AAAF5F340FE23739"><enum>1908.</enum><header>Domestic implementation of the global nuclear detection architecture</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out the mission of the Office under subparagraph (A) of section 1902(a)(4), the Director of the Nuclear Division shall provide support for planning, organization, equipment, training, exercises, and operational assessments to Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial governments to assist such governments in implementing radiological and nuclear detection capabilities in the event of terrorist attacks or other high-consequence events utilizing nuclear or other radiological materials that pose a high risk to homeland security. Such capabilities shall be integrated into the enhanced global nuclear detection architecture referred to in such section 1902(a)(4), and shall inform and be guided by architecture studies, technology needs, and research activities of the Office.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HC7F9C2FF665A4D55A91662EDBC65187B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, or rule to the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office or the Director for Domestic Nuclear Detection of the Department of Homeland Security shall be deemed to be a reference to the Nuclear Division or the Director of the Nuclear Division, respectively, of the Department.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD0C2D818984145BEAD0209748052D244"><enum>6.</enum><header>Explosives Division</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 2 of this Act and as amended by sections 3, 4, and 5 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43424B7DD6B24718AD92B4968AE6B7FA" style="OLC">
<subtitle id="HD9ACE61EC66A4812A9A5D2D738E4FC7A"><enum>E</enum><header>Explosives Division</header>
<section id="H4B93A073964E4283A9CA865D38B14F6C"><enum>2241.</enum><header>Explosives Division</header>
<subsection id="H5599CEB983E748C38C96F3B10943F06F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the CBRNE Office an Explosives Division, headed by a Director of the Explosives Division (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF687BB0CAF84486197D4165008DEAE7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission and responsibilities</header><text>The Director shall be responsible for coordinating departmental strategy and policy relating to terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing explosives that pose a high risk to homeland security, including the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H9DF1E834818F40EC8F71A3B6BA12C53B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing and maintaining the Department’s strategy against explosives threats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H646853B5D1164CD3A3CB7369847CE27D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Serving as the Department representative for explosives threats and related activities with other Federal departments and agencies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H57F9372D186845B99B232E236D3131AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing oversight of the Department’s preparedness, including operational requirements, for explosives threats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H342BD95C082F45798B581DD621CC2D02"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhancing the capabilities of Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial governments, and private entities as appropriate, to counter terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing explosives.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HF886B96AD8744F32A3EFD930C52C8CA8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evaluating and providing guidance to Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial governments and appropriate private entities on detection and communication technology that could be effective during terrorist attacks or other high-consequence events utilizing explosives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB455B7FFFC034BD8B27C945A1BC54E52"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supporting and enhancing the effective sharing and use of appropriate information generated by the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>)), law enforcement agencies, other Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial government agencies, and foreign governments, on explosives threats.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H64326527AF4B43EDB1DD3EEBFE36A8F2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Savings provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall change the authority of the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to lead the emergency management system of the United States. Nothing in this Act shall alter the responsibility of the Chief Medical Officer of the Department of Homeland Security to serve as the principal advisor to the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency on medical and public health issues pursuant to paragraph (1) of section 516(c) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321e">6 U.S.C. 321e(c)</external-xref>).</text></section> <section id="H65F704695BBA47039135CEB1B218234F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H6E39BB537EFF4F41A229C14007EDD0EA"><enum>(1) </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the item relating to title XIX and inserting the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65EE1007BC7148A28A8460D46B0144FD" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="title">TITLE XIX—NUCLEAR DIVISION</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6C6EB59424941B3BDB045028819C8EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 1901 and inserting the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7198475C8A2E45D4BA61C445425D2B85" style="OLC">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1901. Nuclear Division.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7FA0158287BB427AB5EA1309C0E5FACC"><enum>(3) </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the item relating to section 1903;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02BB931C14BD42939F4DACDF6A3206C5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding after the item relating to section 1907 the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H187C2291E5AF49029F087DC3D487998B" style="OLC">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1908. Domestic Implementation of the global nuclear detection architecture.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D2F426343D84012A2EA955DB19D8E7E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9BE046A67CD46B298BEEC989CCAFCEB" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="title">Title XXII—CBRNE Office</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2201. Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, and Explosives Office.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2202. Composition of the CBRNE Office.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2203. Hiring authority.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2204. Grants, cooperative agreements, and other transactions and contracts.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2205. Terrorism risk assessments.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2206. CBRNE communications and public messaging.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2207. Chemical, biological, radiological, nuclear, and explosives intelligence and information sharing.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6211675F67F4881BBF7827417FDD8C0" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Chemical Division</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2211. Chemical Division.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2212. Demonstration projects.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H252729B2E0DA4182A5CB9EC2914F656D" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Biological Division</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2221. Biological Division.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AC6401CFAC34EF896235C5E773F9ADD" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle D—Nuclear Division</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2231. Nuclear Division.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC98D4CB7A7E246319F5A258245B7144C" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle E—Explosives Division</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2241. Explosives Division.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20151210" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 10, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

