<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H883F929309894B80BADE4161BCB0C8D6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4272 IH: Support the Families of Fallen Heroes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4272</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151216">December 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the issuance of a Families of Fallen Heroes Semipostal Stamp.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0F1828EA567D4C35955B25025389B03A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDF0B878D51BA48A2A34B70FE70EC2D72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support the Families of Fallen Heroes Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H326645D880B64F069D7BC3A85C85A0BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Families of Fallen Heroes Semipostal Stamp</header> <subsection id="H8CE68DC06C3241CD9050176D1B0D0595"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to afford a convenient way for members of the public to contribute to funding for programs benefitting the families of fallen service members, the United States Postal Service shall issue a semipostal stamp (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Families of Fallen Heroes Semipostal Stamp</quote>) in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H251319BF30BC4E9CAEC36CC3E8E7A44A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
 <paragraph id="H5E7061D72FEF4BF9AE80F5C286DCCD19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The issuance and sale of the Families of Fallen Heroes Semipostal Stamp under this section shall be governed by the provisions of section 416 of title 39, United States Code, and regulations issued under such section, subject to the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD528F77B7E9F4E7293129CBBC050ADF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Families of Fallen Heroes Semipostal Stamp shall be made available to the public for a period of 4 years, beginning no later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3D927BA06E9F4EA2A9657899239E1823"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disposition of proceeds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After costs have been recovered by the United States Postal Service pursuant to section 416(d)(5) of title 39, United States Code, any amounts becoming available from the sale of the Families of Fallen Heroes Semipostal Stamp (as determined under section 416(d) of such title) shall be transferred, through payments which shall be made at least twice a year, as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBDEBE044A1B44C1A86EDF7AE27E373D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>50 percent of such amounts shall be transferred to the Tragedy Assistance Program for Survivors.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H472EE432E7804D74AD2BA9AADE624C0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>50 percent of such amounts shall be transferred to the Families of the Fallen support program of the United Service Organizations, Inc.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E6687D51C7D41F5AF5EFDF3C13B9FCC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tragedy Assistance Program for Survivors and Families of the Fallen support program of the United Service Organizations, Inc., shall be deemed to be agencies for purposes of applying section 416(d)(1) of title 39, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF937818EEF274BF6B9A359C312B6BDB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>semipostal stamp</quote> refers to a stamp described in section 416(a)(1) of title 39, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

