<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA608A3D302104022B4A75F31AFD9682F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 845 IH: National Forest System Trails Stewardship Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 845</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to publish in the Federal Register a strategy to significantly increase the role of volunteers and partners in National Forest System trail maintenance, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H52969A1AB65144A7B9D89DDFE1991DA8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HECEF6BCECAAE4ECC9293B7B278D6E9FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HCA75D6BC10294D11A20886606F5D953E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Forest System Trails Stewardship Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9258221330BE4663AB346E2077B6A01A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HECEF6BCECAAE4ECC9293B7B278D6E9FC" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H1456D10EAC0E460BADA3F2F168D82119" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCA53A8C7BB1442EE873979062B8F6C45" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE16E1A69338D421EA32F540313D1E4A5" level="section">Sec. 4. National forest system trails volunteer and partnership strategy.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9439C2D9B3924BFE8B7FCCB19BB75234" level="section">Sec. 5. Priority trail maintenance program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2F252E6F08C84CA08620C45C0DAFE5C9" level="section">Sec. 6. Cooperative agreements.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC92121B7CE074437BB112FB152E014E6" level="section">Sec. 7. Stewardship credits for outfitters and guides.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1456D10EAC0E460BADA3F2F168D82119"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HDB18917E165D40088D0768C04F7F8124"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Forest System features a world-class trail system with over 157,000 miles of trails that provide world-class opportunities for hiking, horseback riding, hunting, mountain bicycling, motorized vehicles, and other outdoor activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE77DB6EF4DF846B28BB4B8EC0E9E9A9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the Government Accountability Office, the Forest Service is only able to maintain about one-quarter of National Forest System trails to the agency standard, and the agency faces a trail maintenance backlog of $314,000,000, and an additional backlog of $210,000,000 in annual maintenance, capital improvements, and operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6422117FD784CE488008628B96F4697"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The lack of maintenance on National Forest System trails threatens access to public lands, and may cause increased environmental damage, threaten public safety, and increase future maintenance costs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0DC89582714743AFB8E83C3CDEB0A6B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Federal budget limitations require solutions to National Forest System trail maintenance issues that make more efficient use of existing resources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36B9F77B641E4560A8B1B4BDCE4357FD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Volunteers, partners, and outfitters and guides play an important role in maintaining National Forest System trails, and a comprehensive strategy is needed to ensure that volunteers and partners are used as effectively as possible.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCA53A8C7BB1442EE873979062B8F6C45"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HA5124B93A648467897ABC1B3AE7817E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrative unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrative Unit</term> means a national forest or national grassland.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDED146C7304C44868BA8CBD0ED0FD16A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outfitter or guide</header><text>The term <term>outfitter or guide</term> means an individual, organization, or business who provides outfitting or guiding services, as defined in section 251.51 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82FFA19749434EF49BF0E37571B6BCEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Partner</header><text>The term <term>partner</term> means a non-Federal entity that engages in a partnership.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63AD4FA8F1C442FAA609217F78464FA1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text>The term <term>partnership</term> means arrangements between the Department of Agriculture or the Forest Service and a non-Federal entity that are voluntary, mutually beneficial, and entered into for the purpose of mutually agreed upon objectives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36E01274E860407DA3041DADE8CB962E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Priority area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>priority area</term> means a well-defined region on National Forest System land selected by the Secretary under section 5(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1ED1A3C741674A7F8B00E3D5654C04C2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9F6D2A9D9F543E48A5669622D37EEA1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The term <term>strategy</term> means the National Forest System Trails Volunteer and Partnership Strategy authorized by section 4(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0E6D62ACE5B429DA54AC8B38C189285"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Trail maintenance</header><text>The term <term>trail maintenance</term> means any activity to maintain the usability and sustainability of trails within the National Forest System, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H34589D61599B44BF8B2227897E8CEC12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensuring trails are passable by the users for which they are managed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0186E25279164724A2AAFEFE1EA8B52B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>preventing environmental damage resulting from trail deterioration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BCF4FF2DFCD4E42A37A4F3F18E04D86"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protecting public safety; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C8D8C67A16846DF92A126F3D0C06014"><enum>(D)</enum><text>averting future deferred maintenance costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A25D3AC7AE7404B9FE676F21B4DAB23"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Volunteer</header><text>The term <term>Volunteer</term> has the same meaning given that term in section 553.101 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE16E1A69338D421EA32F540313D1E4A5"><enum>4.</enum><header>National forest system trails volunteer and partnership strategy</header> 
<subsection id="H0947946BE9BE427F93FF035A39341499"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a strategy to significantly increase the role of volunteers and partners in trail maintenance.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE9C569F608EE48D38B925FFA9598556D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required elements</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCAC9636E9523499CAFC8CFB33E1FCA61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>augment and support the capabilities of Federal employees to carry out or contribute to trail maintenance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38609FD78A5F4E7E875AB867DC53910F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide meaningful opportunities for volunteers and partners to carry out trail maintenance in each region of the Forest Service;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1AD3900F873437DBAEF98BD91961F03"><enum>(3)</enum><text>address the barriers to increased volunteerism and partnerships in trail maintenance identified by volunteers, partners, and others;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H888A83DDD8EC4EAB9B6B138F165F00DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prioritize increased volunteerism and partnerships in trail maintenance in those regions with the most severe trail maintenance needs, and where trail maintenance backlogs are jeopardizing access to National Forest lands; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04DE13415B7E40D99027390503DB36D5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>aim to increase trail maintenance by volunteers and partners by 100 percent by the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H72C0E66948304BC8B66F6C1D5C40DC70"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>As a component of the strategy, the Secretary shall study opportunities to improve trail maintenance by addressing opportunities to use fire crews in trail maintenance activities in a manner that does not jeopardize firefighting capabilities, public safety, or resource protection. Upon a determination that trail maintenance would be advanced by use of fire crews in trail maintenance, the Secretary shall incorporate these proposals into the strategy, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be necessary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD4A04E2080F4A2BBEB7A1092050356A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Volunteer liability</header>
<paragraph id="H33C0DA06A0AF4DB7AF45E06C9B92D17E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(d) of the Volunteers in the National Forests Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/558c">16 U.S.C. 558c(d)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including a volunteer affiliated with a partner organization,</quote> after <quote>this Act</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE60C44DCC534471CBECB910A2222BDBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall adopt regulations implementing this section. These regulations shall ensure that the financial risk from claims or liability associated with volunteers undertaking trail maintenance is shared by all administrative units.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H38872BDF93C54401AB4F6B04F793F121"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop the strategy in consultation with volunteer and partner trail maintenance organizations, a broad array of outdoor recreation stakeholders, and other relevant stakeholders.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H844ADE6EAECA464B8E014B0FE286FF0A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Volunteer and partnership coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall require each administrative unit to develop a volunteer and partner coordination implementation plan for the strategy which clearly defines roles and responsibilities for the administrative unit and district staff, and includes strategies to ensure sufficient coordination, assistance, and support for volunteers and partners to improve trail maintenance.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3CC3574426444A53988C04434B356121"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HFBCCF4B5FFE54E1FB79433405047F4F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Secretary shall prepare a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="HDC0CF7AB838B49178C391D90D0793696"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the strategy in addressing the trail maintenance backlog;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFF86D76186F479F974F8F42510CE6D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the increase in volunteerism and partnership efforts on trail maintenance as a result of the strategy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79C612AA51A147AE959D1BA1D19066F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the miles of National Forest System trails maintained by volunteers and partners, and the approximate value of the volunteer and partnership efforts;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF9D9BDAEEF949EBAAF4E80244FB0A54"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the status of the stewardship credits for outfitters and guides pilot program described in section 7 that includes the number of participating sites, total amount of the credits offered, estimated value of trail maintenance performed, and suggestions for revising the program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCB3FA29BF9744149E00A00DA3BE412B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommendations for further increasing volunteerism and partnerships in trail maintenance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04FA6C19866A43EDA3EEEE3D32E2A233"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit the report required by paragraph (1) to—</text> <subparagraph id="H5CDE0D7A7F7645C18CD4F7FDAC8F0AFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC568E45F4F824076885F6D40CD62FFBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9439C2D9B3924BFE8B7FCCB19BB75234" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Priority trail maintenance program</header> <subsection id="H074AB79E50E949048A195B49720290C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>In accordance with subsections (b) and (c), not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall select no fewer than 9 and no more than 15 priority areas for increased trail maintenance accomplishments.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H962294A2FAE84462BE79CEBE8FA20438"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Priority areas shall include a well-defined region on National Forest System land where the lack of trail maintenance has—</text> <paragraph id="H4C08764E6707484BB4E608096AB8DFDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduced access to public land;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC10C6BE34DCC40BDAE26CDE5270ABF3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>led to an increase, or risk of increase, in harm to natural resources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20BE624CBED74A5986E182A579E6D034"><enum>(3)</enum><text>jeopardized public safety;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18BE38EDDA5140AE9E49DC6A74168984"><enum>(4)</enum><text>resulted in trails being impassible by the intended managed users; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FBFB3ADB34244CBA0507BE6B7CC8371"><enum>(5)</enum><text>increased future deferred trail maintenance costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0CFA17B83ED045A4B786A4431A96FE21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In selecting priority areas, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HCFC7F7BFB85242759CC910CB463806C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consider any public input on priority areas received within 3 months of the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58DD4963ECAD42A5B41A732BAE7AA82E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the range of trail users (including motorized and non-motorized trail users); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H357D23D77A9C46EE9C91D83A35D971F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include at least one priority area in each region of the United States Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1C9482CC416C48F98A87287E494FA5FF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Increased trail maintenance</header> 
<paragraph id="H8FBAA8090C184464916EEA21D746835F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Within 6 months of the selection of priority areas under subsection (a), and in accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary shall develop an approach to substantially increase trail maintenance accomplishments within each priority area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8799450968543539345DA7A57B67179"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In developing the approach under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H245B7CEBAB0D49A3A1515D21AD1C3D8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider any public input on trail maintenance priorities and needs within any priority area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39286BCA4D664A239A165648EA947DF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider the costs and benefits of increased trail maintenance within each priority area; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDC60F28BF414F288FA56D03F2572D6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incorporate partners and volunteers in the trail maintenance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C371A6DF1BA489BB27FB818B90AF61D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required trail maintenance</header><text>Utilizing the approach developed under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall substantially increase trail maintenance within each priority area.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H56954F3482484EFCB2F96DD667DB828A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The regional volunteer and partnership coordinators may be responsible for assisting partner organizations in developing and implementing volunteer and partnership projects to increase trail maintenance within priority areas.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD5DB982A3F9442E58BE1CE55416686D8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Revision</header><text>The Secretary shall periodically review the priority areas to determine whether revisions are necessary and may revise the priority areas, including the selection of new priority areas or removal of existing priority areas, at his sole discretion.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F252E6F08C84CA08620C45C0DAFE5C9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header> 
<subsection id="H333A114F1D3A419BA5D8B47B1032CAB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code) with any State, tribal, local governmental, and private entity to carry out this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA9413790481542D48879073BACCBB6B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Cooperative agreements authorized under this section may—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDBD1F56A20C9452786A53EE4DD84F4AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve trail maintenance in a priority area;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFE20C3C859746DABA9E7867E52A3DA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement the strategy; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD91F4BD927624108920F15E180FEB438"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advance trail maintenance in a manner deemed appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC92121B7CE074437BB112FB152E014E6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Stewardship credits for outfitters and guides</header> <subsection id="H818F595E4D484123A14ABD1D34D8FBFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>Within 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, in accordance with this section, the Secretary shall establish a pilot program on not less than 20 administrative units to offset all or part of the land use fee for an outfitting and guiding permit by the cost of the work performed by the permit holder to construct, improve, or maintain National Forest System trails, trailheads, or developed sites that support public use under terms established by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEE2AA11643E24891A7573D912B3C1F80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>In establishing the pilot program authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA38DDFAD4D7E44088F9DE4A3FA1ACCAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>select administrative units where the pilot program will improve trail maintenance; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77CB7D7E5EBA4032927F719F92B4B70C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish appropriate terms and conditions, including meeting National Quality Standards for Trails and the Trail Management Objectives identified for the trail.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

