<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE73B606DB0D14FB198892490F5E903BA" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1171 IH: Volunteer Emergency Services Recruitment and Retention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1171</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150227">February 27, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide recruitment and retention incentives for volunteer emergency service workers.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3E8F52AB743E473583ECC5E41DAFB714" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79E3516985ED4305AEAF4D8D94B8652D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Volunteer Emergency Services Recruitment and Retention Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H225538C7E5664A20B826E3291A8CE3C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elective treatment of length of service award programs as eligible deferred compensation plans</header> <subsection id="H134C4D2940D843A28DBD7173F2081C49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (e) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/457">section 457</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H420CCDF7061548B9AA7775690CA8F7B0" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H0CD25256E0D44720A9516605901F3B01"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Special rules applicable to length of service award plans</header> 
<subparagraph id="H811D17088AF943EF82A7222AD7D2C549"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible deferred compensation plan</term> shall include, at the election of its sponsor, any length of service award plan. Any such election shall be irrevocable. In the case of a length of service award plan whose sponsor has elected to have such plan treated as an eligible deferred compensation plan, such plan shall be administered in a manner consistent with the requirements of this section and such sponsor shall be treated as an eligible employer described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76910ADDA908480BBAB3828974A37186"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Length of service award plan</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> 
<clause id="HD1B2FAD518E64323BA73705DC54665DC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>length of service award plan</term> means any plan paying solely length of service awards to bona fide volunteers (or their beneficiaries) on account of qualified services performed by such volunteers.</text></clause> <clause id="HA2C01DADB4034A97B52F5BAF093C9203"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Bona fide volunteer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual shall be treated as a bona fide volunteer if the only compensation received by such individual for performing qualified services is in the form of—</text> 
<subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E3A727E7EAD4B26971774B4D5A44723"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reimbursement for (or a reasonable allowance for) reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of such services, or</text></subclause> <subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB97F7958623F4E7AB8587C2D2964D0E7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable benefits (including length of service awards), and fees for such services, customarily paid by eligible employers in connection with the performance of such services by volunteers.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HF81916CD3EFB4E4A837D982E499C7AC1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified services</term> means fire fighting and prevention services, emergency medical services, ambulance services, and emergency rescue services.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H200AFD23F160466BA3FC21351E442D83"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Maximum deferral amount</header><text>In the case of a length of service award plan whose sponsor has elected to have such plan treated as an eligible deferred compensation plan, subsection (b)(2) shall be applied by striking <quote>the lesser of—</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>the applicable dollar amount,</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16D3B7CF023442CDBE1A807985F003A7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Distribution requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a length of service award plan whose sponsor has elected to have such plan treated as an eligible deferred compensation plan, subsection (d)(1)(A)(ii) shall be applied by deeming a severance from employment to have occurred at the later of—</text> <clause id="HF6FF60F987534D618337CDFCDAE3033E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the payment date under the terms of the plan, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2460F77971814B6F877F90FBDF527FFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the plan participant ceases to perform qualified services.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6C17203D09F4585970459F00D48209E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitation on accruals</header> <clause id="HCAC0AE05EB314CDBADDDB4104F5022CD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a length of service award plan that is a defined benefit plan (as defined in section 414(j)) whose sponsor has not elected to have such plan treated as an eligible deferred compensation plan, such plan shall be treated as not providing for the deferral of compensation if the aggregate amount of length of service awards accruing with respect to any year of service for any bona fide volunteer does not exceed $5,500. In the case of a length of service award plan described in the preceding sentence that is a defined benefit plan (as defined in section 414(j)), the limitation on the annual deferral shall apply to the actuarial present value of the aggregate amount of length of service awards accruing with respect to any year of service. Such actuarial present value shall be calculated using reasonable actuarial assumptions and methods assuming payment shall be made under the most valuable form of payment of the length of service award under the program with payment commencing at the later of the earliest age at which unreduced benefits are payable under the program or the participant’s current age.</text></clause> 
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22E88A5A1B164D6EBD650B67543E98C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Cost-of-living adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015, the Secretary shall adjust the $5,500 amount under clause (i) at the same time and in the same manner as under section 415(d), except that the base period shall be the calendar quarter beginning July 1, 2014, and any increase under this paragraph that is not a multiple of $500 shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $500.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD7BA8D42E8554EBEBA5023F60867A640"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="HA3360F2E938F4151AE9BADFD5D1A023D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Paragraph (11) of section 457(e) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7E36F63110A4EECA41978F57817A3EE" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H85A1AB2944D440CAB7142A2C6968F384"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Certain plans excluded</header><text>Any bona fide vacation leave, sick leave, compensatory time, severance pay, disability pay, or death benefit plan shall be treated as not providing for the deferral of compensation.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A75AF177C714D4CB4CE1A7E42C58C95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 3121(a)(5)(I) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 457(e)(11)(A)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 457(e)(19)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H466C6F07ED914132BCAC2F0707F9A12D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2014.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCD165D7F02634B6FA34832C30FECB8B1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption of length of service award programs from the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall issue guidance clarifying that a length of service award program described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/457">section 457(e)(19)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is not an employee pension benefit plan under section 3(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(2)</external-xref>).</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

