<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9918570D4B7845AEBC0B27236E741B96" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2139 IH: Veteran’s Benefits Claims Faster Filing Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2139</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O’Rourke</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide notice of average times for processing claims and percentage of claims approved, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H41B7DC055D4F4990AF38E1B08BD4FDBD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7E92C5E8039A45329628A1BDF7314D22" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran’s Benefits Claims Faster Filing Act of 2015</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H19C924B0869A4AFF8E725A618EEDB806"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs notice of average times for processing claims and percentage of claims approved</header> <subsection id="H7090E9CE32C04F27BCCAB8F35348BA4D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall post the information described in subsection (c)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H88BBF8B1BE184212A856CDB190D06044"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in a conspicuous place in each regional office and claims intake facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB119C027764C412497195A4AB031E475"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on the Internet Web site of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H321909E78A384B32B249F1F9BD3CF10B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice to applicants</header> 
<paragraph id="HF9C5F67F984949F18BCEE8741DF9799B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to each person who submits a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary before the person submits such claim—</text> <subparagraph id="H138081FB494042A8A7E3EABE14A887DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of the information described in subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2AD6FDF3766C40AAB6F83E2E89AD8386"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notice that the person is eligible to receive up to an extra year of benefits payments if the person files a claim that is fully developed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C8317396912410A860B149DA884839F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acknowledgment of receipt of notice</header><text>Each person who submits a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary shall include in such application a signed form acknowledging that the person received the information described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5324975CDF5F440BB0F2FE8FF2DC411C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information described</header> 
<paragraph id="H71D532632BC94172B6A7E1458951760D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The information described in this subsection is the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H66EA4410B147465FBB4E1EDDCF5B4ECB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The average processing time of the claims described in paragraph (2) and the percentage of such submitted claims for which benefits are awarded.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H638DDC87A505475FAA5F7982FCB54E2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The percentage of each of the following types of submitted claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for which benefits are awarded:</text> <clause id="HAC055468DBD44230921D03B0102C3FD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Claims filed by veterans who authorized a veterans service organization to act on the veterans’ behalf under a durable power of attorney.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5134366DB25E42B1BF95AB494F692C5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Claims filed by veterans who authorized a person other than a veterans service organization to act on the veterans’ behalf under a durable power of attorney.</text></clause> <clause id="HC1DD25CDD43641D2B6C990A4CF9C50AB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Claims filed by veterans who did not authorize a person to act on the veterans’ behalf under a durable power of attorney.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB665E892468A48B89DC77263ABBFCD10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Claims described</header><text>The claims described in this paragraph are each of the following types of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs:</text> <subparagraph id="HBB460C03B5724F3E8442649A070DBB67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A fully developed claim that is submitted in standard electronic form.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66309C318D0447809A88FCE27558428A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A fully developed claim that is submitted in standard paper form.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D435D74BDD44F7C9ED83802F2DC2AC1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A claim that is not fully developed that is submitted in standard electronic form.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E6D1126C9E440B4A027844FDD4B6DB1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claim that is not fully developed that is submitted in standard paper form.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AAFDC0B2C774526A39FD800DDEB3B14"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A claim that is not fully developed that is submitted in non-standard paper form.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B9853E3DF2A477193A6D4CE33945F13"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Update of information</header><text>The information described in this subsection shall be updated not less frequently than once each fiscal quarter.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

