<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4439307F487840ECB8B7D73C46169E23" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3201 IH: New American Success Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3201</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To support the integration of immigrants to the United States into the economic, social, cultural,
			 and civic life of their local communities and the Nation, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H80B7FF0773AA4CB082F965053BB91530" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD4E54B8AA1204F37B96061A93B33CB59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New American Success Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF59F6F2DF8574CF6B3897B8B9D59FBB8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="HD4E54B8AA1204F37B96061A93B33CB59" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF59F6F2DF8574CF6B3897B8B9D59FBB8" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HD7458156B66E4AB7A4D64AD4A5B93877" level="section">Sec. 3. Findings and declaration of policy.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB921C0B21C614BC3BB3AF9BCAB904CC8" level="title">Title I—Grants</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HDF6940C672BD415AA38E3058A3D55ACD" level="section">Sec. 101. Initial Entry, Adjustment, and Citizenship Assistance Grants.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H40CFF2698ADE4741A8A6CE773A31D261" level="section">Sec. 102. Integration Success Grants.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1A9B2A07F3C84225A636B0F25621562E" level="section">Sec. 103. Integration Success Fund.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HBF8543C3A3644E2C92CC9A6DA98D8465" level="title">Title II—English Language Learning</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HD64240D2713842668AC34C8FAA7920AC" level="section">Sec. 201. Waiver of English requirement for senior new Americans.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
		</section><section id="HD7458156B66E4AB7A4D64AD4A5B93877"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings and declaration of policy</header>
 <subsection id="HDB1D88A7844843CFADF1B133C6DD1B15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HB1503F883A77478789349A3147F7F041"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the Migration Policy Institute, there are 13,400,000 non-citizen residents in the United States with limited proficiency in English.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7EBEFAE63EF425A8F6DCD3CAFEC88FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the Department of Homeland Security, approximately 1,100,000 legal immigrants enter the country annually. About half of these legal immigrants lack full proficiency in English.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50B11F67A3C042E299C027FB589412D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, more than two-thirds of the foreign-born population does not have a postsecondary degree, and foreign-born adults are three times more likely to lack a high school diploma or equivalent than native-born adults.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE32D08AE3794EA8B28F1F8657573C97"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, 19 of the 30 fastest growing occupations require workers with some form of postsecondary education or training.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18AD71A826064277922489891BE3C3EF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>These statistics suggest that a lack of English proficiency and limited education serve as serious impediments to labor market success for immigrants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H989A98996B384B45A97C3F0E446CA002"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A century ago, during the last great wave of immigration to this country, the public and private sectors promoted the integration of newcomers through the Settlement House movement, the founding of the modern public library system, the establishment of universal public education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB39A733B0F6D4220A741ADBE2A9A1423"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Although currently dozens of Federal and State programs support, and thousands of government agencies and nonprofit organizations operate, programs that teach English, promote acquisition of workforce skills, provide citizenship assistance, and otherwise promote the integration of immigrants and their children, such programs are often not coordinated or aligned, limiting the capacity of such programs to identify and test promising practices, leverage resources, or bring effective interventions to scale.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87794D7E853140E3B814309D4C0B1743"><enum>(8)</enum><text>It is in the national interest to facilitate the rapid acquisition of English language skills by immigrants to the United States and to otherwise promote the integration of immigrants and their children into the mainstream of our economy and society.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38B15D92AF9D4A328812AB80EF80B967"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Empowering immigrants and their family members to effectively integrate into the mainstream of the economic, social, cultural, and civic life of their local communities and the Nation as a whole will ensure that United States immigration policies result in more productive and competitive local economies and more cohesive and harmonious communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H403561BE8EA749C6973CFFA6E3CA2824"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Data, policies, and programs relevant to immigrant integration crosscut the responsibilities of numerous Federal agencies as well as those of State and local governments and nongovernmental actors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82D2281A8D6B43029C588F735D316FC6"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The overlapping nature of integration issues and the lack of coordination of immigration policies and programs make it difficult for the President and Congress to understand and respond to pressing integration challenges and opportunities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H882D3F807A7A40C887AB17AAD2EA15FE"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Improved coordination of integration goals, policies, and programs across sectors and levels of government would greatly enhance the ability of the Federal Government to create and maintain an immigration system that is more suited to modern times and benefits the interests of the Federal Government, communities with growing immigrant populations, as well as immigrants and their family members.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15A4B9BAE81147CA8D03688869DCDBE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="H8804DB7CBA5442E0A9F53650FBA5B8A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote the civic, linguistic, and economic integration of immigrants and their young children into the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F9523FB5E364F3D901A39D6B564C70E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish national goals for integrating immigrants and their young children into the United States, and measure the degree to which such goals are met;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1905C65B705044059698D2EBA9873B0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess and coordinate Federal policies, regulations, and programs related to the integration of immigrants, including an assessment of Federal agency jurisdiction and budget concerns;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H624683203E8145B39AA85917C66BFF11"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with State and local governments on integration challenges and opportunities for the purpose of improving Federal integration policy and program efforts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFA337F4BE444F579FDD0B4FEB2EA967"><enum>(5)</enum><text>track the performance of Federal, State, and local integration initiatives, including measures of reach, effectiveness, and cost; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2003C931417B4C51A0DA64198588FA15"><enum>(6)</enum><text>engage stakeholders at different government and nongovernment levels to identify integration opportunities and challenges.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><title id="HB921C0B21C614BC3BB3AF9BCAB904CC8"><enum>I</enum><header>Grants</header>
			<section id="HDF6940C672BD415AA38E3058A3D55ACD"><enum>101.</enum><header>Initial Entry, Adjustment, and Citizenship Assistance Grants</header>
 <subsection id="HC3719383EF204BD48F94B17FF93ED9EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall award Initial Entry, Adjustment, and Citizenship Assistance grants to eligible entities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9BC6C7756BA545F4A338C022399E6EAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity eligible to receive a grant under this section is a unit of local government, community-based organization, or public or private nonprofit organization—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4916D1246CD64C8CBB9210F8C0AEE7FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that provides direct assistance to immigrants to the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H303798303493478C8EAEE4B6C7422151"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that submits to the Secretary of Homeland Security an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as such Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB89FBFD683B4FFD999C86EDFCECA3A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HAC8DF4C95B5143CEB9C66F12BA49C80E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds awarded under this section may be used to provide to an eligible non-citizen assistance relating to the immigration status of such non-citizen, or related services. Such assistance may include—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DC8D953FC1E45B4BF74191EF61C2882"><enum>(A)</enum><text>screening to assess the eligibility of a prospective applicant seeking a change in immigration status;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H76339E472C014486891ECD125FE75CF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>completing immigration applications;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H061063D43345410982FD8A38E8D5DE6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>gathering proof of identification, employment, residence, and tax payment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD61B1CA1B8A415A8207B2C07A0446A0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>gathering proof of relationships to eligible family members;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF12572CF89124FDDBEE6A44DDF696ED9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>applying for any waivers for which an applicant and qualifying family members may be eligible;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H689C97269EE442D1AD1F8459B402AD7B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>advising an applicant on the rights and responsibilities of United States citizenship; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD687DF41FDC04F8689D30606938EBC02"><enum>(G)</enum><text>instruction—</text>
 <clause id="H32F30DA3D12F454EBA45090B0A0C78E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the rights and responsibilities of United States citizenship;</text> </clause><clause id="HDFCDB176C572452DB94DCFD9AC7B5A81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in civics and civics-based English as a second language; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0B51430179AA4AF7AB490A49E1BCA9FE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in applying for United States citizenship.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA852A15D3F68444BA5D0B9B7F4E091BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immigrants eligible for assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A non-citizen is eligible to receive the assistance described in paragraph (1) if such non-citizen is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2BE5B28E33E64B6EB655DBA6D3B7F363"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seeking to become a permanent resident or naturalized citizen; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE69D19FF91844510A37EEC86F43FFD0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seeking relief from removal in order lawfully to remain in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEFB4760C82C4D7EA23DC4120AFE6F8C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, priority shall be given to—</text> <paragraph id="H390555DE4F424F65A6117BD3407CA57A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entities that demonstrate intent to use grant funds to serve individuals living in a State with a foreign-born population of not less than 5 percent that has experienced an increase that is higher than the national average in the population of non-citizen residents during the most recent 10-year period, based on data compiled by the Office of Immigration Statistics or the United States Census Bureau, or units of local government located within such State; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEFA688E6412439A86C2C3EAA72F8616"><enum>(2)</enum><text>entities that demonstrate intent to use grant funds to serve individuals living in any of the 10 States with the highest number of non-citizen residents, based on data compiled by the Office of Immigration Statistics or the United States Census Bureau, or units of local government located within such State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C1BD0F66235482EA30B45C4D8FF6401"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to receive a payment under this section, a participating entity shall submit to the Secretary a certification that the proposed uses of grant funds by the entity are consistent with this section and meet all necessary criteria determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C846ABCC2324A45822D4469AA232DBD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report and evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year for which an entity receives grant funds under this section, the entity shall submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE1A1F972E3F649EE87DEA351B6614F40"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report that describes—</text> <subparagraph id="H26F6BC27ABEE47C69C818645A312F51B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities undertaken by the entity that were funded entirely or partially by the grant funds;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B812890095A416EA89B8FA1480D5798"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the geographic area or areas served by the grant funds;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69D15340EF7F4FA593A563511903FC05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an estimate of the number of non-citizens living in the jurisdiction or service area of the entity, which demonstrates that the entity made a reasonable effort to determine such number;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65A6B1673316476389FC4470F02E70C5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of non-citizens receiving assistance that was funded entirely or partially by grant funds received by the entity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F3E59D800EA4BC589F23F8E2B255AE2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the primary languages spoken in the jurisdiction or service area of the entity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A89B83DAC84438A9186220AFE6B3A36"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of any program of the entity using grant funds under this section, including an assessment of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H57536EFAC6D54DA88DB30706303F1BE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of such program and recommendations for improving the program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA51EFA7C00C74CB3B975B4BA2B55629B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the future needs of immigrants to the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4572F02680646889B7A703A39B797DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the future needs of States and units of local government related to immigrant integration.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C6220794D384145A129F9B05C83A8F1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>State defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBC95744B75084D96BFA7FC442563797E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall be in effect for a period of 10 fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 2018.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H40CFF2698ADE4741A8A6CE773A31D261"><enum>102.</enum><header>Integration Success Grants</header> <subsection id="H1EA75BAFB8FB4A4EB21691082CB65ACC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants Authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may provide grants on a competitive basis to improve the economic, linguistic, and civic integration of immigrants and their children.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF591DF424E664DDFB8C7187EFB09ADEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity eligible to receive a grant under this section is a State or a unit of local government that submits to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, which may include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H708C49397D654E8C8D57AD7465AD6A9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a proposal outlining the methods the entity intends to use to effectively carry out the activities funded by the grant;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09D3A88794BF4834861773A896D7136A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a sociodemographic profile of non-citizens living within the jurisdiction or service area of the entity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB9FD6D37BB5407399A7B13847CCA3CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of opportunities and challenges in improving the economic, linguistic, and civic integration of immigrants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EA8BC5D9BA5428BB05567968D8A853F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comprehensive plan to improve the coordination of relevant immigrant integration services.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF47B532C7FCF4AB0A44542C82C7CDE84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity awarded a grant under this section may use the grant funds—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCCFF714DEE984143BCF059B949B3E918"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expand access to, and improve the quality of, programs supporting the economic advancement of immigrants in areas that include financial literacy, small business development, employment navigation, and training opportunities, including cultural competency training for State, county, and local government officials that provide direct services to immigrants and their families;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7FF83F571B942A38DDE1CD76E65423C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expand programs that provide basic adult education and contextualized English language skills that improve the literacy, numeracy, workforce skills, and educational attainment of immigrants over the age of 18;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E24B45F165042E38E3A89B4908B1DB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expand access to programs that assist immigrants in learning English, obtaining recognized postsecondary credentials or employment, or in building measurable skills to lead to the attainment of an industry-recognized credential or certificate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF10FC9BDEE6D4EDABA8F622DA1C10FEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to educate immigrants about United States history, civics, citizenship rights and responsibilities, democracy, opportunities to engage in the civic life of their community, unit of local government, and State, and the navigation of local systems that support the economic, linguistic, and civic integration of individuals and families.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H692732B9F5554BB499951FABD27EDAA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, priority shall be given to—</text> <paragraph id="H6EC8B8CCDF65419690D430420503BADD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an entity that uses not less than ten percent of matching funds from non-Federal sources;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDE5F36B0CE94472989432DE9D44777C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity that collaborates with at least one public or private entity to carry out the comprehensive plan referred to under subsection (b)(4); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99B9BB8780E04CFDAFDB6D41A5B363BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State—</text> <subparagraph id="HDFC788C258894E298103841DD3925910"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that has a foreign born population of not less than 5 percent and that has experienced an increase in non-citizen residents that is higher than the national average during the most recent 10-year period, based on data compiled by the Office of Immigration Statistics or the United States Census Bureau, or a unit of local government located within such State; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62B03152463E4FF7A58A592F9EB30A0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is one of the 10 States with the highest number of non-citizen residents, based on data compiled by the Office of Immigration Statistics or the United States Census Bureau, or a unit of local government located within such State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4CD97FBAF914BD5B3AE0DACA75FF099"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to receive a payment under this section, a participating entity shall provide the Secretary with a certification that the proposed uses of grant funds by the entity are consistent with this section and meet all necessary criteria determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60163131B1D342339DEB8803EA392167"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report and evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year for which an entity receives a grant under this section, such entity shall submit to the Secretary the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA8E5A773FAF447A2B472D01FFCA64165"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report that describes—</text> <subparagraph id="H4286E7B3D77C479BAF283404B3BB60ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities undertaken by the entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H681F40799A394E9DBC71A51D7411442A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the geographic area or areas served by the grant funds; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E80DB8C15834E40AE439738DECE6F62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the sociodemographic characteristics of individuals served by the grant funds.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AF15B3CE5624FFEAD1BBE5931697561"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of any program of the entity that receives grant funds, including an assessment of—</text> <subparagraph id="H1BB5008CBDAD4512AD5C797BDA1C5A29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of such program and recommendations for improving the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A8D331729CD47A89AA606D54A2E7A3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the future needs of immigrants to the United States; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF12340CF04144852BD92BBD9E42BED28"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the future needs of States and units of local government related to immigrant integration.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H022B9CA324BC48C180DEB1A2DB48C042"><enum>(g)</enum><header>State defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5210E8A509E949F7A7A1B698E509F17D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall be in effect for a period of 10 fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 2018.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H1A9B2A07F3C84225A636B0F25621562E"><enum>103.</enum><header>Integration Success Fund</header> <subsection id="H2632A319BD78480CA97C19652A0A87FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the general fund of the Treasury of the United States a separate account which shall be known as the <quote>Integration Success Fund</quote>. Twenty percent of the amounts deposited into the Integration Success Fund shall remain available until expended to carry out section 101, and 80 percent of the amounts deposited into such fund shall remain available until expended to carry out section 102.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF16D202E27934C0F84E36DA43584EA40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gifts, bequests, and devises</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of services or property, both real and personal, for the purpose of awarding grants under section 101, and 80 percent of the amounts deposited into such fund shall remain available until expended to carry out section 102. Gifts, bequests, or devises of money and proceeds from sales of other property received as gifts, bequests, or devises shall be deposited in the Integration Success Fund established by subsection (a) and shall be available for disbursement to eligible entities in accordance with this title.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="HBF8543C3A3644E2C92CC9A6DA98D8465"><enum>II</enum><header>English Language Learning</header>
 <section id="HD64240D2713842668AC34C8FAA7920AC"><enum>201.</enum><header>Waiver of English requirement for senior new Americans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 312 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1423">8 U.S.C. 1423</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA589295A7614C01809D92C09E3F2356" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H6D0133137C6844F0A93BA0142676C14C"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements under subsection (a) shall not apply to any person who—</text> <paragraph id="H455EAF2DEE724FFBADAA758E720F5922"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is unable to comply with such requirements because of physical or mental disability, including developmental or intellectual disability; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC259E976D7F44C6F8DB065E70994AACB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the date on which the person's application for naturalization is filed under section 334—</text> <subparagraph id="H373916674E874D6499E84D3CAFAD8586"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is older than 65 years of age; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B8459100F7746D78E83AC2E50990F99"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 5 years after being lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C244C0AC8E9420EBF71EB649E3BCBEA"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to any person who, on the date on which the person's application for naturalization is filed under section 334—</text>
 <paragraph id="H16C521E796C8453B88971B567CFAD9FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is older than 50 years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 20 years after being lawfully admitted for permanent residence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E2D6DB3922B444EA64A5A2888970C1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is older than 55 years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 15 years after being lawfully admitted for permanent residence; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9885EFA5F77645B9AA98616D237D957C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is older than 60 years of age and has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 10 years after being lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H073154B489AC4DAEAD160DA6D6DDE043"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may waive, on a case-by-case basis, the requirement under subsection (a)(2) on behalf of any person who, on the date on which the person's application for naturalization is filed under section 334—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1ABF100A11AF45EF887631C9A311B59A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is older than 60 years of age; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4C15DECE287401D9A5429280B1D897D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been living in the United States for periods totaling at least 10 years after being lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


