<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H44D2DFFD7AED4734BB137B4A0405C7B1" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 413 IH: Partnership to Build America Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 413</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150120">January 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000413">Mr. Whitfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001055">Mr. Heck of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001193">Mr. MacArthur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000613">Mr. Dold</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish the American Infrastructure Fund, to provide bond guarantees and make loans to States, local governments, and infrastructure providers for investments in certain infrastructure projects, and to provide equity investments in such projects, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC62AAB50BB064C61AE9D3C4AD44C9D8B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF05B8B41B6CA474BBA4B0E8ECE163190" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Partnership to Build America Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCD1D2D785945452EB22BD997B64794B6"><enum>2.</enum><header>American Infrastructure Fund</header> <subsection id="HEA6125CF86B449888C185C088B9D043A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>American Infrastructure Fund</header> <paragraph id="HB10755C9DB674AB1AE9FA1AFBF31031E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a wholly owned Government corporation—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H06BA0AABA4D64498932C7646319EDA64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which shall be called the American Infrastructure Fund (referred to in this Act as the <quote>AIF</quote>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07062BD578944FEABB8090F7A20E0674"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which shall be headed by the Board of Trustees established under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC8B0AF759A643289DB89F297C68125D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which may have separate subaccounts or subsidiaries for funds used to make loans, bond guarantees, and equity investments under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFCDB1CF8D9C04AD0852BE6CECEDBBC54"><enum>(D)</enum><text>which shall be available to the AIF to pay for the costs of carrying out this section, including the compensation of the Board and other employees of the AIF; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05B8D8980FE74ED593B6E6F1ACF0A555"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the funds of which may be invested by the Board in such manner as the Board determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21E6862DDFCC4A0F8A18292DDD0BA94E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposits to AIF</header><text>All funds received from bond issuances, loan payments, bond guarantee fees, and any other funds received in carrying out this section shall be held by AIF.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C2DCFF8A89040B58173B2D87A4BDFEC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The charter of the AIF shall limit its activities to those activities described as the mission of the Board under subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DD7981EA1C14FB0928D2204B6F7CD48"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The AIF shall register with the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Chairman shall report to Congress annually as to whether the AIF is fulfilling the mission of the Board under subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD014C1751F37476BAC8FE9C9B81E32B6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of AIF</header> 
<subparagraph id="H088F83D0A4F54451AF651C69C7BFA4AC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Accounts</header><text>Title 31, United States Code, is amended in each of sections 9107(c)(3) and 9108(d)(2)—</text> <clause id="HE86331A95C7F444E8738EB0EDCEDA0B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>the American Infrastructure Fund,</quote> after <quote>the Regional Banks for Cooperatives,</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H239FAE111E4046088079DB124DE748BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>those banks</quote> and inserting <quote>those entities</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8138AC784B149F58D87804AB710099A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Bonds</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/149">Section 149(b)(3)(A)(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>American Infrastructure Fund,</quote> after <quote>Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA020A43E20AE48878AAA7D64E359107D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Board of Trustees</header> 
<paragraph id="H826CFE02B0BF4D6AA9FCD9980009FCA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a Board of Trustees of the AIF (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Board</quote>), which shall be composed of 9 members who—</text> <subparagraph id="H16FF66EE356749C2A4BB2BD006A04FA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have substantial experience in bond guarantees or municipal credit; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA6AB983CCD94610933BE551997F3545"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the greatest extent practicable, have extensive experience working with municipal credit, risk management, and infrastructure finance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A9FCB76C3A34123BC55A82C1C286B8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The mission of the Board is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7ABF5C06901E4F2585B8CAF077DF4F05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to operate the AIF and its subsidiaries to be a low cost provider of bond guarantees, loans, and equity investments to State and local governments and infrastructure providers for urban and rural infrastructure projects that—</text> <clause id="HA521C8F5DC524B07B3031A76A9C48439"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide a positive economic impact; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3328DD49DC7742CE8CEE084F797117C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meet such other standards as the Board may develop;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88CF2FFB7CC547AA8ADBDB48CA8365E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to operate the AIF in a self-sustaining manner so as to allow the AIF to repay its infrastructure bonds when such bonds are due;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B7CD7F97C6F4AEF9F401ED2AC0B52DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to not have a profit motive, but to seek at all times to pursue its mission of providing low cost bond guarantees and loans while—</text> <clause id="H9587CDAC35E248B3A25C3EDDEAC239D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>covering its costs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H54F922C0B461412B80CE45D78EF752F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintaining such reserves as may be needed; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCD115331227E48039E53BDE78623D19D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>applying prudent underwriting standards;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB73850D9B1C14765A536C2A7DEEA19DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to only consider projects put forth by State and local governments and not to seek projects directly;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36237CE9397F4EA8BD4DA73A1BA6E431"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to always make clear that no taxpayer money supports the AIF or ever will support the AIF; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD41E6E2D61E04A31A27CDB24DA4BEBC1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to engage in no other activities other than those permitted under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H764838745F3C4913A2A2324A7CFFAB3F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header> <subparagraph id="H0AB076F13B3B4FDC9D412F0AFD38DCB4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial members</header> <clause id="H01C7E8C32F1F4539B58A43C3D47708A6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the date on which bonds are first issued under subsection (d), the President shall appoint, with the advice and consent of the Senate, as members of the Board—</text> 
<subclause id="H3FE04D53A66B4576B368C24AFAC6289B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>2 individuals from a list of at least 5 individuals selected by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBA1D3EB4FDCE4E01BEC6CCBAD03FD1F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>2 individuals from a list of at least 5 individuals selected by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H75B8339C51C743A3A468EF48A72584D1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>2 individuals from a list of at least 5 individuals selected by the Majority Leader of the Senate;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H627898F8EE114AFA89560923B3886348"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>2 individuals from a list of at least 5 individuals selected by the Minority Leader of the Senate; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3C013AABC7104CA89F6E2B3E75C1CFB8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>1 individual selected at will by the President.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H18CBFB4954A4471BBD4CA8AD922BACF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Submission of lists</header><text>Each of the lists described in clause (i) shall be submitted to the President not later than 90 days after the date on which bonds are first issued under subsection (d). If any of such lists are submitted after the date required under this clause, the President may appoint the 2 members of the Board who were to be selected from such list at will.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3BF007C7A67A46AEA2051840D9368A94"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Staggered terms</header><text>The members of the Board appointed pursuant to subparagraph (A)(i) shall serve staggered terms, with 2 each of the initial members of the Board serving for terms of 5, 6, 7, and 8 years, respectively, and the initial Chair selected under subparagraph (D) serving for 9 years. The decision of which Board members, other than the Chair, serve for which initial terms shall be made by the members of the Board drawing lots.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C994DBCE52C40A1A91DA42DC6B9088A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional members</header> <clause id="HB0331DAFE1E04859BA6F00DBA3B4785A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (A), if the term of a member of the Board expires or otherwise becomes vacant, the President shall appoint a replacement for such member, with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among a list of at least 5 individuals submitted by the Board.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H577128C39FCF4EDF81868828016C0E8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Term of service</header> 
<subclause id="H7BB24B13DC6D452BAF0FD9FB28395168"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member of the Board appointed to replace a member whose term is expiring shall serve for a 7-year term.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE38E2FAF28124632ADB606DB143FCEA7"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any member of the Board appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term to which that member's predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of the term.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05E9BA6C8DD5476EAF2A18C0CFFB28FD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The members of the Board shall choose 1 member to serve as the Chair of the Board for a term of 7 years, except that the initial Chair shall serve for a term of 9 years, pursuant to subsection (B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H24D87C08CE0C456B9B00CE2C75EC3596"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Continuation of service</header><text>Each member of the Board may continue to serve after the expiration of the term of office to which that member was appointed until a successor has been appointed.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD39477769A364DBFB903C4326E47E155"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><text>No member of the Board may have a financial interest in, or be employed by, a Qualified Infrastructure Project (<quote>QIP</quote>) related to assistance provided under this section or any entity that has purchased bonds under subsection (d). Owning municipal credit of any State or local government or owning the securities of a diversified company that engages in infrastructure activities, provided those activities constitute less than 20 percent of the company’s revenues, or investing in broadly held investment funds shall not be deemed to create a conflict of interest. The Board may issue regulations to define terms used under this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DB9BD8ED044425199CD8518C5A7F0A8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The members of the Board shall be compensated at an amount to be set by the Board, but under no circumstances may such compensation be higher than the rate prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC19455A4F7243C9B2FFD2B7E1D1AE68"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Board shall employ and set compensation for such staff as the Board determines as is necessary to carry out the activities and mission of the AIF, and such staff may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53, United States Code, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7C1221D7E704A39B54AAAF4ECA3EED1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Board shall establish such procedures as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1803CB206ADD45D2A3A4334654D91EC4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Corporate governance standards</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1B29CCB599BC4AB68FE3881C61BED652"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Board committees generally</header><text>The Board shall maintain all of the committees required to be maintained by the board of directors of an issuer listed on the New York Stock Exchange as of the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93164EEB0DA14CE19110EB9A11B4F2E3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Risk management committee</header><text>The Board shall maintain a risk management committee, which shall—</text> 
<clause id="H88F732B13DBD4391ABF6412E5CD8843F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employ additional staff who are certified by the Board as having significant and relevant experience in insurance underwriting and credit risk management; and</text></clause> <clause id="H17682805020C4430A182734D047EDC41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish the risk management policies used by the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H77E287C5362A4E2DA53DAF0F425A8B4F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>The Board shall, to the extent practicable, follow all standards with respect to corporate governance that are required to be followed by the board of directors of an issuer listed on the New York Stock Exchange as of the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC851AA87D7DF4A86AFD5098E7BEC7433"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Biennial reports</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 2 years, the Board shall produce a report that describes, of the materials, goods, and products that were used to construct, or to support the construction of, qualified infrastructure projects (as described in subsection (c)) and received financing from the American Infrastructure Fund within the most recent 2 calendar years, the percentage of such materials, goods, and products that were created, sourced, or manufactured in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC5C988B506242F686412D126117902B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Infrastructure investment</header> 
<paragraph id="HE5644B9D70204F0C82DFA1477D632188"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Entities eligible for assistance</header><text>The AIF may provide assistance to State and local government entities, nonprofit infrastructure providers, private parties, and public-private partnerships (referred to in this section as <quote>eligible entities</quote>) to help finance qualified infrastructure projects (referred to in this subsection as <quote>QIPs</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4B1AC2E56D444388CECF51ABBBCE861"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forms of assistance</header><text>The AIF may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAC8A5749D44441198F9C937E3FB931F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide bond guarantees to debt issued by eligible entities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22DE302890334F7586D98F80C3947CC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make loans, including subordinated loans, to eligible entities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52EFD8B7237949D5838D9E766027DF87"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make equity investments in QIPs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFE2C64C378D410EB9050B8F4EF5CCB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified infrastructure projects</header><text>A project qualifies as a QIP under this section if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5534E048443D448FA7ED773C1A2283F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the project is sponsored by a State or local government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H293C3D0BF0D94CBCB2C8D9D85148E7BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the infrastructure is, or will be, owned by a State or local government;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2DCBABD0B1BE423EA962D621974685EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the project involves the construction, maintenance, improvement, or repair of a transportation, energy, water, communications, or educational facility;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H770CA94D91D34FF99CCE6386BCAC67E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the recipient of bond guarantees, loans, equity investments, or any other innovative financing technique authorized under this Act provides written assurances prescribed by the AIF that the project will be performed in compliance with the requirements of all Federal laws that would otherwise apply to similar projects to which the United States is a party; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88807F4A39D8426F8B9A3B3388B67D95"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a public transportation capital project as defined in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code, the recipient of bond guarantees, loans, equity investments, or any other innovative financing technique authorized under this Act complies with the grant requirements applicable to grants made under section 5309 of such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4B2283C68394C5F9E7F8A871436894D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application for assistance</header> <subparagraph id="HE8FCF3ABA9724248A15C6545CF126C2E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or local government that wishes to receive a loan or bond guarantee under this section shall submit an application to the Board in such form and manner and containing such information as the Board may require.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF2451D8DE6E44AEF92BA568298A6D96A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement for public sponsorship of private entities</header><text>A private entity may only receive a bond guarantee, loan, or equity investment under this section if the State or local government for the jurisdiction in which the nonprofit infrastructure provider or private partner is located submits an application pursuant to subparagraph (A) on behalf of such nonprofit infrastructure provider or private partner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6DDE6FFA7834ACC960AF9C3E802D1A2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitations on single state awards</header> <subparagraph id="H6AF128EE2F0A4AC987722CCA1DFF1DA2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual limitation</header><text>The Board shall set an annual limit, as a percentage of total assistance provided under this section during a year, on the amount of assistance a single State (including local governments and other infrastructure providers within such State) may receive in assistance provided under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA765E27FEF03480FBACA05304056D804"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cumulative limitation</header><text>The Board shall set a limit, as a percentage of total assistance provided under this section outstanding at any one time, on the amount of assistance a single State (including local governments and other infrastructure providers within such State) may receive in assistance provided under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H014D922B36134B78B78DF80C9CA1FAF7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Loan specifications</header><text>Loans made under this section shall have such maturity and carry such interest rate as the Board determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB91B26A57C614F658EE00EE9A5FB700A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Bond guarantee</header><text>The Board shall charge such fees for Bond guarantees made under this section as the Board determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6203A24C6DD74E79AC662282993949A1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Equity investments</header><text>With respect to a QIP, the amount of an equity investment made by the AIF in such QIP may not exceed 20 percent of the total cost of the QIP.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3AD1D400BC9446508931DD060B311F8D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Public-private partnership requirements</header><text>At least 35 percent of the assistance provided under this section shall be provided to QIPs for which at least 10 percent of the financing for such QIPs comes from private debt or equity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF7702DEDED94935A843B3A14A448B0F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Prohibition on principal forgiveness</header><text>With respect to a loan made under this section, the Board may not forgive any amount of principal on such loan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H91528E12FC8C4AE8A99D7B93A15E6571"><enum>(d)</enum><header>American Infrastructure Bonds</header> 
<paragraph id="H2E6AF677BF67456CA4D3603D97E7144E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the AIF, shall issue bonds, which shall be called <quote>American Infrastructure Bonds</quote>. The proceeds from the American Infrastructure Bonds shall be deposited into the AIF.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBDB83EA8E544E99BA05BDAF4BAA1124"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forms and denominations; interest</header><text>American Infrastructure Bonds shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H246E50F675C14F3586226A67E646A46F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be in such forms and denominations as determined by the Secretary, and shall have a 50-year maturity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC77CE0DFE9AD47A4A9D243F1105A1061"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bear interest of 1 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF8D0A227D74445AAB141512D9E4265D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No full faith and credit</header><text>Interest and principal payments paid to holders of American Infrastructure Bonds shall be paid from the AIF, to the extent funds are available, and shall not be backed by the full faith and credit of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA6DDF30D0FD4FAEAB77E7B894D917EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Amount of bonds</header><text>The aggregate face amount of the bonds issued under this subsection shall be $50,000,000,000.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H360D6D0F0AD64AE8907D508ED16BB65C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sale of American Infrastructure Bonds</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3BA92E478EF8410B9A52622FA0911272"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Competitive bidding process</header><text>The Secretary shall sell $50,000,000,000 of American Infrastructure Bonds—</text> <clause id="H33493842FF794D0C97CBB632556D21BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>through a competitive bidding process that encourages aggressive bidding;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H73EE79B0FAD04F3E975ED86D5EAF4DB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with prospective purchasers bidding on how low of a multiplier they will accept (for purposes of subsection (b)(1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/966">section 966</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) when purchasing the American Infrastructure Bonds, for purposes of applying the foreign earnings exclusion described under that section; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7F38F5D72D8F42D18745FFA6C3E4281B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in a manner that ensures no entities participating in the bidding may collude or coordinate their bids.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H39561EC349724D4C9B3B811F2BF155C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The multiplier described in subparagraph (A)(ii) may not be greater than 6.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BD6B72734C34C639F188DCE772E3B41"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reimbursement of costs</header><text>The Board shall repay the Secretary, from funds in the AIF, for the costs to the Secretary in carrying out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82F130275FEF4A4696A5553DA15DAFD6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional bonds</header> 
<paragraph id="HC96721058AFB4679A8C6ED30D685AC38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board may issue such other bonds as the Board determines appropriate, the proceeds from which shall be deposited into the AIF.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59B392DCE9474501846B768DED543455"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No full faith and credit</header><text>Interest and principal payments paid to holders of bonds issued pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be paid from the AIF, to the extent funds are available, and shall not be backed by the full faith and credit of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HADE864116CB64EDB8AD8024204ED40D3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="HAD9C84584ADA40F69E438684B9BDE7D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Infrastructure provider</header><text>The term <term>infrastructure provider</term> means an entity that seeks to finance a QIP.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71A2A3A618EF4850937EF16729017DD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA3EF5651FB34723A3E1548CE68690F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, any territory or possession of the United States, and each Federally recognized Indian tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2E47123786324690AC336C2A9E5D7A57"><enum>3.</enum><header>Foreign earnings exclusion for purchase of infrastructure bonds</header> 
<subsection id="H61C9D423C8254EDAA0E8DE38D2D9D172"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart F of part III of subchapter N of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32929C64D3BA4BBFBD6D6E531624DE9F" style="OLC"> <section id="H5A8960C1D2C048B58233C91E4EC8881B"><enum>966.</enum><header>Foreign earnings exclusion for purchase of infrastructure bonds</header> <subsection id="H994F8756A2D3449880ED00501376365D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>In the case of a corporation which is a United States shareholder and for which the election under this section is in effect for the taxable year, gross income does not include an amount equal to the qualified cash dividend amount.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H566426598F4547DD8404E1E6243A913B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified cash dividend amount</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified cash dividend amount</term> means an amount of the cash dividends which are received during a taxable year by such shareholder from controlled foreign corporations equal to—</text> <paragraph id="HF7F0F1848F6142939E634BE1B6295B1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the multiplier determined under section 2(d)(5) of the <short-title>Partnership to Build America Act of 2015</short-title> for such shareholder, multiplied by</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A82CD268F394A5FB3D78DC5FCD3FE3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the face amount of qualified infrastructure bonds acquired at its original issue (directly or through an underwriter) by such shareholder.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB1E4264F36EF4D85B743D2DFE4502207"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <paragraph id="H58176A3FA70F43A98B7BADB943910410"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of dividends taken into account under subsection (a) for a taxable year shall not exceed the lesser of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5E318EF95DB6402BB3CC6423860D7776"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cash dividends received by the taxpayer for such taxable year, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE23F6E19165435A8CBA9EF4D52F10D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount shown on the applicable financial statement as earnings permanently reinvested outside the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FED621166D14387AD81897FBCEF5E65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dividends must be extraordinary</header><text>The amount of dividends taken into account under subsection (a) shall not exceed the excess (if any) of—</text> <subparagraph id="H355C7288BC1348F594BB24077BBB17F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cash dividends received during the taxable year by such shareholder from controlled foreign corporations, over</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H26714B02A4C64D709541CAA730EDE25C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the annual average for the base period years of the cash dividends received during each base period year by such shareholder from controlled foreign corporations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3729BE6C36346EABDEB73543F666A53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reduction of benefit if increase in related party indebtedness</header><text>The amount of dividends which would (but for this paragraph) be taken into account under subsection (a) shall be reduced by the excess (if any) of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H94E5968191BA4F6FA01991F92B68F9F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of indebtedness of the controlled foreign corporation to any related person (as defined in section 954(d)(3)) as of the close of the taxable year for which the election under this section is in effect, over</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC0C39506BE9409186ADE44FDC09CC69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of indebtedness of the controlled foreign corporation to any related person (as so defined) as of the close of the preceding taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0AA9ACC9573E4FACAA8516F866DDA4A3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of controlled foreign corporations</header><text>All controlled foreign corporations with respect to which the taxpayer is a United States shareholder shall be treated as 1 controlled foreign corporation for purposes of this subsection. The Secretary may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of this subsection, including regulations providing that cash dividends shall not be taken into account under subsection (a) to the extent such dividends are attributable to the direct or indirect transfer (including through the use of intervening entities or capital contributions) of cash or other property from a related person (as so defined) to a controlled foreign corporation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE9AF722583574AF79B214544BBDD1CF1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCAF2CFC7F6D449B6AAE1A245676596E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified infrastructure bonds</header><text>The term <term>qualified infrastructure bond</term> means a bond issued under section 2(d) of the <short-title>Partnership to Build America Act of 2015</short-title>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6896EFCD31A84F9286003B85ACD35C38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable financial statement</header><text>The term <term>applicable financial statement</term> means, with respect to a taxable year—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8F70A2230F064D27A4E89AFEE22F96D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a United States shareholder which is required to file a financial statement with the Securities and Exchange Commission (or which is included in such a statement so filed by another person), the most recent audited annual financial statement (including the notes which form an integral part of such statement) of such shareholder (or which includes such shareholder)—</text> <clause id="HAF2DEAC994424B8CAF3F76F030A433B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which was so filed for such taxable year, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H40A685A0AD904F41B71D83DBCD3A78B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is certified as being prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0465762771541C598FD7F172BE68247"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any other United States shareholder, the most recent audited financial statement (including the notes which form an integral part of such statement) of such shareholder (or which includes such shareholder)—</text> 
<clause id="H7C2A174690B941629B3DFEE11D584B41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is certified as being prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, and</text></clause> <clause id="HE3D5BFC9F6F442B2937EF77BAEF27385"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is used for the purposes of a statement or report—</text> 
<subclause id="H3A5633986E2B4D3E83593A0FAC89C825"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to creditors,</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAEB9DBB2B9CE43C4A92346AADB9FF1B6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to shareholders, or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA400C8ABF234439781D8E461B23C6978"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for any other substantial nontax purpose.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D826F5D20BA4A739FA1C2BDAD642A36"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Base period years</header> <subparagraph id="HF3CE90EA4C1445C3B56428497C271489"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The base period years are the 3 taxable years—</text> 
<clause id="HA9E9667B8F5547D6939487CA6D3746BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which are among the 5 most recent preceding taxable years ending before the taxable year, and</text></clause> <clause id="H79E571ED0D3C44388312C56B7BA653C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which are determined by disregarding—</text> 
<subclause id="H475E3E1CCB9040DD818AFE1F7E760742"><enum>(I)</enum><text>1 taxable year for which the amount described in subsection (c)(2)(B) is the largest, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF779ABEF9D414968B4A021B496EB479E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>1 taxable year for which such amount is the smallest.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H95EAA5F968E644349EDC6A8E40DAC328"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Shorter period</header><text>If the taxpayer has fewer than 5 taxable years ending before the taxable year, then in lieu of applying subparagraph (A), the base period years shall include all the taxable years of the taxpayer ending before such taxable year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BFEB2BA4C5642FB9CD771F40C2FEED5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mergers, acquisitions, etc</header> <clause id="HBA3BFD994D4A4E1FBDEF93B19B190E6C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 41(f)(3) shall apply for purposes of this paragraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H83916809116C4EE3B7969EE28CB258C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Spin-offs, etc</header><text>If there is a distribution to which section 355 (or so much of section 356 as relates to section 355) applies during the 5-year period referred to in subparagraph (A)(i) and the controlled corporation (within the meaning of section 355) is a United States shareholder—</text> <subclause id="H274949580B504EAEA69B5D9F760A1882"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the controlled corporation shall be treated as being in existence during the period that the distributing corporation (within the meaning of section 355) is in existence, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC28CC7D91F224411AA607BF85FCC4CD8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for purposes of applying subsection (c)(2) to the controlled corporation and the distributing corporation, amounts described in subsection (c)(2)(B) which are received or includable by the distributing corporation or controlled corporation (as the case may be) before the distribution referred to in subclause (I) from a controlled foreign corporation shall be allocated between such corporations in proportion to their respective interests as United States shareholders of such controlled foreign corporation immediately after such distribution.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD6C3E0865D3C4C2A9D4325F1BF3318C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subclause (II) of clause (ii) shall not apply if neither the controlled corporation nor the distributing corporation is a United States shareholder of such controlled foreign corporation immediately after such distribution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CFD3599799846C68977AF8728932209"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dividend</header><text>The term <term>dividend</term> shall not include amounts includable in gross income as a dividend under section 78, 367, or 1248. In the case of a liquidation under section 332 to which section 367(b) applies, the preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent the United States shareholder actually receives cash as part of the liquidation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H802F8629F91A49CD82863A13DAEEB2CF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination with dividend received deduction</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed under section 243 or 245 for any dividend which is excluded from income by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8120274BCD83482295B761522ABC6896"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Controlled groups</header><text>All United States shareholders which are members of an affiliated group filing a consolidated return under section 1501 shall be treated as one United States shareholder.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F8147D66A94452EA2C96FE2D8415315"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Secretary shall require by regulation or other guidance the reporting of such information as the Secretary may require to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA6C06E56E10F45B797BEB32623AADC82"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Denial of foreign tax credit; denial of certain expenses</header> 
<paragraph id="H478D53C0A2744190AFACAC417FE9F969"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign tax credit</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE2AD582D817C44DB9C10E4D2674D3B95"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under section 901 for any taxes paid or accrued (or treated as paid or accrued) with respect to the excluded portion of any dividend.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EB5CC07DE7A40919540477B80B5611E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Denial of deduction of related tax</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed under this chapter for any tax for which credit is not allowable by reason of the preceding sentence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97EE01CC930F4CD1BD849F4A1AC08152"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expenses</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed for expenses directly allocable to the excludable portion described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6FABC98F5B045BC8386B954EC04577D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excludable portion</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), unless the taxpayer otherwise specifies, the excludable portion of any dividend or other amount is the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount of such dividend or other amount as the amount excluded from income under subsection (a) for the taxable year bears to the amount described in subsection (c)(2)(A) for such year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7A2BEAC851745BE99A2386FEA2749A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination with section 78</header><text>Section 78 shall not apply to any tax which is not allowable as a credit under section 901 by reason of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFB31AB1967BA4D04942BA86965C10945"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application of section</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply with respect to the taxable year of the taxpayer in which the taxpayer acquires qualified infrastructure bonds at its original issue (directly or through an underwriter) under section 2(d)(5) of the <short-title>Partnership to Build America Act of 2015</short-title>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD92621CB0D2444C78D4E40DD044C9373"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart F of part III of subchapter N of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="HCD9E79B44BDB4BC7839D36A0478D45F7" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry idref="H5A8960C1D2C048B58233C91E4EC8881B" level="section">966. Foreign earnings exclusion for purchase of infrastructure bonds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5C1C968E8D304F4F85964E06FD5757E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to dividends received for taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

