<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2C87762612074BEAB704A4312B5A5DA9" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 379 IH: National Nurse Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 379</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150114">January 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To designate the same individual serving as the Chief Nurse Officer of the Public Health Service as the National Nurse for Public Health.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0FF8066AE13A4100834417890F9CC177" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF7007E3173334F218A2491116669CD07" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Nurse Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5BD3E91DB02447EEA4914E9AA16AAAE1"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Nurse for Public Health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u">42 U.S.C. 300u et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF51F86CE34CF43D6904618B4978B2809" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H75C50850C8A743E39358707E71800E90"><enum>1711.</enum><header>National Nurse for Public Health</header> 
<subsection id="HCB07552CF0A74858B53A92B428A0A736"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="H12C567AD562F404F935D9AEFB0EAE532"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The same individual designated as the Chief Nurse Officer of the Public Health Service under section 205 shall also be designated by the Secretary as the National Nurse for Public Health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA722029F0F7A4A09A10011BDD6FCFCDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall designate the individual serving as the Chief Nurse Officer of the Public Health Service on such date as the first National Nurse for Public Health. Subsequent designations shall occur in accordance with Commissioned Corps Instruction CC23.4.6 (relating to Chief Professional Officer Nominations), as in effect on February 13, 2008.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H49122391AE154E64A6519248D9E37EDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rank and grade</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Nurse for Public Health shall be of an equivalent rank to the Chief of the Army and Air Force Nurse Corps and the Director of Navy Nurse Corps.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8260F0B6A50340748218FFBA6800BD8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The National Nurse for Public Health shall carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B6D3CC7275345E59812A612D561BEC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Provide leadership and coordination of Public Health Service nursing professional affairs for the Office of the Surgeon General and other agencies of the Public Health Service, including providing representation for the Government of the United States at the Global Forum for Government Chief Nursing and Midwifery Officers and serving as a member of the Federal Nursing Service Council.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EDBC670FB2E4B1CA7E56585FB979702"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Represent the Surgeon General and the agencies of Public Health Service in communications with groups and societies concerned with nursing issues at the local, State, national, and international levels.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC09605C593254FA89AE25269728F6F2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Provide guidance and advice to the Surgeon General and the Nurse Professional Advisory Committee on matters such as standards, recruitment, retention, readiness, and career development of nurses employed by and contracted with agencies of the Public Health Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A2ED40361064777A99CFB40DB06E1EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Conduct outreach and education for purposes of paragraphs (5) through (7).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAEF9737B51684FA5A0FA0E42B87FA53D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Provide guidance and leadership for activities to promote the public health, including encouraging nurses and other health professionals to be volunteers and developing projects that educate the public about and engage the public in prevention practices to achieve better health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3044645E99B34428944F7B62E15291C3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide guidance and leadership to encourage nurses to engage in furthering their education in order to conduct nursing research, increase the awareness of evidence-based practice, and educate future nurses.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC4A02FA44AB4806B34D8B376AB2A572"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide guidance and leadership for activities that will increase public safety and emergency preparedness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C870463014845CD824D1FDC51F1AA3C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prepare and publish a biennial report on the state of the Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service Nurse Category.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H8D0411AF6DE440E1A665CEA15E36C3B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National health priorities—National Prevention Strategy</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HB8731AE0B5AF4312ABCDC64FFF93792A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Nurse for Public Health, in cooperation with the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service, heads of the agencies of the Public Health Service, States, and organizations that represent health professionals, shall continue to participate in the identification of national health priorities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9DF5A54FFC24410AA220A7C1D45CF241"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Addressing national health priorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Nurse for Public Health, in addressing national health priorities, shall encourage volunteerism of nurses and other individuals, and strengthen the relationship between Government agencies and health-related national organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H60F5C229CC144B47B2D45CD60D182B5F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community-based projects</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H32BA4649AC9F4786BAE1C2FD9A458CC0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addressing national health priorities, the National Nurse for Public Health shall—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H5C5BBE0B276B4755AA789D61B170A4CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide guidance and coordination on recommended activities to organizations;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HA92DFAAEEF404B49BEF7FB211A9D1F2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledge successful programs and encourage their replication;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H47C97C1EB7E743BDBE37B3ABE90FCF4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote the dissemination of evidence-based practice in educating the public on health promotion and disease prevention activities;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H1BED4C980B8C42A79B1DD8BFA67C713D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage practicing nurses and other health professionals, including retired health professionals and students enrolled in health professional programs, to participate in health promotion activities and replicate successful health promotion activities in their local communities; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H9A87F73A7D7844C48C48F8F2B7D79647"><enum>(v)</enum><text>collaborate with Federal agencies to monitor activities being conducted through the collection and evaluation of data to determine if national health priorities are being addressed.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H43A98EDB9B174978B7A12AB2C39640DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Outreach and education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting outreach and education under subsection (c)(4), the National Nurse for Public Health shall give priority to the inclusion of diverse approaches, including social media campaigns, to address national health priorities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H475C2C0664EC47F0ABAA3FE1945F5D2C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Nurse for Public Health shall participate in preparing the annual status report of the National Prevention, Health Promotion and Public Health Council under section 4001(h)(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB1E5175A13BC48DCBB08E3D0C4449060"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Dissemination of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Nurse for Public Health shall disseminate information to governmental agencies, schools, and community-based, nonprofit organizations interested in health promotion and improving public health through community action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

