<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H656956DA186542DBBA431312B1792973" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2528 IH: Expanded Access to Real Learning for our Young Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2528</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Education to award grants to States to pay the Federal share of carrying out full-day prekindergarten programs.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H48CF4689C60C4C9EA12760059895577E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4742D2013F9C4F0894BDFFBA83D6145B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header> 
<subsection id="H35060259144F418880C6188637016C3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanded Access to Real Learning for our Young Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EARLY Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE3B1DF47AC8B42909A45CB62E18458C6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Universal prekindergarten and early childhood education grant program</header> <subsection id="H5A11159B6F394164887462B6F7266B38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorization</header><text>From amounts appropriated under subsection (g), the Secretary of Education is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to States to pay the Federal share of carrying out full-day prekindergarten programs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7459AC30EE8142088927C9B507CD7E4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State application</header><text>To receive a grant under this Act, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3060315EC2294C9E9B39928E3B2ECE36"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this Act shall use such grant funds to carry out a prekindergarten program that, at a minimum—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAA47BBEDC1F14B7E8DFAAA41B6CBAD82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if practicable, is located at a public school in the State or, if not practicable, is carried out by a private or other community provider;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16F710CC555143EC864EFB8A214DB896"><enum>(2)</enum><text>permits each 4-year-old child in the State to be voluntarily enrolled by the child’s parent in the prekindergarten program, and which is made available at no cost to families who make a combined income of up to 400 percent of the poverty line;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAF3257A4CBE4BEF8571B37CD43E5018"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is a full-day program that runs the length of the regular school year;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60B8AE80B9DA43CE8A566C123112EBD6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>maintains a maximum class size of 20 children, with at least 1 prekindergarten teacher per classroom;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68063E3750174E82BDDFC0F8195B5EC2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensures that the ratio of children to prekindergarten teachers and teacher aides does not exceed 10 to 1;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0712A3D097224249AB3EAC90FC0022CE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>is taught by teachers who are paid a salary comparable to teachers of kindergarten through grade 12 at public schools in the State;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58A468292AF74EB1A60B0CC2312445F9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>requires the State in which the program is located to determinate a minimum level of parental engagement in their child’s program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7AF983513CCD497481DA01A917BB331A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>meets any other criteria that the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4A02C78C2C194484AE253436CB82D177"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to States that will use the grants to carry out a prekindergarten program at a public school.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD50B3DAB02F244A88E423B1044CDE85B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of a grant under this Act shall not exceed 75 percent of the costs of carrying out the activities described in subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE6B4191AF9404DE094A6761195AE8E98"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Grant funds received under this Act shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal early childhood education funds in the State.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H49BBD0F25368420B9AAC397515899921"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6CD78A3731DF4EB5860A748348EE35DF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H000F6606E81048C3BCFA7AEB109F27AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>parent</term>, <term>poverty line</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9101">20 U.S.C. 9101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBD44E10BD544137BC124052215612E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public school</header><text>The term <term>public school</term> means a public elementary school or public secondary school.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF22127C36CA40D7804A45185FF76410"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


