<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3FD94552FCC343A9AF0119BE7717EDD2" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4006 IH: Statutes at Large Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4006</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151116">November 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide the public with access to the laws of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5DD5655E0C4A47DCB13C532871412196" style="OLC">
 <section id="H85A7372EB4644F90B4AFA58E31AC6B50" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Statutes at Large Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1F87BC9E9F20456EAFF1B977808C0961"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public access to the laws of the United States</header> <subsection id="H8C1925710496417BB369F51D3FCD481A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Archivist requirement To make laws available</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 112 of title 1, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Archivist shall make available anything compiled, edited, indexed, and published under this section to the public at no cost on a website in a searchable, non-proprietary format. The Archivist shall ensure that the searchable online edition of the United States Statutes at Large is prepared in consultation and coordination with entities that develop formatting conventions used for enrolled bills and other legislative materials, which may include the Library of Congress, the Office of the Clerk of the House, the Office of the Secretary of the Senate, the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Office of the Law Revision Council, the Congressional Research Service, the Government Publishing Office, and such other entities that the Archivist considers appropriate.</quote></text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H1D5714418FF24C4EB3C9A129C2760894"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Librarian of Congress requirement To incorporate searchable Statutes at Large Into Legislative
 Information Retrieval System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 209 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/180">2 U.S.C. 180</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC75D47F63752451D9965818F02DE21FA" style="traditional">
 <subsection id="H8BEB5FFE3ED04E0E812FC2E7B85DA3B8"><enum>(f)</enum><text>In addition to the legislative information described in subsection (b), the relevant electronic information made available under section 112 of title 1, United States Code, shall be incorporated into the legislative information service to the extent practicable.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCE1B56631DD14148B9AA9CFA1209D293"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020 to carry out the provisions of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


