<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H567651ED20F046838A0D7BBF4F3A7D74" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 824 IH: State Marriage Defense Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 824</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000458">Mr. Fincher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000602">Mr. Pompeo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000182">Mr. Neugebauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/1/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 1, United States Code, with regard to the definition of <quote>marriage</quote> and <quote>spouse</quote> for Federal purposes and to ensure respect for State regulation of marriage.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H57E4507C0D124B94B3D587A168EEB844" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5191EA9C5D4D4327A47CC20EFC7159E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Marriage Defense Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H51450C5FF4E242008DFC087790E47360"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5094B9A2AD0941E685FAA1523FB04342"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress affirms the States’ legitimate and proper public policy interests in regulating domestic relations and in defining marriage for the residents of their States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63994211F413458EBBEEFA86CBEDA93E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Despite striking down section 3 of the Defense of Marriage Act, the Supreme Court ruling in United States v. Windsor did not institute a new Federal definition of marriage that includes same sex marriage. Instead, United States v. Windsor specifically required the Federal Government to defer to <quote>state sovereign choices about who may be married</quote> in determining marital status for Federal purposes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96A3AC58632F4C9386BFA3866AEF73F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress recognizes that current actions by the Federal Government to afford benefits to certain relationships not recognized as marriages by a person’s State of residence go beyond the Supreme Court’s ruling in United States v. Windsor. These Federal actions create <quote>two contradictory marriage regimes within the same State,</quote> in direct contradiction of United States v. Windsor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55549B580DFC422F98D7BC81654473EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Actions taken by the Federal Government to grant recognition of marital status for persons not recognized as married in their State of domicile undermine a State’s legitimate authority to define marriage for its residents.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD0438E2C373348ABA41E8849CE6B0148"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendment to definition of marriage for Federal purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of title 1, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HD119A8EE35F8435ABE1B3630D8236547" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H5FCEF01690D04212B5EADB1ED3FCBDFD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definition of <quote>Marriage</quote> and <quote>Spouse</quote></header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In determining the meaning of any Act of Congress, or of any ruling, regulation, or interpretation of the various administrative bureaus and agencies of the United States, as applied with respect to individuals domiciled in a State or in any other territory or possession of the United States the term <quote>marriage</quote> shall not include any relationship which that State, territory, or possession does not recognize as a marriage, and the term <quote>spouse</quote> shall not include an individual who is a party to a relationship that is not recognized as a marriage by that State, territory, or possession.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


