<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDD516BBE537747FC83088BE5D7311091" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3280 IH: WIRED Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3280</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to require one-stop delivery systems under
			 such Act to offer services through Internet websites and to direct the
			 Secretary of Labor to develop standards and best practices for such
			 websites, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H959B23D958B640C5BDD795DE8004DC26" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8F7A9C018C3F4991B85717A637E3BA4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Widening Internet Readiness for Employment Development Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>WIRED Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1703C868434048049AF8602BAAAE9DE5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Online provision of one-stop services</header> <subsection id="HD72CCC40E0984A72AB6A1608CD983B46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Online provision of one-Stop services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (D) of section 121(e)(2) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3151">29 U.S.C. 3151(e)(2)(D)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB945D8322976402887089FD1029D5E2D" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H4D0F34D74B484946B4629B174EF7148D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as applicable and practicable, shall make programs, services, and activities accessible to individuals through an Internet website that—</text>
 <clause id="H0845CE2DB4354729A56F9C43C65CB46C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is unique to the particular one-stop delivery system; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0219D11AEF1B494CBDCC71DABC59FFAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the standards and incorporates the best practices established by the Secretary of Labor under subsection (j).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCC76825076FB4CEFBB8AA1C53CFA77C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards and best practices for online provision of services by one-Stop delivery systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 121 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3951">29 U.S.C. 3951</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CD818C16213431780BE787CF31C42B2" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H00FF226E75A54543A9E3A987E3EB35A4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Standards and best practices for online provision of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After soliciting public comments and consulting with and receiving input from relevant parties, including State workforce development boards, the Secretary of Labor shall establish and maintain standards and best practices for Internet websites maintained by one-stop delivery systems under subsection (e)(2)(D), and for the provision of services through such websites. Such standards and best practices shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD0982C7967A84DE38A268A6C3E906432"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a requirement for user-friendly, up-to-date websites available to all dislocated workers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A734D4FEE6540CA8BF961132B47795E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a requirement that such websites prominently display the address and hours of operation of all physical one-stop centers in the local area, and a description of services provided in and events held at each such center;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F6DDA7302B74193B2820AF045D7C29D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">best practices for providing, through such websites, services such as resume assistance, cover letter review, job searching, interview preparations, and online employment-related practice tests, through videos, video-conferencing, or other means;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H375D1D658167400E891A2AE2F3E4876E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>best practices for assuring a secure network and the protection of any personal information;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0FE80518A044B7E90B45F75EB099131"><enum>(5)</enum><text>best practices for incorporating social media and networking capabilities into such websites; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BFB6B726F334358A746A6A418482751"><enum>(6)</enum><text>best practices for making such websites accessible by mobile devices to the extent practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HA5E0366A93B741678201977B6FD07E08"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish the initial standards and best practices required by section 121(j) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (as added by subsection (b)) not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


