<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H021BB5431E3E413C91DADCCCD94580A6" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2010 IH: Regulatory Review and Sunset Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2010</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150423">April 23, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the periodic review and automatic termination of Federal regulations.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD0600305103043A99BC0A43CB3C74EFA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7AF4C0366DE348A89E06E813CD04B113" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulatory Review and Sunset Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF5E9B9CCA5C94FADA5E7F4AB5B67ED3D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFD0971114E8D4A179A3B08740351E3E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require agencies to regularly review significant rules to determine whether the rules should be continued without change, modified, consolidated with another rule, or terminated;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H661BE282FE7B4EA782362E40FE560976"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to require agencies to consider the comments of the public, the regulated community, and Congress regarding the actual costs and burdens of rules reviewed under this Act, and whether the rules are obsolete, unnecessary, duplicative, conflicting, or otherwise inconsistent;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5A01D1588ED4931948FB0245E444851"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to require that any rules continued in effect under this Act meet all the legal requirements that would apply to the issuance of a new rule, including any applicable Federal cost-benefit and risk assessment requirements;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30D041069D0C43D4B3BC0C11B217181C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide for the review of significant rules and other rules through a sunset review process and to provide for the repeal or other change in such rules in accordance with chapters 5 and 7 of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAEE80714004745A28F836F28AF7B97F9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to provide for a petition process that allows the public and appropriate committees of Congress to request that other rules that are not significant be reviewed in the same manner as significant rules; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77B3692FD605451E90252ECC512C728A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to require the Administrator to coordinate and be responsible for sunset reviews conducted by agencies.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5809C7BA0C0946E3AA7A0D36D1638CF9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of rules for sunset review</header> 
<subsection id="H57ED86CA5BEC41FE948DDC184CB8FE91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Covered rules</header><text>A covered rule shall be subject to sunset review in accordance with this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H91B48F2A6210462DBBC8924334AFE906"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public petitions</header> <paragraph id="H1B6108554A0245E896EF02CCE95605AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person adversely affected by a rule that is not a significant rule may submit a petition to the agency that has jurisdiction over the rule requesting that the agency designate the rule for sunset review, which shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H786A851A52F44B6DB2DC4765E17CEDAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be in writing, but is not otherwise required to be in any particular form; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED8D55DB9A4746CDBC127A2CB8480ED7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify the rule for which sunset review is requested with reasonable specificity and state on its face that the petitioner seeks sunset review of the rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31DD3B3686AC4E17AE0648305A2CDC49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Response required for noncomplying petitions</header><text>If an agency determines that a petition submitted under paragraph (1) does not meet the requirements of this subsection, the agency shall provide a response to the petitioner not later than 30 days after the date on which the agency received the petition, which shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF26351D998E0495094A6337ABA1E005E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the petitioner of the problem; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE231D7A8C8DC42A681DA0EE18D43ECA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide information on how to formulate a petition that meets those requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H004AE70C15BD4C108D5D277078CB741C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decision within <enum-in-header>90</enum-in-header> days</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which an agency receives a petition under paragraph (1) that meets the requirements of this subsection, the agency shall transmit a response to the petitioner stating whether the petition was granted or denied, except that the agency may extend such period by a total of not more than 30 days.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A017B1E56AC49659286E3BB715C9BC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Petitions deemed granted for substantial inexcusable delay</header><text>A petition submitted under paragraph (1) is deemed to have been granted by an agency, and such agency is deemed to have designated the rule for sunset review, if a court finds there is a substantial and inexcusable delay, beyond the period specified in paragraph (3), in notifying the petitioner of the determination of the agency to grant or deny the petition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8696C0B39E547A2963085C28AAF96E2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public log</header><text>Each agency shall maintain a public log of petitions submitted under paragraph (1), which shall include the status or disposition of each petition.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA35C7FFB989E456083AF477CD571AA5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional requests</header> 
<paragraph id="H09A7B15DBF894580AF839510076879A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An appropriate committee of Congress, or a majority of the majority party members or a majority of nonmajority party members of such committee, may request in writing that the Administrator designate any rule that is not a significant rule for sunset review.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13E48B6830D142F0869CB842B99E4323"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation by Administrator</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator receives a request under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall designate the rule for sunset review, unless the Administrator determines that it would not be in the public interest to conduct a sunset review of the rule.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05BF02BCA0194098A4E5FF5D8DF52642"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of denial</header><text>If the Administrator denies a request under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall transmit to the committee of Congress making the request a notice stating the reasons for the denial.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1C162307A27D46AA8A88DA1FA5E1446C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication of notice of designation for sunset review</header><text>After designating a rule under subsection (b) or (c) for sunset review, the agency or the Administrator, as applicable, shall promptly publish a notice of that designation in the Federal Register.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H53E97F44438C4AD5909259823757EA50"><enum>4.</enum><header>Criteria for sunset review</header> 
<subsection id="H30DAF68EEBC44FCABCEAD8DB84B8B1CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compliance with other laws</header><text>In order for any rule subject to sunset review to continue without change or to be modified or consolidated in accordance with this Act, such rule shall be authorized by law and meet all applicable requirements that would apply if it were issued as a new rule pursuant to section 553 of title 5, United States Code, or other statutory rulemaking procedures required for that rule.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H144894655A5447858635E9F362F215D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Governing law</header><text>If there is a conflict between applicable requirements and an Act under which a rule was issued, the conflict shall be resolved in the same manner as such conflict would be resolved if the agency were issuing a new rule.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6EC59C2DBFEB4E5582BC5332278FAC54"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable requirements defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>applicable requirements</term> includes any requirement for—</text> <paragraph id="H685760EE45394090993A21FC6EB7533D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>cost-benefit analysis; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H889B2B6C1D6740B7AA039CABFA88643F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>standardized risk analysis and risk assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H1BF20F0C802841E8BBCF8BC71E2C00AE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sunset review procedures</header> <subsection id="HAD04F08106AF437BA5256587D45B29D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Functions of the administrator</header> <paragraph id="H3DE9229F7923435891A0514DED98B560"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of rules subject to review</header> <subparagraph id="HD35142773A01412DB311E6A9C039FDC1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Inventory and first list</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall conduct an inventory of rules in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and publish a first list of covered rules, which shall—</text> 
<clause id="H3132D55616DA43AABB0B0E5FAFD28FC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specify the particular group to which each significant rule is assigned under paragraph (2), and state the review deadline for all significant rules in each such group in accordance with section 6(a)(1); and</text></clause> <clause id="H32779A710F494FE99CEC77A3177D0C50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include other rules subject to sunset review for any other reason, and state the review deadline for each such rule in accordance with section 6(a)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H098FBDC521994141BEC3689947DF8612"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent lists</header><text>After publication of the first list under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall publish an updated list of covered rules at least annually, specifying the review deadline for each rule on the list.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8370279A4E6B43F496571B6DA2A9706C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grouping of significant rules in first list</header> <subparagraph id="H4C5F25B28EEC45D9AD61ED9D6D129107"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Staggered review</header><text>To permit orderly and prioritized sunset reviews, the Administrator shall—</text> 
<clause id="H770A99B6FF564927B1E4FEC676207A18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assign each significant rule in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act to 1 of 4 groups established by the Administrator; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7487B56715004C1E85CA85A8DD26D50E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specify for each such group an initial review deadline in accordance with section 6(a)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A19A7F0183947D5A3173A29FDE23ED8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prioritizations</header><text>In determining which rules shall be given priority in time in the assignment under subparagraph (A)(i), the Administrator shall—</text> <clause id="HC1DDF87A37F54F5AB067A2325766FA18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consult with appropriate agencies; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H99A3D1F306CF4113B1161E637C4BE765"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prioritize rules based on—</text> <subclause id="HD2C3296AC7764F5EB9993C6AE669B2C2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the grouping of related rules under paragraph (3);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBB92D85957264991B532D2C5797F390C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the extent of the cost of each rule and on the regulated community and the public, with priority in time given to those rules that impose the greatest cost;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDF8E9D28474846FFA6DD8318E3750D06"><enum>(III)</enum><text>consideration of the views of regulated persons, including State and local governments;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE6C09D6A9D7F44959924C00636AFF1F6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>whether a particular rule has recently been subject to cost-benefit analysis and risk assessment, with priority in time given to those rules that have not been subject to such analysis and assessment;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8988CD55B0CA4EA9B641977D7814785C"><enum>(V)</enum><text>whether a particular rule was issued under a statutory provision that provides relatively greater discretion to an official in issuing the rule, with priority in time given to those rules that were issued under provisions that provide relatively greater discretion;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H27B1CCD07EEA4360A6A6D7BD1F541357"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the burden of reviewing each rule on the reviewing agency; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA5E9573A745A44D186BBA881EF1AE231"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the need for orderly processing and the timely completion of the sunset reviews of rules in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20DA849DADEA48C58C6474EDB1C5A2FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grouping of related rules</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H092B74A0A3824B7D9D729168CACBA81D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>group related rules under paragraph (2) (and designate other rules) for simultaneous sunset review based upon subject matter similarity, functional interrelationships, and other relevant factors to ensure comprehensive and coordinated review of redundant, overlapping, and conflicting rules and requirements;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDB135661DCC4B219DB2D44D817E0665"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure simultaneous sunset reviews of covered rules without regard to whether they were issued by the same agency; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD89F09C69C284AD3B29B2B05936E3FF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall designate any other rule for sunset review that is necessary for a comprehensive sunset review whether or not such other rule is otherwise a covered rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8541405DD37B47529607E91889F4781E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide timely guidance to agencies on the conduct of sunset reviews and the preparation of sunset review notices and reports required under this Act to ensure—</text> <subparagraph id="H3D88E2619A25463AB367AD27FDD9BB52"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uniform, complete, and timely sunset reviews; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E40786729D0415394B841098F9D408E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notice and opportunity for public comment under section 7(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3ABAE0A486FD4CCB859DB87ACCE3D7A9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Review and evaluation of reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after receiving a preliminary report under subsection (b)(2), the Administrator shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD8359720B7FB4232BE66D1EB2F4835E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review and evaluate each preliminary and final report submitted by an agency under paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D1F763BCDBD4E059FA85E4B3F2BDA69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transmit comments to the head of the agency regarding—</text> 
<clause id="H48F6396E9F6B4268AE7646088C713452"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the quality of the analysis in the report, including whether the agency has properly applied section 4;</text></clause> <clause id="H1ED0968813234B7EADC74A3772BCE6F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the consistency of the proposed action of the agency with actions of other agencies; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H95A493486CA54DA08F61F49B839702AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether the rule should be continued without change, modified, consolidated with another rule, or terminated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8FB758710BE94572809956AAD7166C3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency sunset review procedure</header> <paragraph id="HDDD6E6EF90A3441CAC3597D4B5C5411D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sunset review notice</header><text>Not less than 30 months before the review deadline under section 6(a) for a covered rule issued by an agency, the agency shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB013B0051AEE4023AAC754A902F643BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish a sunset review notice in accordance with section 7(a) in the Federal Register and, to the extent reasonable and practicable, in other publications or media that are designed to reach those persons most affected by the covered rule; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9AFCA732BD4D4F6090AA6F028848C9A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>request the views of the Administrator and the appropriate committees of Congress on whether to continue without change, modify, consolidate, or terminate the covered rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DB94E9D93FC40B494DDBB0B24FF7DAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preliminary report</header><text>In reviewing a covered rule, the agency shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H953C8A1CD3BE4D2BB551C1DF843636C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider public comments and other recommendations generated by a sunset review notice under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC6021959A5045D38D8AE8C0CF4098C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 1 year before the review deadline under section 6(a) for the covered rule, publish in the Federal Register, in accordance with section 7(b), and transmit to the Administrator and the appropriate committees of the Congress a preliminary report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB2A6590348B414BAB2F2ABBACC727CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>The agency shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA9E25DC145CD4A4985612D30E1367FEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the public comments and other recommendations generated by the preliminary report under paragraph (2) for a covered rule;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H602A02AAB9354CA7BE60B27EBF67D815"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with the appropriate committees of Congress before issuing a final report; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56ED82E7BD53424EA9422014DE154A39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less than 90 days before the review deadline of the covered rule, publish in the Federal Register, in accordance with section 7(c)(2) or 7(d), and transmit a final report to the Administrator and the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F0F27F1A9E44128A8B87C1B3AD78C82"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Open procedures regarding sunset review</header><text>In any sunset review conducted under this Act, the agency conducting the review shall make a written record describing the subject of all contacts the agency or Administrator made with non-governmental persons outside the agency relating to the review, which shall be made available, upon request, to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9F2D07DE2FB146849DEA825C0129DFBC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effectiveness of agency recommendation</header><text>If a final report under subsection (b)(3)—</text> <paragraph id="HB8829A0F89004ACCB3DA5C4207FF5D1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommends that a covered rule should be continued without change, the covered rule shall be continued; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF801EE3C0008447DA3F740A1153EA470"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommends that a covered rule should be modified, consolidated with another rule, or terminated, the rule may be modified, so consolidated, or terminated in accordance with section 7(d).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD5ACA0700B604CED9EADAFF935AF4E77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preservation of independence of federal bank regulatory agencies</header><text>The head of any appropriate Federal banking agency, the Federal Housing Finance Board, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight shall have the authority with respect to that agency that would otherwise be granted under subsection (a) to the Administrator.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB2948DFCBE7C410EA6CCD5D59C12AA3F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Review deadlines for covered rules</header> 
<subsection id="HACF6876813564B74A2362E41F2303FFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this Act, the review deadline of a covered rule is as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HBCD6C2A60BDC4C83BC8150AE3AC0E4EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing significant rules</header> <subparagraph id="H99CE32A132AE4FEDB33E843F8DA239D1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For a significant rule in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, the initial review deadline is the last day of the 4-year, 5-year, 6-year, or 7-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, as specified by the Administrator under section 5(a)(2)(A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1104170E1DCB4A62AB6D12233C232EDB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other significant rules</header><text>For a significant rule that is not assigned to such a group specified under section 5(a)(2)(A) on the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the initial review deadline is the last day of the 4-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E5D9ED44A5E4C49828E04DA87937B46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New significant rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a significant rule that first takes effect after the date of the enactment of this Act, the initial review deadline is the last day of the 10-year period beginning on the date on which the rule takes effect.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC058EA49AC4C4A10836CB28C3E621BD6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rules covered pursuant to public petition or congressional request</header><text>For a rule subject to sunset review pursuant to a public petition under section 3(b) or a congressional request under section 3(c), the initial review deadline is the last day of the 3-year period beginning on—</text> <subparagraph id="H48E890A634FD475EA73D580FFA544E2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the agency or Administrator so designates the rule for sunset review; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H051A620CFCCC420BA04B9705A6B39B6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of issuance of a final court order that the agency is deemed to have designated the rule for sunset review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDA9BA16AB664A63857AEC67D681D72D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Related rule designated for review</header><text>For a rule that the Administrator designates under section 5(a)(3) for sunset review because it is related to another covered rule and that is grouped with that other rule for simultaneous review, the initial review deadline is the same as the review deadline for that other rule.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD2DAEFA1B3F148F694B5DE7D1FAF94CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary extension</header><text>The review deadline under subsection (a) for a covered rule may be extended by the Administrator for not more than 6 months by publishing notice thereof in the Federal Register that describes the reasons why the temporary extension is necessary to respond to or prevent an emergency situation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDCD8136609734E0DAD5B9AD658F6E838"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determinations where rules have been amended</header><text>For purposes of this Act, if various provisions of a covered rule were issued at different times, the rule as a whole shall be treated as if it were issued on the later of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H23A735734EDB462EAC13A3799D80B5C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date of issuance of the provision of the rule that was issued first; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H017EDF89B6FD402BA2E9EAAA1863A238"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the most recent review and revision of the rule under this Act was completed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC22A3535C2FC476CB84F85CBF06B1D0D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset review notices and agency reports</header> 
<subsection id="H665C54BCDDFC417DBB7D1113CB52ADFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sunset review notices</header><text>The sunset review notice required under section 5(b)(1) for a covered rule shall—</text> <paragraph id="H521565A6DD5241F2873FCA2132BF7927"><enum>(1)</enum><text>request comments regarding whether the rule should be continued without change, modified, consolidated with another rule, or terminated;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90D4E619FA9F47BD85AED4DC7C4B74E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if applicable, request comments regarding whether the rule meets the applicable Federal cost-benefit and risk assessment criteria; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4E3791CA0D24BD484F99CF52EE37D83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>solicit comments about the past implementation and effects of the rule, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCCC3FD8670724C2EA69B2E6774E6C230"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the direct and indirect costs incurred because of the rule, including the net reduction in the value of private property (whether real, personal, tangible, or intangible), and whether the incremental benefits of the rule exceeded the incremental costs of the rule, both generally and regarding each of the specific industries and sectors the rule covers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD7F14428D194CB8A070A43A307AF0FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the rule as a whole, or any major feature of it, is outdated, obsolete, or unnecessary, whether by change of technology, the marketplace, or otherwise;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H780111E5C57A40958B9CD75859AE0C84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which the rule or information required to comply with the rule duplicated, conflicted, or overlapped with requirements under rules of other agencies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F4826EA1DC843FCB82482532E65E8D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of a rule addressing a risk to health or safety or the environment, what the perceived risk was at the time of issuance and to what extent the risk predictions were accurate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03285EBD6F544BF9BDB20B671DB0E2A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the rule unnecessarily impeded domestic or international competition or unnecessarily intruded on free market forces, and whether the rule unnecessarily interfered with opportunities or efforts to transfer to the private sector duties carried out by the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EDFBF587836496996A6C05672D8776F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>whether, and to what extent, the rule imposed unfunded mandates on, or otherwise affected, State and local governments;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9255F746C6EB4BAFA6D845A025C55C0B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>whether compliance with the rule required substantial capital investment and whether terminating the rule on the next review deadline would create an unfair advantage to those who are not in compliance with the rule;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB7FCEC2ED7B44AD96FF6200E04912B9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>whether the rule constituted the least cost method of achieving its objective consistent with the criteria of the Act under which the rule was issued, and to what extent the rule provided flexibility to those who were subject to the rule;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF105DEF53BB14B13937073F209D259AC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the rule was worded simply and clearly, including clear identification of those who were subject to the rule;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H977F1C690C6C4334967EE6B21BE1CE6F"><enum>(J)</enum><text>whether the rule created negative unintended consequences;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1224AD0BDC24461DBE9131C66D36BB75"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the extent to which information requirements under the rule can be reduced; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD41390A273B4FF9A3CFC38B197A3345"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the extent to which the rule has contributed positive benefits, particularly health, safety, or environmental benefits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE59E62A5087E4BCEABE1DC29FCB44CF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preliminary reports on sunset reviews</header><text>The preliminary report required under section 5(b)(2) on the sunset review of a covered rule shall contain—</text> <paragraph id="HF1486C663F37408F93C8AD1C18980E9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a request for public comments;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04497F4AA7A94F74B92323E242CC0872"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specific requests for factual findings and recommended legal conclusions regarding the application of section 4 to the rule, the continued need for the rule, and whether the rule duplicates functions of another rule;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35516B6AB7794FBD9ECBCFF83D7B22C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a request for comments on whether the rule should be continued without change, modified, consolidated with another rule, or terminated; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17DF1C5D4C5D467CA82ABA085625137B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if consolidation or modification of the rule is recommended, suggestions for the proposed text of the consolidated or modified rule.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H22EEB7D058DB4EE999ABD5B108F5F464"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final reports on sunset reviews</header> <paragraph id="H1D255C947B144AC880AAEECF68B3F7B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The report required under section 5(b)(3) on the sunset review of a covered rule shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H995E91E26D574CA2BCEFCF714C6A2858"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contain the factual findings and legal conclusions of the agency conducting the review regarding the application of section 5 to the rule and the proposed recommendation of the agency as to whether the rule should be continued without change, modified, consolidated with another rule, or terminated;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68124ACD655B452D85C413682263C65F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a rule that the agency proposes to continue without change, so state;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AC8D253979244019618581606D6CD28"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a rule that the agency proposes to modify or consolidate with another rule, contain—</text> <clause id="H0977748EA28140F0A5994FDD2F1977B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a notice of proposed rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, or under other statutory rulemaking procedures required for that rule, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE7612680D4947488BD8F4BA613D0325"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the text of the rule as so modified or consolidated; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H781EED6920F741FCB49EB8111331C0A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of a rule that the agency proposes to terminate, contain a notice of proposed rulemaking for termination consistent with subparagraph (C)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC929CAFBEABD42CF8F59AE2732DF5C6D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>A final report under paragraph (1)(B) shall be published in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDA10253D128749B792714EC68EB2D9E3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header> <paragraph id="H2A2506D4AC564D5CB918700531A48384"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>A final report under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (c)(1) shall be published in the Federal Register, which shall constitute publication of the notice required under subsection (c)(1)(C)(i).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H116C8B8A7AAD4AC0B1BA992312FCE3DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>After publication of a final report under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (c)(1), the agency that conducted the sunset review of the covered rule shall conduct the rulemaking that is required in such final report.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD6C834958C504C61A50579C3FD413166"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Legislative recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the head of an agency determines that a rule in a final report under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (c)(1) cannot be changed, modified, or consolidated with another rule without legislative action, the head of the agency shall include in the final report a description of what legislative changes are required to implement the recommendations in the final report with regard to the rule.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7C29A8250AA84A91BCE957442EBAA54A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Designation of agency regulatory review officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The head of each agency shall designate an officer of the agency as the Regulatory Review Officer of the agency, who shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2E343137762F438D9C1AFBAF17D0B380"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be responsible for the implementation of this Act by the agency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8000CB524AAB49C2B3BC3E0D7DECE072"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report directly to the head of the agency and the Administrator with respect to that responsibility.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H650CA268F9484CA9B9C1AC9B5B6204B2"><enum>9.</enum><header>Relationship to the Administrative Procedure Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede the provisions of chapter 5, 6, or 7 of title 5, United States Code.</text></section> 
<section id="H1A53F867B2F3498E97E55775F6F2BFE2"><enum>10.</enum><header>Effect of termination of a covered rule</header> 
<subsection id="H416E61C2FDB642ECB72F81755470C99F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), if a covered rule is terminated under this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HB55F46B1268745A5ACBDB47A393E44A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act shall not be construed to prevent the President or an agency from exercising any authority that otherwise exists to implement the statute under which the rule was issued;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H139AE9CA73034BBEB43C26AEBF24FD38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in an agency proceeding or court action between an agency and a non-agency party, the rule shall be given no conclusive legal effect, but may be submitted as evidence of prior agency practice and procedure; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4205E3EF5BB7483F94BBD58E4AEEC7B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>this Act shall not be construed to prevent the continuation or institution of any enforcement action that is based on a violation of the rule that occurred before the effectiveness of the rule terminated.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H57EBFA817FE54DE89BFF34A1B33C8FE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect on deadlines</header> 
<paragraph id="H4AD5AB6FFE22452E987CE92D43F6D3DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>deadline</term> means any date certain for fulfilling any obligation or exercising any authority established by or under any Federal rule, or by or under any court order implementing any Federal rule.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36CE5D553B1D4E11858DBA1B4FB99AA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), any deadline for, relating to, or involving any action dependent upon, any rule terminated under this Act is suspended until the agency that issued the rule issues a new rule on the same matter, unless otherwise provided by a law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H820EA0C5318F484CB9B9E7AA871C4524"><enum>11.</enum><header>Judicial review</header> 
<subsection id="H5172D98A4A84487E9F46247FB6D5D21B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public petition</header><text>A denial or substantial inexcusable delay in granting or denying a public petition under section 3(b) shall be considered a final agency action subject to review under section 702 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9B1500C5C4EA43E98DA5AFFCC158BECE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional request</header><text>A denial of a congressional request under section 3(c) shall not be subject to judicial review.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H79CF8A08027E4074BDFFAA208E539B04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Time limitation on filing a civil action</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, an action seeking judicial review of a final agency action under this Act may not be brought—</text> <paragraph id="HF2D5F0F2A70F4DB1B34F855E43B71F96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a final agency action denying a public petition under section 3(b) or continuing without change, modifying, consolidating, or terminating a covered rule, more than 30 days after the date of that agency action; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6226C71D9F934F9BB6BA30C1BE85D1EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an action challenging a delay in deciding on a public petition section 3(b), more than 1 year after the period applicable to the rule under section 3(b)(4).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF5C7D3233F6049638ABFFE99094861A1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of judicial review unaffected</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except to the extent that there is a direct conflict with the provisions of this Act, nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the availability or standard of judicial review for agency regulatory action.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H560942C0E4C74ACB996787683227C031"><enum>12.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H1789546D79494336812EF5D15AED3AF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs in the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FBB7D4D99134BB99907A027469BF42C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551(1) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29DA6CAF225E44B6B6EB10AF29E8448E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committee of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committee of Congress</term> means, with respect to a rule, each standing committee of Congress having authority under the Rules of the House of Representatives or the Senate to report a bill to amend the provision of law under which the rule is issued.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDE1428D4D844C5E9E73E13FC9B6754E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appropriate Federal banking agency</header><text>The term <term>appropriate Federal banking agency</term> has the meaning given that term under section 3(q) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(q)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9707ADAAA9774DFA824E70495391EA4B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered rule</header><text>The term <term>covered rule</term> means a rule that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5B650D8631544788A1731410E528C749"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is determined by the Administrator to be a significant rule; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD17AA891CCA04CA0A6694441E4B1607E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is any other rule designated by an agency or the Administrator for sunset review under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA35D89A3F5714E4BBBC6E6366B53F105"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Major rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major rule</term> means any rule that the Administrator finds has resulted in or is likely to result in—</text> <subparagraph id="H666D10B0A33445838ED59D1CA5CF14CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an annual effect on the economy of $100,000,000 or more;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H981F07A0395741D4B54896D78038D48B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, or local government agencies, or geographic regions; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5311462B2D14B2DA2B408D9C30C9EB7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B91A26FE8214D12A6933E7DCBA02297"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rule</header><text>The term <term>rule</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HDBD93B74A85E4D8A928C44669B425705"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> 
<clause id="HF61B3FFC995E49F899B96F099B17FACD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any agency statement of general applicability and future effect, including agency guidance documents, designed to implement, interpret, or prescribe law or policy, or describing the procedures or practices of an agency, or intended to assist in such actions; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0BD485778DFF4865BBC577D239AA7775"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each set of rules—</text> 
<subclause id="H6D25521CADB94DB5AEFA3C41E2D21459"><enum>(I)</enum><text>designated in the Code of Federal Regulations as a part; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H02B11DCAA54F46379EBB9EEC403B1BF7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that do not appear in the Code of Regulations and are comparable to a part of that Code under guidelines established by the Administrator; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEEB0C6CBA9ED4E99959C85A313992A5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="H5D76D9903E8944899196F5CC6E5DAA86"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regulations or other agency statements—</text> 
<subclause id="HD788168013694809973E76D85C830BD1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>issued in accordance with formal rulemaking provisions of sections 556 and 557 of title 5, United States Code, or in accordance with other statutory formal rulemaking procedures required for such regulations or statements;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H57C54FD977CF4362A7C84DD08765E0A8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that are limited to agency organization, management, or personnel matters;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0112C9FEEFD144149621E4A80CB3D4B3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>issued with respect to a military or foreign affairs function of the United States; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDDAFB7AC103D48848701020D3BB16E52"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>that the Administrator certifies in writing are necessary for the enforcement of the Federal criminal laws;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H7FDD4FA3CF874FF4B17171970475B2AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>regulations, statements, or other agency actions that are reviewed and usually modified each year (or more frequently), or are reviewed regularly and usually modified based on changing economic or seasonal conditions; or</text></clause> <clause id="HB52A3A350F4B4F71B3E91096C8832562"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>regulations or other agency actions that grant an approval, license, permit, registration, or similar authority or that grant or recognize an exemption or relieve a restriction, or any agency action necessary to permit new or improved applications of technology or to allow the manufacture, distribution, sale, or use of a substance or product.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC34DAAC00FD14C1BAB180B1E76AB5632"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Significant rule</header><text>The term <term>significant rule</term> means a rule that the Administrator determines—</text> <subparagraph id="HAAEAB4B00BE54832A1E3325520F16018"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has resulted in or is likely to result in an annual effect on the economy of $100,000,000 or more;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H704E5B4A2DC74E77B24DA8FA3801F93F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a major rule; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD52AE23277D54920AA992A853B29645D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was issued pursuant to a significant regulatory action, as that term is defined in Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review), as in effect on September 30, 1993.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6D99DA54AD04A7BADC33BB38B694840"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Sunset review</header><text>The term <term>sunset review</term> means a review of a rule under this Act.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB36A21D53B74407E88AB39460DB28614"><enum>13.</enum><header>Sunset of this act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall have no force or effect after the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


