<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDEB3EA8CC5A94EF69C5DA82D2963BFE8" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1428 IH: Judicial Redress Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1428</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To extend Privacy Act remedies to citizens of certified states, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9315683C5DDC46F487D455C6B0A72D29" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H94C86225CAED4E8FAE4C1054B72CDA23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Judicial Redress Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD10AED62612C470CBB0336858451DF20"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of Privacy Act remedies to citizens of designated countries</header> <subsection id="HAC5C8BB4889C468385E297D7FE456EDF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil action; civil remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to covered records, a covered person may bring a civil action against an agency and obtain civil remedies, in the same manner, to the same extent, and subject to the same limitations, including exemptions and exceptions, as an individual may bring and obtain with respect to records under—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5C94B6BFE7AD4018832239E72B5E426F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 552a(g)(1)(D) of title 5, United States Code, but only with respect to disclosures intentionally or willfully made in violation of section 552a(b) of such title; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0FB0846E4AB46A79D4D98CDE1D4371B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 552a(g)(1) of title 5, United States Code, but such an action may only be brought against a designated Federal agency or component.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2CB600AE19E04FCA960CDDCEFC59040C" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusive remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The remedies set forth in subsection (a) are the exclusive remedies available to a covered person under this section. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H9B051C32818A489DA21C96C0C3C52A71" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of the Privacy Act with respect to a covered person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of a civil action described in subsection (a), a covered person shall have the same rights, and be subject to the same limitations, including exemptions and exceptions, as an individual has and is subject to under section 552a of title 5, United States Code, when pursuing the civil remedies described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H01F09E6A399C454B85602655D0C9682F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designation of covered country</header> 
<paragraph id="HA18D292AD03446D28AD9C0437DBF0C6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, designate a foreign country or regional economic integration organization, or member country of such organization, as a <quote>covered country</quote> for purposes of this section if—</text> <subparagraph id="H4C5F0C9C45A546C191FFEA1C8FE678D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country or regional economic integration organization, or member country of such organization, has entered into an agreement with the United States that provides for appropriate privacy protections for information shared for the purpose of preventing, investigating, detecting, or prosecuting criminal offenses; or </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5433A542F9554931A2B2B1A55EDAD75E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Attorney General has determined that the country or regional economic integration organization, or member country of such organization, has effectively shared information with the United States for the purpose of preventing, investigating, detecting, or prosecuting criminal offenses and has appropriate privacy protections for such shared information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE3A9E0C3C004D96A69E3B85D0845148"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, revoke the designation of a foreign country or regional economic integration organization, or member country of such organization, as a <quote>covered country</quote> if the Attorney General determines that such designated <quote>covered country</quote>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8C2E058F822B423D94B7FF27951DE94D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not complying with the agreement described under paragraph (1)(A);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE94522DD64324067BCF6987689BFD243"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no longer meets the requirements for designation under paragraph (1)(B); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H270D05BC54F94889B98DEDECDA1F327F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impedes the transfer of information (for purposes of reporting or preventing unlawful activity) to the United States by a private entity or person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H8C8A9DD8940E47B7A5F67A0B8862198C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Designation of designated Federal agency or component</header> <paragraph id="H710B91E83F514DACA305B75297260875"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall determine whether an agency or component thereof is a <quote>designated Federal agency or component</quote> for purposes of this section. The Attorney General shall not designate any agency or component thereof other than the Department of Justice or a component of the Department of Justice without the concurrence of the head of the relevant agency, or of the agency to which the component belongs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEFE170A0818409AB4EC98BE13609C8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may determine that an agency or component of an agency is a <quote>designated Federal agency or component</quote> for purposes of this section, if—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF7773D36A6C41DAAEE7BCD3350D15B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Attorney General determines that information exchanged by such agency with a covered country is within the scope of an agreement referred to in subsection (d)(1)(A); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F3871F6A6404C85B0870C188815FAA6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a country or regional economic integration organization, or member country of such organization, that has been designated as a <quote>covered country</quote> under subsection (d)(1)(B), the Attorney General determines that designating such agency or component thereof is in the law enforcement interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1969B3915EA5431E8F46F347210565AD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal Register requirement; nonreviewable determination</header><text>The Attorney General shall publish each determination made under subsections (d) and (e). Such determination shall not be subject to judicial or administrative review.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H151DC069207742108F4560B5DE41F57C" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any claim arising under this section. </text> </subsection> <subsection id="HDA952C1C8C234307A0EBAEAC3E462A48"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H96CC8CC966E8476ABCA4165EE2E0C428" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 552(f) of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E77135752D64476921C93702070127A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered country</term> means a country or regional economic integration organization, or member country of such organization, designated in accordance with subsection (d).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CD7FA819BA647239A59B6776A80D78B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered person</term> means a natural person (other than an individual) who is a citizen of a covered country.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31F7E10C06024DADAE6D7841BBCBD001"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered record</term> has the same meaning for a covered person as a record has for an individual under section 552a of title 5, United States Code, once the covered record is transferred—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8682A8C964D6459DAD27FF4620D1E71D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by a public authority of, or private entity within, a country or regional economic organization, or member country of such organization, which at the time the record is transferred is a covered country; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA80BE409993A44A2BE2FCCE0EEECD2FA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to a designated Federal agency or component for purposes of preventing, investigating, detecting, or prosecuting criminal offenses. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F94FC8972CD46599F175E5A5B8B2C65"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Designated Federal agency or component</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>designated Federal agency or component</term> means a Federal agency or component of an agency designated in accordance with subsection (e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FB89B2551144B9E88522884609A3004" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Individual</header><text>The term <term>individual</term> has the meaning given that term in section 552a(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6EBFEE34962C4540BFAE9B83EAF550FF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Preservation of privileges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to waive any applicable privilege or require the disclosure of classified information. Upon an agency’s request, the district court shall review in camera and ex parte any submission by the agency in connection with this subsection.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H922C0BA54A1941E68E59D26B44073F12"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


