<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2B50C9A7C193429A9B098B90B9E57C79" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 195 IH: Election Assistance Commission Termination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 195</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To terminate the Election Assistance Commission.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H92135BBAC7044ACE8FF34D6929E8160B" style="OLC">
		<section id="HD8D58259BDD74294A075FDAA3F3E6C11" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Election Assistance Commission Termination Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H67DAF5B30ECA456AB91646209830ED0C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination of election assistance commission</header>
			<subsection id="H09736CF83D7246ACA401BB772DC06DAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20901">52 U.S.C. 20901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the
			 following new title:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AA2E53B5EAE4828A4ED265C43CD5EF2" style="OLC">
					<title id="H2A649C8C2ED846FA8E18B1B465F5CD03"><enum>X</enum><header>Termination of Commission</header>
						<section id="H262A5151141F4BBE9B009220F12544E0"><enum>1001.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective on the Commission termination date, the Commission (including the Election Assistance
			 Commission Standards Board and the Election Assistance Commission Board of
			 Advisors under part 2 of subtitle A of title II) is terminated and may not
			 carry out any programs or activities.</text>
						</section><section id="H6EC79401161C4B9CB9B56ECE1108448B"><enum>1002.</enum><header>Office of management and budget to perform transition functions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 1004, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall,
			 effective upon the Commission termination date—</text>
							<paragraph id="H3F22681F9CA14ADDBA7BAA1CFE36D365"><enum>(1)</enum><text>perform the functions of the Commission with respect to contracts and agreements described in
			 subsection 1003(a) until the expiration of such contracts and agreements,
			 but shall not renew any such contract or agreement; and</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H86E5A7F67C1448C580DD59F66F59218E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take the necessary steps to wind up the affairs of the Commission.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="H7053087F5D6E426E93532F8B507C3D6A"><enum>1003.</enum><header>Savings provisions</header>
							<subsection id="H41F90ACAF8FE42408927D60A54A08DE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prior contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The termination of the Commission under this title shall not affect any contract that has been
			 entered into by the Commission before the Commission termination date. All
			 such contracts shall continue in effect until modified, superseded,
			 terminated, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by an authorized
			 Federal official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or operation of law.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HE17267B692E24E9298E0B3238C3CE586"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Obligations of recipients of payments</header>
								<paragraph id="HCC9ED89FD4D54E939C93A5A33CDDDF19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The termination of the Commission under this title shall not affect the authority of any recipient
			 of a payment made by the Commission under this Act prior to the Commission
			 termination date to use any portion of the payment that remains
			 unobligated as of the Commission termination date, and the terms and
			 conditions that applied to the use of the payment at the time the payment
			 was made shall continue to apply.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H3D18E49365ED4061BF7ED3C1103172EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for States receiving requirements payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a requirements payment made to a State under part 1 of subtitle D of title II, the
			 terms and conditions applicable to the use of the payment for purposes of
			 the State’s obligations under this subsection (as well as any obligations
			 in effect prior to the termination of the Commission under this subtitle),
			 and for purposes of any applicable requirements imposed by regulations
			 promulgated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall
			 be the general terms and conditions applicable under Federal law, rules,
			 and regulations to payments made by the Federal Government to a State,
			 except that to the extent that such general terms and conditions are
			 inconsistent with the terms and conditions that are specified under part 1
			 of subtitle D of title II or section 902, the terms and conditions
			 specified under such part and such section shall apply.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7B575829F964987B3841AB75B680976"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pending proceedings</header>
								<paragraph id="H91DAB78897D84859BAC88470782911D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No effect on pending proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The termination of the Commission under this title shall not affect any proceeding to which the
			 Commission is a party that is pending on the Commission termination date,
			 including any suit to which the Commission is a party that is commenced
			 prior to such date, and the Director of the Office of Management and
			 Budget shall be substituted or added as a party to the proceeding.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H93E6323F7FD54E33A847BDE0C373B38E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of orders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a proceeding described in paragraph (1), an order may be issued, an appeal may be
			 taken, judgments may be rendered, and payments may be made as if the
			 Commission had not been terminated. Any such order shall continue in
			 effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by an authorized
			 Federal official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or operation of law.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H425E98714F3B4C469260E7146981E2A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Construction relating to discontinuance or modification</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any
			 proceeding described in paragraph (1) under the same terms and conditions
			 and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued
			 or modified if the Commission had not been terminated.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H80A53EF92A654E7585A65CFFF7788025"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations for transfer of proceedings</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget may issue regulations providing for the orderly
			 transfer of proceedings described in paragraph (1).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB2BD2C24E6C446680486218910EC712"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Orders and actions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget in the exercise of
			 functions of the Commission under section 1002 shall be subject to
			 judicial review to the same extent and in the same manner as if such
			 orders and actions had been issued or taken by the Commission. Any
			 requirements relating to notice, hearings, action upon the record, or
			 administrative review that apply to any function of the Commission shall
			 apply to the exercise of such function by the Director.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HC3764E4BF11742A79F73E3A11776529C"><enum>1004.</enum><header>Return to Federal Election Commission of authority to carry out certain functions under National
			 Voter Registration Act of 1993</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective on the Commission termination date, there are transferred to the Federal Election
			 Commission any functions transferred to the Election Assistance Commission
			 under section 802 (relating to functions described in section 9(a) of the
			 National Voter Registration Act of 1993).</text>
						</section><section id="H421E51DF1F6D457A950A312841DD9D2E"><enum>1005.</enum><header>Commission termination date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <quote>Commission termination date</quote> is the first date following the expiration of the 60-day period that begins on the date of the
			 enactment of this title.</text></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H373DBC80E5EB4BFC8E595612A10ADB4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination of Technical Guidelines Development Committee</header><text>Section 221 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20961">52 U.S.C. 20961</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new
			 subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C3739264BF5408A8D96185F616AB498" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HAA58818FF2DF4506B380879C96634B70"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the Commission termination date described in section 1005, the Development Committee
			 is terminated.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD66C44EA4AED4398AFB9035B9215D785"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19856B02C2114C22B8997AF653C8C4D1" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="title">Title X—Termination of Commission</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1001. Termination.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1002. Office of Management and Budget to perform transition functions.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1003. Savings provisions.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1004. Return to Federal Election Commission of authority to carry out certain functions under
			 National Voter Registration Act of 1993.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1005. Commission termination date.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H13936F342A0E4282BB733B27F7F0B170"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conforming amendments relating to return of certain authority to federal election commission</header>
			<subsection id="HA1B93906DE2F47629A5FA943F073F734"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971</header><text>Section 311(a) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30111">52 U.S.C. 30111(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="HDC7CF0F5B03E465A8581A4C9D5BE752A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (8);</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H4173D60A7C454FCDB5252375F2ED6FC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (9) and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H197B21AF8E4F48E6AB2DD3125F22CF5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DC86B6A20914E94978C901B2F36F3EE" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H31D6797C54064B8FB412739DC9198A26"><enum>(10)</enum><text>carry out the duties described in section 9(a) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H361E18CC6F4B430A933D82F4879435F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National voter registration act of 1993</header><text>Section 9(a) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20508">52 U.S.C. 20508(a)</external-xref>) is amended by
			 striking <quote>Election Assistance Commission</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal Election Commission</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H64C0DE98DC5A4E128B9D8C607011141A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the Commission termination date described
			 in section 1005 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (as added by section
			 2(a)).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


