<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H59CC8B7EFB28470895D6DBDDC7F8921E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1179 IH: Preserving the Work Requirement for Welfare Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1179</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150227">February 27, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000570">Mr. Ryan of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000594">Mr. Paulsen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000064">Mr. Young of Indiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000363">Mr. Kline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit waivers relating to compliance with the work requirements for the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8E9E3F6849BC4C1D8E976DD491B99A29" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF6A9DE481E2B4C72B88B35CCA1C68600" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving the Work Requirement for Welfare Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0352B192A6744800B3FE71A2DAF1B5A9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on TANF waivers relating to compliance with the TANF work requirements</header> <subsection id="HC7CD2572F2264900BB0FF93E3A1CC6C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Health and Human Services may not do the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H06E384933DB24C4B92B386FD2031484A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Finalize, implement, enforce, or otherwise take any action to give effect to the Information Memorandum dated July 12, 2012 (Transmittal No. TANF–ACF–IM–2012–03), or to any administrative action relating to the same subject matter set forth in the Information Memorandum or that reflects the same or similar policies as those set forth in the Information Memorandum.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7E21C9E916D4B7DB4BD770584F891D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Authorize, approve, renew, modify, or extend any experimental, pilot, or demonstration project under section 1115 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</external-xref>) that waives compliance with a requirement of section 407 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/607">42 U.S.C. 607</external-xref>) through a waiver of section 402 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/602">42 U.S.C. 602</external-xref>) or that provides authority for an expenditure which would not otherwise be an allowable use of funds under a State program funded under part A of title IV of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to compliance with the work requirements in section 407 of such Act to be regarded as an allowable use of funds under that program for any period.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H63046A538F5547D78EEB338B60B695DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rescission of waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any waiver relating to the subject matter set forth in the Information Memorandum or described in subsection (a)(2) that is granted before the date of the enactment of this Act is hereby rescinded and shall be null and void.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

