<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23B07497D1DA4BCA8119771D34DAFE27" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3844 IH: Energy and Minerals Reclamation Foundation Establishment Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3844</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151028">October 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish the Energy and Minerals Reclamation Foundation to encourage, obtain, and use gifts,
			 devises, and bequests for projects to reclaim abandoned mine lands and
			 orphan oil and gas well sites, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA26EF38E749F4391929DF83CE45632B2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H576EA01F1EBD44B2B3E97E619B7E6D8C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy and Minerals Reclamation Foundation Establishment Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H25A84F1532094B2E80CAB99CD55C9F59"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H27CDF69455EE4F25AC11DD1B1D831BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abandoned mine lands</header><text>The term <quote>abandoned mine lands</quote> means all hardrock mines in the United States that were abandoned before January 1, 1981, and all coal mines in the United States that were abandoned before August 3, 1977, regardless of surface or mineral ownership.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H417391E8B21448D7BD7B7EE0FFB31F89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <quote>Board</quote> means the Board of Directors of the Foundation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7691803DA4F7468BB7DFCFD862CA3A42"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Directors of the Board.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AEB1570BAFF47DD864E6F0F4BFBB15E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <quote>Foundation</quote> means the Energy and Minerals Reclamation Foundation established by this Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H25F9DC2CF14F4A6185566196C5621522"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interest in real property</header><text>The term <quote>interest in real property</quote> includes mineral rights, rights-of-way, and easements, appurtenant or in gross.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC06A5EC1028049D3B03571C275D6FCB1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Orphaned oil and gas well sites</header><text>The term <quote>orphaned oil and gas well sites</quote> means all oil and gas wells in the United States that have no responsible or liable parties, regardless of surface or mineral ownership.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15258CCAB9A640B2BF3C18EE20CCDE01"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H71B0922B1F2E4A09B9865F0AA7C38078"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Split estate lands</header><text>The term <quote>split estate lands</quote> means lands with respect to which the surface is or will be in non-Federal ownership and a mineral interest is owned by the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H0BC25FD05E9F466E83D3A1CB4BF1B2CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Energy and Minerals Reclamation Foundation</header>
 <subsection id="H9D38B64D33D8433C9B82393E26605ABB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Energy and Minerals Reclamation Foundation. The Foundation is a charitable and nonprofit corporation domiciled in the District of Columbia.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54219AF28A8E4DC9950FDDEA0E8372CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Foundation is to encourage, obtain, and use gifts, devises, and bequests of real and personal property for abandoned mine lands and orphaned oil and gas well site reclamation projects that further the conservation of natural, scenic, historic, scientific, educational, wildlife habitat, or recreational resources.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE545A5B05FEF451AA7A18C56E7B53F0A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants and contracts</header><text>The Foundation may use gifts, devises, bequests, and matching funds from the Secretary under section 10(b) to make grants and award contracts for projects that are—</text>
 <paragraph id="H44AE401858D4469B98E495D0E97730D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>approved by the Board of the Foundation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAD596E9B3FE42B88DA07B66D887DFE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consistent with the purpose of the Foundation under subsection (b).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F7A86B3FE204E5283E9853A2A34435E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation and conflicts of interest</header>
 <paragraph id="HF4684B036BF14612B1485A6921346735"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation shall have no power, other than as an insubstantial part of its activities, to spend funds or engage in activities that are not in furtherance of subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4ADC9815CF5E4B0981A37E6D4B260D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Political activities</header><text>The Foundation shall not participate or intervene in any political campaign on behalf of any candidate for public office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H098356EB13584FA7BA3E703A4BBAF9A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conflict of interests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Director or officer or employee of the Foundation shall participate, directly or indirectly, in the consideration or determination of any question before the Foundation affecting—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H396BE1CD310B49F6A5A6F3A442B9FC81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the direct or indirect financial or personal interests of the Director, officer, or employee; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H765B2C872F9643D5B34FC4D7625F067F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the interests of any corporation partnership, entity, or organization in which such Director, officer, or employee—</text>
 <clause id="H8A915C63BBEB4E50B82232EDB435C07B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an officer, member of the board, or trustee; or</text> </clause><clause id="HE5738EFEE29F4C719C33F24E116E2F9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has any direct financial interest.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4024B961B464085950D9F8A1A184045"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative expenditures</header><text>Of the amount available to the Foundation for expenditure each fiscal year, not more than 10 percent may be used for administrative expenses.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HFB87A9CE8904481E996127F94ED80F64"><enum>4.</enum><header>Board of directors</header>
			<subsection id="H6E972CCE90B44F93BE657E2664E5744D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and membership</header>
 <paragraph id="H00B2D5D1C68644DEADD4736F4672E8F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation shall have a governing Board of Directors (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Board</quote>), which shall consist of 15 Directors.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7520ACC305C4371A4BC12680378B4AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Education and experience of directors</header><text>The Directors must be educated or have actual experience in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB0A9B6E7B2C0448C9E1B6CBBB4849C0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>energy or minerals production; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6683E8A5B0604FDE9DA15D05FC77A365"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reclamation of mine lands or oil and gas fields; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA50B9ACC992246BA8BE4E03674688C69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>energy and mineral resource financing, law, or research.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1614E2D828B4EC3B0C08EAEF36A7243"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Representation of diverse areas of expertise</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Directors shall represent diverse areas of expertise relating to mining and mine reclamation, and development and reclamation of oil and gas fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D84179EBE3048099DD7BCBE01EC0772"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ex officio director</header><text>The Director of the Office of Surface Mining of the Department of the Interior shall be an ex officio, nonvoting Director.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H38073F06FA4F42F4B84A5A835588617E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Appointment and terms</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2BB6828B14E4497C91704BD38E6BC5D8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Interstate Mining Compact Commission and the Interstate Oil and Gas Compact Commission, shall appoint the initial Directors. Thereafter the Secretary shall no longer have such authority, and subsequent appointments shall be made by the Chairman with the advice and consent of a majority of the Directors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EB0E912B8A847C4964E347EA4F68610"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Non-federal status</header><text>Appointment and service as a Director of the Board shall not constitute employment by, or the holding of an office of, the United States for the purposes of any Federal law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AE76F17A82B42C49B84CB9155AB1555"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Terms, generally</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (D), each Director shall be appointed for a term of 6 years.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2700E4F815F24E48A8E7E191D82BC6C4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Initial appointments</header><text>Of the Directors initially appointed—</text>
 <clause id="H0E0405CD024C4399A185A4E71A2755C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one-third shall be appointed for a term of 2 years;</text> </clause><clause id="H8A31343C88604FE7AAA4A3EED6E71848"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one-third shall be appointed for a term of 4 years; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6D4B10328BC64AF7AD08E88075A0A975"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>one-third shall be appointed for a term of 6 years.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ED321514A3C4B09B0B5DFC547765FBC"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy on the Board shall be filled within 120 days after the occurrence of such vacancy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF7C3D7CFC3644829E1FD6553E52D13D"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No individual may serve more than 12 consecutive years as a Director.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADAF21435E424FA8B03CD9BEF5B13BED"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Director misses three consecutive meetings of the Board, that individual may be removed from the Board by a majority vote of the Directors and that vacancy shall be filled in accordance with this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85F19115AA324F899D0FCA7DFD38A932"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chairman</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Board shall be elected by the Board from the Directors. An individual shall serve for a 2-year term as Chairman, and may be reelected to the post during the individual’s tenure as a Director.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H05F8E91A39E1450E8AE3855B5724A61A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the current voting Directors shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBCACA2937B9B4E2A96E61838975746F8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Board shall meet at the call of the Chairman at least once each year.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H4AAA94B17FAB4FAD8138C8411031F732"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reimbursement of expenses</header><text>Directors shall serve without pay, but may be reimbursed by the Foundation for the actual and necessary traveling and subsistence expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties for the Foundation. Such reimbursement may not exceed such amount as would be authorized under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code, for the payment of expenses and allowances for individuals employed intermittently in Federal Government service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4089F56570094B06B8A3D110951E9AC5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>General powers</header><text>The Board may complete the organization of the Foundation by—</text> <paragraph id="HCAA98AC188724B87B44C59486CB5A049"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appointing officers and employees (subject to subsection (g)(1));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AC9815CD49C4D1B901CAE74AD61D522"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adopting a constitution and bylaws consistent with the purpose of the Foundation under section 3(b) and the other provisions of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4ABAA211BC84594A518512649C56BCA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>undertaking other such acts as may be necessary to function and to carry out this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H267149759AF34FAEBE956B260E639FF6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Officers and employees</header><text>Officers and employees of the Foundation—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE9D9D01491A846F783721C54ADE027BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not be appointed until the Foundation has sufficient funds to pay for their services;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H33D09060139746B19E196516D2083660"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointment in the competitive service; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF57CD30D02B74952AC09CD58366036F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3862FBEE85D94E95B2BEAE647812D0A0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Corporate powers and obligations</header>
 <subsection id="HB86C1577E0874FFA8DC6D1F0D6EA2DED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation—</text> <paragraph id="HBB8C31B5552E4744B057B592815C5D6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall have perpetual succession;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF8B31BC9084F42907682122DF70B11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may conduct business throughout the several States, territories, and possessions of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF59CCD3106545A38C486213B7E07F3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall have a principle office in the metropolitan area of the District of Columbia that shall at all times maintain a designated agent in the District of Columbia to accept service of process for the Foundation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD93606E2B62D4750AF19A0780184C971"><enum>(4)</enum><text>may maintain as many offices as considered necessary by the Board outside of the metropolitan area of the District of Columbia.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C520CEA901A468E83EBBED47524CC94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice and service of process</header><text>The serving of notice to, or service of process upon, the agent required under subsection (a)(3), or mailed to the business address of such agent, is deemed as service upon or notice to the Foundation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H629C5F4285244D95A4AFB91A2E2A63B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Seal</header><text>The Foundation shall have an official seal selected by the Board, which shall be judicially noticed.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H81C4ED8CABD34854918EE44FEB8276C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Powers</header>
 <paragraph id="H6EB73D06E3E94621AEBF413F243A3AB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out its purpose, the Foundation shall have, in addition to powers otherwise authorized under this Act, the usual powers of a corporation acting as a trustee in the District of Columbia.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BA7F295AD7B4AC99CACAF2E2BA2795C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Included powers</header><text>The powers of the Foundation under this subsection include the power to—</text> <subparagraph id="HCBAF7792A1F344DA9D6CC638F1A847B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accept, receive, solicit, hold, administer, and use any gift, devise, or bequest, either absolutely or in trust, of real or personal property or any income therefrom or other interest therein;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD85A2386316043BCAF8286F1D2AC2314"><enum>(B)</enum><text>unless otherwise required by the instrument of transfer by which the Foundation acquires property, sell, donate, lease, invest, reinvest, retain, or otherwise dispose of any property or income therefrom;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28639012F1CB42BD8EA9FFEC1040AD0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>borrow money and issue bonds, debentures, or other debt instruments;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA001189E90E4DEA84462AB865FA0B20"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sue and be sued, and complain and defend itself in any court of competent jurisdiction, except that the Directors shall not be personally liable except for gross negligence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD91EE533AB3F436CAF0336FF87C746D1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>enter into contracts or other arrangements with public agencies, private organizations, and persons, and to make such payments as may be necessary to carry out the purposes thereof; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D6CE1B78C2A4719B7AFCF2E3D0D00E6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>do any and all acts necessary and proper to carry out the purpose of the Foundation under section 3(b).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF9C7DD62BE14D4682AFA6E9DABD5F7E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Acquisition of property</header>
 <paragraph id="HFB71E314567E403C82E967596397DE2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to its powers under subsection (d), the Foundation may acquire, hold, and dispose of lands, waters, or other interests in real property by donation, gift, devise, purchase or exchange.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4FC8EF915948D0A4AE30C5397ACACF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption from condemnation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No lands or waters, or interest therein, that are owned by the Foundation and are determined by the Secretary to be valuable for energy and mineral production, shall be subject to condemnation by any State or political subdivision, or any agent of instrumentality thereof.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0C3E5844D545479195E7771F5B374DDC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Administrative services and support</header>
 <subsection id="HB6B95F19F007436599223A2328A6A30D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Startup funds</header><text>For the purposes of assisting the Foundation in establishing an office and meeting initial administrative, project, and other startup expenses, the Secretary may provide to the Foundation $2,000,000 from funds appropriated under section 10(a) for each of fiscal years 2016 and 2017. Such funds shall remain available to the Foundation until they are expended.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H1BACD8118F2340B8AE34F707BC004778"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header>
 <paragraph id="H9212211F8AB040FBB341D27E2BEB21F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide the Foundation use of Department of the Interior personnel, facilities, and equipment, subject to such limitations, terms, and conditions as the Secretary shall establish.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC765BF171CB64BBAB8363CD99D32F308"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>The Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="HDFDA3CF9A17B4DC4897C386C667565E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may require the Foundation to reimburse the Secretary for the costs of providing personnel, facilities, and equipment under this subsection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B4B679C2CF74B1185C54601622D0E7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall require such reimbursement beginning with expenses incurred by the Foundation after the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H916A0E5355524E3C90EE30D2A8BEA7E4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Audits and activities summary</header>
 <subsection id="H485EE4B3B0F3413FA8F1BEC8C6863D2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>For purposes of section 10101 of title 36, United States Code, the Foundation shall be treated as a corporation in part B of subtitle II of such title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAB9CDE2FE32A446E86C05039A6FA0573"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities summary</header><text>The Foundation shall, within 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, transmit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a summary of its proceedings and activities during such fiscal year, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7425BCB1BCF54A229724DBA4AD31C189"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a full and complete statement of its receipts, expenditures, and investments;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBECE6F2ACE244864BE9255450E218F9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of all acquisition and disposal of real property by the Foundation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H540A9E9B05944DE7AE463A91021A9864"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a detailed statement of the recipient, amount, and purpose of each grant made by the Foundation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E0C37FABCA6494EA0DE14F79222834E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>copies of all minutes of Board meetings;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85E52438BD3F464BBCE0951DCC521E49"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a copy of the Foundation bylaws; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F931524078E412D96C443EF4A0BE72A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a copy of the audit for such fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H881544D3AE8B4F5781F12920EE28BD0F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Relief with respect to certain Foundation acts or failure to act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General may petition in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia for such equitable relief as may be necessary or appropriate if the Foundation—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD9B44E30B32140A799D6F2849F54ACD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engages in, or threatens to engage in, any act, practice, or policy that is inconsistent with its purpose set forth in section 3(b); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H409780CFDBA04F2587959A1508363451"><enum>(2)</enum><text>refuses, fails, or neglects to discharge its obligations under this Act, or threatens to do so.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HAB6C7A6203DC4C428B5AD367302BC650"><enum>9.</enum><header>United States release from liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States shall not be liable for any debts, defaults, acts, or omissions of the Foundation, nor shall the full faith and credit of the United States extend to any obligations of the Foundation.</text>
		</section><section id="H89B4A98C6891429DAFC3399E84866552"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="H5983FDFC9AA64C4AABBB2B349C1BEB13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Startup funds</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $4,000,000 to carry out section 6(a).</text> </subsection><subsection id="HED3AF74B94EA49E994DEE6923C2395A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020, which shall be made available by the Secretary to the Foundation to match, on a one-for-one basis, private contributions made to the Foundation.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


