<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H82A0FCF581D54CEE8BC5A3B4D08FC6F6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3889 IH: Safer Prescribing of Controlled Substances Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3889</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151103">November 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require certain practitioners authorized to prescribe controlled substances to complete
			 continuing education.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0A25507454DF409BB8AE413B3E84E4B2" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCB6EB15ED55D4A78A70536546425FF90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Prescribing of Controlled Substances Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H069741C3D8D54FD1836075F5B21122CF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuing education requirements for certain practitioners prescribing controlled substances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8CD88AE6FA894A81AABC328E10228DFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (f), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Attorney General shall register</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsection (i), the Attorney General shall register</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEFEC273C68F4EC09AE8EAA98AA12BCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2C18C43E67A4F24B2A69352A1AA6DB2" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H7CD0E29E91B846D4A45C594985D815D5"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE3BF9659156E4646B86774110DE71E6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered practitioner</term> means a practitioner that is not a hospital, pharmacy, or veterinarian.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H34F5F39853FC40D395A8C101570762B7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As a condition of granting or renewing the registration of a covered practitioner under this part to dispense, or conduct research with, controlled substances in schedule II, III, IV, or V, the Attorney General shall require the covered practitioner to complete training (through classroom situations, seminars at professional society meetings, electronic communications, or otherwise) that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines meets the requirements under paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39263DDD680F4B838DFE524708AABBE5" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The training provided for purposes of paragraph (2) shall, at a minimum, expose covered practitioners to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBAC2D1CE13CA4503B00790D0CA872778"><enum>(A)</enum><text>best practices for pain management, including alternatives to prescribing controlled substances and other alternative therapies to decrease the use of opioids;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC5E06857D2240C1BBF9606CE420F771"><enum>(B)</enum><text>responsible prescribing of pain medications, as described in Federal prescriber guidelines for nonmalignant pain;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA77ABB7DEB5B453BA809BBD97A768494"><enum>(C)</enum><text>methods for diagnosing, treating, and managing a substance use disorder, including the use of medications approved by the Food and Drug Administration and evidence-based nonpharmacological therapies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA0C369B64264888B3F0756A0F0BD3A7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>linking patients to evidence-based treatment for substance use disorders; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31423FEC24C74B22A3CA8E3161B66C66"><enum>(E)</enum><text>tools to manage adherence and diversion of controlled substances, including prescription drug monitoring programs, drug screening, informed consent, overdose education, and the use of opioid overdose antagonists.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3E2F2ABEAA34B70B25976C49DB8774F" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration shall establish or support the establishment of not less than 1 training module that meets the requirements under paragraph (3) that is provided—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCAF800F59D734066B9BC73619DD2B0BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to any covered practitioner registered or applying for a registration under this part to dispense, or conduct research with, controlled substances in schedule II, III, IV, or V;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F8BC91C40C74930995B39C9C4E7617F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>online; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B2CA2EAA26848379C9FDEDB68C9E7E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>free of charge.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB18F6059A57B4F0BB70CF08D46FD6EB4" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish, maintain, and periodically update a publically available database providing information relating to training modules that meet the requirements under paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB33B24A1558F4D48839C51A84265ECE1" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall evaluate and make publically available a report describing how exposure to the training required under this subsection has changed prescribing patterns of controlled substances.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


