<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H886B5ECD9C744DBFBE537A41A4B4943D" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3306 IH: POWER Cuba Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3306</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize the export of energy resources, energy technologies, and related services to Cuba, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H62B36FC8EB37453D959FA3C4381310F2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H910F2C0A23554F17A074495A626AB7E0" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promote Opportunities With Energy Resources for Cuba Act</short-title></quote> or <quote>POWER Cuba Act</quote>. </text></section> <section id="HC29370BC6AF145AE8313D56C3C9E661D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6AF434734A5E44F4B087FAF518A91C1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cuba produced an estimated 49,000 barrels per day of petroleum and other liquid fuels for production of energy in 2014 and consumed 171,000 barrels per day of petroleum and other liquids. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H619CF285705846F9A62C80DD50AE21FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Cuba imports most of its oil supply from Venezuela, which provides crude oil at a heavily subsidized rate under a 2000 energy agreement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A8802C3AD194D47897A32BDAC2BFDA0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As of January 2015, Cuba had 124,000,000 barrels of proven crude oil reserves, according to Oil and Gas Journal (OGJ). The prospects of finding oil in the deep waters off the northern coast of Cuba attracted many oil and gas companies from around the world. However, due to geological and technological challenges, offshore deep water exploration activity has so far yielded no results. Exploration in Cuba has now shifted onshore, to areas along Cuba’s northern coast. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B614DF4C7B1434EAFDEF407229FF211"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Cuba has four refineries, all of which are owned by Cuba Petroleos, the state-owned oil and natural gas company. Total crude oil refining capacity was 301,400 barrels per day in January 2015, according to Oil and Gas Journal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H044B7584712048F58BF1DFB685339F36"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In an effort to diversify its energy portfolio, Cuba has set a goal of producing 24 percent of its electricity from renewable sources by 2030. Cuba’s current renewable energy output accounts for only 4.3 percent of its total electricity production. To meet this goal, Unión Eléctrica, the state-owned power company, is planning 13 wind projects with a total capacity of 633 megawatts. In addition, Cuba plans to add 755 megawatts of biomass-fired capacity, 700 megawatts of solar capacity, and 56 megawatts of hydroelectric power.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20DB611304694B78A184BB728A04EF7C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The end of trade restrictions could generate a new market for many types of supplies and services from the United States energy industry.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H46DFEACFB47C4E2DB375DE7F5C5BEDAB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Oil and gas exports</header> 
<subsection id="HD871CE4FD7FF45BCB251D7DCE4DDA091"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Energy Policy and Conservation Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 103 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6212">42 U.S.C. 6212</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H753A0B453D0E407B8CDC2615461F0B39" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HDD54745742A54A4B80A299DB127B09AD"><enum>(g)</enum><text>This section shall not apply to the export of oil to Cuba.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E1B486F196E4D6087E8DAA220543A18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Natural Gas Act</header><text>Section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H538C1D4107CA4640A34CAF528067D1C5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H3B989A62913F4B798D7D79FB1C821FE3"><enum>(g)</enum><text>This section shall not apply to the export of LNG to Cuba.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H846B1A56AFE74D588D3D765EA8A027B0" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Export of energy resources, energy technologies, and related services to Cuba</header> 
<subsection id="H86728BF478E9416FBAD49D0EDCAA1882" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President is authorized to permit any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States—</text> <paragraph id="H94EE6296C69E44AEA57FE15A44E14906" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to export energy resources and energy technologies to Cuba;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5366315B270E421DA6F8595C4F2091B5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to export services related to energy resources and energy technologies described in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF98787F02AD74013B870FD4072B675CB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to establish facilities related to energy resources and energy technologies described in paragraph (1) and services described in paragraph (2);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EAC7A62BA6C404A93411B26D5EF054C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to conduct any transaction incident to carrying out an activity described in any of paragraphs (1) through (3); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75290D6E01CA4688B3EA9EDC937F40FE" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to enter into, perform, and make and receive payments under a contract with any individual or entity in Cuba with respect to the provision of energy resources and energy technologies described in paragraph (1) and services described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7764B696D5B94132AB4AE1B69D9C942B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter for 4 years, the President shall submit to the relevant committees of Congress a report on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H89077D5C32274EF592B28CB0201D6548" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H59F2F7C333254D4DB9B9EE3F90CB76E0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Energy resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>energy resources</term> means conventional sources of energy, including oil, gas, coal, petrochemicals, and nuclear energy.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E45749EF84A443EB098B04FA78B27C1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy technologies</header><text>The term <term>energy technologies</term> means equipment and expertise to enable the production of energy, including renewable sources of energy such as wind, solar, hydro-power, geothermal, and bio-fuels.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE3A6154C900E4B4A804C2654BE3037F1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States</header><text>The term <term>person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H97AA49AD3D734D8FA650FD4C1E37AF1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any individual, wherever located, who is a citizen or resident of the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H665537D9B3984F92B07855B6D071542B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person located in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9327E8C0B34E43979063830EA8B2D08E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any corporation, partnership, association, or other organization organized under the laws of the United States or of any State, territory, possession, or district of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBADD8407D334E4FA5D30DD9689B21E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any corporation, partnership, association, or other organization, wherever organized or doing business, that is owned or controlled by a person or organization described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF36A066C313A49E7ACA7E3A80D0A60D8" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relevant committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>relevant committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7B0D4C8832694F7AA66A6BBE668C2ACF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC788D6892DE466098C343DCE20F9E17" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

