<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H08532BEBD7024604892C2E5ACA4B9E97" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3205 IH: History Is Learned from the Living Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3205</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish the History Is Learned from the Living grant program to enable communities to learn
			 about historical movements in the United States in the past century
			 through the oral histories of community members who participated in those
			 movements, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5B12D94B169E42B299212C5300CFE587" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD7EC49AD873F4EFB9EDA0C5BBBEFABED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>History Is Learned from the Living Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HACFB40BBEEA4415EA5B80FE605E54DF7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding preservation of stories of heroes of historical movements in the United States</header> <subsection id="HDBEC105802574AF7AF2337899DCCDB14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H130C890DF7404651B2687461A6E42E5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The historical movements in the United States over the past century have been integral to growth, progress, and innovation in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD81CE30A05DB49498F837A16ED736F03"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notable examples of such historical movements include the Women’s Suffrage, Reagan Revolution, Peace, Veteran, Civil Rights, Tea Party, Chicano (El Movimiento), Pro-Life, Environmental, and Deficit Reduction Movements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93971E2E49174045B2A1604212CEA93A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Martin Luther King, Jr., Phyllis Schlafly, Cesar Chavez, William Buckley, Susan B. Anthony, and Ronald Reagan are among the many well-known heroes of such historical movements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AA4F835440A44CD892F51C571983CE8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the well-known heroes of such historical movements, there are numerous unsung heroes living in local communities across the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H927B85E0869B42929EF9BF1A1E976298"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the stories of the unsung heroes of historical movements in the United States over the past century should be preserved and archived, and the historical movements in which they participated remembered, for generations to come.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H246A0C471BB543598995851266B2D1F6"><enum>3.</enum><header>History Is Learned from the Living grant program</header>
 <subsection id="HAAEA2D9E61D44684B683A351FB306029"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the History Is Learned from the Living grant program (in this section referred to as the <quote>HILL grant program</quote>), to be carried out by the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C3D6B3313C941F0909CF34E52A53A29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Under the HILL grant program, the Secretary shall make 1-year grants in the amount of $50,000 to community groups, organizations, or institutions to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9916A27C8DFC41B2BF595C1C42EFFB36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out projects through which the community may learn about historical movements in the United States in the past century through the oral histories of members of the community who participated in those movements; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85D54787ADD645108E1E3B9C4214D064"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary a digital report on the projects, in such form and containing such information as may be specified by the Secretary, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE7F1D14DFA4B472998DFDFC49B8255C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each oral history described in paragraph (1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10D8B380AF4E4E37A690018FF0FBFF35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the relevance of such oral history; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EF5B8DB74AC46A28296E5A8F41CB9AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the background of the community member to whom the oral history belongs.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H32DA0FD5CC50425DA4E5E5323796F3B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, a community group, organization, or institution shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H47BDDA731CE8479E88178ECD484354FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preservation of oral histories</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a system to preserve and make available to the public the digital reports submitted under subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H26D46995F0BF4A1790326F35A15E9798"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the HILL grant program $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2017 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


