<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H80F93D969AA54F8BAA11689E9D62E586" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2297 : Hezbollah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2297</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150518">May 18, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc>Received, read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To prevent Hezbollah and associated entities from gaining access to international financial and other institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H03ACF33F4D03417F8FF2F160ACE738D0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9DCFE692B49D4C73B73CC8092AA297CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H9448F59A4F494FDEA89E0304FB1210CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hezbollah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H3C68077B29C94573B344F9C9255004E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="H9DCFE692B49D4C73B73CC8092AA297CF" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HEC3C4F5BED094F189992B6D4F37C7F2A" level="section">Sec. 2. Statement of policy.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8237450A62E04597A859A69AE7CF871D" level="title">Title I—Prevention of access by Hezbollah to international financial and other institutions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3638EA9C57264AA5B62C2B09B662F97E" level="section">Sec. 101. Briefing on imposition of sanctions on certain satellite providers that carry al-Manar TV.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4F0BBE5CA7A34105910F1A1B6287DE7D" level="section">Sec. 102. Sanctions with respect to financial institutions that engage in certain transactions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H19B1BE81E3734145BFC817855E9FCF96" level="title">Title II—Reports on designation of Hezbollah as a significant foreign narcotics trafficker and a significant transnational criminal organization</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H10ED08B80A7B414EB70E2F527EF32125" level="section">Sec. 201. Report on designation of Hezbollah as a significant foreign narcotics trafficker.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD3408CACCC054B21843AE072793F505A" level="section">Sec. 202. Report on designation of Hezbollah as a significant transnational criminal organization.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA956513897124FA4B988B799A103CC0F" level="section">Sec. 203. Rewards for Justice and Hezbollah’s fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7F5A23C3B05640A2AC4DC91FA4B70F9F" level="section">Sec. 204. Report on activities of foreign governments to disrupt global logistics networks and fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities of Hezbollah.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H02CC80C9AE8C44DEB11745105D384AF6" level="section">Sec. 205. Appropriate congressional committees defined.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC1C75A5516DF4FA9B61A6BB9DC1334EE" level="title">Title III—Miscellaneous provisions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HEFB427BFDB63435A96A72F01393B7A1D" level="section">Sec. 301. Rule of construction.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H68AC78BBAC1644FBB97FEEE210589BEE" level="section">Sec. 302. Regulatory authority.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3CE41DAF3EC541EFA2D64B93F94DF9B2" level="section">Sec. 303. Termination.</toc-entry></toc> </subsection></section> 
<section id="HEC3C4F5BED094F189992B6D4F37C7F2A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="HF161E7E09A624FFABBF6673FC8136423"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevent Hezbollah’s global logistics and financial network from operating in order to curtail funding of its domestic and international activities; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15B1E26DF1264284ADDF3C166FBFA3FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilize all available diplomatic, legislative, and executive avenues to combat the global criminal activities of Hezbollah as a means to block that organization’s ability to fund its global terrorist activities.</text> </paragraph></section> <title id="H8237450A62E04597A859A69AE7CF871D"><enum>I</enum><header>Prevention of access by Hezbollah to international financial and other institutions</header> <section commented="no" id="H3638EA9C57264AA5B62C2B09B662F97E"><enum>101.</enum><header>Briefing on imposition of sanctions on certain satellite providers that carry al-Manar TV</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall provide to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a briefing on the following:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H10861B60CE9E496286BF98FBAED44E1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The activities of all satellite, broadcast, Internet, or other providers that knowingly provide material support to al-Manar TV, and any affiliates or successors thereof.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5588D15C4D1A40D1A19DDC9B9088CDE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to all providers described in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HD48FC7D9910A43EFA0054DB55B921720"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of those providers that have been sanctioned pursuant to Executive Order No. 13224 (September 23, 2001); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA1F4D73C284B4F938AA5C44F28CD51FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of those providers that have not been sanctioned pursuant to Executive Order No. 13224 and, with respect to each such provider, the reason why sanctions have not been imposed.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H4F0BBE5CA7A34105910F1A1B6287DE7D"><enum>102.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to financial institutions that engage in certain transactions</header> 
<subsection id="HDC0499191CDF4DFFA9CFEFC1B79F8701"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibitions and conditions with respect to certain accounts held by foreign financial institutions</header> 
<paragraph id="H321D2CD14CB04F97B135236D8F3B93FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State and in consultation with the heads of other applicable departments and agencies, shall prohibit, or impose strict conditions on, the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that the Secretary determines, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, engages in an activity described in paragraph (2).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1034BBA4DDB044B69FA294B05EC7144E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities described</header><text>A foreign financial institution engages in an activity described in this paragraph if the foreign financial institution—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFFAA2E35A986498B95746708F3D55C7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>knowingly facilitates a significant transaction or transactions for Hezbollah;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86ACF91C894E4F079A13002DE83C8994"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly facilitates a significant transaction or transactions of a person designated for acting on behalf of or at the direction of, or owned or controlled by, Hezbollah;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76D20D13BF3D4BDDB1803CA87B161065"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly engages in money laundering to carry out an activity described in subparagraph (A) or (B);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F9E9A669EC542D1B98C6D7351926215"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly facilitates a significant transaction or transactions or provides significant financial services to carry out an activity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C), including—</text> 
<clause id="H0C483E574A3B472AAF4BB460A0E8E822"><enum>(i)</enum><text>facilitating a significant transaction or transactions; or</text> </clause> <clause id="H8694429C82B74FD4B9398B25C3A45742"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing significant financial services that involve a transaction of covered goods; or</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF01DD49BAFD488D84903E847E4F5B35"><enum>(E)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF8C51DC7B30F4196B6258E6CD4F509EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly facilitates, or participates or assists in, an activity described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D), including by acting on behalf of, at the direction of, or as an intermediary for, or otherwise assisting, another person with respect to the activity described in any such subparagraph;</text> </clause> <clause id="HE10E7F4B8C0B444C919E7A00213CFB8E" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly attempts or conspires to facilitate or participate in an activity described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D); or</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H34D0A980E5264804B856B9BB4B928D84" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is owned or controlled by a foreign financial institution that the Secretary finds knowingly engages in an activity described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA8EB485A411488DB71035451107F62F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed under paragraph (4) of this subsection to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section 206(a).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C9B20B7354F4192A4C3B5B65CB6F054"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe and implement regulations to carry out this subsection.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H890ACC87EF8D4FA5B7225A1DCBDE349D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header> <paragraph id="HC23EFCB8F3244E768420BB6D3F127B4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State and in consultation with the heads of other applicable departments and agencies, may waive, on a case-by-case basis, the application of a prohibition or condition imposed with respect to a foreign financial institution pursuant to subsection (a) for a period of not more than 180 days, and may renew such waiver for additional periods of not more than 180 days, on and after the date that the Secretary of the Treasury, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H160FA9C4D3C24DBA9D85DAB15A323F05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2EAEF6ED92148139E1123EF0CEC7FB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the reasons for such determination.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BC1527B4ADE488A8F540BF82C4D0169"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1)(B) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE283CC886B6C47D4A1C5C687A8844B1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provisions relating to foreign financial institutions</header> <paragraph id="HF8A11375C795422FB8F1C15F30B02A10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE266D2977A624D838D840C102C01C327"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies each foreign central bank that the Secretary determines engages in one or more activities described in subsection (a)(2)(D); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC570455A808E4BA6A8D9048D99C6EFB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides a detailed description of each such activity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC6226639F68C43348EBBD5EDF5A7DF52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule to allow for termination of sanctionable activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall not be required to apply sanctions to a foreign financial institution described in subsection (a) if the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State and in consultation with the heads of other applicable departments and agencies, certifies in writing to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text> <subparagraph id="HAB634522368E4A3B9FDAB00D98F955D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such foreign financial institution—</text> 
<clause id="HCBDF7B6C8B24409CA795AD971E4654B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is no longer engaging in the activity described in subsection (a)(2); or</text> </clause> <clause id="H72CA402B2DB949BF8FB0F76954D54429"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has taken and is continuing to take significant verifiable steps toward terminating the activity described in such subsection; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED0A8012662D4E9BBBBC56C82FB37874"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary has received reliable assurances from the government with primary jurisdiction over such foreign financial institution that such foreign financial institution will not engage in any activity described in such subsection in the future.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H35C2BC84AD3E4B3EBF0151F45B31EEEA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C4E1B1EAF8A48FF87A2C08B5C7F02E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCAB405B5970740ECBEBDE9EEE5DFB12C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Account; correspondent account; payable-through account</header><text>The terms <term>account</term>, <term>correspondent account</term>, and <term>payable-through account</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 5318A of title 31, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H373FD07A05664127979ACE770F11E8F0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="HC310572BC63E484A9F3D3B4C30E5BA64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HD17A4E61B1EA47D2A89F524F2767D3C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB54C06EF2EB04658A126EC7CCC59D7A8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Covered goods</header><text>The term <term>covered goods</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1027.100 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC2E2033CAE743A4AED69137E9DAC1AA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> means a financial institution specified in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), (F), (G), (H), (I), (J), (K), (M), (N), (P), (R), (T), (Y), or (Z) of section 5312(a)(2) of title 31, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE1FDCF63483446B48CE8A5A76C8D5F40"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution; domestic financial institution</header> 
<clause id="H997948AD8963426E82391962AED3F167"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign financial institution</term> has the meaning of such term in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, and includes a foreign central bank.</text> </clause> <clause id="H4544A0FD37D54FFB9042124FC66ACB1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Domestic financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>domestic financial institution</term> has the meaning of such term as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1CCA54EF969E49C49108442C83A78A5D"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Hezbollah</header><text>The term <term>Hezbollah</term> means—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H464B09F20ABB4D3FA62E86A18E695DD4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any person—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H8561E1CCD1E646B69E6B0C3971CBC332"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the property of or interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text> </subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H03634D5E15A84A89ADF946D8B8BB2E81"><enum>(II)</enum><text>who is identified on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Asset Control of the Department of the Treasury as an agent, instrumentality, or affiliate of Hezbollah; and</text> </subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H19727954AB9F45AFABA68CBAC920D1B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8017F58B5DC14F3183CF744C04281E72"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Money laundering</header><text>The term <term>money laundering</term> means any of the activities described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 1956(a) of title 18, United States Code, with respect to which penalties may be imposed pursuant to such section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H319C10EEB0B341189D5F091A17E0B2A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury may further define the terms used in this section in the regulations prescribed under this section.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></title> <title id="H19B1BE81E3734145BFC817855E9FCF96"><enum>II</enum><header>Reports on designation of Hezbollah as a significant foreign narcotics trafficker and a significant trans-<linebreak/>national criminal organization</header> <section id="H10ED08B80A7B414EB70E2F527EF32125"><enum>201.</enum><header>Report on designation of Hezbollah as a significant foreign narcotics trafficker</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DB99CE7B2664B29BA86A5E91A246F1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed report on whether Hezbollah meets the criteria for designation under the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1901">21 U.S.C. 1901 et seq.</external-xref>) as a significant foreign narcotics trafficker, and if the President determines that Hezbollah does not meet such criteria, a detailed justification as to which criteria have not been met.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC382D8A09C1646BF81D181B1BC8D1797"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be transmitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HD3408CACCC054B21843AE072793F505A"><enum>202.</enum><header>Report on designation of Hezbollah as a significant transnational criminal organization</header> <subsection id="HD978BCD014BD4893AF7DFE4E377733C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H19893BDEDCF94B56955BC2C07CA119A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hezbollah meets the criteria for designation as a significant transnational criminal organization under Executive Order No. 13581 (76 Fed. Reg. 44757); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CA958271EC4412AB0DB6A7B80D95DB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President should so designate Hezbollah as a significant transnational criminal organization.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C6F037FAF444FA5A2967B7BB1530B48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HC1612690DBE64CE09817ABA8FD70300D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate committees of Congress a detailed report on whether the Hezbollah meets the criteria for designation as a significant transnational criminal organization under Executive Order No. 13581 (76 Fed. Reg. 44757), and if the President determines that Hezbollah does not meet such criteria, a detailed justification as to which criteria have not been met.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H68C836E1D501430BA10314A715B41E99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be transmitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA956513897124FA4B988B799A103CC0F"><enum>203.</enum><header>Rewards for Justice and Hezbollah’s fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities</header> 
<subsection id="HB6DB1DFDEAB74B9398C8CC9F2EE7B42E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that details actions taken by the Department of State through the Department of State rewards program under section 36 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708</external-xref>) to obtain information on fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities of Hezbollah and its agents and affiliates.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H2AC3443DDDEC4A81B2D7DE509A4230D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the actions described in subsection (a).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HF8FF9B5CC9D543DF842160C9CC74CA7B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H2860F2D3550142B39EB9EE1F69402B8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4982C3A2EE6A45858338EFBFD635B093"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7F5A23C3B05640A2AC4DC91FA4B70F9F"><enum>204.</enum><header>Report on activities of foreign governments to disrupt global logistics networks and fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities of Hezbollah</header> <subsection id="H5F9F46FDB190422E96A21378A37C94D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H0BF0BE6767A44D6B8D2393A8B869835D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1BB5DDB06210467593368F58E9F8C42C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of countries that support Hezbollah, or in which Hezbollah maintains important portions of its global logistics networks;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27804C6BCDC74C48A56E117839D37F62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to each country on the list required by subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H8C29B92BB04C40CDAAF5F49A5467EE21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of whether the government of such country is taking adequate measures to disrupt the global logistics networks of Hezbollah within the territory of such country; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HF85ACD2B4D65445AA7FC7498EFA0715D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a country the government of which is not taking adequate measures to disrupt such networks—</text> 
<subclause id="H6DBD9403250940918AD8B3CC69253424"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an assessment of the reasons such government is not taking such adequate measures; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H71BCDE80A82D4ADF9B6B983578FD0C94"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description of measures being taken by the United States to encourage such government to improve measures to disrupt such networks;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5DCD3769E9C498FBFB2AF1433CDFDAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list of countries in which Hezbollah, or any of its agents or affiliates, conducts significant fundraising, financing, or money laundering activities;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H928CFD39117E453DAF2A9EC44DEDA2C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with respect to each country on the list required by subparagraph (C)—</text> 
<clause id="HA327E34CBB2E4AAEAA33AF293CABFE2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of whether the government of such country is taking adequate measures to disrupt the fundraising, financing, or money laundering activities of Hezbollah and its agents and affiliates within the territory of such country; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H44C4651717524ADCADF5149914DF6E73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a country the government of which is not taking adequate measures to disrupt such activities—</text> 
<subclause id="H6E31201D80534E3684D9F196FFE6FA89"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an assessment of the reasons such government is not taking such adequate measures; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H95E941A27CF549739E40867CAB233629"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description of measures being taken by the United States to encourage such government to improve measures to disrupt such activities; and</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA3EC7D5A9AB4910B7E17CC58227D74E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a list of methods that Hezbollah, or any of its agents or affiliates, utilizes to raise or transfer funds, including trade-based money laundering, the use of foreign exchange houses, and free-trade zones.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4433238EADD49AE9FC3ACC1654E8F46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form to the greatest extent possible, and may contain a classified annex.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E971B3AA91C489A8A46E34C8FF5EEA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Global logistics networks of Hezbollah</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>global logistics networks of Hezbollah </term>, <term>global logistics networks</term>, or <term>networks</term> means financial, material, or technological support for, or financial or other services in support of, Hezbollah.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H26642F643EFD4BAA8749422F27D19D71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing on Hezbollah’s assets and activities related to fundraising, financing, and money laundering worldwide</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the heads (or their designees) of other applicable Federal departments and agencies shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the disposition of Hezbollah’s assets and activities related to fundraising, financing, and money laundering worldwide.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5880B71FCE2B4C93B6ED2853452A12D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H651B0EE7958A43A380481D9A8D2DD9F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE76DC2B4B01346B4B900B2BE212D1A58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="H02CC80C9AE8C44DEB11745105D384AF6"><enum>205.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided, in this title, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HBD435B14A33244CF8EEE7C0D426EDEEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB8A6120C89CD42B085FEE22C357392FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Finance, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></section></title> 
<title id="HC1C75A5516DF4FA9B61A6BB9DC1334EE"><enum>III</enum><header>Miscellaneous provisions</header> 
<section id="HEFB427BFDB63435A96A72F01393B7A1D"><enum>301.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or any amendment made by this Act shall apply to the authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text> </section> <section id="H68AC78BBAC1644FBB97FEEE210589BEE"><enum>302.</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H651A314BCE5D49CAAFC85E8EFFFAA822"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H22C3F571DB4C4D0AB2E476567B931452"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text>Not less than 10 days before the promulgation of regulations under subsection (a), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees (as such term is defined in section 203) of the proposed regulations and the provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act that the regulations are implementing.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H3CE41DAF3EC541EFA2D64B93F94DF9B2"><enum>303.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the President certifies to Congress that Hezbollah—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA86A84A76F4D42BCAFAF17F6FC486168"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is no longer designated as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFAE1865BB7B1403C98EB258DDF221A7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is no longer listed in the Annex to Executive Order No. 13224 (September 23, 2001; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism); and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC06C2408909A4A8BB7242E3AF98C26B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>poses no significant threat to United States national security, interests, or allies.</text> </paragraph></section></title> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20150514">Passed the House of Representatives May 14, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role><proxy display="yes">Robert F. Reeves,</proxy><role>Deputy Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

