<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7A97FC21BD14D0FA90020C0AF436C6F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2215 IH: Outdoor Recreation Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2215</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150501">May 1, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to broaden an exemption to the minimum wage and maximum hours provisions of that Act for certain seasonal workers in national parks and forests.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3B24DA6075FA486C81BE47E0523FDBA3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0228B4AFE0FE4D3D8652CD3BABF0FD97" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Outdoor Recreation Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HA6EEECC160AC4D88B868FBB8667B8BFD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption for certain seasonal workers in national parks and forests</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13(a)(3) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/213">29 U.S.C. 213(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7028900D412E4122BA2886E70226442E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>except that</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Secretary of Agriculture</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF1C10F4A2B749E4A2C5CFA2CCE1044C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>, provided that, for the purposes of this paragraph, an employee of an entity engaged in providing services or facilities directly related to outfitting and guiding or similar outdoor recreation activities, or rental of outdoor recreational equipment (including services, facilities, or equipment relating to rafting, boating, zip lines, campgrounds, horseback riding, bicycling, hiking, guest ranches, summer camps, hunting, and fishing), or a private entity engaged in providing services and facilities directly related to skiing, shall be considered an employee employed by an establishment which is a recreational establishment</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H9BC5B2B98B4643BE890A0DB827784C93"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notification of change of exemption</header> 
<subsection id="HC94EB0C28B6E4DD4B01E6C97AC0878CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In connection with any contract, permit, license, or other agreement entered into between the Federal Government and an employer of an employee described in section 13(a)(3) of the Fair Labor Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/213">29 U.S.C. 213(a)(3)</external-xref>) prior to the date of enactment of this Act, the head of the agency that entered into such contract, permit, license, or other agreement shall—</text> <paragraph id="H17BF68DB6542483789F3C5566A1E6558"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify the holder of such contract, permit, license, or other agreement, of the applicability of the exemption in such section, as amended by this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CF7F5B7E3A54F67B8C943CF1D45A8FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modify such contract, permit, license, or other agreement to reflect the change to such exemption as a result of the amendment made by section 1, including by removal of the contract clause set forth in Appendix A of part 10 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, if such clause is included in such contract, permit, license, or other agreement, without requiring consideration or any other amendment to the terms and conditions of such contract, permit, license, or other agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6A036550DC994DBF9C95DE8D8CEE1A91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>No action taken under this section shall be considered a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment within the meaning of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


