<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1D84FC7E057F4593A45996AE71D75A49" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3189 RH: FORM Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 253</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3189</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 114–332, Part I]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga of Michigan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151116">November 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer of Minnesota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000458">Mr. Fincher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000548">Mr. Garrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000570">Mr. Guinta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151116">November 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151116">November 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 23, 2015</action-instruction></action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Reserve Act to establish requirements for policy rules and blackout periods of
			 the Federal Open Market Committee, to establish requirements for certain
			 activities of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and to
			 amend title 31, United States Code, to reform the manner in which the
			 Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System is audited, and for other
			 purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HCD7C0CBC2300431E9ABC32200DB225A9" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
		<section id="H7844A9C171C94A14992A3DEF42714A5C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H0A42C8ADC1114E539B9BF77AF47EC442"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fed Oversight Reform and Modernization Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>FORM Act of 2015</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HD5515FC086F547B6850266558BBAFD92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
					<toc-entry idref="H7844A9C171C94A14992A3DEF42714A5C" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H285FA70B8EF247E4B165FD3624EAB71B" level="section">Sec. 2. Requirements for policy rules of the Federal Open Market Committee.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD79D59912CDF4945A44F92C956A986F3" level="section">Sec. 3. Federal Open Market Committee blackout period.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEE1B2EC816124919BBC141DE5174C8CC" level="section">Sec. 4. Membership of Federal Open Market Committee.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBB4B01C5C10C482BB152F8395485BF28" level="section">Sec. 5. Requirements for stress tests and supervisory letters for the Board of Governors of the
			 Federal Reserve System.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H990B772BFBF8467BBB242E5B853A4DCC" level="section">Sec. 6. Frequency of testimony of the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve
			 System to Congress.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD599511C9017463E811FB5883E222F69" level="section">Sec. 7. Vice Chairman for Supervision report requirement.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4E9EE66104CB48CF9E063EC3C8D6DE9C" level="section">Sec. 8. Economic analysis of regulations of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE612444EEACE439FAC2DC48CAB04E7D4" level="section">Sec. 9. Salaries, financial disclosures, and office staff of the Board of Governors of the Federal
			 Reserve System.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H357D5EE4C343476CB6DE1F4CC1DB7668" level="section">Sec. 10. Requirements for international processes.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBD59C15ABF1D460895A5C48155F10D73" level="section">Sec. 11. Amendments to powers of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFF55D846781648FE8C0BE45E1E202937" level="section">Sec. 12. Interest rates on balances maintained at a Federal Reserve bank by depository institutions
			 established by Federal Open Market Committee.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBFA81E13A77248099920CF0E6EC52090" level="section">Sec. 13. Audit reform and transparency for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H285FA70B8EF247E4B165FD3624EAB71B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements for policy rules of the Federal Open Market Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/221">12 U.S.C. 221 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 2B the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DACDE59686140DFBC8CA3E30B78673F" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
				<section id="H589FF17AE2384AA89C1D0015BB9237BB"><enum>2C.</enum><header>Directive Policy Rules of the Federal Open Market Committee</header>
 <subsection id="HB44C97630D9E484693AAE260E78BE480"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="H15C07D822F8E420198BB4CFB9280B88A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21D16AF27F2E45308687ED11F1D5DEDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Directive Policy Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Directive Policy Rule</term> means a policy rule developed by the Federal Open Market Committee that meets the requirements of subsection (c) and that provides the basis for the Open Market Operations Directive.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB1A58AA764E4451B3385AB58F97FBD2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>GDP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>GDP</term> means the gross domestic product of the United States as computed and published by the Department of Commerce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H581E7A8BBE714DF6B132B5B2E6E2156A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intermediate Policy Input</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Intermediate Policy Input</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C07B77E072847E6B0E2D8303A7AC864"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may include any variable determined by the Federal Open Market Committee as a necessary input to guide open-market operations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74EE4B5B08AF4D3185E9DF43CAC65754"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include an estimate of, and the method of calculation for, the current rate of inflation or current inflation expectations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DDA652C214D4DAA993C4912106481AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include, specifying whether the variable or estimate is historical, current, or a forecast and the method of calculation, at least one of—</text>
 <clause id="HAC7354395D8A448AA0EA22472D5347CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of real GDP, nominal GDP, or potential GDP;</text> </clause><clause id="HD8EA9C59A1BB434C92066A5FAC0DB902"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of the monetary aggregate compiled by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and Federal reserve banks; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B0145A3A65048DDA408A7A43569E2DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an interactive variable or a net estimate composed of the estimates described in clauses (i) and (ii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB23FB6F23A0544288EE94A87E3E0C87A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Legislative day</header><text>The term <term>legislative day</term> means a day on which either House of Congress is in session.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8CA55B08A09429182D89806843CBCC3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Open Market Operations Directive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Open Market Operations Directive</term> means an order to achieve a specified Policy Instrument Target provided to the Federal Reserve Bank of New York by the Federal Open Market Committee pursuant to powers authorized under section 14 of this Act that guide open-market operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02908DF6096844CBB1FCE5E0E1E28DF9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Policy Instrument</header><text>The term <term>Policy Instrument</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFDF36621ADEA41FE82B19C0606E71121"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the nominal Federal funds rate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D8982A2C21D47958240AD6BC876E223"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the nominal rate of interest paid on nonborrowed reserves; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14A6F2B7D54F44A488F0817057092DF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the discount window primary credit interest rate most recently published on the Federal Reserve Statistical Release on selected interest rates (daily or weekly), commonly referred to as the H.15 release.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52E9E691818849458EA79DC993B2F762"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Policy Instrument Target</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Policy Instrument Target</term> means the target for the Policy Instrument specified in the Open Market Operations Directive.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3994B75561C471D88122837D0444EC9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Reference Policy Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Reference Policy Rule</term> means a calculation of the nominal Federal funds rate as equal to the sum of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5328F6AAD7F5430DA257B49503E3C478"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rate of inflation over the previous four quarters.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D5BA5BC6D1D46179A1FC9B106E27C40"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One-half of the percentage deviation of the real GDP from an estimate of potential GDP.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE94A3505172442EAA06106F908146173"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One-half of the difference between the rate of inflation over the previous four quarters and two percent.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C9A56837C494B7A8EB40030BEB1AB1A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Two percent.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7DCDFFD457C4334B03EE822E054A5DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submitting a Directive Policy Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 hours after the end of a meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee, the Chairman of the Federal Open Market Committee shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Comptroller General of the United States a Directive Policy Rule and a statement that identifies the members of the Federal Open Market Committee who voted in favor of the Rule.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H44BCD4E00B5E40D28412D3FAFF8A7747"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for a Directive Policy Rule</header><text>A Directive Policy Rule shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE6961CAF724F40779A821A3A35171269"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the Policy Instrument the Directive Policy Rule is designed to target;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43AEF1891F9E4D0F964B97CF73B65819"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the strategy or rule of the Federal Open Market Committee for the systematic quantitative adjustment of the Policy Instrument Target to respond to a change in the Intermediate Policy Inputs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9BE949F41F2400F89DC531309D89784"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include a function that comprehensively models the interactive relationship between the Intermediate Policy Inputs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24B52CDE2D1D4A4D8B41550DBBC7ADFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include the coefficients of the Directive Policy Rule that generate the current Policy Instrument Target and a range of predicted future values for the Policy Instrument Target if changes occur in any Intermediate Policy Input;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E26E5174EEF4648A1178D9363846A28"><enum>(5)</enum><text>describe the procedure for adjusting the supply of bank reserves to achieve the Policy Instrument Target;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H950AC96FEECB4958B3095D8C33849FBE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a statement as to whether the Directive Policy Rule substantially conforms to the Reference Policy Rule and, if applicable—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD1232B72C97A4E14A8942AFA7300561A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an explanation of the extent to which it departs from the Reference Policy Rule;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60C52F6092664EB8B2C61EFFB7D29DE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a detailed justification for that departure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB245F115733C4C7591BEF5D4BF85E5AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the circumstances under which the Directive Policy Rule may be amended in the future;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0354803CFA70458EAED4BF3F8F3D8741"><enum>(7)</enum><text>include a certification that such Rule is expected to support the economy in achieving stable prices and maximum natural employment over the long term; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E63CFB67FDF45CE96E1BE5FD860373D"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a calculation that describes with mathematical precision the expected annual inflation rate over a 5-year period.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H622F47EF65844C3BA5587C0749D48F47"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall compare the Directive Policy Rule submitted under subsection (b) with the rule that was most recently submitted to determine whether the Directive Policy Rule has materially changed. If the Directive Policy Rule has materially changed, the Comptroller General shall, not later than 7 days after each meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee, prepare and submit a compliance report to the appropriate congressional committees specifying whether the Directive Policy Rule submitted after that meeting and the Federal Open Market Committee are in compliance with this section.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H8D5AEAFEBE164332B8318DB85ED1A5DD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Changing market conditions</header>
 <paragraph id="H1749365928EE48C9BE418AB21FC3D08A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require that the plans with respect to the systematic quantitative adjustment of the Policy Instrument Target described under subsection (c)(2) be implemented if the Federal Open Market Committee determines that such plans cannot or should not be achieved due to changing market conditions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H416EE550739A4C89BB4C0839E9AE4554"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO approval of update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon determining that plans described in paragraph (1) cannot or should not be achieved, the Federal Open Market Committee shall submit an explanation for that determination and an updated version of the Directive Policy Rule to the Comptroller General of the United States and the appropriate congressional committees not later than 48 hours after making the determination. The Comptroller General shall, not later than 48 hours after receiving such updated version, prepare and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a compliance report determining whether such updated version and the Federal Open Market Committee are in compliance with this section.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BCDD4DEA1974DBFBC9C59FE448F266D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Directive Policy Rule and Federal Open Market Committee not in compliance</header>
 <paragraph id="HF04F773DC5D04918B032158B6E15EA5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Comptroller General of the United States determines that the Directive Policy Rule and the Federal Open Market Committee are not in compliance with this section in the report submitted pursuant to subsection (d), or that the updated version of the Directive Policy Rule and the Federal Open Market Committee are not in compliance with this section in the report submitted pursuant to subsection (e)(2), the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall, if requested by the chairman of either of the appropriate congressional committees, not later than 7 legislative days after such request, testify before such committee as to why the Directive Policy Rule, the updated version, or the Federal Open Market Committee is not in compliance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H60FFC37E39AE4162BD6DB6D9F67F3610"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (b) of section 714 of title 31, United States Code, upon submitting a report of noncompliance pursuant to subsection (d) or subsection (e)(2) and after the period of 7 legislative days described in paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall audit the conduct of monetary policy by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Open Market Committee upon request of the appropriate congressional committee. Such committee may specify the parameters of such audit.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H117E7DED92634A54BF3C6FB807D3C91E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Congressional hearings</header><text>The Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall, if requested by the chairman of either of the appropriate congressional committees and not later than 7 legislative days after such request, appear before such committee to explain any change to the Directive Policy Rule.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD79D59912CDF4945A44F92C956A986F3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Open Market Committee blackout period</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12A of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/263">12 U.S.C. 263</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D0A8E6357BE4BF6BF1F74C034EAA78B" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H91702A7D4E8441C595A5D3A3D3026916"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Blackout period</header>
 <paragraph id="H3870EEF4B98942299D52AE22E2563980"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a blackout period, the only public communications that may be made by members and staff of the Committee with respect to macroeconomic or financial developments or about current or prospective monetary policy issues are the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA407174A7C5B4EC3993C1A4181B1170E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dissemination of published data, surveys, and reports that have been cleared for publication by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H890BA413B3794A2CA9E34DB6880DBC34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Answers to technical questions specific to a data release.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H044B4B12944B4EB08DA9C08C6AF11CFF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Communications with respect to the prudential or supervisory functions of the Board of Governors.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A7ACBE41322492987B6FEEA3559425E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Blackout period defined</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, and with respect to a meeting of the Committee described under subsection (a), the term <term>blackout period</term> means the time period that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF5616D63282B4B2CA0AF3EB02B5E2195"><enum>(A)</enum><text>begins immediately after midnight on the day that is one week prior to the date on which such meeting takes place; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H931959B4BA3846118312A6B9A37609D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ends at midnight on the day after the date on which such meeting takes place.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H550A6BC7D6AB4DE6989243570F00646C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemption for Chairman of the Board of Governors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from participating in or issuing public communications.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE1B2EC816124919BBC141DE5174C8CC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Membership of Federal Open Market Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12A(a) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/263">12 U.S.C. 263(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF9A7AEE46B0E4B939C1391F83D17A6D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>five</quote> and inserting <quote>six</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8A093023E9C4A24AEA532936BC21F36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>One by the board of directors</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>One by the boards of directors of the Federal Reserve Banks of New York and Boston; one by the boards of directors of the Federal Reserve Banks of Philadelphia and Cleveland; one by the boards of directors of the Federal Reserve Banks of Richmond and Atlanta; one by the boards of directors of the Federal Reserve Banks of Chicago and St. Louis; one by the boards of directors of the Federal Reserve Banks of Minneapolis and Kansas City; and one by the boards of directors of the Federal Reserve Banks of Dallas and San Francisco.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35F2A3E6AB5740AEA8ADB8123FD4E79A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after the second sentence the following: <quote>In odd numbered calendar years, one representative shall be elected from each of the Federal Reserve Banks of Boston, Philadelphia, Richmond, Chicago, Minneapolis, and Dallas. In even-numbered calendar years, one representative shall be elected from each of the Federal Reserve Banks of New York, Cleveland, Atlanta, St. Louis, Kansas City, and San Francisco.</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HBB4B01C5C10C482BB152F8395485BF28"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requirements for stress tests and supervisory letters for the Board of Governors of the Federal
			 Reserve System</header>
 <subsection id="H8C266E6FAB174678B679C15D286405B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Stress test rulemaking, GAO review, and publication of results</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 165(i)(1)(B) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365(i)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5794313DA1794C528F4379D0AA80EE3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending clause (i) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06008AE0895D47DA9E10652FA86DF159" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <clause id="HC4E4943F2E504A1C8969FC4A036BC429"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HAC0E6B9DCFAD4F0789752B614144C64D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue regulations, after providing for public notice and comment, that provide for at least 3 different sets of conditions under which the evaluation required by this subsection shall be conducted, including baseline, adverse, and severely adverse, and methodologies, including models used to estimate losses on certain assets; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEB6507A554484D7695815A74327ABA09"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide copies of such regulations to the Comptroller General of the United States and the Panel of Economic Advisors of the Congressional Budget Office before publishing such regulations;</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE877232EE442466D85F4E7C934A849BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (v), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, including any results of a resubmitted test</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0E2CF7CC6AE4287B11779481AC7AB56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of CCAR</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 165(i)(1) of such Act is further amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6035C9296D29405F9B6F9B9F4A0D7977" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H0392FA4F33D841D0BACF22DC54246B2D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to CCAR</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of subparagraph (B) shall apply to all stress tests performed under the Comprehensive Capital Analysis and Review exercise established by the Board of Governors.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H70BCEF5595F14929815106942BCC8B0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication of the number of supervisory letters sent to the largest bank holding companies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 165 of such Act is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C3CBF4FCA714EC29F5D4495BDE6F4D3" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HDDEE15B54B9446F09B864A824D6E7732"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Publication of supervisory letter information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors shall publicly disclose—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB4EBDBCC64824B1A819458E03BDBE03D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the aggregate number of supervisory letters sent to bank holding companies described in subsection (a) since the date of the enactment of this section, and keep such number updated; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8124457B563E47CAAAB9AC71C60F8F72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the aggregate number of such letters that are designated as <quote>Matters Requiring Attention</quote> and the aggregate number of such letters that are designated as <quote>Matters Requiring Immediate Attention</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section><section id="H990B772BFBF8467BBB242E5B853A4DCC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Frequency of testimony of the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to Congress</header> <subsection id="H4896AB520F754654BAF7EFFFD398C9D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2B of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/225b">12 U.S.C. 225b</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF0ADFD65B97647CDB98946E4677FA330"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>semi-annual</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>quarterly</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H16557CA94774451F87A277E9BE196380"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H343EA5AD7C1244E0A810E58F0D4975F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and October 20</quote> after <quote>July 20</quote> each place it appears; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F70CBFEA7B44A42AC0ADA542B8AE045"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and May 20</quote> after <quote>February 20</quote> each place it appears.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66054FB5D07545E9BB50484EAC29A9DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (12) of section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/247b">12 U.S.C. 247b(12)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>semi-annual</quote> and inserting <quote>quarterly</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD599511C9017463E811FB5883E222F69" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Vice Chairman for Supervision report requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (12) of section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/247">12 U.S.C. 247(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB77795F9F981431281B33AEA0794BACD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating such paragraph as paragraph (11); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAEDCB4351EE4A118F9F418B3B318450"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in such paragraph, by adding at the end the following: <quote>In each such appearance, the Vice Chairman for Supervision shall provide written testimony that includes the status of all pending and anticipated rulemakings that are being made by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. If, at the time of any appearance described in this paragraph, the position of Vice Chairman for Supervision is vacant, the Vice Chairman for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (who has the responsibility to serve in the absence of the Chairman) shall appear instead and provide the required written testimony. If, at the time of any appearance described in this paragraph, both Vice Chairman positions are vacant, the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall appear instead and provide the required written testimony.</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H4E9EE66104CB48CF9E063EC3C8D6DE9C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Economic analysis of regulations of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</header>
 <subsection id="H972E58B60D3541208951EDAF76CA5E78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to Federal Reserve Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/248">12 U.S.C. 248</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (l) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E620CB1D34246B291F08BA12E6080D7" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H0193FBBCED0D451C87D50F146F32E840"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Consideration of economic impacts</header>
 <paragraph id="HC759B2BA8C594EE5A5B7000D5346800B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before issuing any regulation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE6839257AEFF4346A2164FC8BC34E474"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clearly identify the nature and source of the problem that the proposed regulation is designed to address and assess the significance of that problem;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BA00BF9DBB34F9C977B2D47D29F6702"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess whether any new regulation is warranted or, with respect to a proposed regulation that the Board of Governors is required to issue by statute and with respect to which the Board has the authority to exempt certain persons from the application of such regulation, compare—</text>
 <clause id="H421F8D6797844EAB92C775938E77332F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the costs and benefits of the proposed regulation; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2E115753CF2646DA9D8182B6A5E3D405"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the costs and benefits of a regulation under which the Board exempts all persons from the application of the proposed regulation, to the extent the Board is able;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62C0845F24294AF68332D7342949CB08"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the qualitative and quantitative costs and benefits of the proposed regulation and propose or adopt a regulation only on a reasoned determination that the benefits of the proposed regulation outweigh the costs of the regulation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C36112F0E634E1BBCCFD4F2E6BBDD16"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and assess available alternatives to the proposed regulation that were considered, including any alternative offered by a member of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee and including any modification of an existing regulation, together with an explanation of why the regulation meets the regulatory objectives more effectively than the alternatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7334D7B6D6FB4E50BB696ABA10AAE90F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that any proposed regulation is accessible, consistent, written in plain language, and easy to understand and shall measure, and seek to improve, the actual results of regulatory requirements.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2616781B4EE04C05B92D39E0566BF4E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations and actions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBF62AB48A35248F68E006587A92D5E85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required actions</header><text>In deciding whether and how to regulate, the Board shall assess the costs and benefits of available regulatory alternatives, including the alternative of not regulating, and choose the approach that maximizes net benefits. Specifically, the Board shall—</text>
 <clause id="H373F8A6C096E441E92FD99C75F6615B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluate whether, consistent with achieving regulatory objectives, the regulation is tailored to impose the least impact on the availability of credit and economic growth and to impose the least burden on society, including market participants, individuals, businesses of different sizes, and other entities (including State and local governmental entities), taking into account, to the extent practicable, the cumulative costs of regulations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H967D30309EAB405BAED14C1240D3431E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evaluate whether the regulation is inconsistent, incompatible, or duplicative of other Federal regulations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC84E65A8F4FE4687A3653C86DCE00048"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a proposed regulation that the Board is required to issue by statute and with respect to which the Board has the authority to exempt certain persons from the application of such regulation, compare—</text>
 <subclause id="HD01865A9D8F14CC18CA24D0E972270C8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the costs and benefits of the proposed regulation; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H51FC586D4CF4457B962C4293ADC06411"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the costs and benefits of a regulation under which the Board exempts all persons from the application of the proposed regulation, to the extent the Board is able.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD131C6A416B84604893AA0E5EBF40716"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition, in making a reasoned determination of the costs and benefits of a proposed regulation, the Board shall, to the extent that each is relevant to the particular proposed regulation, take into consideration the impact of the regulation, including secondary costs such as an increase in the cost or a reduction in the availability of credit or investment services or products, on—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H9BA3F045BD724E18BCFCD4C8EBFF68AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the safety and soundness of the United States banking system;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5BEF4739990A4833B8A46FEAE46FCF65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>market liquidity in securities markets;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE9F017965C91435C96D15278835B8DB8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>small businesses;</text> </clause><clause id="H271FFAB6DB1C4EE99CC78C636F24A2E1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>community banks;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H347D27AB48004991B9941FA07B088D69"><enum>(v)</enum><text>economic growth;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1310D43A81994AB5A98C4600408CC09F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>cost and access to capital;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H7AEE053322DD42B3B513097500747622"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>market stability;</text> </clause><clause id="H7A563C88D9BD4C83B1C099236BA6F5D1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>global competitiveness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBA10C6E542064D62B3A513A87A3BC4CB"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>job creation;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H108C04985A3C47479531D2F7C79B5809"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the monetary policy transmission mechanism; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC91D2E87BA294C9AAC6CDAC3EAE91F32"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>employment levels.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2E48EA6D1C471FA1251B14E273151F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Explanation and comments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall explain in its final rule the nature of comments that it received and shall provide a response to those comments in its final rule, including an explanation of any changes that were made in response to those comments and the reasons that the Board did not incorporate concerns related to the potential costs or benefits in the final rule.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H2536FC740AC04EF2A1B8897A5CF64980"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Postadoption impact assessment</header>
 <subparagraph id="HDF1A44DB803642C3B533BCE5CEE7A082"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whenever the Board adopts or amends a regulation designated as a <quote>major rule</quote> within the meaning of section 804(2) of title 5, United States Code, it shall state, in its adopting release, the following:</text>
 <clause id="HF101D3F7E7E846C7BD612AEC7CDD1B5E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes and intended consequences of the regulation.</text> </clause><clause id="H91E9A5F6E8334B8097E7C05735BFE753"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assessment plan that will be used, consistent with the requirements of subparagraph (B), to assess whether the regulation has achieved the stated purposes.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB9F8B1FE40DC49B58C3B2ACAD86D52EC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate postimplementation quantitative and qualitative metrics to measure the economic impact of the regulation and the extent to which the regulation has accomplished the stated purpose of the regulation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H54B2F5BC6D934B1795CEB38907E11639"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reasonably foreseeable indirect effects that may result from the regulation.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E8DA56FC16D468FBB8CD2095B2552FC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements of assessment plan and report</header> <clause id="H5A559D652C4E417B860A1E429F0FD8DE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Requirements of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assessment plan required under this paragraph shall consider the costs, benefits, and intended and unintended consequences of the regulation. The plan shall specify the data to be collected, the methods for collection and analysis of the data, and a date for completion of the assessment. The assessment plan shall include an analysis of any jobs added or lost as a result of the regulation, differentiating between public and private sector jobs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA204D65002B4BB8B67F740CE06E9707"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Submission and publication of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall, not later than 2 years after the publication of the adopting release, publish the assessment plan in the Federal Register for notice and comment. If the Board determines, at least 90 days before the deadline for publication of the assessment plan, that an extension is necessary, the Board shall publish a notice of such extension and the specific reasons why the extension is necessary in the Federal Register. Any material modification of the assessment plan, as necessary to assess unforeseen aspects or consequences of the regulation, shall be promptly published in the Federal Register for notice and comment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H186A67595DC44FE5886BE0B521A21DCF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Data collection not subject to notice and comment requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Board has published the assessment plan for notice and comment at least 30 days before the adoption of a regulation designated as a major rule, the collection of data under the assessment plan shall not be subject to the notice and comment requirements in section 3506(c) of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Paperwork Reduction Act). Any material modification of the plan that requires collection of data not previously published for notice and comment shall also be exempt from such requirements if the Board has published notice in the Federal Register for comment on the additional data to be collected, at least 30 days before the initiation of data collection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H044DC4AACDB244C1B8D98B96D0DEE1F4"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Final action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after publication of the assessment plan in the Federal Register, the Board shall issue for notice and comment a proposal to amend or rescind the regulation, or shall publish a notice that the Board has determined that no action will be taken on the regulation. Such a notice will be deemed a final agency action.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC7F7D994624E709F2B4067D9379FE3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered regulations and other actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solely as used in this subsection, the term <term>regulation</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HD04F7FB252F644D4AB0149FB3555A82E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a statement of general applicability and future effect that is designed to implement, interpret, or prescribe law or policy, or to describe the procedure or practice requirements of the Board of Governors, including rules, orders of general applicability, interpretive releases, and other statements of general applicability that the Board of Governors intends to have the force and effect of law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA8F8AE17623411797952A29E716563C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="H857304EA965B4A08B164F2C9FAD94602"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a regulation issued in accordance with the formal rulemaking provisions of section 556 or 557 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8D526EA907AA41289A9190350C71CE84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a regulation that is limited to the organization, management, or personnel matters of the Board of Governors;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD818A05531374B53A47D5E56ACC9D8CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a regulation promulgated pursuant to statutory authority that expressly prohibits compliance with this provision; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB021B07BA1444B5EB7FA42ED99BF4684"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a regulation that is certified by the Board of Governors to be an emergency action, if such certification is published in the Federal Register.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF836264D58AA4EB9A4639AC13C6E6DF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall apply to the requirements regarding the conduct of monetary policy described in section 2.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE612444EEACE439FAC2DC48CAB04E7D4"><enum>9.</enum><header>Salaries, financial disclosures, and office staff of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve
			 System</header>
 <subsection id="HE035C7927F334D7B9F3F610A5CFB2E9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/248">12 U.S.C. 248</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3E2170DCC1004E7A92D2CFBE0A62408B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating the second subsection (s) (relating to <quote>Assessments, Fees, and Other Charges for Certain Companies</quote>) as subsection (t); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF97DC12F3D594769BA8EA523D639DD66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5480DD6D54145D899AB5C5A621958F5" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA13D0DE1FBC340F29A3F2B0B777E686B"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Ethics standards for members and employees</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF1D4018E7CA74172B036C2994E6E6B80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibited and restricted financial interests and transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members and employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall be subject to the provisions under section 4401.102 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, to the same extent as such provisions apply to an employee of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE72A47C1731F4EAB89CFE824A6F4E16D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of brokerage accounts and availability of account statements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members and employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H2DB4584404074DD7B8E825452131E1B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disclose all brokerage accounts that they maintain, as well as those in which they control trading or have a financial interest (including managed accounts, trust accounts, investment club accounts, and the accounts of spouses or minor children who live with the member or employee); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EEBFF8705664AC1838EBA9793ACD469"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any securities account that the member or employee is required to disclose to the Board of Governors, authorize their brokers and dealers to send duplicate account statements directly to Board of Governors.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7ABCB8D772D443EDB4F7789E0D4FA3A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibitions related to outside employment and activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members and employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall be subject to the prohibitions related to outside employment and activities described under section 4401.103(c) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, to the same extent as such prohibitions apply to an employee of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9DEEEBD2DF3542F2977B620C79E9AFAA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional ethics standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members and employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall be subject to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H63C0AD9363014EFCACA894BDE1D4E0CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the employee responsibilities and conduct regulations of the Office of Personnel Management under part 735 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB927AAB2CD094CD8B223184F7016957A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the canons of ethics contained in subpart C of part 200 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, to the same extent as such subpart applies to the employees of the Securities and Exchange Commission; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAEEA2164D994F0886AAEF36FB0FE967"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regulations concerning the conduct of members and employees and former members and employees contained in subpart M of part 200 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, to the same extent as such subpart applies to the employees of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB598C0B255B14247A56C4DA7F9DAC962"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Disclosure of staff salaries and financial information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall make publicly available, on the website of the Board of Governors, a searchable database that contains the names of all members, officers, and employees of the Board of Governors who receive an annual salary in excess of the annual rate of basic pay for GS–15 of the General Schedule, and—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDD3AC0A29D134087AD62A5BC50A587EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the yearly salary information for such individuals, along with any nonsalary compensation received by such individuals; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD39CD2EBF4F84B24BE2182C2FE191030"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any financial disclosures required to be made by such individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25211AA399AF49588CA1375D3B14EDE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office staff for each member of the Board of Governors</header><text>Subsection (l) of section 11 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/248">12 U.S.C. 248</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Each member of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may employ, at a minimum, 2 individuals, with such individuals selected by such member and the salaries of such individuals set by such member. A member may employ additional individuals as determined necessary by the Board of Governors.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H357D5EE4C343476CB6DE1F4CC1DB7668" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>10.</enum><header>Requirements for international processes</header>
 <subsection id="HED4C59B38B0A41C58B0F23D50A877C39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of Governors requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/248">12 U.S.C. 248</external-xref>), as amended by section 9 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75778F8CC0D04DBAAA34105D26A3F90D" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H5725B501BEA7424FA0FA3BD07375074E"><enum>(w)</enum><header>International processes</header>
 <paragraph id="H36EEAC52061F40DD840DD5F7E9789929"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of process; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 30 calendar days before any member or employee of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Board of Governors shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H72F1BF3B6A0442C7B2FDE752D77025EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a notice of the process, including the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process, to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30CF403FDA8B4A129A3F99F808DC8991"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Board of Governors; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB06C52FB48A4E6EA513A8F4844D2A6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit public comment, and consult with the committees described under subparagraph (A), with respect to the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B31BA951A294D68A63244D08CE3DD9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public reports on process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the end of any process described under paragraph (1), the Board of Governors shall issue a public report on the topics that were discussed during the process and any new or revised rulemakings or policy changes that the Board of Governors believes should be implemented as a result of the process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36AE2491803F42A49B3B6ED705B9341F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of agreements; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 90 calendar days before any member or employee of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Board of Governors shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H60C0BBAB963F4F888591AF8985B1E9C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a notice of agreement to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A1B29140BA44C0CA48DE12A11859962"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Board of Governors; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDCD2B3DDBBC4BB4AEC77E04EE42F749"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consult with the committees described under subparagraph (A) with respect to the nature of the agreement and any anticipated effects such agreement will have on the economy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB818BD75724742F5BCDDE0E63EAFDA8D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>process</term> shall include any official proceeding or meeting on financial regulation of a recognized international organization with authority to set financial standards on a global or regional level, including the Financial Stability Board, the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (or a similar organization), and the International Association of Insurance Supervisors (or a similar organization).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H892D3ABA20214E2C95A2907E73268328"><enum>(b)</enum><header>FDIC requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACB00F41AEAA41CA845E13F9DB675608" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<section id="HFCA1D7414E66438D8A34939CA82CD3A8"><enum>51.</enum><header>International processes</header>
 <subsection id="H64A4BE4644274FC9BC615CE3D35F8ACC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice of process; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 30 calendar days before the Board of Directors participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Board of Directors shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD0E374FABF6349C9A11F9B0D465A23D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a notice of the process, including the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process, to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41BFC0368F594FA39E8DA4BB4F23A6DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Corporation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2D42FADBE964534AC7B1A8E5E277126"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit public comment, and consult with the committees described under paragraph (1), with respect to the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAFAC0B25AB4242D58880577910500F1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public reports on process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the end of any process described under subsection (a), the Board of Directors shall issue a public report on the topics that were discussed at the process and any new or revised rulemakings or policy changes that the Board of Directors believes should be implemented as a result of the process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5A7C4503DCFD4C03A736A3355D6E02F9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of agreements; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 90 calendar days before the Board of Directors participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Board of Directors shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H72873EF455D44A3EA78C7947748B02B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue a notice of agreement to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98894A65B8414F27B31BCD8CC49F1B16"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Corporation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6A59C07877048F7BACA9943DA17E90B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the committees described under paragraph (1) with respect to the nature of the agreement and any anticipated effects such agreement will have on the economy.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93B321399B5F4C7CAA228106FE0245C0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>process</term> shall include any official proceeding or meeting on financial regulation of a recognized international organization with authority to set financial standards on a global or regional level, including the Financial Stability Board, the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (or a similar organization), and the International Association of Insurance Supervisors (or a similar organization).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H55EDC85F880A47C1A555F3ADFDB41ED1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treasury requirements</header><text>Section 325 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48AD83A686594E8199FC484A95F5EB84" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
					<subsection id="HC6DA140A44004AE7BA0FE9A427D6A339"><enum>(d)</enum><header>International processes</header>
 <paragraph id="H84224CEE548141CB8CBC1B3FCB0D5EE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of process; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 30 calendar days before the Secretary participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC85521041A024EF2B0711ABC27A7762E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a notice of the process, including the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process, to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF99C2844AD347AFAB34410ED3B1F1AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Department of the Treasury; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FED8F41ADA44C70B99BB813D55DAB26"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit public comment, and consult with the committees described under subparagraph (A), with respect to the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28921A6C0AD44CCC8A4752578F9C2843"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public reports on process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the end of any process described under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall issue a public report on the topics that were discussed at the process and any new or revised rulemakings or policy changes that the Secretary believes should be implemented as a result of the process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1ED892815EBB4464B236296094F2ED34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of agreements; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 90 calendar days before the Secretary participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE3A4A465BAD342A1AD401E2CD6EEAD8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a notice of agreement to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE38D2DBFB5224034BD93228A899A90E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Department of the Treasury; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6086828AA7794AFF8F57637DF7D92076"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the committees described under subparagraph (A) with respect to the nature of the agreement and any anticipated effects such agreement will have on the economy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF29643E404E64C5692FD338125DDBBED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>process</term> shall include any official proceeding or meeting on financial regulation of a recognized international organization with authority to set financial standards on a global or regional level, including the Financial Stability Board, the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (or a similar organization), and the International Association of Insurance Supervisors (or a similar organization).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCA630121CC374AF7841E7494FEF2F864"><enum>(d)</enum><header>OCC requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 1 of title LXII of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/21">12 U.S.C. 21 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8E63B81936154C8492C6062E0EE6D809"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CF8329772F046D1BF3566B8F5D63F10" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <section id="H4E949FA33BC54A79B27310994F4D18AB"><enum>5156B.</enum><header>International processes</header> <subsection id="HF05A76FB52F94A37A61F3A58B2B0B9A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice of process; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 30 calendar days before the Comptroller of the Currency participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Comptroller of the Currency shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C217769D4CF482789720D1C9F7997C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a notice of the process, including the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process, to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08CB54A9CF614DCCBCDC597F78B5C116"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE9B49F7E4A3430D8B0D5FB318A42D69"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit public comment, and consult with the committees described under paragraph (1), with respect to the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB110484288314F6B9CC16B4A3885E79D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public reports on process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the end of any process described under subsection (a), the Comptroller of the Currency shall issue a public report on the topics that were discussed at the process and any new or revised rulemakings or policy changes that the Comptroller of the Currency believes should be implemented as a result of the process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAB847771C15E40479AC94AEC00758C7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of agreements; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 90 calendar days before the Comptroller of the Currency participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Board of Directors shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H13174A2333B041E5B3CADF58D3A54497"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue a notice of agreement to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H887E276CBF62414B9B8CBD0858498A77"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA26BDBAC51334A60BA013B9E3D665D4B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the committees described under paragraph (1) with respect to the nature of the agreement and any anticipated effects such agreement will have on the economy.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE57EFACD8544ECD963CEF595B1FEFCC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>process</term> shall include any official proceeding or meeting on financial regulation of a recognized international organization with authority to set financial standards on a global or regional level, including the Financial Stability Board, the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (or a similar organization), and the International Association of Insurance Supervisors (or a similar organization).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H641C1B154C4C441D815DC2407C8523D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the table of contents for such chapter, by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="HDAE774696DA542DEAE4915A5BB6E322D" reported-display-style="italic"> <toc changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" idref="H4E949FA33BC54A79B27310994F4D18AB" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic"> <toc-entry level="section">5156B. International processes.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE339569F22F14A59B6FC4DAA36BA4143"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Securities and Exchange Commission requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78d">15 U.S.C. 78d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H967E7190D6A34A28A75378370CF1CED2" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
					<subsection id="HF75814550B45402BAD89008CE384E321"><enum>(j)</enum><header>International processes</header>
 <paragraph id="HF94F18F144C64A0AB785F77738608D21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of process; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 30 calendar days before the Commission participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Commission shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H535778F22A484589A71267EFACCE3489"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a notice of the process, including the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process, to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C36FEF348EE44D0A8AA0A2209EB4D7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Commission; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H338BCA16759D475E8F8BB7FB67DDADEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit public comment, and consult with the committees described under subparagraph (A), with respect to the subject matter, scope, and goals of the process.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5729CA8E6AF349D8AB00DAFD2667E614"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public reports on process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the end of any process described under paragraph (1), the Commission shall issue a public report on the topics that were discussed at the process and any new or revised rulemakings or policy changes that the Commission believes should be implemented as a result of the process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD78CE7519634DBDBE03BE2330BC31CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of agreements; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 90 calendar days before the Commission participates in a process of setting financial standards as a part of any foreign or multinational entity, the Commission shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2DE64414FAAA4CA1B4C83A4DE5A73A73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a notice of agreement to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27FCE12337AB413191E1D74F0A1E1E78"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such notice available to the public, including on the website of the Commission; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3ECAE50441B4BFCA3EDA8F4070D9E5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the committees described under subparagraph (A) with respect to the nature of the agreement and any anticipated effects such agreement will have on the economy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA08C455F33DA4FD1A2673D14DE8D5DF4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>process</term> shall include any official proceeding or meeting on financial regulation of a recognized international organization with authority to set financial standards on a global or regional level, including the Financial Stability Board, the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (or a similar organization), and the International Association of Insurance Supervisors (or a similar organization).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HBD59C15ABF1D460895A5C48155F10D73" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>11.</enum><header>Amendments to powers of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</header>
 <subsection id="HDF90D66FCF9C4C0F862DEB35206708EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13(3) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/343">12 U.S.C. 343(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H786F12F57E2A43F5AE610D1928F2E185"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC8D7126A02C54023BDEC3D67F15607BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>that pose a threat to the financial stability of the United States</quote> after <quote>unusual and exigent circumstances</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9C361F8D9294684A1348753BCD06C1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and by the affirmative vote of not less than nine presidents of the Federal reserve banks</quote> after <quote>five members</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H686B5156089E41C68AFEFC527753AA82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C1BC97444C94AC19A252A175023C636"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2502FB44AB1247D1895D4CB11D4297DB" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <text>Federal reserve banks may not accept equity securities issued by the recipient of any loan or other financial assistance under this paragraph as collateral. Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this sentence, the Board shall, by rule, establish—</text><subclause id="H75D4B055975D4AB18919BE00207DEF40"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a method for determining the sufficiency of the collateral required under this paragraph;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HAB2EC0C4C28D4ADDB3202155B3CA5AA9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>acceptable classes of collateral;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H411092ECD5B14BF59CBCE361355872CC"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any discount of such value that the Federal reserve banks will apply for purposes of calculating the sufficiency of collateral under this paragraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H71775226A5BF4C66BF93F71650A68532"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a method for obtaining independent appraisals of the value of collateral the Federal reserve banks receive.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25425823CBB741BE89172AB9ACCFED60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <clause id="H441FA6E9C248479EBD8CDBF9ECCF98A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBFFABC4FBD4D471BACB15E51B477C05C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>A borrower shall not be eligible to borrow from any emergency lending program or facility unless the Board and all federal banking regulators with jurisdiction over the borrower certify that, at the time the borrower initially borrows under the program or facility, the borrower is not insolvent.</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF92CFFC3BE734E388976B4D562DD9BAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>financial institution</quote> before <quote>participant</quote> each place such term appears;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB26F08C483B0421C8F53A0D3E7C50220"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(i), by inserting <quote>financial institution</quote> before <quote>participants</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H172FB25FC5E24DA5ADF752A9EB9CEA57"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="H6A4A8A92A8244E218B9B7F8C19497B75" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H4A1902F047D4423381BA4FAC1CE20C81"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Penalty rate</header> <clause id="H0F38BB3BF6394C4195B21DEB1E5804A1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the Board shall, with respect to a recipient of any loan or other financial assistance under this paragraph, establish by rule a minimum interest rate on the principal amount of any loan or other financial assistance.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5A479F53FE4746F4983BFDF8E37B8C23"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Minimum interest rate defined</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>minimum interest rate</term> shall mean the sum of—</text> <subclause id="HE8B0D7F7FF9D492DB480530DB025B588"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average of the secondary discount rate of all Federal Reserve banks over the most recent 90-day period; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4C988281D8564ED8A4C4706DF20C669C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the average of the difference between a distressed corporate bond yield index (as defined by rule of the Board) and a bond yield index of debt issued by the United States (as defined by rule of the Board) over the most recent 90-day period.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5584613602394BD2A4F627DE786CB966"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Financial institution participant defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>financial institution participant</term>—</text> <clause id="HEF201129A1A24ADF8F4F7818071B9BD1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a company that is predominantly engaged in financial activities (as defined in section 102(a) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5311">12 U.S.C. 5311(a)</external-xref>)); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC1359EC1BAA947728E69165199490D08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include an agency described in subparagraph (W) of section 5312(a)(2) of title 31, United States Code, or an entity controlled or sponsored by such an agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA24A0405912940948710B60F6CC06531"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11(r)(2)(A) of such Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H55F49A678A1B4784BC7D0F77160346F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (ii)(IV), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HACC5132BD2FF412C8338EF7FE58C1C92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H58864259447041AFAF175865547C99F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="H0A1E5A33BFD84A7BBE0187E332DCA972" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H639356BFABAA4264809F5F64BCC3711B" indent="up2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the available members secure the affirmative vote of not less than nine presidents of the Federal reserve banks.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFF55D846781648FE8C0BE45E1E202937"><enum>12.</enum><header>Interest rates on balances maintained at a Federal Reserve bank by depository institutions
 established by Federal Open Market Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 19(b)(12) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/461">12 U.S.C. 461(b)(12)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>established by the Federal Open Market Committee</quote> after <quote>rate or rates</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HBFA81E13A77248099920CF0E6EC52090"><enum>13.</enum><header>Audit reform and transparency for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</header>
 <subsection id="H46D921A5F6BC403A839E0181BD2FFBFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 714 of title 31, United States Code, or any other provision of law, the Comptroller General of the United States shall complete an audit of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal reserve banks under subsection (b) of such section 714 within 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3D2ADD3636334DD98DB954EBF47736F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H37F34CE1B6CA4958A535E141C3F97CED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the audit required pursuant to subsection (a) is completed, the Comptroller General—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDE47FF02F84C4965B2B0BACEA90946EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall submit to Congress a report on such audit; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBA45C96165A4D2A87FD8609B364C4B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall make such report available to the Speaker of the House, the majority and minority leaders of the House of Representatives, the majority and minority leaders of the Senate, the Chairman and Ranking Member of the committee and each subcommittee of jurisdiction in the House of Representatives and the Senate, and any other Member of Congress who requests the report.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48FB2AB64A7A4F5CA7AA9F14D2E5D1B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include a detailed description of the findings and conclusion of the Comptroller General with respect to the audit that is the subject of the report, together with such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Comptroller General may determine to be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47B4BEE4B7AF4FBB8A61B7B4E5307288"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeal of certain limitations</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 714 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking the second sentence.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC1439909789643B89B5FEC47756672E7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H1D8B842BACB842CD9DAAC57EF9F5C915"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 714 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H3720787517384601A05D441481297690"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(3), by striking <quote>or (f)</quote> each place such term appears;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF19C6BEABF2B458BAC40E6609A2CFFC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), by striking <quote>the third undesignated paragraph of section 13</quote> and inserting <quote>section 13(3)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A14FA87031B4610B1ECC64037DC01D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subsection (f).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3FF776732E24ADCBEF6C1C20A8366E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal Reserve Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (s) (relating to <quote>Federal Reserve Transparency and Release of Information</quote>) of section 11 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/248">12 U.S.C. 248</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H994DE44A8EBF4C67915EACAAD0409249"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A), by striking <quote>has the same meaning as in section 714(f)(1)(A) of title 31, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>means a program or facility, including any special purpose vehicle or other entity established by or on behalf of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or a Federal reserve bank, authorized by the Board of Governors under section 13(3), that is not subject to audit under section 714(e) of title 31, United States Code</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H61D7702FFC814D8194B030168FD6E14D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>or in section 714(f)(3)(C) of title 31, United States Code, the information described in paragraph (1) and information concerning the transactions described in section 714(f) of such title,</quote> and inserting <quote>the information described in paragraph (1)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E4C2D5979D4476E85E51CDBEFC20CB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and section 13(3)(C), section 714(f)(3)(C) of title 31, United States Code, and</quote> and inserting <quote>, section 13(3)(C), and</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4AF2FA1D0C254D8CB673B9B4F1B9AE5E"><enum>14.</enum><header>Reporting requirement for Export-Import Bank</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall include, as part of the monthly Federal Reserve statistical release titled <quote>Industrial Production or Capacity Utilization</quote> (or any successor release), an analysis of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H95D0DDF57FD84F3BA1807921E751740E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the impact on the index described in the statistical release due to the operation of the Export-Import Bank; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45BC681807754EEC9C2092FCAD81192F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of foreign industrial production supported by foreign export credit agencies, using the same method used to measure industrial production in the statistical release and scaled to be comparable to the industrial production measurement for the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H95E3E4997AA04CFBB0B8A00662A83697"><enum>15.</enum><header>Membership of Board of Directors of the Federal reserve banks</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/302">12 U.S.C. 302</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD44052E73B6849A39C79F2B02422AB3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the eleventh undesignated paragraph (relating to Class B), by striking <quote>and consumers</quote> and inserting <quote>consumers, and traditionally underserved communities and populations</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB6DE6FDBCDF47D989A2A8BC120C3B27"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the twelfth undesignated paragraph (relating to Class C), by striking <quote>and consumers</quote> and inserting <quote>consumers, and traditionally underserved communities and populations</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20151116">November 16, 2015</action-date> <action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc> <action-date date="20151116">November 16, 2015</action-date> <action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

