<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF11F9203EB174A909449707716D063B7" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4063 IH: Promoting Responsible Opioid Management and Incorporating Scientific Expertise Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4063</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151118">November 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000689">Mr. Mica</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve the use by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of opioids in treating veterans, to improve
			 patient advocacy by the Secretary, and to expand the availability of
			 complementary and integrative health, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H91775EA2D192468BB1A51C73181C0D39" style="OLC">
		<section id="H369C7A9736A9407698BE9143F0A14E3E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H0982C2F8AEA84B33987917A09DF3FA2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Responsible Opioid Management and Incorporating Scientific Expertise Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Jason Simcakoski PROMISE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7CED434405E74B5FB63CD53EA5A5D526"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H369C7A9736A9407698BE9143F0A14E3E" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H986CEAF2154E40349EE428F3839630A1" level="title">Title I—Opioid Therapy and Pain Management</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H64071C225B234785B41DC409A4C95DD3" level="section">Sec. 101. Guidelines on management of opioid therapy by Department of Veterans Affairs and
			 Department of Defense and implementation of such guidelines by Department
			 of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBE750C1BD0444C7F93C1CE5D24D18615" level="section">Sec. 102. Improvement of opioid safety measures by Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBFB45EFAA83E4B3FBE090F7D8D86E503" level="section">Sec. 103. Strengthening of joint working group on pain management of the Department of Veterans
			 Affairs and the Department of Defense.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H619B1907915E44B59B02B1525FB30783" level="section">Sec. 104. Review, investigation, and report on use of opioids in treatment by Department of
			 Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEDD9E8E4DCBE4E669B444F758984A73F" level="title">Title II—Patient Advocacy</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5092A0B7503B476AB4499597D74B707A" level="section">Sec. 201. Community meetings on improving care furnished by Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H85567A2879084023BA05FAD60B2BB355" level="section">Sec. 202. Improvement of awareness of patient advocacy program and patient bill of rights of
			 Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9ABA397CBD604CAF98C5DF16CB0953E8" level="section">Sec. 203. Comptroller general report on patient advocacy program of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6D67A0DCBE9743CE8653B8B6F3166C8C" level="title">Title III—Complementary and Integrative Health</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8C65F856FC40492188E9ECF511CBDCB3" level="section">Sec. 301. Expansion of research and education on and delivery of complementary and integrative
			 health to veterans.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H589F2704155A421EB4C6A50A065F700E" level="section">Sec. 302. Pilot program on integration of complementary alternative medicines and related issues
			 for veterans and family members of veterans.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBD0D861AACB74C5C812657C591F4E6DC" level="title">Title IV—Fitness of Health Care Providers</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H19F1F91A7536473C8CD02FFE9CD373DA" level="section">Sec. 401. Additional requirements for hiring of health care providers by Department of Veterans
			 Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA2FAF75B9BC04D4C84AD458C55C1812A" level="section">Sec. 402. Provision of information on health care providers of Department of Veterans Affairs to
			 State Medical Boards.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFCC8739B190442ACBBDAD953DAFA9C8E" level="section">Sec. 403. Report on compliance by Department of Veterans Affairs with reviews of health care
			 providers leaving the Department or transferring to other facilities.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF27B236725544F14B4CC0EF072B3F0BB" level="title">Title V—Other Veterans Matters</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB4EAF7B0A60342818060A80A861C56C0" level="section">Sec. 501. Audit of Veterans Health Administration programs of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><title id="H986CEAF2154E40349EE428F3839630A1"><enum>I</enum><header>Opioid Therapy and Pain Management</header>
			<section id="H64071C225B234785B41DC409A4C95DD3"><enum>101.</enum><header>Guidelines on management of opioid therapy by Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of
			 Defense and implementation of such guidelines by Department of Veterans
			 Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="H0B72997DE1D3467495A88CE3D9EE72F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly update the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain to include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H141EB7B230BE42BC9DEBA99913500734"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with subsection (b), common recommended guidelines for safely prescribing opioids for the treatment of chronic, non-cancer pain in outpatient settings as compiled by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF945373D5F2447B496B9244DB2484339"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Enhanced guidance with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H86C05D028B4C49F482F83483566A1CBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the administration of two or more drugs that may result in a life-limiting drug-to-drug interaction, including benzodiazepines;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC769F5ACE23F4A22B08ACC0E831CB724"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the treatment of patients with current acute psychiatric instability or substance use disorder or patients at risk of suicide; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBB49B141AE445168F0A95EDEA67BDAE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the use of opioid therapy to treat mental health disorders other than opioid use disorder.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87139C11A08A4DF1B68E4B79D0C5F174"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Enhanced guidance with respect to the treatment of patients with behaviors or comorbidities, such as post-traumatic stress disorder, psychiatric disorders, or a history of substance abuse or addiction, that requires a consultation or comanagement of opioid therapy with one or more specialists in pain management, mental health, or addictions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95CBBD4154CE4413A5CAFAC18829B50B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Enhanced guidance with respect to the conduct by health care providers of an effective assessment for patients receiving opioid therapy, including patients on long-term opioid therapy, to determine—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0ED5D44BE9F24D3A853DB687558A2F29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether opioid therapy is meeting the expected goals of the patient and health care provider of relieving pain, improving function, and providing patient satisfaction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FFF82F135404A799D287CF54DC748FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether opioid therapy should be continued.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E0BF59414C240A390789E3F360C3ACE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Guidance that each health care provider of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense, before initiating opioid therapy to treat a patient as part of the comprehensive assessment conducted by the health care provider, use the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department of Veterans Affairs (or successor tool), which shall include the ability to access the most recent patient information from the prescription drug monitoring program of each State that has such a program to assess the risk for adverse outcomes of opioid therapy for the patient, including with respect to the concurrent use of controlled substances, including benzodiazepines.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC663244E7F5A4C1EAFB50FE91906DFCA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Guidelines to govern the methodologies used by health care providers of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense to safely titrate and taper opioid therapy when adjusting or discriminating the use of opioid therapy, including with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H02D338E6302347FA8B111063C7AFD674"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prescription of the lowest effective dose based on patient need;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4574B8F103BB49EBAFD6EAD13DFA7694"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use of opioid only for a limited period of time; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60852DE418E14A7081B4182B2BBBD810"><enum>(C)</enum><text>augmentation of opioid therapy with other pain management therapies and modalities.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEADF4A1DB634D63A86323A1F87B3EB6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Guidelines with respect to appropriate case management for patients receiving opioid therapy who transition between inpatient and outpatient health care settings, which may include the use of care transition plans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0139BB740F164ED4ACFCA4456F8A3931"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Guidelines with respect to appropriate transfer of case management responsibility for patients receiving opioid therapy who transition from receiving care furnished by the Secretary of Defense to receiving care furnished by other health care providers after the patient has been discharged or separated from the Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71781329F1814747AB5ECD62E61C110A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Enhanced standards with respect to the use of routine and random urine drug tests for all patients before and during opioid therapy to help prevent substance abuse, dependence, and diversion, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB519875FDBC043B39500BE409D7719DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that such tests occur not less frequently than once each year; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC8BB478FD044E8B937134AA437FA9D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that health care providers appropriately interpret and respond to the results from such tests to tailor pain therapy, safeguards, and risk management strategies to each patient.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DF9F438ADFB473FB543F3F0FA5007AB"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Guidance that health care providers discuss with patients, before initiating opioid therapy, options for pain management therapies without the use of opioids and options to augment opioid therapy with other clinical and complementary and integrative health services to minimize opioid dependence.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3BEF2E7838084482B5783A4A76BE499D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of certain guidelines developed after deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention issues the guidelines described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) after the date on which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense jointly update the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain pursuant to such subsection, the Secretaries shall jointly modify the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain to incorporate such guidelines of the Director.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA78AC8F3F7064B2F9F01B66BF363D640"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation before update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before updating the guideline under subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly consult with the Pain Management Working Group of the Department of Veterans Affairs–Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee established by section 320 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0C42FC14953C469DBA64C8D0D6471218"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HDE5B0A894FC34DD0A270BE2839F84E9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>controlled substance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE20B16FC239F47479B8EE5B953BE184E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, territories, and possessions of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBE750C1BD0444C7F93C1CE5D24D18615"><enum>102.</enum><header>Improvement of opioid safety measures by Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="H538C4BD18E134B8DAE7471BCC06C73C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of opioid safety initiative</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall expand the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department of Veterans Affairs to include all medical facilities of the Department.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H5257BF06D58C48CCAE386BE1D3F2188C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pain management education and training</header>
 <paragraph id="H344D84A3D419483EAE68FE4E62C39D70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department, the Secretary shall require all employees of the Department responsible for prescribing opioids to receive education and training described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B9F6293D8C64257BFD449B8CD80F834"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Education and training</header><text>Education and training described in this paragraph is education and training on pain management and safe opioid prescribing practices for purposes of safely and effectively managing patients with chronic pain, including education and training on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H06B3CD33DD4E47F0BFBFA2F4292A7E36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The implementation of and full compliance with the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain, including any update to such guideline.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H289C0D1FD7634CFA92F7406DBBB23D2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The use of evidence-based pain management therapies, including cognitive-behavioral therapy, non-opioid alternatives, and non-drug methods and procedures to managing pain and related health conditions including complementary alternative medicines.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CB054BA370A43318D243100DC5363D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Screening and identification of patients with substance use disorder, including drug-seeking behavior, before prescribing opioids, assessment of risk potential for patients developing an addiction, and referral of patients to appropriate addiction treatment professionals if addiction is identified or strongly suspected.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2858730EBDD3440685DFEFA4E90F39F4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Communication with patients on the potential harm associated with the use of opioids and other controlled substances, including the need to safely store and dispose of supplies relating to the use of opioids and other controlled substances.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E62B0C0F2B6431AAF7C09733B469C7D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other education and training as the Secretary considers appropriate to ensure that veterans receive safe and high-quality pain management care from the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD391F25F3354C2091F43AD40E745655"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of existing program</header><text>In providing education and training described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall use the Interdisciplinary Chronic Pain Management Training Team Program of the Department (or success program).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D15A58BB9434D1C9F52BB9B8A62AA90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pain management teams</header>
 <paragraph id="HC4AEFF9102CC4FBF85555C442E1A900F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department, the director of each medical facility of the Department shall identify and designate a pain management team of health care professionals, which may include board certified pain medicine specialists, responsible for coordinating and overseeing pain management therapy at such facility for patients experiencing acute and chronic pain that is non-cancer related.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H77E46FD9CADE40F8BF262E7B1D3C3C25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of protocols</header>
 <subparagraph id="H09739FC162D84D64ACA5E46ECB8E5AA2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In consultation with the Directors of each Veterans Integrated Service Network, the Secretary shall establish standard protocols for the designation of pain management teams at each medical facility within the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7BB80C8C66A46DFA9759F312125F8E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation on prescription of opioids</header><text>Each protocol established under subparagraph (A) shall ensure that any health care provider without expertise in prescribing analgesics or who has not completed the education and training under subsection (b), including a mental health care provider, does not prescribe opioids to a patient unless that health care provider—</text>
 <clause id="H9B1A4E951BA3431D9A388AF2F898F5D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consults with a health care provider with pain management expertise or who is on the pain management team of the medical facility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C1EBAD4AF144AA394F07B7C725B4172"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refers the patient to the pain management team for any subsequent prescriptions and related therapy.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84282D08C5304A8E868ED9369C097819"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6A5B344C2715493FB2A956C20B97AF3C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the director of each medical facility of the Department shall submit to the Under Secretary for Health and the director of the Veterans Integrated Service Network in which the medical facility is located a report identifying the health care professionals that have been designated as members of the pain management team at the medical facility pursuant to paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AEA066BEC2E4D9296FAA802CDA34198"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) with respect to a medical facility of the Department shall include—</text>
 <clause id="HE7614FCEC00B43E6962D9E665478AEC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a certification as to whether all members of the pain management team at the medical facility have completed the education and training required under subsection (b); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDED2C1451FF94545BFE4E786A01A941F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a plan for the management and referral of patients to such pain management team if health care providers without expertise in prescribing analgesics prescribe opioid medications to treat acute and chronic pain that is non-cancer related.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE29D92790DA8485A91F21A02D0CDC524"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tracking and monitoring of opioid use</header>
 <paragraph id="H6095F7BC82C1403E811940E22C57A247"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prescription drug monitoring programs of states</header><text>In carrying out the Opioid Safety Initiative and the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H379494BBF7B3408A994D8CB4BD50E24A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure access by health care providers of the Department to information on controlled substances, including opioids and benzodiazepines, prescribed to veterans who receive care outside the Department through the prescription drug monitoring program of each State with such a program, including by seeking to enter into memoranda of understanding with States to allow shared access of such information between States and the Department;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE1D41EE62C24C168FE042EB9561889F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include such information in the Opioid Therapy Risk Report; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3A4C15099274B1A9E9A012FE46CE7F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require health care providers of the Department to submit to the prescription drug monitoring program of each State information on prescriptions of controlled substances received by veterans in that State under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2B40DD7C87C4745BA52D472AA9CB04C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on tracking of data on opioid use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the feasibility and advisability of improving the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department to allow for more advanced real-time tracking of and access to data on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE5870541A754D028FF7709C86EE908F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the key clinical indicators with respect to the totality of opioid use by veterans;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47D7B4E3E0AF437F8AC460F8A3596F4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>concurrent prescribing by health care providers of the Department of opioids in different health care settings, including data on concurrent prescribing of opioids to treat mental health disorders other than opioid use disorder; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54BAA8B7E74F4946931E8098B27724B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mail-order prescriptions of opioid prescribed to veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8230680ED27D44D29C65729B32653128"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Availability of opioid receptor antagonists</header>
					<paragraph id="H6E236D3110144044B816F9815D80F1DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Increased availability and use</header>
 <subparagraph id="H466A5978D4E74FA0A2CC55CA9A273156"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall maximize the availability of opioid receptor antagonists approved by the Food and Drug Administration, including naloxone, to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4B8F11D103B47ADAC02617B13EC6FEE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability, training, and distributing</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="HF0ED223792164EA1916CFC595397E427"><enum>(i)</enum><text>equip each pharmacy of the Department with opioid receptor antagonists approved by the Food and Drug Administration to be dispensed to outpatients as needed; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2FD9AF36F3A49CFB85078C92448620B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expand the Overdose Education and Naloxone Distribution program of the Department to ensure that all veterans in receipt of health care under laws administered by the Secretary who are at risk of opioid overdose may access such opioid receptor antagonists and training on the proper administration of such opioid receptor antagonists.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2474D6F2090D4A7789B2C0E44941D379"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Veterans who are at risk</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B), veterans who are at risk of opioid overdose include—</text> <clause id="H3C78952C0755460DBC0949DAC212BB12"><enum>(i)</enum><text>veterans receiving long-term opioid therapy;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H733D92822E3A4BE6A75B9477DC6E8110"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>veterans receiving opioid therapy who have a history of substance use disorder or prior instances of overdose; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0121B19A928A4E3FABEEC6EB735E2E6A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>veterans who are at risk as determined by a health care provider who is treating the veteran.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA10BBAEAEA54D64B4DD1DD1FED4AA8D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on carrying out paragraph (1), including an assessment of any remaining steps to be carried out by the Secretary to carry out such paragraph.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B867B4846B04677BD4DB62892A6FB84"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain information and capabilities in opioid therapy risk report tool of the
			 Department</header>
 <paragraph id="H35276E741F9D4FEC91C7B466E4D7563D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department—</text> <subparagraph id="HB95256FCBFD3408A94DC91DDBA4AEF58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on the most recent time the tool was accessed by a health care provider of the Department with respect to each veteran; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49FCDF363260411A94355CAC7AA6B077"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on the results of the most recent urine drug test for each veteran.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66474230CA3A4869856C911F4C5F9697"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Capabilities</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool the ability of the health care providers of the Department to determine whether a health care provider of the Department prescribed opioids to a veteran without checking the information in the tool with respect to the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0451625939141879A784DD6994D6B10"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Notifications of risk in computerized health record</header><text>The Secretary shall modify the computerized patient record system of the Department to ensure that any health care provider that accesses the record of a veteran, regardless of the reason the veteran seeks care from the health care provider, will be immediately notified whether the veteran—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA8FC57E38C4244D6830226BD5E4B922D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is receiving opioid therapy and has a history of substance use disorder or prior instances of overdose;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H717FECB818FB418185108244827BA078"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has a history of opioid abuse; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H48CF51A181774C71B08B33FA1B6F8CDC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is at risk of becoming an opioid abuser as determined by a health care provider who is treating the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCA83122AD7E47169C24B87A238969D3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFF8828ED83684A70A7D8D7C51C7539B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>controlled substance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87EE8BC4CFF44027A9DBFF0CC886FD37"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, territories, and possessions of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBFB45EFAA83E4B3FBE090F7D8D86E503"><enum>103.</enum><header>Strengthening of joint working group on pain management of the Department of Veterans Affairs and
			 the Department of Defense</header>
 <subsection id="H29D0F976D4794AD09238048742F68636"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the Pain Management Working Group of the Health Executive Committee of the Department of Veterans Affairs–Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee established under section 320 of title 38, United States Code, includes a focus on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HAAEA9D7FCDC04401BCF550D481E40763"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The opioid prescribing practices of health care providers of each Department.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3F45FF0D214F3195645F7954FC96E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The ability of each Department to manage acute and chronic pain among individuals receiving health care from the Department, including training health care providers with respect to pain management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2FD4DE9DF964C4DA0C3DB9884AC4BAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The use by each Department of complementary and integrative health and complementary alternative medicines in treating such individuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD24FF821826E44BEAFC0629BAC9E8D78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The concurrent use by health care providers of each Department of opioids and prescription drugs to treat mental health disorders, including benzodiazepines.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67C1014A6F8A46C1B148B8772E813CAF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The practice by health care providers of each Department of prescribing opioids to treat mental health disorders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CB91435627747C791D5496D53C824EB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The coordination in coverage of and consistent access to medications prescribed for patients transitioning from receiving health care from the Department of Defense to receiving health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C21F6090A5D46C6A5330B662AE4CFE2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The ability of each Department to identify and treat substance use disorders among individuals receiving health care from that Department.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97A3C177DF17473DB12A6B8B08FC899A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination and consultation</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the working group described in subsection (a)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6DDF6C3679C44DF1ADDACA611EE722C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinates the activities of the working group with other relevant working groups established under section 320 of title 38, United States Code, including the working groups on evidence-based practice, patient safety, pharmacy, psychological health, and psychological health;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDB78D6BB4E2446BA3D66D54A60DE4E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consults with other relevant Federal agencies, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, with respect to the activities of the working group; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF063AEF13FC94355AD204C624187A6CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consults with the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense with respect to, reviews, and comments on the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain, or any successor guideline, before any update to the guideline is released.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA55747376D694BA58143429689DFEE56"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the working group described in subsection (a) is able to meaningfully consult with respect to the updated guideline required under subsection (a) of section 101, as required by subsection (b) of such section, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H619B1907915E44B59B02B1525FB30783"><enum>104.</enum><header>Review, investigation, and report on use of opioids in treatment by Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
				<subsection id="HFC7AB0DE18644C07AB3F26DA018E8C07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Comptroller general report</header>
 <paragraph id="H136EC36FDB384862ACDE62D2BC352D59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the opioid prescribing practices of health care providers of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF5704CCEACE40AE8AC4480D8F64DF74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H8E9947286C7C4C4DA6465E3AD9B8444D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Recommendations on such improvements to the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department as the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE00C3003D684460B1D3C2F703D30912"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information with respect to—</text> <clause id="HFBA3655F7D4E4F678D26DCF5B81F7531"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deaths resulting from sentinel events involving veterans prescribed opioids by a health care provider of the Department;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H08E674D742BD4A0891DA3FB6A566132E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>overall prescription rates and prescriptions indications of opioids to treat non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5D153C051A3D4CFCB74C023C36FE7D79"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the prescription rates and prescriptions indications of benzodiazepines and opioids concomitantly by health care providers of the Department;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9CBD829E30B04F22B9B117BD7A3FD26C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the practice by health care providers of the Department of prescribing opioids to treat patients without any pain, including to treat patients with mental health disorders other than opioid use disorder; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7D778660721A433DAAAB304A07EF0BDF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the effectiveness of opioid therapy for patients receiving such therapy, including the effectiveness of long-term opioid therapy.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H571E3BA2F45F43B48E9E1D4FF6635DD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of processes of the Department in place to oversee opioid use among veterans, including procedures to identify and remedy potential over-prescribing of opioids by health care providers of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0701715494B44117B0B619FFA80B5CCC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the implementation by the Secretary of the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DEB841745CC46798FFECD5289B6E8CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quarterly progress report on implementation of comptroller general recommendations</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than 30 days after the end of each quarter thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a progress report detailing the actions by the Secretary during the period covered by the report to address any outstanding findings and recommendations by the Comptroller General of the United States under subsection (a) with respect to the Veterans Health Administration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCE6385188C4F42298E4C5B8CC8BFDD98"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual review of prescription rates</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually for the following five years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report, with respect to each medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to collect and review information on opioids prescribed by health care providers at the facility to treat non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients that contains, for the one-year period preceding the submission of the report, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF42F7F2EBF8148DB86FFD3B94E28C7C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of patients and the percentage of the patient population of the Department who were prescribed benzodiazepines and opioids concurrently by a health care provider of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1626B2B90C3744718B26F6FCE276E36B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of patients and the percentage of the patient population of the Department without any pain who were prescribed opioids by a health care provider of the Department, including those who were prescribed benzodiazepines and opioids concurrently.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E6472A0779A4C3AA4787FCF1B441059"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients and the percentage of such patients who were treated with opioids by a health care provider of the Department on an inpatient-basis and who also received prescription opioids by mail from the Department while being treated on an inpatient-basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD4932E0E5244547BA0A4FB25A48B9EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients and the percentage of such patients who were prescribed opioids concurrently by a health care provider of the Department and a health care provider that is not health care provider of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64E17D330313431395574BC41CF606DC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>With respect to each medical facility of the Department, information on opioids prescribed by health care providers at the facility to treat non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients, including information on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9109DB6EE7F74CA69CA003B2B372D0E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the prescription rate at which each health care provider at the facility prescribed benzodiazepines and opioids concurrently to such patients and the aggregate such prescription rate for all health care providers at the facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H055499AE0E3A4E96B2EE280696936D31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the prescription rate at which each health care provider at the facility prescribed benzodiazepines or opioids to such patients to treat conditions for which benzodiazepines or opioids are not approved treatment and the aggregate such prescription rate for all health care providers at the facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82AFDD25EB0A47CB86D9CDBD7030E625"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the prescription rate at which each health care provider at the facility prescribed or dispensed mail-order prescriptions of opioids to such patients while such patients were being treated with opioids on an inpatient-basis and the aggregate of such prescription rate for all health care providers at the facility; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4AF165A9C0540C696141F290300F16D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the prescription rate at which each health care provider at the facility prescribed opioids to such patients who were also concurrently prescribed opioids by a health care provider that is not a health care provider of the Department and the aggregate of such prescription rates for all health care providers at the facility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE017BAB61449398E8248E2BFA13A26"><enum>(6)</enum><text>With respect to each medical facility of the Department, the number of times a pharmacist at the facility overrode a critical drug interaction warning with respect to an interaction between opioids and another medication before dispensing such medication to a veteran.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H876146D68A8148D682B141E0012299C1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Investigation of prescription rates</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a prescription rate with respect to a health care provider or medical facility of the Department conflicts with or is otherwise inconsistent with the standards of appropriate and safe care, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H180DBE1DCAB54BB9B2854B8C87E6DC3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediately notify the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives of such determination, including information relating to such determination, prescription rate, and health care provider or medical facility, as the case may be; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D0EAD3471B04A35ABCCE60CD29FA393"><enum>(2)</enum><text>through the Office of the Medical Inspector of the Veterans Health Administration, conduct a full investigation of the health care provider or medical facility, as the case may be.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF77D403567F64E79AFFC8F3B4D84251E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prescription rate defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>prescription rate</term> means, with respect to a health care provider or medical facility of the Department, each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE0EDB395ED544A9891A582CFBC86181F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of patients treated with opioids by the health care provider or at the medical facility, as the case may be, divided by the total number of pharmacy users of that health care provider or medical facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H272C40E8D969462594EF81112A4CE0F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The average number of morphine equivalents per day prescribed by the health care provider or at the medical facility, as the case may be, to patients being treated with opioids.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B68E1735392425390AD30CD8996AC4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Of the patients being treated with opioids by the health care provider or at the medical facility, as the case may be, the average number of prescriptions of opioids per patient.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HEDD9E8E4DCBE4E669B444F758984A73F"><enum>II</enum><header>Patient Advocacy</header>
			<section id="H5092A0B7503B476AB4499597D74B707A"><enum>201.</enum><header>Community meetings on improving care furnished by Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
				<subsection id="HCA9989049DD1475E9F88728CFA6EB50F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Community meetings</header>
 <paragraph id="H7C92E941A7F84CC9A3EF783C0D339B04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medical centers</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary shall ensure that each medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs hosts a community meeting open to the public on improving health care furnished by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E1D82B04E924D3E9A9035E9D335FD88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community based outpatient clinics</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary shall ensure that each community based outpatient clinic of the Department hosts a community meeting open to the public on improving health care furnished by the Secretary.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74B2379E37EA49749B4DFC450DCDFAF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attendance by Director of veterans integrated service network or designee</header>
 <paragraph id="H9A7BDB8CA78B44AC8EF2B9B996BB1855"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each community meeting hosted by a medical facility or community based outpatient clinic under subsection (a) shall be attended by the Director of the Veterans Integrated Service Network in which the medical facility or community based outpatient clinic, as the case may be, is located. Subject to paragraph (2), the Director may delegate such attendance only to an employee who works in the Office of the Director.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A45765CD4484EC98030EE09195B83AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attendance by director</header><text>Each Director of a Veterans Integrated Service Network shall personally attend not less than one community meeting under subsection (a) hosted by each medical facility located in the Veterans Integrated Service Network each year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EEF947A794744A0A74961B1333112F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall notify the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives, and each Member of Congress (as defined in section 104) who represents the area in which the medical facility is located of a community meeting under subsection (a) by not later than 10 days before such community meeting occurs.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H85567A2879084023BA05FAD60B2BB355"><enum>202.</enum><header>Improvement of awareness of patient advocacy program and patient bill of rights of Department of
 Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in as many prominent locations as the Secretary determines appropriate to be seen by the largest percentage of patients and family members of patients at each medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE5292EF4D8154B93BA330A6A5FABEC70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>display the purposes of the Patient Advocacy Program of the Department and the contact information for the patient advocate at such medical facility; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8855A9BFD388408682AFAE9D2715E86D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>display the rights and responsibilities of—</text> <subparagraph id="H740F7FD0E3ED4C78BAB2D7C6CDEFF086"><enum>(A)</enum><text>patients and family members and patients at such medical facility; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE60F9A475604C088597D5ECD726BA19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to community living centers and other residential facilities of the Department, residents and family members of residents at such medical facility.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H9ABA397CBD604CAF98C5DF16CB0953E8"><enum>203.</enum><header>Comptroller general report on patient advocacy program of Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="H573D10D70E324B7583B3159DF0F17F93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the Patient Advocacy Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE0B96DF06F3344009B102F7123E919E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H3485E2C174DC44028DEADFA75F6E3076"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the Program, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H624A3481A56A4225AE4A7814532648BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purpose of the Program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97DC7B3D38ED4E1FBF6EA54AAF014122"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the activities carried out under the Program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BFA8ECC14A944B0956FD05830EBDBB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the sufficiency of the Program in achieving the purpose of the Program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFD2281F1C194981AFF6A4180B2D6044"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the sufficiency of staffing of employees of the Department responsible for carrying out the Program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B493CD4849C48EDA42DC95F4F5C27CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the sufficiency of the training of such employees.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1CE065B5966422B95F270E0023BBC3C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2A20D394634F4178AAD4A92DDA2194B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the awareness of the Program among veterans and family members of veterans; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D423ED8AA734278A58BE46962EFE5D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of the Program by veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H61899503E0F3426ABE94B1D97D4CBE36"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Such recommendations and proposals for improving or modifying the Program as the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15ADDAF005CD4AA1AE2C699DCEF8212D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Such other information with respect to the Program as the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H6D67A0DCBE9743CE8653B8B6F3166C8C"><enum>III</enum><header>Complementary and Integrative Health</header>
			<section id="H8C65F856FC40492188E9ECF511CBDCB3"><enum>301.</enum><header>Expansion of research and education on and delivery of complementary and integrative health to
			 veterans</header>
 <subsection id="H8260275A95DA4EB28900615C086266D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a commission to be known as the <quote>Creating Options for Veterans’ Expedited Recovery</quote> or the <quote>COVER Commission</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>). The Commission shall examine the evidence-based therapy treatment model used by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for treating mental health conditions of veterans and the potential benefits of incorporating complementary alternative treatments available in non-Department facilities (as defined in section 1701 of title 38, United States Code).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H85343447B5104710A9B93A3F96CE6434"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Commission shall perform the following duties:</text> <paragraph id="H219E74B3253042D5A7756047C727E8A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Examine the efficacy of the evidence-based therapy model used by the Secretary for treating mental health illnesses of veterans and identify areas to improve wellness-based outcomes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FAB423A87BB4217B18CD45CCC143817"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Conduct a patient-centered survey within each of the Veterans Integrated Service Networks to examine—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFE203A6A69004D55961C7D1A060205ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the experience of veterans with the Department of Veterans Affairs when seeking medical assistance for mental health issues through the health care system of the Department;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B1EDAD057AA4A069C1A6F42FE7E5607"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the experience of veterans with non-Department facilities and health professionals for treating mental health issues;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDCC99BE9FB14A7AA4B8A7FE1D78E375"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the preference of veterans regarding available treatment for mental health issues and which methods the veterans believe to be most effective;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA17E263032E48F08248F1137E6F1FF6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the experience, if any, of veterans with respect to the complementary alternative treatment therapies described in paragraph (3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ABD51E0E245483A9731FB664FA5C38F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the prevalence of prescribing prescription medication among veterans seeking treatment through the health care system of the Department as remedies for addressing mental health issues; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A79A5CEA6644D579B82AD456CA6FFE5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the outreach efforts of the Secretary regarding the availability of benefits and treatments for veterans for addressing mental health issues, including by identifying ways to reduce barriers to gaps in such benefits and treatments.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2093F204B6D400E8AD1C273C79732ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Examine available research on complementary alternative treatment therapies for mental health issues and identify what benefits could be made with the inclusion of such treatments for veterans, including with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H093094BB9F5944C0AAED2B8E32B2B233"><enum>(A)</enum><text>music therapy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30711C862756455794BFD7A319D049F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equine therapy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96A9B9D48F9A4BB0AAB3AFFBACBF8914"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training and caring for service dogs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F6F3210F4B843A5804FDEA3801D5E20"><enum>(D)</enum><text>yoga therapy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB6BB783FBDD44668F4CF7D4A53E9320"><enum>(E)</enum><text>acupuncture therapy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB8F2ADF31D04A459EFD605C46E967DB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>meditation therapy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1576DADE96AE49798CDAA6969460FDB0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>outdoor sports therapy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB957B62F14734618B2DAD768D9D4B825"><enum>(H)</enum><text>hyperbaric oxygen therapy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6561797BD06487E8A9562D9EDFC3530"><enum>(I)</enum><text>accelerated resolution therapy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H242458EB6B724C60BB5968382429AD29"><enum>(J)</enum><text>art therapy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF644FDC7EAD4A5D9BEED2BDDC2E5C1E"><enum>(K)</enum><text>magnetic resonance therapy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CF6BF6E1B6A4204AD539B277051DFD9"><enum>(L)</enum><text>other therapies the Commission determines appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE14BD36DA58F42549B1D248D80A0F456"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Study the sufficiency of the resources of the Department to ensure the delivery of quality health care for mental health issues among veterans seeking treatment within the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H820AC4EC32D14C239552AE38D31E07C7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Study the current treatments and resources available within the Department and assess—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA10D7CA31794D07ADC92A3394D83491"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of such treatments and resources in decreasing the number of suicides per day by veterans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19450DE913364DEFBD8C2106CB64997A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of veterans who have been diagnosed with mental health issues;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97632E05C9564E18B05302B14D71EDF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of veterans using the resources of the Department who have been diagnosed with mental health issues;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0FEF4F76FB44ACCB43DA65EADB7CFCD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the percentage of veterans who have completed counseling sessions offered by the Department; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85B2469D8D25403A8A72E357053B95BB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the efforts of the Department to expand complementary alternative treatments viable to the recovery of veterans with mental health issues as determined by the Secretary to improve the effectiveness of treatments offered with the Department.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2045FE8200641C5BF5D8EA48053EF15"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="HCE24580C94A84541A818581D4392C9D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 10 members, appointed as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H397B3EE54B29429AB5B6C5F13EABB368"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDDB739F3CC14398BF0CE4A81D5C131D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57A679B1A257474C96C4C4D3A8229371"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2CEE08898FD4DCA910D2E1423A4146C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F996A07D4024F85AB184A33738AB22D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Two members appointed by the President, at least one of whom shall be a veteran.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A873FE2A2424C1BB8DE25B2BB218250"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Members of the Commission shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H62C55F2BB2BA418E84BE34955783C6B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals who are of recognized standing and distinction within the medical community with a background in treating mental health;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF77CE9880884F2C998211443C0AF848"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals with experience working with the military and veteran population; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EF5DF1D86FD4A35AF49AC038A52F869"><enum>(C)</enum><text>individuals who do not have a financial interest in any of the complementary alternative treatments reviewed by the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2805FC44FB08446589530C28BC792AEB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairman</header><text>The President shall designate a member of the Commission to be the Chairman.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D0CE38D05524B4AB75D504DC512C017"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Period of appointment</header><text>Members of the Commission shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF871D7F05A04457DADD15D30BED2B8A4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69142EC11E834AA1A2BC82CD6F82BE0E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Appointment deadline</header><text>The appointment of members of the Commission in this section shall be made not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFA2F014BF8849E09A53CCFA425709A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Powers of commission</header>
					<paragraph id="H62413D74D3A4478BB4801FDBBF3F1509"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7C63CA9F718F4646A5809D0B28A79C3D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Commission shall hold its first meeting not later than 30 days after a majority of members are appointed to the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H286EEF53330C4EBCAC61FE87DDA587C8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Meeting</header><text>The Commission shall regularly meet at the call of the Chairman. Such meetings may be carried out through the use of telephonic or other appropriate telecommunication technology if the Commission determines that such technology will allow the members to communicate simultaneously.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EBDB4878ACE490A9E483F66CDD0761D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Commission may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out the responsibilities of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4800F59CC540494F9D331CA8CFE267DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information from federal agencies</header><text>The Commission may secure directly from any department or agency of the Federal Government such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out the duties of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8089030C17D84103ADAEEF7D5B0D7B12"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information from nongovernmental organizations</header><text>In carrying out its duties, the Commission may seek guidance through consultation with foundations, veteran service organizations, nonprofit groups, faith-based organizations, private and public institutions of higher education, and other organizations as the Commission determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92349145197042CF9BF8075B69E8E481"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Commission records</header><text>The Commission shall keep an accurate and complete record of the actions and meeting of the Commission. Such record shall be made available for public inspection and the Comptroller General of the United States may audit and examine such record.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5B434D0B36C4810A2921160543F9A01"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Personnel records</header><text>The Commission shall keep an accurate and complete record of the actions and meetings of the Commission. Such record shall be made available for public inspection and the Comptroller General of the United States may audit and examine such records.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE76D3D4BED70483599D217EDA6948539"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Compensation of members; travel expenses</header><text>Each member shall serve without pay but shall receive travel expenses to perform the duties of the Commission, including per diem in lieu of substances, at rates authorized under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3967D4562B143249097E3B97230D6A8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Chairman, in accordance with rules agreed upon the Commission, may appoint fix the compensation of a staff director and such other personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its functions, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, without regard to the provision of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that no rate of pay fixed under this paragraph may exceed the equivalent of that payable for a position at a level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H3A4B048F06EF493E8A2407605735BD29"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Personnel as federal employees</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4D8D4E1965214EB69F03D2A429815B3E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The executive director and any personnel of the Commission are employees under section 2105 of title 5, United States Code, for purpose of chapters 63, 81, 83, 84, 85, 87, 89, and 90 of such title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7CD688BC4AF40FA917241946B2C7AF6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Members of the commission</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to apply to members of the Commission.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF08AD08ECD44AD09176763E06263CAD"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Contracting</header><text>The Commission may, to such extent and in such amounts as are provided in appropriations Acts, enter into contracts to enable the Commission to discharge the duties of the Commission under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8B9D90CCDCD4A95907A1EBE1C510EFD"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Expert and consultant service</header><text>The Commission may procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with section 3109 or title 5, United States Code, at rates not to exceed the daily rate paid to a person occupying a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 3109 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EABEBD9DE1F410CBD66C7F0D19EEFCF"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Postal service</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as departments and agencies of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2630D33AA44B4A6CA7B25C66CC207468"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Physical facilities and equipment</header><text>Upon the request of the Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Commission to carry out its responsibilities under this Act. These administrative services may include human resource management, budget, leasing accounting, and payroll services.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F2C6EB369824FB0B0BFAFDF950BDF47"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header>
					<paragraph id="HD26D327C08E440FC993544A6C73D2201"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCF211BB915DC4E4EAC931DF503D2DB69"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Commission first meets, and each 30-day period thereafter ending on the date on which the Commission submits the final report under paragraph (2), the Commission shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate and the President a report detailing the level of cooperation the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (and the heads of other departments or agencies of the Federal Government) has provided to the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FE2D10F1F064DA098DAEDC3EBBAE12E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other reports</header><text>In carrying out its duties, at times that the Commission determines appropriate, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate and any other appropriate entities an interim report with respect to the findings identified by the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7227CCC4D064408B90651E72127A16A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the first meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the President, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs a final report on the findings of the Commission. Such report shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H782D031EED4E4386AF1FF6F26BC380CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Recommendations to implement in a feasible, timely, and cost efficient manner the solutions and remedies identified within the findings of the Commission pursuant to subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5911773B0BE142CFAA0083D4AFD19C86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the evidence-based therapy model used by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for treating veterans with mental health care issues, and an examination of the prevalence and efficacy of prescription drugs as a means for treatment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84E1CD81E007435085D22D25CB5DEC68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The findings of the patient-centered survey conducted within each of the Veterans Integrated Service Networks pursuant to subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D1682942F444788AF7BD6A22DC62AB3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An examination of complementary alternative treatments described in subsection (b)(3) and the potential benefits of incorporating such treatments in the therapy models used by the Secretary for treating veterans with mental health issues.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H929855F399A74C9C87EFF8D86D325AA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Commission submits the final report under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H797CB03DC8664B35A5770680DC3E2A18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An action plan for implementing the recommendations established by the Commission on such solutions and remedies for improving wellness-based outcomes for veterans with mental health care issues.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H061E522E11B94664B37759917025DDB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A feasible timeframe on when the complementary alternative treatments described in subsection (b)(3) can be implemented Departmentwide.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CDED65DF40B474EADE87003F925F0E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to each recommendation established by the Commission, including any complementary alternative treatment, that the Secretary determines is not appropriate or feasible to implement, a justification for such determination and an alternative solution to improve the efficacy of the therapy models used by the Secretary for treating veterans with mental health issues.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H293222394A274BAD9A09BF6F2E0A7817"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination of commission</header><text>The Commission shall terminate 30 days after the Commission submits the final report under subsection (e)(2).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H589F2704155A421EB4C6A50A065F700E"><enum>302.</enum><header>Pilot program on integration of complementary alternative medicines and related issues for veterans
			 and family members of veterans</header>
				<subsection id="H9A25371BE7CF4AAAAEEAB99630C9FA39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header>
 <paragraph id="HB79445A03CCC437BB841AF3849B3DFDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs receives the final report under section 301(e), the Secretary shall commence a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of using wellness-based programs (as defined by the Secretary) to complement the provision of pain management and related health care services, including mental health care services, to veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB196D31C25284E11A64D42E770EC6AA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters addressed</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall assess the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H502F69241F764E8FAA3204D2022EB264"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Means of improving coordination between Federal, State, local, and community providers of health care in the provision of pain management and related health care services to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6204CD4D62D14961A0696C135D6F75FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Means of enhancing outreach, and coordination of outreach, by and among providers of health care referred to in subparagraph (A) on the pain management and related health care services available to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BC7AE8F8A75491BB4D45C8F96421001"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Means of using wellness-based programs of providers of health care referred to in subparagraph (A) as complements to the provision by the Department of pain management and related health care services to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5446FF96B1634666800C94855FD0BDAE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether wellness-based programs described in subparagraph (C)—</text> <clause id="H2405BDD425204A918553DF29ADB1138C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are effective in enhancing the quality of life and well-being of veterans;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H24792722826A47808B39CA288BACADE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are effective in increasing the adherence of veterans to the primary pain management and related health care services provided such veterans by the Department;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H61D8C24752FA439F86F8251ADD3714DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have an effect on the sense of well-being of veterans who receive primary pain management and related health care services from the Department; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H40E75B37FC5B44FEAF72B1F5663079EF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are effective in encouraging veterans receiving health care from the Department to adopt a more healthy lifestyle.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3DE22FA2BA2423FB5DD923A5E4A6AD2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a)(1) for a period of three years.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H1EE0606E5E714C8A9DE708D331874DE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Locations</header>
 <paragraph id="H8C4947F6E93D4717A7BEF635684E03DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a)(1) at facilities of the Department providing pain management and related health care services, including mental health care services, to veterans. In selecting such facilities to carry out the pilot program, the Secretary shall select not fewer than 15 medical centers of the Department, of which not fewer than two shall be polytrauma rehabilitation centers of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41B4294A3F0B4F7C8663815523D93262"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medical centers with prescription rates of opioids that conflict with care standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting the medical centers under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give priority to medical centers of the Department at which there is a prescription rate of opioids that conflicts with or is otherwise inconsistent with the standards of appropriate and safe care.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42F6B5D3C0844C6E83D5838E5F96C89B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Provision of services</header><text>Under the pilot program under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall provide covered services to covered veterans by integrating complementary and alternative medicines and integrative health services with other services provided by the Department at the medical centers selected under subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H27E9A1ADC70246C8B9155DB34914D98E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered veterans</header><text>For purposes of the pilot program under subsection (a)(1), a covered veteran is any veteran who—</text> <paragraph id="H348A240F5DD4451EABC06ED548E67940"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a mental health condition diagnosed by a clinician of the Department;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BDB1AEA697746CB85C4A983DC9543EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experiences chronic pain;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFF7017CD1564199BCF8D66A1124FEB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has a chronic condition being treated by a clinician of the Department; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DBC59E40CA645709A9C79320C309B2B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is not described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) and requests to participate in the pilot program or is referred by a clinician of the Department who is treating the veteran.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27B7DE9DC0394C05BF7B9D8AF5129C49"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered services</header>
 <paragraph id="H200B46C2CF78482DBA144EF65B78DBE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of the pilot program, covered services are services consisting of complementary and integrative health services as selected by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE190FBD4B8942A4826EEE6EA49C79DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of services</header><text>Covered services shall be administered under the pilot program as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="HF7F974814D6746F0B7966D1E7765ED45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Covered services shall be administered by professionals or other instructors with appropriate training and expertise in complementary and integrative health services who are employees of the Department or with whom the Department enters into an agreement to provide such services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50C63BB0DB434F7FACE0B435B00FF8E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered services shall be included as part of the Patient Aligned Care Teams initiative of the Office of Patient Care Services, Primary Care Program Office, in coordination with the Office of Patient Centered Care and Cultural Transformation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD532CEA55B846C4858CC869B1F5C80E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Covered services shall be made available to—</text> <clause id="H0281823064174BE1910A1886566147EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>covered veterans who have received conventional treatments from the Department for the conditions for which the covered veteran seeks complementary and integrative health services under the pilot program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE155A34B65E34E47B5DB334751D7BFEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>covered veterans who have not received conventional treatments from the Department for such conditions.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDBAA3B61698540B383CC99943B959667"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H1F6899E87CD04B7682F8541E62D48773"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date on which the Secretary commences the pilot program under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5169651E9C944E328BB8DDB952D7BBB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H153EA53466494D1BA9782CD42CFF537F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The findings and conclusions of the Secretary with respect to the pilot program under subsection (a)(1), including with respect to—</text>
 <clause id="H7A290EB1C8164F05A654BC19538FC81C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use and efficacy of the complementary and integrative health services established under the pilot program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB7560DD642E84CD1B9919BACB7B480BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the outreach conducted by the Secretary to inform veterans and community organizations about the pilot program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8041C670384E4B098A2B83463A0863DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an assessment of the benefit of the pilot program to covered veterans in mental health diagnoses, pain management, and treatment of chronic illness.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H725AD70463C7483BB56B2127C937A80E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identification of any unresolved barriers that impede the ability of the Secretary to incorporate complementary and integrative health services with other health care services provided by the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H163BA3B607FA44F49B73FB20514875DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such recommendations for the continuation or expansion of the pilot program as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C04DAD94B6A467DA3727B14F7083321"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Complementary and integrative health defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>complementary and integrative health</term> shall have the meaning given that term by the National Institutes of Health.</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="HBD0D861AACB74C5C812657C591F4E6DC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Fitness of Health Care Providers</header> <section id="H19F1F91A7536473C8CD02FFE9CD373DA"><enum>401.</enum><header>Additional requirements for hiring of health care providers by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As part of the hiring process for each health care provider considered for a position at the Department of Veterans Affairs after the date of the enactment of the Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall require from the medical board of each State in which the health care provider has a medical license—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE35FD5F057FC4C798FB300195735D07A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on any violation of the requirements of the medical license of the health care provider during the 20-year period preceding the consideration of the health care provider by the Department; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E35DDBC8DBF41EDA88C4F0D1641FD27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on whether the health care provider has entered into any settlement agreement for the disciplinary charge relating to the practice of medicine by the health care provider.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="HA2FAF75B9BC04D4C84AD458C55C1812A"><enum>402.</enum><header>Provision of information on health care providers of Department of Veterans Affairs to State
			 Medical Boards</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 552a of title 5, United States Code, with respect to each health care provider of the Department of Veterans Affairs who has violated a requirement of the medical license of the health care provider, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to the medical board of each State in which the health care provider is licensed detailed information with respect to such violation, regardless of whether such board has formally requested such information.</text>
			</section><section id="HFCC8739B190442ACBBDAD953DAFA9C8E"><enum>403.</enum><header>Report on compliance by Department of Veterans Affairs with reviews of health care providers
 leaving the Department or transferring to other facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the compliance by the Department of Veterans Affairs with the policy of the Department—</text>
 <paragraph id="H22AF341B1545433F8C5E9B4D50A4D18D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conduct a review of each health care provider of the Department who transfers to another medical facility of the Department, retires, or is terminated to determine whether there are any concerns, complaints, or allegations of violations relating to the medical practice of the health care provider; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA44E6FECA73946E2A228DE85D164566E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to take appropriate action with respect to any such concern, complaint, or allegation.</text> </paragraph></section></title><title id="HF27B236725544F14B4CC0EF072B3F0BB"><enum>V</enum><header>Other Veterans Matters</header> <section id="HB4EAF7B0A60342818060A80A861C56C0"><enum>501.</enum><header>Audit of Veterans Health Administration programs of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HB4D59A7D228C44E78F12BE5C677BCD7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall seek to enter into a contract with a nongovernmental entity under which the entity shall conduct a audits of the programs of the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs to identify ways to improve the furnishing of benefits and health care administered by the Veterans Health Administration to veterans and families of veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5B2F781F279F4356B1AD03917E205A95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Audit requirements</header><text>In carrying out each audit under subsection (a), the entity shall perform the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA85B50798EA7419281A0D50DE0AAEBE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Five-year risk assessments to identify the functions, staff organizations, and staff offices of the Veterans Health Administration that would lead towards the greatest improvement in furnishing of benefits and health care to veterans and families of veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8B65015A5E045F3B33F3532AE2698F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Development of plans that are informed by the risk assessment under paragraph (1) to conduct audits of the functions, staff organizations, and staff offices identified under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7383C5C6ED6547A195806073F3D36AF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Conduct audits in accordance with the plans developed pursuant to paragraph (2).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43C9D95DE4FC4BF9843D51816F705A46"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which each audit is completed under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8E3616286CE842E3A02339FB330FB1B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the audit;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB1C0720072840A9A95C3CA62D9C3514"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the findings of the entity that conducted the audit with respect to the audit; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07E4AC689B114773B7950CDEDB20B52F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such recommendations as the Secretary determines appropriate for legislative or administrative action to improve the furnishing of benefits and health care to veterans and families of veterans.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


