<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H97C2B94A18194DE4BFFC329FAC16A0AC" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1749 IH: Smuggled Tobacco Prevention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1749</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150413">April 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000596">Mr. Pierluisi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce tobacco smuggling, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC0374902E9FA42DBAAD35ACAA821B370" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8B70E004C6F40C3BD587A0711FE9656" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H58099A89C6D04991B37A956668863E45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Smuggled Tobacco Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7FC123D696A3486C8D026A616A8D66C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="HA8B70E004C6F40C3BD587A0711FE9656" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBD0794017EE54BBA9D3E7E2729CB74DA" level="title">TITLE I—Amendments to Internal Revenue Code of 1986</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H068702C23ABA4C95BEA415CA388B805F" level="section">Sec. 101. Amendment of 1986 code.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE10645B504FF4C5995EA3A5C194F6125" level="section">Sec. 102. Machines used to manufacture or package tobacco products or processed tobacco.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H45FAF46AFEE34FBCB698CA32A7480021" level="section">Sec. 103. Improved marking and labeling.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA72096F3F5B945F48764AD0E0C38C60D" level="section">Sec. 104. Wholesalers and manufacturers, importers, and sellers of tobacco production machines
			 required to have permit.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3F076BE4F45D4B289876C0FB8FF62977" level="section">Sec. 105. Conditions of permit.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF514482AF68547219C0BC1E400D3E6EE" level="section">Sec. 106. Records to be maintained.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H62FE067894EE4EEDA081AEB0423FABE6" level="section">Sec. 107. Reports.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H434F4B8B956441348C2B8CC60FBA2608" level="section">Sec. 108. Fraudulent offenses.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6E78BE6B14BE42E48737EF7919771DCA" level="section">Sec. 109. Penalties.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H59901978326F484A89DC2364B25EA9E9" level="section">Sec. 110. Coordination with other government officials.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H53FB7AC632394E3A8F305C352E328353" level="section">Sec. 111. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3B4B4B404F464D47985C5087C8891E82" level="section">Sec. 112. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H93BED52B63E7495286489E3122C61956" level="section">Sec. 113. Effective date.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6FFDD477AF734D788A5116E354E87032" level="title">TITLE II—Import Fraud</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF169166374F547CDA83C7548D9C73309" level="section">Sec. 201. Maximum penalty for importation of tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes by
			 fraudulent means.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7C82F252A489421B87712C6A7586997D" level="title">TITLE III—Exclusions regarding Indian Tribes and Tribal matters</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA6773C75EB614BE5A59CCDCB7908C7E6" level="section">Sec. 301. Exclusions regarding Indian Tribes and Tribal matters.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><title id="HBD0794017EE54BBA9D3E7E2729CB74DA"><enum>I</enum><header>Amendments to Internal Revenue Code of 1986</header>
 <section id="H068702C23ABA4C95BEA415CA388B805F"><enum>101.</enum><header>Amendment of 1986 code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this title an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
			</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE10645B504FF4C5995EA3A5C194F6125"><enum>102.</enum><header>Machines used to manufacture or package tobacco products or processed tobacco</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C1F900779F2483ABFD9681020BC84DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5762">Section 5762</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H77FD50AE9EEF431B826B55783576A285"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c), and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E69C9BF395742F1B0CF99488439E097"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77726197794E4D9E84A9B60ECBA67404" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H36C3D0C1ABC040758817BCD2C27BD175"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Machines used To manufacture or package tobacco products or processed tobacco</header> <paragraph id="H6CC020CE2963494E9438154F27FBCFD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transfer of manufacturing machines to licensed persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any tobacco production machine may be sold, leased, imported, exported, delivered, or otherwise made available only to persons—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE46F355737464A3A882128CC3801A8BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lawfully engaged in—</text> <clause id="HBDC3941B3AD14A76A3072ADA1603FA60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sale, lease, importation, exportation, or delivery of such machines,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H99E337C77F974517982E061FF643323C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the manufacture or packaging of tobacco products or processed tobacco, or</text> </clause><clause id="HE9DDCD54FC20497F88C4337F220162B9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application of unique identification markings onto tobacco product or processed tobacco packages pursuant to section 5723, and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3E104C4400F4D30AC99B99EE494BA0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that have all Federal, State, local, and Indian tribal government permits, registrations, and licenses required to engage in such activities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43E538823B5D42249108B5BC2A7CEA34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer of machines to persons engaged in illegal manufacture of contraband</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No tobacco production machine shall knowingly be manufactured for or be (directly or indirectly) sold, leased, imported, exported, delivered, or otherwise made available to any person engaged in the illegal manufacture, distribution, or sale of counterfeit or contraband tobacco products or processed tobacco, unique identification markings, or other tax-payment indicia.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HAD8E2BA0318C4109A7354BDE24C19FEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Registration of machines</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1FD7B677ECE14C7FBE08DD03A00B7191"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Every person having possession or custody of, or having control over, the installation of any tobacco production machine shall register such machine with the Secretary immediately on its being installed, by subscribing and filing with the Secretary a statement, in writing, setting forth the particular place where such machine is installed, the kind of machine and its capacity, the owner thereof, the owner’s place of residence, and the purpose for which the machine has been or is intended to be used.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BD81609626C4E9AB01E572F90406281"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, this paragraph shall not apply to any tobacco production machine not used or intended to be used—</text>
 <clause id="H1015501025334F669362987046359648"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the manufacture or production of cigarette or cigars, or to manufacture any other tobacco product or processed tobacco,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H29AC2A4CF6D94CD790A114937EC3A2DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to package any tobacco product or processed tobacco, or</text> </clause><clause id="H4A2BF83BCE494BD19F564A890D46F116"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to apply unique identification markings to any package.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9638A3AE80BB4A8EB00924C0A55BEF84"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Records</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0BE4E2D5D95841FC82423E9239476506"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person selling, leasing, importing, exporting, delivering, or otherwise making available a tobacco production machine shall maintain and keep records, as the Secretary prescribes by regulation, relating to any transfers of the machine, including the name, address, other contact information, and any permit, registration, or license number of the person receiving delivery of the machine, or to whom the machine is otherwise transferred, as the case may be.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DCC67A8D9B6455C8A571D034D8F57BA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>5-Year holding period for records</header><text>Any record required to be maintained and kept under subparagraph (A) shall be kept for the 5-year period beginning on the first date such record is required to be so maintained and kept.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H339F02B81CAA4498A76ECD4D7EA72004"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability of records</header><text>Such records shall be available for inspection by any internal revenue officer during business hours.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85EE15EA8E9E4E0AB2D1E9161615775D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text>An ordinary commercial record or invoice shall satisfy the requirements of this paragraph if such record or invoice contains all of the information required under subparagraph (A).</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H46B1B169931E439B981B91711AF6B6AA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Violations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1B42D49093EA470783D718572B4EDF09"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whoever knowingly violates paragraph (1), (2), or (3) shall, for each offense, be fined not more than $10,000 or an amount equal to 3 times the fair market value of the tobacco product machine involved (whichever is greater), or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89C756C87C1C4B8E959D6EC768524E7A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text>Whoever knowingly violates paragraph (4) shall, for each offense, be fined not more than $10,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4CCFABA10DB4B98A7CB31B6012D641E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tobacco production machine</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5702">Section 5702</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6FDB2B32B924DF2A84C3EB63FD413EA" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H8A6282CFFD7C4FC39C571E6970947BF0"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Tobacco production machine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tobacco production machine</term> means any machine (or component integral to the operation of such a machine) used to manufacture or package tobacco products or processed tobacco or to apply unique identification markings or other tax-payment indicia to packages of tobacco products or processed tobacco. Such term includes any machine used to produce tobacco products for compensation, lease, or hire, or otherwise used in a commercial setting.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1F395330236E48F3ADBC6B8375EF9B85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 5762 (as so redesignated) is amended by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (a) and (b)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HEDC4D920F2F14635AE8509B0D92AEACE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to transfers more than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H45FAF46AFEE34FBCB698CA32A7480021"><enum>103.</enum><header>Improved marking and labeling </header>
 <subsection id="HB10C5345588641BCB311FE4DE7FE535C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5723">section 5723</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF6757E169BF4573ABEEDA5A5927A007" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HF61E22F6D6824005A47F828BB0B72266"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Marks, labels, and notices</header> <paragraph id="H42E3A96B32E445D5A8723A1AE6BF2A1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), every package of tobacco products, processed tobacco, or cigarette papers or tubes shall, before removal, bear the marks, labels, and notices that the Secretary by regulation prescribes.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HA6069DBCD2294615953E562C5BB2BF5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Marking requirements for domestic market</header>
 <subparagraph id="H26F037CE3532431E95462454B778B1F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each person who is a manufacturer or importer of tobacco products or processed tobacco shall (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary) ensure that, before any product intended for sale or distribution within the United States is removed, a unique identification marking is affixed to or forms part of each package of tobacco product or processed tobacco manufactured or imported by such person for sale or distribution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8742948050D94C9680F657EA99FD5067"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Markings on individual packages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any markings required to be placed on a tobacco product or processed tobacco package by this subsection shall be placed on the innermost sealed container visible from the outside of the individual package. For any tobacco product or processed tobacco package that contains multiple smaller packages of tobacco products or processed tobacco, any markings required to be so placed on tobacco product or processed tobacco packages shall be placed on all the individual tobacco product or processed tobacco packages.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A4C39D2CE2A44F4A74442B3CA1E8037"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Markings on aggregate packing modes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To facilitate efficient tracking and tracing of tobacco products or processed tobacco through the distribution system, all manufacturers or importers of tobacco products or processed tobacco shall, in addition to such unique identification marking, also, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, ensure that unique identification markings are affixed to or form part of aggregate packing modes (such as cartons, cases, and master cases for cigarettes). The Secretary shall determine the size, location, and methods for such markings. The Secretary shall establish regulations requiring that all persons within the distribution chain, up to but not including the ultimate retailer, utilize the unique identification markings on aggregate packing modes to facilitate the tracking and tracing of tobacco products or processed tobacco through the distribution system.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H863CF7E26E214A95BAE3EBCC1FDEB1C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Marking requirements for exports</header><text>A unique identification marking shall be affixed to or form part of each package of tobacco product or processed tobacco that is exported, or sold for export, that distinguishes it from those products or processed tobacco intended for sale or distribution within the United States. The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe the size, location, and other characteristics of such marking, and it may contain a serial number that is assigned to the country of export, except that no such serial number shall be required on tobacco products or processed tobacco sold at retail to consumers by duty free stores for consumption beyond the jurisdiction of the internal revenue laws of the United States. Such tobacco products or processed tobacco shall instead bear markings indicating the tobacco product or processed tobacco is only for duty-free sale to consumers, as prescribed through regulation by the Secretary, before the product or processed tobacco is removed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2232B07B8B1640928662F76F61069350"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of federal unique identification marking</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Smuggled Tobacco Prevention Act of 2015</short-title>, the Secretary shall by regulation require the use of a unique identification marking on all products subject to tax under this chapter.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA8112AC4DDA34950A8754D8296E6482D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unique identification marking</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5723">Section 5723</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="HA61A4316C09D48CA943E229682AD6F78" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H69366DDAA1B14C3D9F6E4BF0EF61D51F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Unique identification marking</header> <paragraph id="H2C5FCE6D3BE44A2CAA2562677D9525CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No tobacco product or processed tobacco may be sold, offered for sale, distributed, mailed, or otherwise delivered for final sale to any consumer in the United States unless the unique identification marking that meets the requirements of this section (and any regulations prescribed thereunder) is affixed to or forms part of the package in which it is contained.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H1AB0EAD93CA54C399CDD5D6BD669E4DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>System specifications</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6EADFF284E9D4C889EE4F76A9D846334"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary shall design such system to coordinate and avoid interference with State, local, and Indian tribal tax stamps and markings, facilitate collection of the tax imposed by this chapter, impede contraband tobacco trafficking, minimize counterfeit marking, allow for more effective tracking and tracing of tobacco products and processed tobacco, facilitate the enforcement of related Federal laws, and utilize such available technology as may promote the purposes of this chapter.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B0A1A73E2BF4FD99CB912AFA33C6442"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall prescribe the method and manner in which such unique identification markings are to be distributed, purchased, and applied to or made part of tobacco product and processed tobacco packages, and may provide for the cancellation of such markings.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDFF75CD94244F2380FA922EA5A8698F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The unique identification marking must provide (through the marking or record associated with the marking) such information as the Secretary by regulation prescribes, including:</text>
 <clause id="H5B584A98A4E84E7D9F383423ABC0CD97"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A unique serial number or tracking code for each tobacco product or processed tobacco package or aggregate package.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4A87D83F903549D88F59BAB93B0CEB8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The name and address of the person purchasing the marking (and, if different, of the person ensuring the marking is affixed to or made part of the package).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H905C8EA218D241D58503C1C01D6FE422"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The name and address of the first unrelated person purchasing or otherwise receiving the tobacco product or processed tobacco from the person who ensures the marking is affixed to or made part of the package and the date of such purchase or receipt.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3479063FDA414D4299309BC8954AE8FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The information described in subparagraph (C) may be required to, to the extent practicable—</text> <clause id="H21AE7382960346F885C08751F2A3D164"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be cryptographically encrypted, and</text>
									</clause><clause id="H890675D687014F7D8A34741C52954934"><enum>(ii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H29ED0E3F63084A929ED0A67D4157CF7B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be readable by a portable scanning device (or similar device) to be utilized by regulatory and law enforcement officials at the time and place of inspection, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4DD05B851EEC4139A1B3A2EF42107BBD" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>be otherwise accessible remotely at such time and place.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H800DF7B5BB91472FBD8B6D4257A87071"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unrelated person</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>unrelated person</term> means a person other than a related person within the meaning of section 267(b) or 707(b)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2506BFB5A31149CA888253A6478DD276"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5723">Section 5723</external-xref>, as amended by subsection (b), is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H7026D7DF30174E40BD982D73E6027061" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H53ECDEAE7F8248CA90CA10AA49EAB7E9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Package defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>package</term> means a pack, box, carton, or container of any kind or, if no other container, any wrapping (including cellophane), in which a tobacco product or processed tobacco is sold, offered for sale, distributed, or otherwise delivered for final sale to any consumer.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H547DE5A592E1486095E5969E1CB60F80"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Unique identification marking defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>unique identification marking</term> means a device in such design and denomination as the Secretary authorizes by regulation that is affixed to or made part of a package of a tobacco product or processed tobacco. Such markings shall contain overt security features for public authentication and covert security features embedding a unique, secure, encrypted identifier onto the marking, enabling law enforcement authentication, production control, and tracking and tracing of the product or processed tobacco bearing the marking.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBBDC0181EA914A4EAE742F40E997D791"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of subsection (f), and paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (b), of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5723">section 5723</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HA72096F3F5B945F48764AD0E0C38C60D"><enum>104.</enum><header>Wholesalers and manufacturers, importers, and sellers of tobacco production machines required to
			 have permit</header>
 <subsection id="H0E96636D4436426E9C9A6DC69132DB74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Wholesalers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5712">Section 5712</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>, as a wholesaler,</quote> after <quote>or processed tobacco</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF92D08C4C8254E99ADF56B8D2BEEF6BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Manufacturers, importers, and sellers of tobacco production machines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5712">Section 5712</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>or as an export warehouse proprietor</quote> and inserting <quote>, as an export warehouse proprietor, or as a manufacturer, seller, or importer of tobacco production machines</quote>.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H3F076BE4F45D4B289876C0FB8FF62977"><enum>105.</enum><header>Conditions of permit</header>
 <subsection id="HFB26315AF46F4D4CA7180C2AE9E3A8E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5713">section 5713</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H734AACB62FEA480F81C592C510CFD556" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H2579CD2EE8E947BBBC8DFCE7E6A26BA2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance</header> <paragraph id="H28BF65AD10834EA6AC3148BE5D181593"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person shall not engage in business as a manufacturer or importer of tobacco products or processed tobacco, as a wholesaler, as an export warehouse proprietor, or as a manufacturer, seller, lessor, or importer of tobacco production machines without a permit to engage in such business. Such permit, conditioned upon compliance with this chapter and regulations issued thereunder, shall be issued in such form and in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe, to every person properly qualified under sections 5711 and 5712. Any entity granted such a permit is not eligible to provide any services the Secretary may elect to procure to facilitate the purposes of section 5723. Permit holders shall automatically count output and register, record, and transmit the quantities measured, in the form, conditions, and time limits established by the Secretary. A new permit may be required at such other time as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H501AE7F140314B24AE31FEBA350252F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall not issue a permit under this section unless—</text> <subparagraph id="HA28F01D8636F42258A4C8A88080AD2D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicant is in compliance with the requirements of—</text>
 <clause id="H58DCB69F10C44D32A5D707D2CBB095AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this chapter,</text> </clause><clause id="H0C0220821CE449939C28A558EB184F7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/114">chapter 114</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5818919956E0436BBC7423B2A1AE38C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Act of October 19, 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/375">15 U.S.C. 375 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <term>Jenkins Act</term>),</text> </clause><clause id="HC64C774FCDE040A8BAED64CB73F84D0D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Fair and Equitable Tobacco Reform Act of 2004, and any amendments made thereby,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H97FBB0ACAB4C4A72A06B6093F4F2A94A"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act, and any amendments made thereby,</text> </clause><clause id="H74CF557CBECF4C1D9F1924BD67B81214"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Prevent All Cigarette Trafficking Act of 2009, and any amendments made thereby, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H91BD16FD80674BA09AC00AEBEAF03638"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any related regulations thereunder,</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">as in effect on the date of the issuance of the permit,</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA18190EDA19C45A8944F4DB8CD3794D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant certifies that the applicant is in compliance with all other Federal, State, local, and Indian tribal laws relating to the taxation, manufacture, importation, exportation, distribution, marketing, sale, or transportation of tobacco products, processed tobacco, or tobacco production machines, as in effect on the date of the issuance of the permit, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFBC4B2C2FFA40E48B56AD7E9B71516C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant identifies in the application any violation of a law described in subparagraph (A) or (B) by the applicant resulting in a penalty under any such law during the 5-year period ending on the date of the application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3F832E4F621C444497EDF86AE5A8D4B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Suspension or revocation</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5713">section 5713(b)(1)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>or any other law described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(2)</quote> after <quote>this chapter</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HF514482AF68547219C0BC1E400D3E6EE"><enum>106.</enum><header>Records to be maintained</header> <subsection id="HED7D4388A99E498FBED566BAD785B725"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5741">Section 5741</external-xref> is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3916346484C04B6C9F0424A534BEE61A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—</quote> before <quote>Every manufacturer</quote>,</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H64B0FEA1BF8F4B95AFDCA96F30AD7A0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>every wholesaler,</quote> after <quote>every importer,</quote>,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26C1F7B62EE7486FB5A9584E6E6ADA16"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>such records</quote> and inserting <quote>records concerning the chain of custody of the tobacco products and processed tobacco (including the foreign country of final destination for packages marked for export) and the serial numbers, marks, labels, and notices required under section 5723, and such other records</quote>, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H370F2D0EA393408EBEA505BBECCF39FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block id="HA5D1AA5A739C44218235C7CDF897F0D6"> <subsection id="HEF60CE3EB98641DEA77E5E05C7002716"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retailers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Retailers shall maintain records of receipt, and any non-retail sale or delivery, of tobacco products and processed tobacco. Such records shall be available to the Secretary for inspection and audit. An ordinary commercial record or invoice shall satisfy the requirements of this subsection if such record shows the date of receipt, from whom tobacco products or processed tobacco were received, and the quantity of tobacco products or processed tobacco received (or, in the case of non-retail sale or delivery, the date of sale or delivery, to whom the tobacco products or processed tobacco were sold or delivered, and the quantity of the tobacco products or processed tobacco sold or delivered). To the extent the Secretary determines that the records maintained by retail entities licensed pursuant to section 555(b) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1555">19 U.S.C. 1555(b)</external-xref>) satisfy the recordkeeping requirements of this section, no additional records shall be required for such entities under this section. The preceding provisions of this subsection shall not be construed to limit or preclude other recordkeeping requirements imposed on any retailer.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H17C63B0BDE7A4B53ADA4FFD3800C9FD5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Records concerning marks and chain of custody</header><text>Records concerning the chain of custody and the marks, labels, and notices required under section 5723 shall be available for inspection by any internal revenue officer during business hours.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H575B8577584049BE915A1721ADD7C84A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation with Health and Human Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5741">section 5741</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H62FE067894EE4EEDA081AEB0423FABE6"><enum>107.</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5722">Section 5722</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF5C821D4A3E34FEAB8E1E0BC2B5DEEEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—</quote> before <quote>Every manufacturer</quote>, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88366042375546628BB1CE9BC635AE05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51EE8AC7FB404CFF89E60ED2BF3178E5" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HEA932ACAB03544E1966FA35B0861D675"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports by export warehouse proprietors</header><text>Prior to exportation of tobacco products or processed tobacco from the United States, the export warehouse proprietor shall submit a report (in such manner and form as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe) to enable the Secretary to identify the shipment and assure that it reaches its intended destination.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H434F4B8B956441348C2B8CC60FBA2608"><enum>108.</enum><header>Fraudulent offenses</header>
 <subsection id="HD9DF43FE759149CB87A3E036364A6BD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5762">section 5762</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1A707447C4B54A06839AB5AA3102F917"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and redesignating paragraphs (2) through (6) as paragraphs (1) through (5), respectively, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD780F759509C431293848D6D84478EBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not more than $10,000</quote> and inserting <quote>not more than $10,000 or an amount equal to 3 times the amount of the tax imposed under this chapter on the tobacco product involved (whichever is greater)</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4AC302404074B53B7D9A2821DC9A0E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Offenses relating to distribution of tobacco products, etc</header>
 <paragraph id="H4B772E30417E4F8B8BFDE319B1907D8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 5762 (as amended by section 102 of this Act) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H3A306CDD535440E5B31F90184B5960DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA02098BF73FE4095B81A54F11493E1A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H7BB0D97576114B02A3856BB5FDDE553A"> <subsection id="H9E38F5A1D7354529B93AAA03C9DFA13D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Offenses relating to distribution of tobacco products, etc</header><text>It shall be unlawful—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1F82C8F8404F47209FAC233ADCBF2B5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for any person to engage in business as a manufacturer or importer of tobacco products, processed tobacco, or cigarette papers and tubes, as a wholesaler, or an export warehouse proprietor, or as a manufacturer, seller, or importer of tobacco production machines without filing the bond and obtaining the permit where required by this chapter or regulations thereunder,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCA83B79AFA445BBA2CDAFB443FD2F66"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a manufacturer or importer of tobacco products, or wholesaler to knowingly ship, transport, deliver, or receive any tobacco products from or to any person other than a person who has obtained the permit required by this chapter, a retailer, or a person handling such products solely for purposes of shipment or delivery; except that an importer who has obtained the permit required by this chapter may receive, from a foreign manufacturer or a foreign distributor, foreign tobacco products that have not previously entered the United States,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA3EAD51C105E4203863DCA1EFBF2EEE6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for a manufacturer or importer of processed tobacco or a wholesaler to knowingly ship, transport, deliver, or receive any tobacco products or processed tobacco from or to any person other than a person who has obtained the permit required by this chapter,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18BD2400F75242128B93E63AB271A5CD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a manufacturer or importer of processed tobacco to knowingly ship, transport, sell, or deliver processed tobacco to any person other than a manufacturer of processed tobacco, a manufacturer of tobacco products, or an export warehouse proprietor,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9895318702244D1A8FBB1D2CD499CAC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for any person (other than the original manufacturer of such tobacco products or processed tobacco or an export warehouse proprietor authorized to receive any tobacco products or processed tobacco that have previously been exported and returned to the United States) to knowingly receive any tobacco products or processed tobacco that have previously been exported and returned to the United States,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B8442A287FF4481A916DA56BEE0A3AD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>for any export warehouse proprietor to knowingly ship, transport, sell, or deliver for sale any tobacco products or processed tobacco to any person other than the original manufacturer of such tobacco products or processed tobacco, another export warehouse proprietor, a duty free store, or a foreign purchaser,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88879006D5C64E1791CC04C62E48A6B0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>for any person (other than a manufacturer, wholesaler, or an export warehouse proprietor permitted under this chapter) to knowingly ship, transport, receive, or possess, for purposes of resale, any tobacco product or processed tobacco not in packages marked pursuant to regulations issued under section 5723, other than for direct return to a manufacturer for repacking or for re-exportation or to an export warehouse proprietor for re-exportation,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5D1A1DF5E2B4866A7C9C7F4C4332F8A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>for any manufacturer, importer, export warehouse proprietor, or wholesaler permitted under this chapter to make any false entry in, to fail to make an entry in, or to knowingly fail to maintain properly any record or report required by this chapter or the regulations promulgated thereunder with the intent to defraud the United States,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H17E19F04C5764C1EB0A1AFC76074C24C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>for any person, with the intent to defraud the United States, to alter, mutilate, destroy, obliterate, or remove any mark or label required under this chapter upon a tobacco product or processed tobacco held for sale, or to create, possess, or apply on any tobacco product or processed tobacco or its packaging any counterfeit versions of any such marks or labels, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DC500634B244B55B95EF13BA93E555E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>for any person to sell at retail more than 3,000 cigarettes in any single transaction (or series of related transactions), or, in the case of other tobacco products, an equivalent quantity as determined by regulation.</text>
									</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Any person violating any of the provisions of this subsection shall, upon conviction, be fined as
			 provided in section 3571 of title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned
			 for not more than 5 years, or both.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31562D707BB34F00B66997B363EE693B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 5762(d) (as so redesignated) is amended by striking <quote>and (b)</quote> inserting <quote>, (b), and (c)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C5E674303F9485F8297CB3C850DD9F9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other offenses</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 5762 (as so redesignated) is amended by striking <quote>not more than $1,000</quote> and inserting <quote>not more than $2,500 or an amount equal to the tax imposed under this chapter on the tobacco product or processed tobacco involved (whichever is greater)</quote>.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H6E78BE6B14BE42E48737EF7919771DCA"><enum>109.</enum><header>Penalties</header>
				<subsection id="HE692F5F2D5DE44D780BE9B52A528EB6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H2105C0681BCC4E30B525F48A952E1688"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5761">section 5761</external-xref> is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HC20E623750AB4589AB4BEF1D94452279"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>willfully</quote> and inserting <quote>knowingly</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F876475C5B544DC8A58C1034C91F565"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$1,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$10,000</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDE3BEE3E1F24ACEAEC9EA3087FEC282"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5761">section 5761</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>5 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>10 percent</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC15958F114374AAABE3F917940743189"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty amounts adjusted for inflation</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5761">Section 5761</external-xref> is amended by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (g) and inserting after subsection (e) the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FF20C8EB79549088872803C2A04DA74" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HAFC2758015254C1BBEF77D4F4DD8A5BF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header>
 <paragraph id="HA01FD8BB15B94A748ECD6AB0C42B56BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a calendar year beginning after 2015, the penalty dollar amounts provided under this chapter shall each be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9BE1A33E425B48D09BAC2E3EA101AEB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FCD33DEAF4C43ACB5C30CF7F99C08BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2014</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91E8F0BC1A034792A0675D72E1111D28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any amount as adjusted under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $10, such amount shall be rounded to the next highest multiple of $10.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="H59901978326F484A89DC2364B25EA9E9"><enum>110.</enum><header>Coordination with other government officials</header>
 <subsection id="HD281DD7D1BFC460B82996C45C86D5CBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter F of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/52">chapter 52</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FE4A56AEAE945ACA068EDABAF5827DF" style="OLC"> <section id="H1F4C1D37164449DAAB1CD1386FEAE947"><enum>5755.</enum><header>Coordination with other government officials</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall make reasonable efforts to coordinate with other Federal agencies and with officials of foreign, State, local, Indian tribal, and other governments to promote the purposes of this chapter, to prevent and reduce tobacco tax evasion and contraband trafficking in tobacco products and processed tobacco, to enforce settlement agreements between tobacco companies and State or other governments and related laws, or for other law enforcement or administration purposes.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="HB382B5C4258B4EA7B7CBF282C17D5260"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information sharing</header>
 <paragraph id="HA427471C968F41F286B6B1E161D0304C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(o)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B72A12433AE4E8E8C51C30C760C419E" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H2492F344E4554926A4E4908803633943"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information sharing for tobacco product law administration and enforcement purposes</header> <clause id="HC26A8B75708F45D9A35363724DF33285"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Federal, State, local, and tribal governments</header><text>Returns and return information with respect to taxes imposed by chapter 52 may be open to inspection by or disclosure to officers and employees of any Federal agency, the State Tax Administrators, or any other agency of any State, local, or Indian tribal government responsible for the administration and enforcement of laws and regulations relating to tobacco products and processed tobacco, or their legal representative, solely for use in such administration and enforcement, unless the Secretary determines that such disclosure would seriously impair Federal tax administration.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0F5E78D0D2864EE7A7CE0E5AA07F5C62"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Foreign governments and organizations</header><text>The Secretary shall, upon written request, disclose returns and return information with respect to taxes imposed by chapter 52 to officers and employees of any agency of any foreign government, OLAF (European Anti-Fraud Office), EUROPOL, INTERPOL, or the World Customs Organization responsible for the administration and enforcement of laws and regulations relating to tobacco products and processed tobacco, or their legal representative, solely for use in such administration and enforcement, if the Secretary obtains written assurances from such government or organization that the information will be held in confidence and used only for such use. No return or return information shall be disclosed under this clause if the Secretary determines that such disclosure would seriously impair Federal tax administration.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDB697BF5EC904D5D82D052B8FD2B4FE2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Public information</header><text>The identity and business address of those persons that have a valid permit, pursuant to chapter 52, to engage in business as a manufacturer, wholesaler, or importer of tobacco products or processed tobacco, as an export warehouse proprietor, or as a manufacturer, seller, or importer of tobacco production machines (as defined in section 5702(q)) shall be made publicly available at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE996C5DBF041E1A4DD26D5FCAF50B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="HDDE35861B8F3494EAD18E79D131A8877"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> is amended—</text> <clause id="H852D3BC0F3E345C3B5C213014951DD20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or any local</quote> in paragraph (2) and inserting <quote>any local</quote>,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA482EA6128B44BA19D5072633785137E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or any agency described in subsection (o)(1)(C)(i)</quote> after <quote>subsection (l)(7)(D)</quote> in paragraph (2),</text> </clause><clause id="HA435AA48351640E0B244515ACD5AB60F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or subsection (n)</quote> in paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>subsection (n), or subsection (o)(1)(C)(i)</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7843ECEF08C4F17A458A0AEF2DEDE51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Paragraph (4) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(p)</external-xref> is amended—</text> <clause id="H6896E50D4DA247ADB07C2C4D8D795C94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(o)(1)(A)</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>(o)(1)(A) or (C)(i)</quote>, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H981C63D14B6D466481921F42D307FBB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(15), or (16),</quote> and inserting <quote>(15), or (16), or (o)(1)(C)(i),</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67FB60BFDFA14B2297EFA91E9B538D15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7213">section 7213(a)</external-xref> is amended—</text>
 <clause id="H6642B4F3B4C94113AB9902A4A8BC62EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(21) or</quote> and inserting <quote>(21),</quote>, and</text> </clause><clause id="HBFAAA7326ECC4DD6A9D17FAE5EEBBE85"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (7)</quote> and inserting <quote>or (7), or (o)(1)(C)(i)</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA06D89343A7942B2AB4D5E128088D900"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter F of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/52">chapter 52</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H4EB636CED8B9474B81E167F8F127270A" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="H1F4C1D37164449DAAB1CD1386FEAE947" level="section">Sec. 5755. Coordination with other government officials.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="H53FB7AC632394E3A8F305C352E328353"><enum>111.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <subsection id="H4324B1DC0611483ABDC4147102511D73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Export warehouse proprietor</header><text>Subsection (i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5702">section 5702</external-xref> is amended by inserting before the period the following: <quote>or any person engaged in the business of exporting tobacco products from the United States for purposes of sale or distribution. Any duty free store that sells, offers for sale, or otherwise distributes to any person in any single transaction (or series of related transactions) more than 3,000 cigarettes, or an equivalent quantity of other tobacco products as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe, shall be deemed an export warehouse proprietor under this chapter</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H48EE45AB566B47218FEAF141592C8173"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retailer; wholesaler</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5702">Section 5702</external-xref>, as amended by this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HF6540C36DEB54083821B93F372F1D289">
 <subsection id="H1BB72D78F28644AFB31C058DBD8C1C08"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Retailer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>retailer</term> means any person who sells, or offers for sale, any tobacco product at retail. The term <term>retailer</term> includes any duty free store that sells, offers for sale, or otherwise distributes at retail in any single transaction (or series of related transactions) not more than 3,000 cigarettes, or not more than an equivalent quantity of other tobacco products as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFDB9AFF0734B434486237A14F58AB1F9"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Wholesaler</header><text>The term <term>wholesaler</term> means any person engaged in the business of purchasing tobacco products for resale at wholesale, or any person acting as an agent or broker for any person engaged in the business of purchasing tobacco products for resale at wholesale.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="H3B4B4B404F464D47985C5087C8891E82"><enum>112.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subsection id="HEF395C7802444C948D5BE3659C3604E9"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2)(C) of section 2341 of title 18, United States Code is amended by inserting <quote>in regard to State, local, or Indian tribal government taxes,</quote> before <quote>a person</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HA8C934A9332B4BEBA504AA21466482BD"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Sections 2314 and 2315 of title 18, United States Code, are each amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9FA5B80A2EE5484A913F5407A6563192"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">State</header-in-text></quote> in the heading thereof; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9C0C855D3D64422A060DA296742933A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>tax stamps</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>tax stamps or markings</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02A2844695B74EE082EECED8473E9F58"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The headings for subchapters B, C, and E of chapter 52 are each amended by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subchapter" style="OLC">, processed tobacco,</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subchapter" style="OLC">products</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H5FE8B274DB1E426BBC04BA6937B477C2"><enum>(d)</enum><text>The items relating to subchapters B, C, and E in the table of subchapters for chapter 52 are each amended by inserting <quote>, processed tobacco,</quote> after <quote>products</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF9B49BBF3B3848CB9E5E9818FB5125AA"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The heading for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/52">chapter 52</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="chapter" style="OLC">, processed tobacco,</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="chapter" style="OLC">products</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC7CA6FAC723478A8D132A00C60C6081"><enum>(f)</enum><text>The item relating to chapter 52 in the table of chapters for subtitle E is amended by inserting <quote>, processed tobacco,</quote> after <quote>products</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H93BED52B63E7495286489E3122C61956"><enum>113.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the amendments made by this title shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</section></title><title id="H6FFDD477AF734D788A5116E354E87032"><enum>II</enum><header>Import Fraud</header>
			<section commented="no" id="HF169166374F547CDA83C7548D9C73309" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><header>Maximum penalty for importation of tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes by fraudulent
			 means</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H3C14899E16674B97B1A80B380E616C8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Maximum penalty</header><text>Section 592(c)(1) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1592">19 U.S.C. 1592(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE194A200AB3B473C8FB707CDF8817A8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A fraudulent violation of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2C0390B63D24FCFA8CCA1B86B496854" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H28248C21D03B417499B443F51BB98A41"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a fraudulent violation of subsection (a)</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H23CAA383131C498C87BAB1BD76AA56CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87310E2BC97B4630A2BD3D230FFAA326" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HD42FA6535C694652AFF31D80E4981BCC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of importation of tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes subject to tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/52">chapter 52</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, a fraudulent violation of subsection (a) is punishable by a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the sum of—</text>
 <clause id="H02DDF91178124940A5BBB7E6BDE02B5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the domestic value of the merchandise, and</text> </clause><clause id="HF902891E6E694EEA95E0CD1243CC0889"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>four times the amount of Federal excise tax that could be imposed on the merchandise, if applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE7CFB56CB0B94EC98ACEFE007E4341C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date which is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and shall apply with respect to violations of section 592 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (as so amended) that occur on or after that date.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H7C82F252A489421B87712C6A7586997D"><enum>III</enum><header>Exclusions regarding Indian Tribes and Tribal matters</header>
			<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6773C75EB614BE5A59CCDCB7908C7E6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>301.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exclusions regarding Indian Tribes and Tribal matters</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB4418E7091549D595506C35107CA724"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to amend, modify, or otherwise affect—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB657A811EA96428CBC9FC404DF049AFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any agreements, compacts, or other intergovernmental arrangements between any State or local government and any government of an Indian tribe relating to the collection of taxes on tobacco products sold in Indian country;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H301B54AA1F5346C08535CE700ECD8F02"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any State laws that authorize or otherwise pertain to any such intergovernmental arrangements or create special rules or procedures for the collection of State, local, or tribal taxes on tobacco products sold in Indian country;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H213A016E4B754541808D2123124DB17A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any limitations under Federal or State law, including Federal common law and treaties, on State, local, and tribal tax and regulatory authority with respect to the sale, use, or distribution of tobacco products or processed tobacco by or to Indian tribes, tribal members, tribal enterprises, or in Indian country;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD0EDCA0019B4308977AAF4C9E0C7156"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Federal law, including Federal common law and treaties, regarding State jurisdiction, or lack thereof, over any Indian tribe, tribal member, tribal enterprise, Indian reservations, or other land held by the United States in trust for one or more Indian tribes; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E611F0DEE654C32A9912CC19B3444EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any State or local government authority to bring enforcement actions against persons located in Indian country.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C1CF30D8A8B42F7B8FD20AC258DBD57"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordination of law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act (other than the amendments relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) shall be construed to inhibit or otherwise affect any coordinated law enforcement effort by 1 or more States or other jurisdictions, including Indian tribes, through interstate compact or otherwise, that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7BDF08E002B447FBA61C7130DE9B624"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for the administration of tobacco product laws or laws pertaining to interstate sales or other sales of tobacco products or processed tobacco;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H470E0EADAB5E4967BE74D821BDE961DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for the seizure of tobacco products, processed tobacco, or other property related to a violation of such laws; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E2E75D69C344D9DA3FC723066EF74F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishes cooperative programs for the administration of such laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9D8A538079C48F684BBEF4F3906D27A"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treatment of State and local governments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to authorize, deputize, or commission States or local governments as instrumentalities of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57F2316A912C4FFFA50C49BE3C75FF7F"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement within Indian Country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall prohibit, limit, or restrict enforcement by the Attorney General of the United States of this Act or an amendment made by this Act within Indian country.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DAE85A77F0644B99002A7759ECB7D20"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ambiguity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any ambiguity between the language of this section or its application and any other provision of this Act shall be resolved in favor of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5982210489594B31B568DCB18AA2AE1F"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87EB2BCBAAC244E4BFB22F529C63E0CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Indian country</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1151 of title 18, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA63DAF5CFE1C4C49A172AD6C73A98692"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>tribal enterprise</term> means any business enterprise, regardless of whether incorporated or unincorporated under Federal or tribal law, of an Indian tribe or group of Indian tribes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2AA88C61A864070918D48F8F598D192"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Indian reservation</term> has the meaning given that term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/168">section 168(j)(6)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H238D151AB344490BA57F40D4F2079365"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4(e) of the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b(e)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H427813BAA2B04962B90CD70E5CEDDDF3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the terms <term>tobacco products</term> and <term>processed tobacco</term> have the meanings given such terms by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5702">section 5702</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body> </bill> 

