<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H923F217C2E974C57B3117479CF41E14F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 373 IH: Good Samaritan Search and Recovery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 373</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150114">January 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001055">Mr. Heck of Nevada</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001070">Mr. Hardy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior and Secretary of Agriculture to expedite access to certain Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of each Secretary for good Samaritan search-and-recovery missions, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2BFCA2555F094C0A8DE2661AB31FD63F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H60985827F5DF47EBB15F6D31759C7A4C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Good Samaritan Search and Recovery Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7151C4D40E31426F9E28BD65FDF9ED1E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited access to certain Federal land</header> <subsection id="HD1D9A60978C94C6CB07BBB2709D2330E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H2AAF26861FC34E4E830D174724341FAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible</term>, with respect to an organization or individual, means that the organization or individual, respectively, is—</text> <subparagraph id="HA573A01AC343484BAAB9C53968F7EF4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acting in a not-for-profit capacity; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB40C6B20CD274BA28C6FDDBF5989FC46"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certificated in training that meets or exceeds standards established by the American Society for Testing and Materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H709D8B9D7D40464FB1BD0E336C3A18A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission</term> means a search for 1 or more missing individuals believed to be deceased at the time that the search is initiated.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CDA11DE3B574EDAA7E444878F3AE64A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H217CE726C3344ACDB090A7B474803EAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process</header> <paragraph id="H2670BA417DD74EE097418DFD65E2A6BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Secretary shall develop and implement a process to expedite access to Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary for eligible organizations and individuals to request access to Federal land to conduct good Samaritan search-and-recovery missions.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD99A51F81514B79B9A6DF2AACBCA015"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process developed and implemented under this subsection shall include provisions to clarify that—</text> <subparagraph id="H8788754B8CA9483CAF8A07236601AA82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an eligible organization or individual granted access under this section—</text>
<clause id="H1630064D0DEE418CB9FED107B160D1F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be acting for private purposes; and</text></clause> <clause id="HED2D324B42584F29AF3BA899B7860119"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not be considered to be a Federal volunteer;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H98FC9E10FBAE4793A6E009A1A7893013"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an eligible organization or individual conducting a good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission under this section shall not be considered to be a volunteer under section 102301(c) of title 54, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6B09B77367E4C909BB3F37C3AE4D66C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Tort Claims Act</quote>), shall not apply to an eligible organization or individual carrying out a privately requested good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission under this section; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5F0BB929B62547C0BF40863800587280"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Employees Compensation Act</quote>), shall not apply to an eligible organization or individual conducting a good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission under this section, and the conduct of the good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission shall not constitute civilian employment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC7200AFA0C0641A7991DFCA79C51FA2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Release of Federal Government from liability</header><text>The Secretary shall not require an eligible organization or individual to have liability insurance as a condition of accessing Federal land under this section, if the eligible organization or individual—</text>
<paragraph id="H0FF9252A6A7F4C1890CFF83E90A0AF5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acknowledges and consents, in writing, to the provisions described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of subsection (b)(2); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D591BF56AF94EFFAC157C862A95D5E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>signs a waiver releasing the Federal Government from all liability relating to the access granted under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAE473917DB9845028A41824E6512ED84"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval and denial of requests</header>
<paragraph id="H332CF97CE3CC41A2974D42875F14737C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall notify an eligible organization or individual of the approval or denial of a request by the eligible organization or individual to carry out a good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission under this section by not later than 48 hours after the request is made.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6B9CCC692DC4DFCB32D7304473D05BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary denies a request from an eligible organization or individual to carry out a good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission under this section, the Secretary shall notify the eligible organization or individual of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H77003550D16841A9BCF4640905E1A7BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reason for the denial of the request; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8546CCF0A9364824B02207E22C4DA203"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any actions that the eligible organization or individual can take to meet the requirements for the request to be approved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H724C6A29AD6E4848A850A062185E8018"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Secretary shall develop search-and-recovery-focused partnerships with search-and-recovery organizations—</text> <paragraph id="HC42236AB599F4ECA999A95EB185A2649"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate good Samaritan search-and-recovery missions on Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H812286D17D624173815B6FBCC453D552"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expedite and accelerate good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission efforts for missing individuals on Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HB90E10035E234839AAC780494C049E80"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretaries shall submit to Congress a joint report describing—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA0001B76EDF749E898523655D96AD106"><enum>(1)</enum><text>plans to develop partnerships described in subsection (e)(1); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H570CCCBE654D417281A597DAFC9F24AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts carried out to expedite and accelerate good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission efforts for missing individuals on Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of each Secretary pursuant to subsection (e)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


