<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H00785507AE65417EB44258A70EB2CB1C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 875 IH: Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 875</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150211">February 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for alternative financing arrangements for the provision of certain services and the
			 construction and maintenance of infrastructure at land border ports of
			 entry, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H40545D62FCBB4A9ABACF6A239B7AD098" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBD34A88C900A410DB06E14914E221AC2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cross-Border Trade Enhancement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H91A12103133E41189AD5AEFE4090D5A7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCD2E1D8F37F34E1F957772FFF4EB4049"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator; Administration</header><text>The terms <term>Administrator</term> and <term>Administration</term> mean the Administrator of General Services and the General Services Administration, respectively.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H417629D75EA544CF8CAB8802B5656083"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H081B5BAC29224FDDBADD1D27D823752E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC98BF070F05A47978EE67178008E7A78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAB7DF2D41C640F4B621522D13E18665"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a corporation, partnership, trust, association, or any other public or private entity, including a State or local government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1F9F680AF37423999BAAA9484196515"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relevant committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>relevant committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB65B14185F584986BC4CED9097B86CD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1871EBF57EB949C4BF093A9C0C93DF18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CF55DED7B5A40009FA275387B2A2CCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABA85A4872A84246B92357BB9197FD20"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94A8DB9DDF75432D8F0FC254508D5F67"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4846BB15AC5748A59D9A98E89054F464"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD78B03BF515949A785CB79450D7B2DC0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HAC3A52A6E6064330B42C1A28E379AF4E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority to enter into agreements for the provision of certain services at land border ports of
			 entry</header>
			<subsection id="H76578B54808D47B4B813C05C6AED664F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To Enter Into Agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="HC8F9FF8D642446C0852D6406D12A3AB2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 451 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1451">19 U.S.C. 1451</external-xref>), and consistent with section 560 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2013 (division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/6">Public Law 113–6</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 378) and section 559 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2014 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/211">6 U.S.C. 211</external-xref> note) the Commissioner may, during the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and upon the request of any person, enter into an agreement with that person under which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H855156DB3C494ECA992DFD8BFB2C5A43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>U.S. Customs and Border Protection will provide the services described in paragraph (2) at a land border port of entry; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55DC8CCE6E9B493F9DE8DEAE774E5937"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that person will pay the fee described in subsection (b) to reimburse U.S. Customs and Border Protection for the costs incurred in providing such services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1512E085103041868A2A2B4EECEE4F02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Services described</header><text>Services described in this paragraph are any services related to customs, agricultural processing, border security, or inspection-related immigration matters provided by an employee or contractor of U.S. Customs and Border Protection at land border ports of entry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB916171948434C2DBF86A57E3B7EC43B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Commissioner may not modify existing requirements or reimbursement fee agreements in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act unless the relevant person requests a modification to include services described in this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H205CF023356A4991BA2FA137DAD4B484"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to reduce the responsibilities or duties of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to provide services at land border ports of entry that have been authorized or mandated by law and are funded in any appropriation Act or from any accounts in the Treasury of the United States derived by the collection of fees.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H629A405D124549DBB011BDF66DDDFBD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fee</header>
 <paragraph id="H5A0C39F9B25E4B36A741E6B11FB37268"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person requesting U.S. Customs and Border Protection services shall pay a fee pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a) in an amount equal to the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H55EFB80BA8BD406C9B9587325642FB5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a proportionate share of the salaries and expenses of the individuals employed by U.S. Customs and Border Protection who provided such services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92494CBDBE47489CAE298F3A5B99D03C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other costs incurred by U.S. Customs and Border Protection relating to such services, such as temporary placement or permanent relocation of such individuals.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2E997245063400189865EA76EEEA1CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oversight of fees</header><text>The Commissioner shall develop a process to oversee the activities reimbursed by the fees authorized under paragraph (1) that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H042D4662BAE949B6A47566D4CE5B8519"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a determination and report on the full cost of providing services, including direct and indirect costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C72F1E251E44B22B774F2F8D4902AE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a process for increasing such fees, as necessary;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7C7F5A47E6E460CB8632F985D0D2F39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the establishment of a monthly remittance schedule to reimburse appropriations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EF30206581C49659A5FBFB4B6DE6529"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the identification of overtime costs to be reimbursed by such fees.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE243999B32224D34A38C6117E38BCB3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deposit of funds</header><text>Amounts collected in fees under paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H141F105260724EBC87ACABC5F65A4456"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be deposited as an offsetting collection;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC571259BEA0D44789FC490F676E6F6EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall remain available until expended, without fiscal year limitation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAF5DC550363413ABD65A182EF571C4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall directly reimburse each appropriation account for the amount paid out of such account for—</text> <clause id="HFEE047C246B345F085B1A753E8F3E710"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any expenses incurred for providing U.S. Customs and Border Protection services to the person paying such fee; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0D95B444A47E4C5EB59DD8013E6D8FB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other costs incurred by the U.S. Customs and Border Protection relating to such services.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17C6649C81914B91B516B6787B4A7871"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination</header> <subparagraph id="H0F6F62293B6E4E70966AD8F66369E606"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner shall terminate the services provided pursuant to an agreement with a private sector or government entity under subsection (a) upon receiving notice from the Commissioner that such entity failed to pay the fee imposed under paragraph (1) in a timely manner.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A9B0869E9C64053BEA28A20A6F43B07"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of termination</header><text>At the time services are terminated pursuant to subparagraph (A), all costs incurred by U.S. Customs and Border Protection to provide services to the entity described in subparagraph (A), which have not been reimbursed by the entity, will become immediately due and payable.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1404EAD85E1B4319908FBD3811C0DCB2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interest</header><text>Interest on unpaid fees will accrue from the date of termination based on current Treasury borrowing rates.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C4A7DE9352F4F038C10E4ED40B60A25"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Any private sector or government entity that fails to pay any fee incurred under paragraph (1) in a timely manner, after notice and demand for payment, shall be liable for a penalty or liquidated damage equal to 2 times the amount of such fee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE138F668D2E4224ABACCFCC808BABFB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 3 days before entering into an agreement under this section, the Commissioner shall notify—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD3459838160F43858FAE58D86E045526"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the relevant committees of Congress; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A1AB446DA1E4EFD9DC5AEA1631D18C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the members of Congress who represent the State or district in which the facility at which services will be provided under the agreement.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H060B2F9AD1CE42ACAD50DF3A06ADEAD7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Evaluation of alternative financing arrangements for construction and maintenance of infrastructure
			 at land border ports of entry</header>
 <subsection id="HE66E8392E16C4E528767ECF6792E36D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agreements authorized</header><text>Consistent with section 559 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2014 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/211">6 U.S.C. 211</external-xref> note), during the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner and the Administrator may, for purposes of facilitating the construction, alteration, operation, or maintenance of a new or existing facility or other infrastructure at a port of entry under the jurisdiction, custody, and control of the Commissioner or the Administrator—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6A67512D8429447E9594868311AE13E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enter into cost-sharing or reimbursement agreements with any person; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H33628D5D7B384FDBBD978CA3D61909CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accept donations from any person of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1C903A5495F240618C630FB210B18524"><enum>(A)</enum><text>real or personal property (including monetary donations); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D4240783D734D9E803343C855E41EFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nonpersonal services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0EF55763EA947C6A0CACF9A2B139863"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allowable uses of agreements</header><text>The Commissioner and the Administrator, with respect to an agreement authorized under subsection (a), may—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB5EA7948B5F84953B45F21F944698362"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use such agreements for activities related to an existing or new port of entry, including expenses related to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5A85AA9461A447F49FBD69CB755B5E67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>land acquisition, design, construction, repair, or alternation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H297742B90633411BA5E04192AFBE410D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>furniture, fixtures, or equipment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B7ABE5061E64EC2A66B92470B3B2FD4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the deployment of technology or equipment; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31DA3EAD84794A2E917CE001699E4D67"><enum>(D)</enum><text>operations and maintenance; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD52593970D4483A87341F8362688880"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, transfer such property or services between the Commissioner and the Administrator for activities described in paragraph (1) that are related to a new or existing port of entry under the jurisdiction, custody, and control of the relevant agency.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF602B47F1BB1457D983AF5EFAAC72E17"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evaluation procedures</header>
				<paragraph id="H6E92276E198742E888D5439D41D2DC4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAE7559F2712D4CA6B4727030DE82A41D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirements for procedures</header><text>The Commissioner, in consultation with the Administrator and consistent with section 559 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2014 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/211">6 U.S.C. 211</external-xref> note), shall issue procedures for evaluating a proposal submitted by a person for an agreement authorized under subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F72FA1405DB429EA3FB6D8C9C609F62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The procedures issued under subparagraph (A) shall be made available to the public through the Department of Homeland Security website.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE61FDE2A036D4DB59F9C45DAEB2C6F84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specification</header><text>In making a donation under subsection (a)(2), a person may—</text> <subparagraph id="H08A272813F034950BF594E1064AF3FD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate the land port of entry facility or facilities that the donation is intended to support; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9084179E45084B85934522301F37FB74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specify the period during which the contributed property or nonpersonal services shall be used.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CD7EFD4A0C6448B909A32BBAD772EB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplemental funding</header><text>Any property, including monetary donations and nonpersonal services donated pursuant to subsection (a) may be used in addition to any other funds, including appropriated funds, property, or services made available for the same purpose.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H277C43256D8D4A5986AB203D03C93F7E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Return of donation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC51874B2C8D54B4382072B7501ABFD20"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Return required</header><text>If the Commissioner or the Administrator does not use the property or services donated pursuant to subsection (a) for the specific facility or facilities designated under paragraph (2)(A) or during the period specified under paragraph (2)(B), such donated property or services shall be returned to the person that made the donation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93F5E0CEC34A44BC92F7DE4B3DAB33FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interest prohibited</header><text>No interest may be owed on any donation returned to a person pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13FB08463EE841729BD0F1FE7B56F9DF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Determination and notification</header> <subparagraph id="HF782869D1A0E44F0B7C03EDD970F2CC5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after receiving a proposal pursuant to subsection (a) with respect to the construction or maintenance of a facility or other infrastructure at a land border port of entry, the Commissioner or the Administrator shall—</text>
 <clause id="H16D88C5E14584D7BA9AF70243F3F1619"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make a determination with respect to whether or not to approve the proposal; and</text> </clause><clause id="H750169C69472484D81FA7129EE672A2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the person that submitted the proposal of—</text>
 <subclause id="H5265B5FEB0CC4398B4E975AA2DFCD637"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the determination; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H119FCB44BCAB4A6FBCF1AE40C599ABF9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the Administrator did not approve the proposal, the reasons for such determination.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23E63C5DE8694B74B963EA818C1ED2A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making the determination under subparagraph (A)(i), the Commissioner or the Administrator shall consider—</text>
 <clause id="HA7833B5E09384DD48EB1A8669B2DAE53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the impact of the proposal on reducing wait times at that port of entry and other ports of entry on the same border;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H313A4ED7BC334B21B169BD0A538EA31C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the potential of the proposal to increase trade and travel efficiency through added capacity; and</text> </clause><clause id="H1571CBC9021F4136856241AC3518BA54"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the potential of the proposal to enhance the security of the port of entry.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H814F311562AD4382A176997457B57CFD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report and notice to Congress</header><text>The Commissioner, in collaboration with the Administrator, shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD4A239F133F141C8AB43DBC2FA689A6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit an annual report to the relevant committees of Congress on the agreements entered into under subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83BB415530BD428A969AA8619551DFC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less than 3 days before entering into an agreement with a person under subsection (a), notify the members of Congress that represent the State or district in which the affected facility is located.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


