<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H859261E4F40E47F082FE812F50A869EE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3865 IH: Cradle Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3865</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151029">October 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000613">Mr. Dold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001193">Mr. MacArthur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000570">Mr. Guinta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for alternative and updated certification requirements for participation under Medicaid
			 State plans under title XIX of the Social Security Act in the case of
			 certain facilities treating infants under one year of age with neonatal
			 abstinence syndrome, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3088196380264D1FB12432DD22EBD4E3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2504334D4F964A0FAF1C7FB5F29E5FA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cradle Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H91B2FB9E20DA4F37886BA4469055BE2A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H61C82F9BE08040F4B3AF2E6A5E43229F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Neonatal abstinence syndrome (referred to in this section as <quote>NAS</quote>) is a group of conditions a newborn can have if the newborn was exposed to drugs, including opioids while in the womb before birth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB60AAF25340C4E2D808B330CBD9A5F7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to a report of the Government Accountability Office (referred to in this section as the <quote>GAO report</quote>) symptoms of NAS include irritability, loud crying, stiffness, sweating, vomiting, diarrhea, poor feeding, seizures, and respiratory distress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EA240971C3249429C3B1E5D0B9994B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the GAO report, it is recommended that newborns with NAS receive a thorough evaluation and specialized and innovative treatment, when warranted.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2FE196306F04185A2FEF26F1E629731"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the GAO report, there is a program gap of available treatment programs for both pregnant women and newborns with NAS.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H740E2C20F2354A97AD1E7539DA3F790F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the GAO report, newborns with NAS stayed in the hospital on average 16 days with an average hospital bill of $53,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC359382632034B7BB603DE002C90AF92"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to GAO reports, NAS has more than quadrupled in the past decade, increasing from 1.2 per 1,000 hospital births per year in 2000 to 5.8 per 1,000 hospital births per year in 2012; and some regional studies have reported much higher incidences.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H877F08B495C340BE858BA07AA72CF8A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Addressing the treatment of infants diagnosed with NAS will take innovative, specialized, and collaborative efforts.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H6B6BAD196C144713A003A7EE89C1B0AE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidelines for certification for participation under Medicaid State plans of certain facilities
			 treating infants under one year of age with neonatal abstinence syndrome</header>
 <subsection id="H436C7E3B61934FD7A14692B157052FAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish guidelines, in accordance with subsection (b), for State agencies and recognized national listing or accrediting bodies to follow for purposes of certifying a residential pediatric recovery center as qualifying for a provider agreement for participation under a State plan under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a residential pediatric recovery center may satisfy the requirements set forth in such guidelines, in lieu of any comparable requirements otherwise applicable to such a center for purposes of certification for participation under such a State plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H937E7C59C38D45CD94F45640C8BB9F0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidelines described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines established under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE9A04B075A72465DBE7354BAF1E74621"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for physical environment requirements and other necessary requirements specifically applicable to treating individuals who are under one year of age with the diagnosis of neonatal abstinence syndrome without any other significant medical risk factors; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H748AD7C9D71347C8AE848F03F6D01D45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take into account that certain physical environment requirements, and any other requirements, needed for centers or facilities treating adults may not be necessary for centers or facilities treating individuals described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78DBF2A1CB354D3584816C13AA3EB63E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Residential pediatric recovery center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <term>residential pediatric recovery center</term> means a center or facility that furnishes items and services to infants who are under one year of age with the diagnosis of neonatal abstinence syndrome without any other significant medical risk factors and mothers of such infants.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H04088DCB36EF49CF9B73AE6245F20F9F"><enum>4.</enum><header>State law licensure of certain facilities satisfies certification requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of a State that recognizes and licenses residential pediatric recovery centers (as defined in section 3(c)), such a center that is licensed, in accordance with such State law, shall be treated as satisfying any comparable requirements otherwise applicable to such a center for purposes of certification for participation under the State plan under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H380FE6960B58453BAE105935F4C95E05"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that residential pediatric recovery centers (as defined in section 3(c)) should offer counseling and other services to mothers (and other appropriate family members and caretakers) of infants receiving treatment at such centers. Such services may include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H236F7CA69A8D413DA06216F9772D9DEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Counseling or referrals for services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7364499197D47D796FC467C0EA66998"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Activities to encourage mother-infant bonding.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C4F16A80F0F40F6AF91502D8B780297"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Training on caring for such infants.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB64E76ABD8A545D7A56A80323AC9E20A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Activities to encourage transparency of relevant State mandatory reporting requirements.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


