<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6D7B176B443548C896273D1F81DD0507" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 475 IH: GI Bill Processing Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 475</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the laws administered by the
			 Secretary of Veterans Affairs relating to educational assistance, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HEF763B9DB8FA40D4986222EFE6504325" style="OLC">
 <section id="H87CE434E16D04113B413CA14B6C3C61F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>GI Bill Processing Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H19A8A2A73CA64387B6F2F2B06A90D4C5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvement of information technology of the Veterans Benefits Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HBA9B357C976F4FE082B8B6E29A0F5603"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Processing of certain educational assistance claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, to the maximum extent possible, make such changes and improvements to the information technology system of the Veterans Benefits Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs to ensure that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H096424594A7249D18D1C5D6A25F3624E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the maximum extent possible, all original and supplemental claims for educational assistance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, are adjudicated electronically; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC9515F2D3A04789A69113A63A6D4579"><enum>(2)</enum><text>rules-based processing is used to make decisions with respect to such claims with little human intervention.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CA99D18487A455BB7CF223CFD08494B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on the changes made pursuant to the requirements of subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2CAEE7BE46494116B6BA1C1B5F6421CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs $30,000,000 to carry out this section during fiscal years 2015 and 2016.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA8DD686B0C294D3D826548183A9324CC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Approval of courses of education provided by public institutions of higher learning for purposes of
			 All-Volunteer Force Educational Assistance Program and Post-9/11
			 Educational Assistance conditional on in-State tuition rate for veterans</header>
 <subsection id="H21CAED7FB4E3431D88746F71A43FAE73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 702(b) of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>July 1, 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>July 1, 2016</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0B2EBF2DFE88464499D1818561FB3D21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3679(c)(2)(B) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or 3319</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>of this title or to whom educational assistance is transferred under section 3319 of this title</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AEE0A0CB9184102BD38649510299F59" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Recodification and improvement of election process for Post-9/11 Educational Assistance Program</header> <subsection id="HD33DF6ABEA664FC589626D256B92BFEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of chapter 33 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB93F2706B2CA4A02AB40CE4E2DB0B231" style="USC">
					<section id="H41BA5FEC2367481EBB5D186057EA723F"><enum>3326.</enum><header>Election to receive educational assistance</header>
 <subsection id="H0581001028674618B0B28FC9CA518304"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Individuals eligible To elect participation in post-9/11 educational assistance</header><text>An individual may elect to receive educational assistance under this chapter if such individual—</text> <paragraph id="HF952FBDBE9704B438E252B11EFEF5BE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as of August 1, 2009—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE45C85E125EB4062AB837D2A09E0804F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is entitled to basic educational assistance under chapter 30 of the title and has used, but retains unused, entitlement under that chapter;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD77DABD8EF142C0A0CF47A2F7975FEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is entitled to educational assistance under chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 of title 10 and has used, but retains unused, entitlement under the applicable chapter;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E1CA25971784A21814D9172949C12D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is entitled to basic educational assistance under chapter 30 of this title but has not used any entitlement under that chapter;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE90FCEC0715D485CB80C4D845EC5C07C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is entitled to educational assistance under chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 of title 10 but has not used any entitlement under such chapter;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08468C87C7914FB2BE4EFDFDDB0B846B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is a member of the Armed Forces who is eligible for receipt of basic educational assistance under chapter 30 this title and is making contributions toward such assistance under section 3011(b) or 3012(c) of this title; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA71F3810170F47E88F217B760396CD27"><enum>(F)</enum><text>is a member of the Armed Forces who is not entitled to basic educational assistance under chapter 30 of this title by reason of an election under section 3011(c)(1) or 3012(d)(1) of this title; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H717E829E171B453AA4665D0C07B10E10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as of the date of the individual’s election under this paragraph, meets the requirements for entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5DDB9D438F34BF687CBA8474685B327"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cessation of contributions toward GI bill</header><text>Effective as of the first month beginning on or after the date of an election under subsection (a) of an individual described by paragraph (1)(E) of that subsection, the obligation of the individual to make contributions under section 3011(b) or 3012(c) of this title, as applicable, shall cease, and the requirements of such section shall be deemed to be no longer applicable to the individual.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HF157F60A9682429D9B4B15AD6050083A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revocation of remaining transferred entitlement</header>
 <paragraph id="HB17820F8C91F4AE8A167FD017DE0FD55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Election to revoke</header><text>If, on the date an individual described in paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(C) of subsection (a) makes an election under that subsection, a transfer of the entitlement of the individual to basic educational assistance under section 3020 of this title is in effect and a number of months of the entitlement so transferred remain unutilized, the individual may elect to revoke all or a portion of the entitlement so transferred that remains unutilized.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD6858FBE2549D2AF23A1719AC0CE42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of revoked entitlement</header><text>Any entitlement revoked by an individual under this paragraph shall no longer be available to the dependent to whom transferred, but shall be available to the individual instead for educational assistance under chapter 33 of this title in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B9004989ECF425A8F3557C6F9269BD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of unrevoked entitlement</header><text>Any entitlement described in paragraph (1) that is not revoked by an individual in accordance with that paragraph shall remain available to the dependent or dependents concerned in accordance with the current transfer of such entitlement under section 3020 of this title.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5705074FA5646E7B2F0955B20DDCDED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Post-9/11 educational assistance</header>
 <paragraph id="HF286B99AE46A4DD886B1B1314E53670D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2) and except as provided in subsection (e), an individual making an election under subsection (a) shall be entitled to educational assistance under this chapter in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, instead of basic educational assistance under chapter 30 this title, or educational assistance under chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 of title 10, as applicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCEEB5803C2547E9ABE1424E2B455A40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on entitlement for certain individuals</header><text>In the case of an individual making an election under subsection (a) who is described by paragraph (1)(A) of that subsection, the number of months of entitlement of the individual to educational assistance under this chapter 33 shall be the number of months equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE3FB0AEA2D1D454F8175B295196082D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of months of unused entitlement of the individual under chapter 30 of this title, as of the date of the election, plus</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B4AE290206546E6B26ECD71FCAED959"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of months, if any, of entitlement revoked by the individual under subsection (c)(1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC10B05F3E73C405F859866EEC7E75208"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Continuing entitlement to educational assistance not available under 9/11 assistance program</header> <paragraph id="H2E6BA534E6AD44738D90DA812935F66A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the event educational assistance to which an individual making an election under subsection (a) would be entitled under chapter 30 of this title, or chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 of title 10, as applicable, is not authorized to be available to the individual under the provisions of this chapter the individual shall remain entitled to such educational assistance in accordance with the provisions of the applicable chapter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4FE8F847C7143FFBE7B4B914D95E6EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Charge for use of entitlement</header><text>The utilization by an individual of entitlement under paragraph (1) shall be chargeable against the entitlement of the individual to educational assistance under this chapter at the rate of one month of entitlement under this chapter for each month of entitlement utilized by the individual under paragraph (1) (as determined as if such entitlement were utilized under the provisions of chapter 30 of this title, or chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 of title 10, as applicable).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDED7839195A8427ABF65A7C3869E6F0C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional post-9/11 assistance for members having made contributions toward GI bill</header>
 <paragraph id="H907FC04FFBAC432CAFE495D14CFFDBDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional assistance</header><text>In the case of an individual making an election under subsection (a) who is described by subparagraph (A), (C), or (E) of paragraph (1) of that subsection, the amount of educational assistance payable to the individual under this chapter 33 as a monthly stipend payable under paragraph (1)(B) of section 3313(c) of this title, or under paragraphs (2) through (7) of that section (as applicable), shall be the amount otherwise payable as a monthly stipend under the applicable paragraph increased by the amount equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H287DC9AD8B554AB0A50725577C9B2859"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount of contributions toward basic educational assistance made by the individual under section 3011(b) or 3012(c) of this title, as of the date of the election, multiplied by</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3C0CA4003CE4D299EAFF01C0DD68492"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the fraction—</text> <clause id="H615E8F4F2DE94B2D9DF8CB64F8DFD27D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the numerator of which is—</text>
 <subclause id="HCC7D1A6DE62441F58F36EC23FAE27454"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of months of entitlement to basic educational assistance under chapter 30 of this title remaining to the individual at the time of the election; plus</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H07423B830E114DD8A1892551147B715A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of months, if any, of entitlement under such chapter 30 revoked by the individual under subsection (c)(1); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAD41A3B7A9594EBABC7BCE53F5DCCA67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the denominator of which is 36 months.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07418A57BA474DAE917541BC1D2C2432"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Months of remaining entitlement for certain individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual covered by paragraph (1) who is described by subsection (a)(1)(E), the number of months of entitlement to basic educational assistance remaining to the individual for purposes of paragraph (1)(B)(i)(II) shall be 36 months.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B2EC8B7700A444597767292C08735BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing of payment</header><text>The amount payable with respect to an individual under paragraph (1) shall be paid to the individual together with the last payment of the monthly stipend payable to the individual under paragraph (1)(B) of section 3313(c) of this title, or under subsections (b) through (g) of that section (as applicable), before the exhaustion of the individual’s entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34575BF5A115436BA635B5C4C3B1BB0A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Continuing entitlement to additional assistance for critical skills or speciality and additional
 service</header><text>An individual making an election under subsection (a)(1) who, at the time of the election, is entitled to increased educational assistance under section 3015(d) of this title, or section 16131(i) of title 10, or supplemental educational assistance under subchapter III of chapter 30 of this title, shall remain entitled to such increased educational assistance or supplemental educational assistance in the utilization of entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter, in an amount equal to the quarter, semester, or term, as applicable, equivalent of the monthly amount of such increased educational assistance or supplemental educational assistance payable with respect to the individual at the time of the election.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HBC1CCC946620421989BC15D942FDB80E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Alternative election by Secretary</header>
 <paragraph id="H737C071ABA0F4399B9DA5642D9AA6C99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an individual who, on or after January 1, 2016, submits to the Secretary an election under this section that the Secretary determines is clearly against the interests of the individual, the Secretary may make an alternative election on behalf of the individual that the Secretary determines is in the best interests of the individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52738E7AA7334FFC981D9ECB89B0E528"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary makes an election on behalf of an individual under this subsection, the Secretary shall notify the individual by not later than seven days after making such election and shall provide the individual with a 30-day period, beginning on the date of the individual’s receipt of such notice, during which the individual may modify or revoke the election made by the Secretary on the individual’s behalf. The Secretary shall include, as part of such notice, a clear statement of why the alternative election made by the Secretary is in the best interests of the individual as compared to the election submitted by the individual. The Secretary shall provide the notice required under this paragraph by electronic means whenever possible.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF527E12F46704EBB9070240560D057E0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Irrevocability of elections</header><text>An election under subsection (a) or (c)(1) is irrevocable.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H10F2E0FC57A147429F43AE82BF7669C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4B9FA0F73A74EF18D7209EF53423F40" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">3326. Election to receive educational assistance.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3912455999A94583805E5FEA1BB3A1BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 5003 of the Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/252">Public Law 110–252</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3301">38 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref> note) is hereby repealed.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0927D391BD7483AAC830A4A04F5B873" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Centralized reporting of veteran enrollment by certain groups, districts, and consortiums of
			 educational institutions</header>
 <subsection id="HE9970797BC024522BE56BA3DD8946320"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3684(a) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB8342F58A4E841CD8EB1FD39EF0DA0C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>32, 33,</quote> after <quote>31,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FF522F1F53541A6A79B4175BDAEF975"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC800FEFEDB9D4E809508DCA8B7F1E0BB" style="USC"> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9ADE043F2A4C4901940CD853498D568A" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>educational institution</term> may include a group, district, or consortium of separately accredited educational institutions located in the same State that are organized in a manner that facilitates the centralized reporting of the enrollments in such group, district, or consortium of institutions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A417816641E49B6BE84AD9C7DDDAA40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to reports submitted on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE626FF1054994061B0E152AD86E11E1D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Provision of information regarding veteran entitlement to educational assistance</header>
 <subsection id="HA3D2D4867F1245598F1A0B97085A0445"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/36">chapter 36</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AB9E716DA804C69BE4A727A35A25B90" style="USC">
 <section id="HAE962C9DC315490E9F4D9AB914F9BC62"><enum>3699.</enum><header>Provision of certain information to educational institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For each veteran or other individual pursuing a course of education that has been approved under this chapter using educational assistance to which the veteran or other individual is entitled under chapter 30, 32, 33, or 35 of this title, the Secretary shall make available to the educational institution offering the course information about the amount of such educational assistance to which the veteran or other individual is entitled. Such information shall be provided to such educational institution through an Internet website and shall be regularly updated to reflect any amounts used by the veteran or other individual.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA23BF01B742E462197ED5D22FF3F372F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3698 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFF7369CF9D14202995C561FC077C700" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">3699. Provision of certain information to educational institutions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


