<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9A9C722889DD472EAE557A4D2816E152" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 102 IH: Corporate Crime Database Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 102</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a corporate crime database, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFFE847BE230940B5916803F803A6B63D" style="OLC">
		<section id="HA9A87A2F52834F4D922FD398B2F5B1AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corporate Crime Database Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H09408E11E9104DC08CF07AF93DC9EA4C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Attorney General to acquire data on corporate-related crime</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under the authority of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/534">section 534</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, and in accordance with this
			 Act, the Attorney General shall acquire data, for each calendar year,
			 regarding all administrative, civil, and criminal judicial proceedings
			 initiated or concluded by the Federal Government and State governments
			 against any corporation or corporate official acting in an official
			 capacity involving a felony or misdemeanor charge or any civil charge
			 where potential fines may be $1,000 or more.</text>
		</section><section id="H75AA5BEA86C24A5DAC180B1247746F9B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administrative details</header>
			<subsection id="H7EE03EAF222D441EADD71FA831464D11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting by Federal agencies</header><text>Each department and agency within the Federal Government shall report details about all
			 administrative, civil, and criminal judicial proceedings initiated or
			 concluded in that department or agency’s jurisdiction to the Attorney
			 General in a uniform manner and in a form prescribed by the Attorney
			 General.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6BFDCD0766F84945A8404B82B0E642BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish guidelines for the collection of data and otherwise to carry
			 out the purposes of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H728B93C8615341228E78F9CCAE9C797A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of causes of action</header><text>Nothing in this Act creates a cause of action or a right to bring an action. This Act does not
			 limit any existing cause of action or right to bring an action.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA3D101C5546E4435B0D519B9870156C2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Public Web site</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General shall establish and maintain a publicly available Web site with a database of
			 information regarding improper conduct by all corporations with revenues,
			 as determined under rules prescribed by the Attorney General, of over
			 $1,000,000,000 per annum.</text>
		</section><section id="HBF748D0D30D24BEC8E36B4970A1B6CB8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Information included in database</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The database—</text>
			<paragraph id="H9965C8577D594ABFB34927045EF8EDC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall consist of information regarding all administrative, civil, and criminal judicial proceedings
			 initiated or concluded by the Federal Government and State governments
			 against any corporation or corporate official acting in an official
			 capacity involving a felony or misdemeanor charge or any civil charge
			 where potential fines may be $1,000 or more; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H76EC7BC93EDC472CB74E316706EB8C6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall include, for each proceeding, a brief description of the proceeding, including the agency
			 bringing the charge, the charge, the name of the company charged, the
			 ultimate parent company of the company charged, the locations of both the
			 company and parent company, and the outcome of the action if any,
			 including plea agreements, consent decrees, findings of innocence,
			 convictions, fines and other penalties.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H047837D12C8646199077EB40AAA37A3D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Input of data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General shall design and maintain the database in a manner that allows the appropriate
			 officials of each Federal department or agency directly to input and
			 update in the database information relating to actions that department or
			 agency has taken with regard to criminal or civil enforcement actions.</text>
		</section><section id="H54983C8D791643F9BA284F153C968AC6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General shall prepare an annual report to Congress detailing the number of civil,
			 administrative, and criminal enforcement actions brought against any
			 corporation or corporate official acting in an official capacity as well
			 as the ultimate disposition (including the magnitude and category of any
			 penalties assessed).</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


