<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB8C73B92B3B54FD296DD64D2127D8851" public-private="public" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 515 RS: International Megan’s Law to Prevent Demand for Child Sex Trafficking</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 296</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 515</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>January 28, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20150204">February 4, 2015</action-date><action-desc> Read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>November 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</sponsor>, with an amendment and an amendment to the title</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect children from exploitation, especially sex trafficking in tourism, by providing advance
			 notice of intended travel by registered child-sex offenders outside the
			 United States to the government of the country of destination, requesting
			 foreign governments to notify the United States when a known child-sex
			 offender is seeking to enter the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7EBCD12608BC4FCFB896724645996916" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak>
		<section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HBA095D23944F4870901CDF06664B8359" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H1CA3124B03194FAABC09B8542CEF5BC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Megan’s Law to Prevent Demand for Child Sex Trafficking</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HD8FD1683EABE4F46B335321428737F84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><toc-entry idref="HBA095D23944F4870901CDF06664B8359" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEAAD70BB8BA841B7AC9865EB5132715D" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDE33119609CC4435AF9F256237B0E3A9" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1E344026EF68446798B3D183C862F225" level="section">Sec. 4. Angel Watch Center.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H72D910BBA2C4405CBFA8A39EEFCC8F34" level="section">Sec. 5. Sense of Congress provisions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H67419B84EFFC46B383B7A478C9A2D416" level="section">Sec. 6. Enhancing the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBEEFCA055DF4468FBE6F7D78055CDC38" level="section">Sec. 7. Assistance to foreign countries to meet minimum standards for the elimination of
			 trafficking.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7CB6794670054C1288D47E3EEFB87D8D" level="section">Sec. 8. Rules of construction.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HEAAD70BB8BA841B7AC9865EB5132715D" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7640755754E64F4AABD2594F59EEC4F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Megan Nicole Kanka, who was 7 years old, was abducted, sexually assaulted, and murdered in 1994, in the State of New Jersey by a violent predator living across the street from her home. Unbeknownst to Megan Kanka and her family, he had been convicted previously of a sex offense against a child.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA89B2FF664A14D958CBF2FEF1AB17131"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 1996, Congress adopted Megan’s Law (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/145">Public Law 104–145</external-xref>) as a means to encourage States to protect children by identifying the whereabouts of sex offenders and providing the means to monitor their activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0322F9B794B4EF18E170F304CAD10F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2006, Congress passed the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/248">Public Law 109–248</external-xref>) to protect children and the public at large by establishing a comprehensive national system for the registration and notification to the public and law enforcement officers of convicted sex offenders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE666C2B6569949BE9A5E1D36ED462A22"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Law enforcement reports indicate that known child-sex offenders are traveling internationally, and that the criminal background of such individuals may not be known to local law enforcement prior to their arrival.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94721A919A58468AAF079A37137AA4B6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The commercial sexual exploitation of minors in child sex trafficking and pornography is a global phenomenon. The International Labour Organization has estimated that 1.8 million children worldwide are victims of child sex trafficking and pornography each year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H47FFA46985344EC3945FDC4B7616D014"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Child sex tourism, where an individual travels to a foreign country and engages in sexual activity with a child in that country, is a form of child exploitation and, where commercial, child sex trafficking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D1B3D998A2145F6AA7A452532FD222C"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to research conducted by The Protection Project of The Johns Hopkins University Paul H. Nitze School of Advanced International Studies, sex tourists from the United States who target children form a significant percentage of child sex tourists in some of the most significant destination countries for child sex tourism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4787DB10D5FE4A21BBBD4D50D9E7FFB5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In order to protect children, it is essential that United States law enforcement be able to identify child-sex offenders in the United States who are traveling abroad and child-sex offenders from other countries entering the United States. Such identification requires cooperative efforts between the United States and foreign governments. In exchange for providing notice of child-sex offenders traveling to the United States, foreign authorities will expect United States authorities to provide reciprocal notice of child-sex offenders traveling to their countries.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HDE33119609CC4435AF9F256237B0E3A9" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H899EACCE94EB4123B1D7AD443AC0A88C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Center</term> means the Angel Watch Center established pursuant to section 4(a).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H75126327A63E41C38A6066A837D48F93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child-sex offender</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD50AD5B898674AE8BFC40A9C317B88EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>child-sex offender</term> means an individual who is a sex offender described in paragraph (3) or (4) of section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>) by reason of being convicted of a child-sex offense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC42F98FAFA254BA7AB0B227B91AD96F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definition of convicted</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>convicted</term> has the meaning given the term in paragraph (8) of section 111 of such Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33A822F536B048EBB5D061A9993E5296"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Child-sex offense</header> <subparagraph id="H100F44C3A0CA4D9D9C56626F631056BD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>child-sex offense</term> means a specified offense against a minor, as defined in paragraph (7) of section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>), including—</text>
 <clause id="H4A6337B0D448431EAAF33B4B2428D7CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an offense (unless committed by a parent or guardian) involving kidnapping;</text> </clause><clause id="HD77C256EA64E49CCAF7DBE48894062BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an offense (unless committed by a parent or guardian) involving false imprisonment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8DBC4AB6A17743A795AF897BDF13DC17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>solicitation to engage in sexual conduct;</text> </clause><clause id="HE19C85F13970455E98E355EBCA288FCA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>use in a sexual performance;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0685894BEA754786A947DFF20F715F0A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>solicitation to practice prostitution;</text> </clause><clause id="H76B72A196C7948FC96D93B066F62EE20"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>video voyeurism as described in section 1801 of title 18, United States Code;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H55CDB8CD58444CE19E6E78D488479A03"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>possession, production, or distribution of child pornography;</text> </clause><clause id="H1D727EFC5D134BADA35D615CE9D285C4"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>criminal sexual conduct involving a minor, or the use of the Internet to facilitate or attempt such conduct; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H19389CFEFE814E93ABE3180D4A028FB4"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>any conduct that by its nature is a sex offense against a minor.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75CB3322106E4EA388B42971A768BDBD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other offenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>child-sex offense</quote> includes a sex offense described in paragraph (5)(A) of section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 that is a specified offense against a minor, as defined in paragraph (7) of such section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21C25A4AABAE40ACA87FD094FB5CB5C2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Foreign convictions; offenses involving consensual sexual conduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The limitations contained in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 111(5) of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 shall apply with respect to a child-sex offense for purposes of this Act to the same extent and in the same manner as such limitations apply with respect to a sex offense for purposes of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7A6D85C1F15141B6956D169C1A3B3343"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>jurisdiction</term> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H358FA1199C3643FABF5377805DF1BA92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE040A724CD9A408D89840E161A6B4B4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The District of Columbia.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4ABA2045921B41D8B7B011F6BF81C60D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4D1123E923C34767BE6BE3ABF895E82A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Guam.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H07492D7903F34B0D9AACF22396EDCD23"><enum>(E)</enum><text>American Samoa.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H44E035097CA447F58A025E13EB690F26"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Northern Mariana Islands.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2252F705004F42DC951BAEC3F99E009F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The United States Virgin Islands.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE491426B42B64697A2D2D28805A2B45D"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent provided in, and subject to the requirements of, section 127 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16927">42 U.S.C. 16927</external-xref>), a federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF604C42FBC284D7EA15DC7A0C0779852"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years.</text> </paragraph></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H1E344026EF68446798B3D183C862F225" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>4.</enum><header>Angel Watch Center</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H08540A4766CE46D08D13D6A4E78249EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish within the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) of the Department of Homeland Security a Center, to be known as the <quote>Angel Watch Center</quote>, to carry out the activities specified in subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4C1EE9CED3DB47AA8139D207E2CF937D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall be headed by the Director of ICE, in collaboration with the Commissioner of United States Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and in consultation with the Attorney General.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD8F90119573E43E3B3D22A9A89C30F23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall consist of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9502D4207C5544E28CD9847773FC2D85"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of ICE.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B809034652D4040B20BE8310D5AF8DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of CBP.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H951F47D4A48E44E8BC6D406E2DE1BD97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Individuals who are designated as analysts in ICE or CBP.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05B83085F1E847578465ACCBBF529952"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals who are designated as program managers in ICE or CBP.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA979B7BDA85F41E982EB200C92D58F66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Activities</header> <paragraph id="HBDA849A8BFD24D578E7D0F95F9CEA903"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Center shall carry out the following activities:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3F77E5FFAE104D608EFA25A89D871CFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Receive information on travel by child-sex offenders.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD9685F05E554BA98859891F866CE335"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish a system to maintain and archive all relevant information, including the response of destination countries to notifications under subsection (e) where available, and decisions not to transmit notification abroad.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66E9E8C61CCE406F9824F9E934ADF8EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Establish an annual review process to ensure that the Center is consistent in procedures to provide notification to destination countries or not to provide notification to destination countries, as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF06C4A6002154A02BD5E8C0AA9498B78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Office shall make available to the Center information on travel by child-sex offenders in a timely manner for purposes of carrying out the activities described in paragraph (1) and subsection (e).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4FDB1F55B14432C9D385469EF4DD200"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notification</header>
				<paragraph id="H0D0FA96A656143969FCA5FDF48ECA856"><enum>(1)</enum><header>To countries of destination</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9E50C1FF9AE84971875DA22325E41422"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Center may transmit notice of impending or current international travel of a child-sex offender to the country or countries of destination of the child-sex offender, including to the visa-issuing agent or agents in the United States of the country or countries.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6188137A7D784C23A7F163C82D4D23C3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The notice under this paragraph may be transmitted through such means as determined appropriate by the Center, including through an ICE attaché.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B9D2BE699EA48E9AC01AD3FE0CB6B8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>To offenders</header>
					<subparagraph commented="no" id="H9E1DE578DDE84BD59EA5867B75BD0ECD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>General notification</header>
 <clause id="H879B7C41150049878D9BF403D5ADCB87"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Center transmits notice under paragraph (1) of impending international travel of a child-sex offender to the country or countries of destination of the child-sex offender, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in conjunction with any appropriate agency, shall make reasonable efforts to provide constructive notice through electronic or telephonic communication to the child-sex offender prior to the child-sex offender’s arrival in the country or countries.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEF0A0CC36AC0473E9E1ADBB7164859C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to provide constructive notice under clause (i) shall not apply in the case of impending international travel of a child-sex offender to the country or countries of destination of the child-sex offender if such constructive notice would conflict with an existing investigation involving the child-sex offender.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2EDE4429E1154CD7A0A7532EDCF50618"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specific notification regarding risk to life or well-being of offender</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Center has reason to believe that to transmit notice under paragraph (1) poses a risk to the life or well-being of the child-sex offender, the Center shall make reasonable efforts to provide constructive notice through electronic or telephonic communication to the child-sex offender of such risk.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H523FE3851F014FA387C65F48D445E636"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Specific notification regarding probable denial of entry to offender</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Center has reason to believe that a country of destination of the child-sex offender is highly likely to deny entry to the child-sex offender due to transmission of notice under paragraph (1), the Center shall make reasonable efforts to provide constructive notice through electronic or telephonic communication to the child-sex offender of such probable denial.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50A5CD7180ED480689905849F6BA822B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of paragraph (1) shall terminate with respect to a child-sex offender beginning as of the close of the last day of the registration period of such child-sex offender under section 115 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16915">42 U.S.C. 16915</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H608146E1860045EBAA2E521B20B8D431"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Complaint review</header><text>The Center shall establish a mechanism to receive complaints from child-sex offenders affected by notifications of destination countries of such child-sex offenders under subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1555794C38394F44839170E2EC460C7A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>The Center shall seek to engage in ongoing consultations with—</text> <paragraph id="HC80C2F77ED5D4AA68D8C04254C4B5BB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations, including faith-based organizations, that have experience and expertise in identifying and preventing child sex tourism and rescuing and rehabilitating minor victims of international sexual exploitation and trafficking;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2055ACF42544E76BA2D4C30FB5110A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the governments of countries interested in cooperating in the creation of an international sex offender travel notification system or that are primary destination or source countries for international sex tourism; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H069B3268FEC148278FEFF7957FAE8B15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Internet service and software providers regarding available and potential technology to facilitate the implementation of an international sex offender travel notification system, both in the United States and in other countries.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8603723A689649039F2BD08B5F8DC897"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State may provide technical assistance to foreign authorities in order to enable such authorities to participate more effectively in the notification program system established under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H72D910BBA2C4405CBFA8A39EEFCC8F34" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sense of Congress provisions</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H5B6738157C8947BC98BA80DED0D4CF1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bilateral agreements</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the President should negotiate memoranda of understanding or other bilateral agreements with foreign governments to further the purposes of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, including by—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H1EECB74BD9FD42D8A97E45F37CD00C34"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing systems to receive and transmit notices as required by title I of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H060F3354C12E4A8288684EC566E69264"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing mechanisms for private companies and nongovernmental organizations to report on a voluntary basis suspected child pornography or exploitation to foreign governments, the nearest United States embassy in cases in which a possible United States citizen may be involved, or other appropriate entities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB95018922C4F4CCD8CE3293E77E28776"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification to the United States of Child-Sex Offenses Committed Abroad</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the President should formally request foreign governments to notify the United States when a United States citizen has been arrested, convicted, sentenced, or completed a prison sentence for a child-sex offense in the foreign country.</text>
 </subsection></section><section changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H67419B84EFFC46B383B7A478C9A2D416" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>6.</enum><header>Enhancing the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 108(b)(4) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7106">22 U.S.C. 7106(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end before the period the following: <quote>, including severe forms of trafficking in persons related to sex tourism</quote>.</text>
 </section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HBEEFCA055DF4468FBE6F7D78055CDC38" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>7.</enum><header>Assistance to foreign countries to meet minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President is strongly encouraged to exercise the authorities of section 134 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152d">22 U.S.C. 2152d</external-xref>) to provide assistance to foreign countries directly, or through nongovernmental and multilateral organizations, for programs, projects, and activities, including training of law enforcement entities and officials, designed to establish systems to identify sex offenders and provide and receive notification of child sex offender international travel.</text>
		</section><section changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H7CB6794670054C1288D47E3EEFB87D8D" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H2706FBA09A62499F92C20FA4E8FAF8DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Justice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preclude or alter the jurisdiction or authority of the Department of Justice under the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>), including section 113(d) of such Act, or any other provision of law, or to affect the work of the United States Marshals Service with INTERPOL.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF470429DB1D94529A66797F31741F6DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Angel Watch Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preclude the Angel Watch Center from transmitting notice with respect to any sex offender described in paragraph (3) or (4) of section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>) or with respect to any sex offense described in paragraph (5) of such section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA9DCFB75FC1D47E6BCCA5CEDABE187A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security investigations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities carried out under this Act shall not impede, hinder, or otherwise impact negatively any investigations of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC">
		<section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H9BC43FD553B24919B7816894DEE19D49" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H2117D261E78C44DB960652285BFFD5D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0FA13A1F33AE47F8BE4E84AE6A2CE2F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" reported-display-style="italic"><toc-entry idref="H9BC43FD553B24919B7816894DEE19D49" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id121b403ee5c34cd4bb0536315274394f" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idcf9642c9f5f446f492761e05d44e3565" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id9254af3c6a524408972e440aa2f413d6" level="section">Sec. 4. Angel Watch Center.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id435083be350542a3aa4e237c84697352" level="section">Sec. 5. Notification by the United States Marshals Service.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id541f66f3180e42c4bbbb176477e2747c" level="section">Sec. 6. International travel.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idd7953717508e4510b61bee64f08b677d" level="section">Sec. 7. Reciprocal notifications.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idcd83c5b320dd40938cd832cce3d6e663" level="section">Sec. 8. Unique passport identifiers for covered sex offenders.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idc2dab01c2e1a4fe5ada55bf590fa7b32" level="section">Sec. 9. Implementation plan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id4b83a87dfe4b4a8eb6e448ffc3de5cd9" level="section">Sec. 10. Technical assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="ida3e6002041b44c4ea318f5e178c2b22f" level="section">Sec. 11. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idd74e91997bb24b6e90555d1e7ef1f351" level="section">Sec. 12. Rule of construction.</toc-entry></toc> </subsection></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id121b403ee5c34cd4bb0536315274394f" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idcf380c6ac8cc49c6981aac8293503ae7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Megan Nicole Kanka, who was 7 years old, was abducted, sexually assaulted, and murdered in 1994, in the State of New Jersey by a violent predator living across the street from her home. Unbeknownst to Megan Kanka and her family, he had been convicted previously of a sex offense against a child.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf593fb2e66f54416b38f011a2c822069"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 1996, Congress adopted Megan’s Law (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/145">Public Law 104–145</external-xref>) as a means to encourage States to protect children by identifying the whereabouts of sex offenders and providing the means to monitor their activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6ea72b2473554675accb91adfd483054"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2006, Congress passed the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/248">Public Law 109–248</external-xref>) to protect children and the public at large by establishing a comprehensive national system for the registration and notification to the public and law enforcement officers of convicted sex offenders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8640ab2807d64f9081b62fe2dee95b6c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Law enforcement reports indicate that known child-sex offenders are traveling internationally.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9060718021684781a5d70889f01c30fa"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The commercial sexual exploitation of minors in child sex trafficking and pornography is a global phenomenon. The International Labour Organization has estimated that 1,8000,000 children worldwide are victims of child sex trafficking and pornography each year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ideedd991c9872461bafe8e97fa235aa02"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Child sex tourism, where an individual travels to a foreign country and engages in sexual activity with a child in that country, is a form of child exploitation and, where commercial, child sex trafficking.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idcf9642c9f5f446f492761e05d44e3565" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id0e087feb32ed43d787f5e1d96d3c1de8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Center</header><text>The term <term>Center</term> means the Angel Watch Center established pursuant to section 4(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide8c40c67bceb4c37bd84a23506c7c474"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Convicted</header><text>The term <term>convicted</term> has the meaning given the term in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9fdf134344fe409bbaf25b82dcf5ff20"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered sex offender</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, the term <term>covered sex offender</term> means an individual who is a sex offender by reason of having been convicted of a sex offense against a minor.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f7c3e5cc6354e46b178cc42af0f593c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Destination country</header><text>The term <term>destination country</term> means a destination or transit country.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id041feaff03ac4a868759038cc5612e8e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interpol</header><text>The term <term>INTERPOL</term> means the International Criminal Police Organization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id04dc5b313bbd45ac81fc4b116ec6cd72"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>The term <term>jurisdiction</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idf3eff02a5f984e15aa78713748ae79cc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0b6060e63a364a9cbcac2b3b1ec4ca76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6007558ebf144cb3880a0c7e01c1b4f1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ab7e1dd4d5d41dc92c98b3f38214e4c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Guam;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ecc7a33293747acabd9d6b2dc34edeb"><enum>(E)</enum><text>American Samoa;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84e7d88d683a474abfbd5d6ffcffa221"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Northern Mariana Islands;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12e8de679cd248ba9c1797ae5d537770"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the United States Virgin Islands; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52e1e39dbd614e1e9ca56a07434379e8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to the extent provided in, and subject to the requirements of, section 127 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16927">42 U.S.C. 16927</external-xref>), a Federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id40cd1abc652240a0bf58fec19a483656"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id72af9b6b52594a848834a9908fa019fd"><enum>(8)</enum><header>National sex offender registry</header><text>The term <term>National Sex Offender Registry</term> means the National Sex Offender Registry established by section 119 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16919">42 U.S.C. 16919</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9b2d95886624444bb5c5a9693cd6e0da"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Sex offender under sorna</header><text>The term <term>sex offender under SORNA</term> has the meaning given the term <term>sex offender</term> in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id67fc50b0312a4dcfbfbbfb1cd42684aa"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Sex offense against a minor</header> <subparagraph id="id89a3c11673e746f896c1a206d7ca317b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>sex offense against a minor</term> means a specified offense against a minor, as defined in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida2d96d7dfd3d4435b2da432d2bb1247e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other offenses</header><text>The term <term>sex offense against a minor</term> includes a sex offense described in section 111(5)(A) of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911(5)(A)</external-xref>) that is a specified offense against a minor, as defined in paragraph (7) of such section, or an attempt or conspiracy to commit such an offense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfb4e898fe6545bba3548a0b93e6665c"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Foreign convictions; offenses involving consensual sexual conduct</header><text>The limitations contained in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 111(5) of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911(5)</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to a sex offense against a minor for purposes of this Act to the same extent and in the same manner as such limitations apply with respect to a sex offense for purposes of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id9254af3c6a524408972e440aa2f413d6" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>4.</enum><header>Angel Watch Center</header>
 <subsection id="id003fc8d13778494485fb33c4ae89c5d9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish within the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of U.S. Immigrations and Customs Enforcement a Center, to be known as the <quote>Angel Watch Center</quote>, to carry out the activities specified in subsection (e).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id489efb51b80447b6a5eb08265a0723ed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Incoming notification</header>
 <paragraph id="idf615dfa3591643bdb5b738ad12ab9f44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Center may receive incoming notifications concerning individuals seeking to enter the United States who have committed offenses of a sexual nature.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4107d77dcb18434c9c9bde7ad83e48f7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Upon receiving an incoming notification under paragraph (1), the Center shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id02df638c3f83478b950973acb624fcfa"><enum>(A)</enum><text>immediately share all information received relating to the individual with the Department of Justice; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba227116fa1740d2a9261af6afd7d751"><enum>(B)</enum><text>share all relevant information relating to the individual with other Federal, State, and local agencies and entities, as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id17ff769ba0994e099a5e565120b5529a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall collaborate with the Attorney General to establish a process for the receipt, dissemination, and categorization of information relating to individuals and specific offenses provided herein.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8b5d78127e1d475f957eeae9b07194dc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Center shall be headed by the Assistant Secretary of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, in collaboration with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id48bc0b00862547ce9b90c7cca743de13"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Center shall consist of the following:</text> <paragraph id="idf4e7c85ba2bc497d87fe107cf6bd47bb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc36d939c1b664f87884d6948e730202b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd3cbf8728fab46b4ba4572dbe12e7522"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Individuals who are designated as analysts in U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0938dd870cab4aba869a9b649f3eff72"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Individuals who are designated as program managers in U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc08712ec1c2142af8f435b3fbb45cafb"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Activities</header>
 <paragraph id="idf25f19e0210c4353a0534f6a4f43f3f4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Center shall, using all relevant databases, systems and sources of information, not later than 48 hours before scheduled departure, or as soon as practicable before scheduled departure—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8bc1d48acf644d149abc7a0f8525fc35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine if individuals traveling abroad are listed on the National Sex Offender Registry;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70655743c6124ee5907c3702680bbe7b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center case management system or other system that provides access to a list of individuals who have provided advanced notice of international travel to identify any individual who meets the criteria described in subparagraph (A) and is not in a system reviewed pursuant to this subparagraph; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56b537b4617b4ba0a78b9007f3da17df"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide a list of individuals identified under subparagraph (B) to the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center to determine compliance with title I of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id31b06e5c6f364589a58ef03cbd7b0b61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision of information to center</header><text>Twenty-four hours before the intended travel, or thereafter, not later than 72 hours after the intended travel, the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall provide, to the Angel Watch Center, information pertaining to any sex offender described in subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idc56a8d03b4bd41dba79436d5ed100722"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advance notice to destination country</header>
 <subparagraph id="id0d85e088a4fc4aa69bd562145db205e1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Center may transmit relevant information to the destination country about a sex offender if—</text> <clause id="id61a4117692fa44979aa3cd182b5c2aa2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the individual is identified by a review conducted under paragraph (1)(B) as having provided advanced notice of international travel; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide20da742bec84facb54622f9caf4d6d3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>after completing the activities described in paragraph (1), the Center receives information pertaining to a sex offender under paragraph (2).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb9a7f300b7c148d5baf7a244b7a45ae6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The Center may immediately transmit relevant information on a sex offender to the destination country if—</text>
 <clause id="id2d5e3e27285345669d70d8f7145454f5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Center becomes aware that a sex offender is traveling outside of the United States within 24 hours of intended travel, and simultaneously completes the activities described in paragraph (1); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfaea4b1c1c4a4cc2aa63bf720f0815fe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Center has not received a transmission pursuant to paragraph (2), provided it is not more than 24 hours before the intended travel.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c3e402e687246f591288e9dfc9678fb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text>Upon receiving information that a notification sent by the Center regarding an individual was inaccurate, the Center shall immediately—</text>
 <clause id="idc485f698dce74d17a54a1197b42e8691"><enum>(i)</enum><text>send a notification of correction to the destination country notified;</text> </clause><clause id="idb20894a86c71453ebe1ef911873270dd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>correct all data collected pursuant to paragraph (6); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4a9f78e10fd446e1986e3858e80860ff"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if applicable, notify the Secretary of State for purposes of the passport review and marking processes described in section 240 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/457">Public Law 110–457</external-xref>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc02c6ba7563a42888ecfdf4c8ef3b8ab"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The notification under this paragraph may be transmitted through such means as are determined appropriate by the Center, including through U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement attaches.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1bbad0dba2845068dd3bfd1fa2f0f80"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Memorandum of agreement</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall enter into a Memorandum of Agreement with the Attorney General to facilitate the activities of the Angel Watch Center in collaboration with the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center, including the exchange of information, the sharing of personnel, access to information and databases in accordance with paragraph (1)(B), and the establishment of a process to share notifications from the international community in accordance with subsection (b)(1).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idc104e59c05924445a193cb8b2bc6b419"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Passport application review</header>
 <subparagraph id="idcda0c001af7c4bdeaea74e92cdc1241b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Center shall provide a written determination to the Department of State regarding the status of an individual as a covered sex offender (as defined in section 240 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/457">Public Law 110–457</external-xref>) when appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd0b9817d7784e058411e503e47b7d38"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall take effect upon certification by the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Attorney General that the process developed and reported to the appropriate congressional committees under section 9 has been successfully implemented.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bf7085c33f84a67a237c054dc3d337a"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Collection of data</header><text>The Center shall collect all relevant data, including—</text> <subparagraph id="ideba87f54c6774b0ba6de6a24a181bcd1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a record of each notification sent under paragraph (3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideba2a356cf3c46da92b8d90a1f4e0ce9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the response of the destination country to notifications under paragraph (3), where available;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa7644f0dc82472aa6f5936ced591b14"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any decision not to transmit a notification abroad, to the extent practicable;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf964ed14cd24b9ebfe6a5a2b2e8fcfa"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of transmissions made under subparagraphs (A),(B), and (C) of paragraph (3) and the countries to which they are transmitted, respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40f16541bf7c44198449ebf32b5e906f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the information was transmitted to the destination country before scheduled commencement of sex offender travel; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4eb2cff108741b1981d379529486966"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other information deemed necessary and appropriate by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id64d3ad438273438b9b4242ca72c001cc"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Complaint review</header> <subparagraph id="id27F9EA6D24D34DCFAB4A177C37721333"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Center shall—</text>
 <clause id="idE5386264607F46B4B139379D1B00B38C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish a mechanism to receive complaints from individuals affected by erroneous notifications under this section;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC3C4FB23821F4BFEA7AC5845E0A48C8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that any complaint is promptly reviewed; and</text> </clause><clause id="idbeb9c79a7ea34317ad2b3aaa1db420c1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a complaint that involves a notification sent by another Federal Government entity, notify the individual of the contact information for the appropriate entity and forward the complaint to the appropriate entity for prompt review and response pursuant to this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb55c8bca66ac49c9a3ec0b5dc52a7e8f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Response to complaints</header><text>The Center shall, as applicable—</text> <clause id="id59358e0c513e41eb9b1c46aa9eb3594c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide the individual with notification in writing that the individual was erroneously subjected to international notification;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3f6e4862ae1a4e48bc4aec59583c2c46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>take action to ensure that a notification or information regarding the individual is not erroneously transmitted to a destination country in the future; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9d2bde7a0cfa45b8aa0a31372f40f2f4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>submit an additional written notification to the individual explaining why a notification or information regarding the individual was erroneously transmitted to the destination country and describing the actions that the Center has taken or is taking under clause (ii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida329059956ca47c586317a67100251be"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public Awareness</header><text>The Center shall make publicly available information on how an individual may submit a complaint under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e7bfccf7bf54b88b404810297c9cadf"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reporting Requirement</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit an annual report to the appropriate congressional committees (as defined in section 9) that includes—</text>
 <clause id="id3743a60277d64f86a8dc7a801afcc24c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of instances in which a notification or information was erroneously transmitted to the destination country of an individual under paragraph (3); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id18076d783307445a94ecf09cdc57ea03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the actions taken to prevent similar errors from occurring in the future.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7159608437ff4bb4a06ca6ee5de52d43"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Annual review process</header><text>The Center shall establish, in coordination with the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, and INTERPOL, an annual review process to ensure that there is appropriate coordination and collaboration, including consistent procedures governing the activities authorized under this Act, in carrying out this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id873b979b1682465c8ac6cbfcb873a9aa"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>The Center shall make available to the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center information on travel by sex offenders in a timely manner.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id882108b6adde4f8488da0d8bcd8b58d4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>sex offender</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="ida09bc56889a343a99c63c20847540b60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a covered sex offender; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idaa6b4b049aed43cf82d96c054033a8d3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an individual required to register under the sex offender registration program of any jurisdiction or included in the National Sex Offender Registry, on the basis of an offense against a minor.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id435083be350542a3aa4e237c84697352" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>5.</enum><header>Notification by the united states marshals service</header>
 <subsection id="id3e2e069ed7be47c0abe8b463deff0062"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center may—</text> <paragraph id="id6fae6687adb84fc59933d48224409d9d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transmit notification of international travel of a sex offender to the destination country of the sex offender, including to the visa-issuing agent or agents in the United States of the country;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idba18d75d569e40e288bd98b411875a22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>share information relating to traveling sex offenders with other Federal, State, local, and foreign agencies and entities, as appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4e4a13db26934ca2a2f2b085ababe7a9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>receive incoming notifications concerning individuals seeking to enter the United States who have committed offenses of a sexual nature and shall share the information received immediately with the Department of Homeland Security; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide353c751c70c40a883652d3a8c27c8af"><enum>(4)</enum><text>perform such other functions at the Attorney General or the Director of the United States Marshals Service may direct.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb0301aaa36384670b5cc1839f1bb9a0e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consistent notification</header><text>In making notifications under subsection (a)(1), the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall, to the extent feasible and appropriate, ensure that the destination country is consistently notified in advance about sex offenders under SORNA identified through their inclusion in sex offender registries of jurisdictions or the National Sex Offender Registry.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="iddd4f3541234f4970a5b4fd89fbc85cec"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this Act, the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="ida347e76862fa4bcd9e83b2fda156b7ef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make the case management system or other system that provides access to a list of individuals who have provided advanced notice of international travel available to the Angel Watch Center;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9ebcfcf813ed4c728938c6c0104e82ec"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide the Angel Watch Center a determination of compliance with title I of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>) for the list of individuals transmitted under section 4(e)(1)(C);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4831e335b73b47e0a6f0e0dba9d36751"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make available to the Angel Watch Center information on travel by sex offenders in a timely manner; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb758ae77876644dcbb1b09bc5ec69d70"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with the Department of State regarding operation of the international notification program authorized under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfacf9a9b749244bbb134e765a663d5f1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text>Upon receiving information that a notification sent by the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center regarding an individual was inaccurate, the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall immediately—</text>
 <paragraph id="ida0db248b727b493286c3332cbaeac91b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>send a notification of correction to the destination country notified;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2e2ee3d146c347289a5e167e4e387a52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>correct all data collected in accordance with subsection (f); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f474aaa91de4232a7ef7734b6f16ca2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if applicable, send a notification of correction to the Angel Watch Center.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd2c1acfe73a443fba67f9441c853530e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The notification under this section may be transmitted through such means as are determined appropriate by the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center, including through the INTERPOL notification system and through Federal Bureau of Investigation Legal attaches.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id09fa8b42fe23484f86e79c8fa99cbaaa"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Collection of data</header><text>The Attorney General shall collect all relevant data, including—</text> <paragraph id="id08eabcd3643d4510aa4e21e20e2ec7dc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a record of each notification sent under subsection (a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida434825b23ee43b1b1b8b4a7cc53f703"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the response of the destination country to notifications under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), where available;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id604e5d037a0a40ad8c5fb2d5475786e9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any decision not to transmit a notification abroad, to the extent practicable;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id150028769fa646f9ae0b955171caae75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of transmissions made under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) and the countries to which they are transmitted;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb8472496efac4b6db94bf9e264a13f5b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>whether the information was transmitted to the destination country before scheduled commencement of sex offender travel; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf978b73d71634f3fb180fbf8442927bf"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other information deemed necessary and appropriate by the Attorney General.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0DE041658D4A4D19AAC7968C57030294"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Complaint review</header> <paragraph id="id56D4AA8E24574D128EAABAC1F784FB1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idF92B2CD62DFD4629B2CDE894F80DEB12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a mechanism to receive complaints from individuals affected by erroneous notifications under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA8A70235CAC3461396B2606F97D9B490"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that any complaint is promptly reviewed; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD0491FF9BA6249B79E033E70A00BED6A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a complaint that involves a notification sent by another Federal Government entity, notify the individual of the contact information for the appropriate entity and forward the complaint to the appropriate entity for prompt review and response pursuant to this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id679D1BADE3F14791BDAB0BA45ECAA05A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Response to complaints</header><text>The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall, as applicable—</text> <subparagraph id="id4F1AF65911AE479A8F349B22F0571A34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide the individual with notification in writing that the individual was erroneously subjected to international notification;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5A6BB3A62D9A44928E5147896A9F9E2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take action to ensure that a notification or information regarding the individual is not erroneously transmitted to a destination country in the future; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0A193D4D02F2473CA802D46ACA3B95E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit an additional written notification to the individual explaining why a notification or information regarding the individual was erroneously transmitted to the destination country and describing the actions that the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center has taken or is taking under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC4FB5D870AD54E508D19E79A63F3E5DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public Awareness</header><text>The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall make publicly available information on how an individual may submit a complaint under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE37CD23583C64A3EB91A9A5BD90CE755"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting Requirement</header><text>The Attorney General shall submit an annual report to the appropriate congressional committees (as defined in section 9) that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5E0BBF10016949F6B335F4518FF1BBB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of instances in which a notification or information was erroneously transmitted to the destination country of an individual under subsection (a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75ED03B1F7E04919ADB6D3A0128C0101"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the actions taken to prevent similar errors from occurring in the future.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1e1ff298764147f2975049ca1bcc4bae"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>sex offender</term> means—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf9b899de6516465d9ecd0842d760576b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a sex offender under SORNA; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id466cca74d19b4f4eb0730db99a2ecae6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a person required to register under the sex offender registration program of any jurisdiction or included in the National Sex Offender Registry.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id541f66f3180e42c4bbbb176477e2747c" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>6.</enum><header>International travel</header>
			<subsection id="id094a7ac8f83240cdaddb647db81ce3c4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement that sex offenders provide international travel related information to sex offender
 registries</header><text>Section 114 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16914">42 U.S.C. 16914</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idcc33f60eab25400e81e7df1ad2353d1d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id578e702105914317a86224e175d791e1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8); and;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24c3c51d8ded4a72be4b9a2709bef8ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC8FEA44A2DF2494A89B75966863953E5" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id80c5682824d246d2b253bfc9a4afd917"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Information relating to intended travel of the sex offender outside the United States, including any anticipated dates and places of departure, arrival, or return, carrier and flight numbers for air travel, destination country and address or other contact information therein, means and purpose of travel, and any other itinerary or other travel-related information required by the Attorney General.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idffac956c60514425acf55c954b53c540"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01B25ABCE2B4414294ADDE96F6C2B990" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="idc18b43cc43e446b68c3b7a83cf51f43c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Time and manner</header><text>A sex offender shall provide and update information required under subsection (a), including information relating to intended travel outside the United States required under paragraph (7) of that subsection, in conformity with any time and manner requirements prescribed by the Attorney General.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id58cb09fd557e4ab3a9eafd567b7a5717"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments to section 2250 of title 18, united states code</header><text>Section 2250 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id8c19dedf6acf4683b25a2dc69550a931"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida9fbd2e9ca124bb8b97f66ef1fde7ceb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66dd431ed8ac4d24a79097b284d894ac" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id2783141a0c3c4f44af7288ad894fffe8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>International travel reporting violations</header><text>Whoever—</text>
 <paragraph id="idc267fdd122ab466b8cdd4e52db16b640"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is required to register under the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2d0611f4c1044fc09d861c2255943f6e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly fails to provide information required by the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act relating to intended travel in foreign commerce; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id314b521337ff42828e561f0abcec0376"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engages or attempts to engage in the intended travel in foreign commerce;</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="id06b0884f0d974bb9b9f2413950c0f7a0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsections (c) and (d), as redesignated, by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (a) or (b)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ided4967d6e9e343d1bbcc741db2c35452"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>In carrying out this Act, and the amendments made by this Act, the Attorney General may use the resources and capacities of any appropriate agencies of the Department of Justice, including the Office of Sex Offender Sentencing, Monitoring, Apprehending, Registering, and Tracking, the United States Marshals Service, INTERPOL Washington-U.S. National Central Bureau, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Criminal Division, and the United States Attorneys’ Offices.</text>
 </subsection></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idd7953717508e4510b61bee64f08b677d" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reciprocal notifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, should seek reciprocal international agreements or arrangements to further the purposes of this Act and the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>). Such agreements or arrangements may establish mechanisms and undertakings to receive and transmit notices concerning international travel by sex offenders, through the Angel Watch Center, the INTERPOL notification system, and such other means as may be appropriate, including notification by the United States to other countries relating to the travel of sex offenders from the United States, reciprocal notification by other countries to the United States relating to the travel of sex offenders to the United States, and mechanisms to correct and, as applicable, remove from any other records, any inaccurate information transmitted through such notifications.</text>
		</section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idcd83c5b320dd40938cd832cce3d6e663" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>8.</enum><header>Unique passport identifiers for covered sex offenders</header>
 <subsection id="id3625f6a05c2247a5948d162fab5c8ae0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to public law 110-457</header><text>Title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/457">Public Law 110–457</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5daf0b171f6545148894e628cc573a44" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <section id="id92874e321b4b4c7ab8758687b788da8b"><enum>240.</enum><header>Unique passport identifiers for covered sex offenders</header> <subsection id="idf5398b78abb3414da57874a39c572088"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Immediately after receiving a written determination from the Angel Watch Center that an individual is a covered sex offender, through the process developed for that purpose under section 9 of the International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders, the Secretary of State shall take appropriate action under subsection (b).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="iddfc44d0bc3ce4c0cb1cd3fdd4b31b779"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority to use unique passport identifiers</header>
 <paragraph id="idc2385ccd7c9f46afa1569d3f3ee89cf9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (2), the Secretary of State shall not issue a passport to a covered sex offender unless the passport contains a unique identifier, and may revoke a passport previously issued without such an identifier of a covered sex offender.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb50ee3f62ccb4ebf8d7e9668d379b51d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to reissue</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary of State may reissue a passport that does not include a unique identifier if an individual described in subsection (a) reapplies for a passport and the Angel Watch Center provides a written determination, through the process developed for that purpose under section 9 of the <short-title>International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</short-title>, to the Secretary of State that the individual is no longer required to register as a covered sex offender.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5dd3756151c84f07917503387106f75e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Defined terms</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id398a99c3d2244ba3a242d21274b1afc2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered sex offender</term> means an individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6007be69fbb0493b8195a7614f5a40bf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a sex offender, as defined in section 4(f) of the International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d780fa399c7483aad811ff6c5658689"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is currently required to register under the sex offender registration program of any jurisdiction;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide64acb97c4e7413a8a59a169c2614fd0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>unique identifier</term> means any visual designation affixed to a conspicuous location on the passport indicating that the individual is a covered sex offender; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id70f866d5b1c1408880b02940daabb455"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>passport</term> means a passport book or passport card.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id93f8b04f897c4806bcd3532f385c25a6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Attorney General, and their agencies, officers, employees, and agents, shall not be liable to any person for any action taken under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4c6936b28a594c5ea515f5540a6df2d8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>In furtherance of this section, the Secretary of State may require a passport applicant to disclose that they are a registered sex offender.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2ecbb8c6e08543579c15fd18b0bffa05"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect upon certification by the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Attorney General, that the process developed and reported to the appropriate congressional committees under section 9 of the International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation and Other Sexual Crimes Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders has been successfully implemented.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idc2dab01c2e1a4fe5ada55bf590fa7b32" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>9.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header>
 <subsection id="ida9786719189f4df39b63febedeaae0bb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, and the Attorney General shall develop a process by which to implement section 4(e)(5) and the provisions of section 240 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/457">Public Law 110–457</external-xref>, as added by section 8 of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idd59811cd7b62424c9b01379389e03f23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, and the Attorney General shall jointly submit a report to, and shall consult with, the appropriate congressional committees on the process developed under subsection (a), which shall include a description of the proposed process and a timeline and plan for implementation of that process, and shall identify the resources required to effectively implement that process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9235137E03F04ECEBB215627ABB8A18F"><enum>(c)</enum><header><term>Appropriate congressional committees</term> defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="idF53A3BFEEE114C228E0BDDD50DB39EDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id28C0FC7A8C714CF8A02CACE8926C63A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id33F43DB9080C4EB19B071EFAE4076B7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id023FCCC59C3543E2B383E656B494B23B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id3E913279BA84463985CF00DB06245AE7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3E84323AADE9430F882723165AB04C17"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idDA128287A6F645FCAA2FA6F46730C8B7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7CCB4EE3E0324E75895A58E8B7BFEEA5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id4b83a87dfe4b4a8eb6e448ffc3de5cd9" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>10.</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, may provide technical assistance to foreign authorities in order to enable such authorities to participate more effectively in the notification program system established under this Act.</text>
 </section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="ida3e6002041b44c4ea318f5e178c2b22f" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>11.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Homeland Security such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
 </section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idd74e91997bb24b6e90555d1e7ef1f351" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>12.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit international information sharing or law enforcement cooperation relating to any person pursuant to any authority of the Department of Justice, the Department of Homeland Security, or any other department or agency.</text></section></legis-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>An Act to protect
children and others from sexual abuse and exploitation,
including sex trafficking and sex tourism, by providing
advance notice of intended travel by registered sex offenders
outside the United States to the government of
the country of destination, requesting foreign governments
to notify the United States when a known sex offender
is seeking to enter the United States, and for
other purposes.</quote>.</official-title-amendment><endorsement><action-date>November 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment and an amendment to the title</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


