<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE7600564C3CD40788AC963161B33EE37" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1708 IH: Robin Danielson Feminine Hygiene Product Safety Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1708</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a program of research regarding the risks posed
			 by the presence of dioxin, synthetic fibers, chemical fragrances, and
			 other components of feminine hygiene products.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6F281A92FE4F42C8A78FB617E89EAEA4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H34D8529027DF4BD2AC9F0F424109F5E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Robin Danielson Feminine Hygiene Product Safety Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC905863305AD47E3B6BF24065E162A3B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2E57E42F6F0B4B0587BEC3C30A2A7F18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Feminine hygiene products are widely used by women in the United States today, but there is not enough research on the components of these products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D7970029C154605B3D3E6E21375D990"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Women may be exposed to substances in tampons and other menstrual products for as long as 60 years over the course of their reproductive lives. The average woman may use as many as 16,800 tampons in her lifetime. A woman on menopausal hormone therapy may use as many as 24,360 tampons in her lifetime.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4952D67DE0F94B64A2EFD1EC6A407B53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Trace amounts of dioxins can be found in tampons or other feminine hygiene products. The Environmental Protection Agency and the International Agency for Research on Cancer, an arm of the World Health Organization, have concluded that dioxins are a probable human carcinogen (cancer-causing agent).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0A0FB930A994B70BF0BB2AED733BB83"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Food and Drug Administration (referred to in this section as the <quote>FDA</quote>) has historically relied on data provided by manufacturers of feminine hygiene products in determining product safety.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H318345B3C1A64CE58FE234BC1444BB48"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Although the FDA currently requires tampon manufacturers to routinely monitor dioxin levels in raw materials and finished tampons, this information is not readily available to the public. The FDA should consider whether to expand regulation to include other types of feminine hygiene products and a broader list of contaminants.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF1092898E1F9406CA7E3870B05648780"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research on dioxin and other potentially harmful components of feminine hygiene products</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part F of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/287d">42 U.S.C. 287d et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following section:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H84619509B1E449F597A4B83AAAEC6FA2" style="OLC">
				<section id="H5907524A993D4B86B3FE98D5601FC1AF"><enum>486C.</enum><header>Research on dioxin and other potentially harmful components of feminine hygiene products</header>
					<subsection id="HB8A5F9C258214A9BA1E9B6CFA37E8650"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research</header>
 <paragraph id="H227E495F4CDB42999CF2528EA37EA3CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of NIH, in collaboration with the Director of the Office, shall provide for the conduct or support of research to determine the extent to which the presence of dioxins, synthetic fibers, chlorine, and other components (including contaminants and substances used as fragrances, colorants, dyes, and preservatives) in tampons and other feminine hygiene products—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H89980807BB144FFDB49E6598D4B59344"><enum>(A)</enum><text>poses any risks to the health of women who use the products, including risks relating to cervical cancer, endometriosis, infertility, ovarian cancer, breast cancer, immune system deficiencies, pelvic inflammatory disease, toxic shock syndrome, and bacterial and yeast infections; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3229374D2424F76BB6BC7EF862F871C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>poses any risks to the health of children of women who used such products during or before the pregnancies involved, including risks relating to fetal and childhood development.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA36F963B6A934711888BD3AF0FF4CD51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement regarding data from manufacturers</header><text>Research under paragraph (1) shall include research to confirm the data on tampons and other feminine hygiene products submitted to the Commissioner of Food and Drugs by manufacturers of such products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDB0232A4E9E409A9E00285982A12BF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>feminine hygiene products</quote> means tampons, pads, liners, cups, sponges, douches, wipes, sprays, and similar products used by women with respect to menstruation or other genital-tract secretions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79C88E5062E3408E8BDF6BD10F6986C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Reports on the results of research under subsection (a) shall be periodically submitted to the Congress, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Chairman of the Consumer Product Safety Commission. Such reports shall be made available to the public through the data system and clearinghouse program established under section 486A, or through other appropriate means.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC50ACD48B3B74011AD9B571E84394E5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


