<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H20B4D30621D04D18BE783F368D148C0A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3542 IH: Early Learning Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3542</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150917">September 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide support for pre-kindergarten education through an Early Education Trust Fund, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3F67E6F1E064479A8DA054BF7D376DA0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2BC28BAD04434308836A0BD7596BAC48" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Early Learning Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1198F458B384E279F29DCF8105CD6B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expenditures for pre-kindergarten education</header> <subsection id="H538296A0175C4BAF9A6DC2468A3C2B0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than August 15 of each year, beginning with 2018, from amounts in the Early Education Trust Fund established by section 3, the Secretary of Education (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall award to the State pre-kindergarten agency for each State the amount estimated under subsection (b)(1)(A) for such State and year, subject to paragraphs (1)(A) and (2) of subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6459518E6CB1492094359D53CB79A765"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions for awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts may only be awarded under subsection (a) to a State pre-kindergarten agency for a State for a year if the head of such agency—</text>
 <paragraph id="H04FFA588D9CA44CB953DF59AFE2BA57D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submits to the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="HF57D3C58D2B84BFFAD2E8369E424D672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than June 15 of such year, an estimate of the amount described in paragraph (1) of subsection (c) for such State and year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6F501EFE5BC7455E80329921BA766601"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than November 1 of such year, for each enrolled 4-year-old in such State, the number of hours for which such 4-year-old is enrolled at a pre-kindergarten program in such State for the school year beginning in such year; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A3D71C352F14DEA8127A37F95642755"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides such assurances as the Secretary may require that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4124A197B6B64252AE022AE942E572EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such amounts will be used only to support pre-kindergarten programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16BF4BB0E4E944ACA3321C32617BF48F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State will expend for pre-kindergarten programs, during the 1-year period beginning on August 15 of such year not less than the amount expended by the State for such programs during the 1-year period beginning on August 15 of the previous year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A19336660564C048FC5DF030439742F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each resident of the State who is 4 years old on October 1 of such year has the opportunity to enroll in a free pre-kindergarten program.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4806EA668CF64D51934646E0F98BD278"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount described</header>
 <paragraph id="HDE4DADF935C34897B963B976DD73DD12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount described in this paragraph is, with respect to a State and a year, the sum of the products determined under paragraph (2) for all enrolled 4-year-olds in the State for the year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAAA46CECF4F9454AA10533D6AF7A2850"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Product determined</header><text>The product determined under this paragraph for an enrolled 4-year-old for a year is the product of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H685C35F6544E493085944822E27F9CD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$5 (adjusted annually by the Secretary of Education for inflation, beginning with 2019, on the basis of the consumer price index for all urban consumers); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H98A966DBCA2D4D9C87A2FD32989616BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of hours reported under subsection (b)(1)(B) for such enrolled 4-year-old for the school year beginning in such year (not to exceed 1,600).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2BC63616C6C451E9E7F1EA9DA3A7606"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Adjustments to payments</header>
 <paragraph id="HD2C0D4F1445F45F4A1E7B74EF356FFA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reconciliation of payment</header><text>For each State pre-kindergarten agency for a year:</text> <subparagraph id="H51CAB6B0CAD34DA3B21679EC1DDF2E45"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Overpayment</header><text>If the amount awarded under subsection (a) is greater than the amount described in paragraph (1) of subsection (c), the amount to be awarded under subsection (a) for the following year shall be reduced by the difference between such amounts.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFC5D7D4E29245C8885F6F4260BDF997"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Underpayment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the amount awarded under subsection (a) is less than the amount described in paragraph (1) of subsection (c), not later than December 31 of such year, from amounts in the Early Education Trust Fund established by section 3, the Secretary shall award to such State pre-kindergarten agency the difference between such amounts, subject to paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF58AA9FD1EFE4C969119744F5B3CCA33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Insufficient funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, as of a date, the amounts available to be awarded on such date from the Early Education Trust Fund are less than the amounts to be awarded on such date under this section without regard to this paragraph, the Secretary shall ratably reduce the amounts to be awarded.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02546AAF4B8E4AFCA5D0EA6C5035CF0A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2F74D9A0D5DE4ADFBE9363E2AD3E44E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enrolled 4-year-old</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>enrolled 4-year-old</term> means, with respect to a year, an individual who, as of October 1 of such year—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H821885A6C42B4166A3F73A31C7FF6027"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is 4 years old; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF799EFC095A47E69A2CD102ABC2E892"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is enrolled at a pre-kindergarten program for at least 900 hours for the school year beginning in such year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37A74BB4D55D4CB3ADA785644226B7D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pre-kindergarten program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pre-kindergarten program</term> means a program that is—</text> <subparagraph id="HB14DAE963F9045958466BC26CAF3E9B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offered by a nonprofit or governmental entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAE26CC8B96042AE99C4DB62E2D25872"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designed to provide pre-kindergarten education for at least 900 hours during a school year; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA89D337FD91042FB9CE18E0DFA037958"><enum>(C)</enum><text>accredited by the State pre-kindergarten agency for the State in which such program operates or by another accrediting entity approved by such State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD3237606DB43AD9B789DEF49DBB965"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State pre-kindergarten agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State pre-kindergarten agency</term> means, with respect to a State, the agency responsible for oversight of pre-kindergarten education in the State.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7B68C29E54BD436BBC75200054795A26"><enum>3.</enum><header>Early Education Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H0211C94ECC794CA0AED2B991A536DC73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of Trust Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Early Education Trust Fund</quote>, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to such Trust Fund as provided in this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF26B04A49AAF4D21885E592B400C08E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer to Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the Early Education Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the taxes received in the Treasury under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/59A">section 59A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to surtax for Early Education Trust Fund).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H638332CC4B304DF4AD9B95F757248705"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures from Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts in the Early Education Trust Fund shall be available, without further appropriation, to carry out section 2.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4C57EA66F8A14B828C74C134BEF4DEF9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="HE40A78B9D92146368B0690DB5FA7F815"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transfer of amounts</header><text>The amounts appropriated by subsection (b) shall be transferred at least monthly from the general fund of the Treasury to the Early Education Trust Fund on the basis of estimates made by the Secretary of the Treasury of the amounts referred to in such subsection. Proper adjustments shall be made in the amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates were in excess of or less than the amounts required to be transferred.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9F401FE4D7A411FA28B07BD2B832CA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management</header><text>The Early Education Trust Fund shall be managed under the rules specified in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9602">section 9602</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H69E0D3DD7E644B6B9DDEC598A964B390"><enum>4.</enum><header>Surtax for Early Education Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="HF5CA5F7FCC2E40979664FA4B8F631DB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after part VI the following new part:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H623109EF1B694A7F9F02034976C3712C" style="OLC">
					<part id="HC9C82F4CC13445E3A02F0C2F7549077A"><enum>VII</enum><header>Surtax for Early Education Trust Fund</header>
						<toc container-level="part-container" idref="HC9C82F4CC13445E3A02F0C2F7549077A" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H6D08FB5F8C754FF9BE3D99EC4F353B64" level="section">Sec. 59A. Surtax for Early Education Trust Fund.</toc-entry>
						</toc>
						<section id="H6D08FB5F8C754FF9BE3D99EC4F353B64"><enum>59A.</enum><header>Surtax for Early Education Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H82F60004E8534C5A9326E9019401C464"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header><text>In the case of a taxpayer other than a corporation and an estate or trust, there is hereby imposed (in addition to any other tax imposed by this subtitle) a tax equal to 1.5 percent of so much of the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer as exceeds $500,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EBEF7082B0140D682593D6CCC0ACD02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Not treated as tax imposed by this chapter for certain purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tax imposed under this section shall not be treated as tax imposed by this chapter for purposes of determining the amount of any credit under this chapter or for purposes of section 55.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA690937BBBA147DDB641124FB97C4433"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of parts for subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to part VI the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H897B232682654B3FA38A17C926320A04" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="part">Part VII. Surtax for Early Education Trust Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D48BC4397994878B98D20589B4AD290"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Section 15 Not To Apply</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall not be treated as a change in a rate of tax for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/15">section 15</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H765552E0D0D44061930937765DB7D903"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

