<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEFEA9DE2ED1441D9BFC68BC0F4839798" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3455 IH: Gun Trafficking Prevention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3455</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150909">September 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000622">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prevent gun trafficking.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HAC9C0E7468064837B3D112E638CD31F4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H761D116B62A84BD9A0AD24FCAF1714DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gun Trafficking Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1332688A239B420B88F32441D1ECD746"><enum>2.</enum><header>Firearms trafficking</header> <subsection id="H73D50A8553C242EEA15B23B0B08A1957"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD59ED7E601334C6892E9A18515F8CF85" style="USC">
					<section id="H7F76D27B2FF64C0FBBDA4E2BA60DC2FC"><enum>932.</enum><header>Trafficking in firearms</header>
 <subsection id="H8C71A1012B6748B4AF5E42884A2F076D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offenses</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), it shall be unlawful for any person, in or affecting interstate commerce—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0D3058FA39FB41A696F413F757518649"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to purchase, attempt to purchase, or transfer a firearm, with the intent to deliver the firearm to another person who the transferor knows, or has reasonable cause to believe, is prohibited by Federal or State law from possessing a firearm;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D205B1346B246C49BBB1CF8E97EAD60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in purchasing, attempting to purchase, or transferring a firearm, to intentionally provide false or misleading material information on a Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives firearms transaction record form; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB70B071E26D4A09BEC93D95614A393F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to knowingly direct, promote, or facilitate conduct that violates paragraph (1) or (2).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDAC3E46C1284094BA9439D753104EA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gift exceptions</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a firearm that is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0C176A4C07D34EC58CECBE6C5E120CE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lawfully acquired by a person to be given to another person not prohibited from possessing a firearm under Federal or State law as a gift; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H025AADF6D1FB44E6837CEC6D57F946DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>lawfully received or otherwise acquired by a court-appointed trustee, receiver, or conservator for, or on behalf of, an estate or creditor or by a person to carry out a bequest, or an acquisition by intestate succession under the laws of the State of residence of the person.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9AA6201AE0B340FE91E953D007721B91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <paragraph id="HBEDA911675374A75B7438A058421C2AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who violates this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57C1F7A36B4B46119036C51A817D78A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organizer enhancement</header><text>If a violation of subsection (a) is committed by a person in concert with 5 or more other persons with respect to whom such person occupies a position of organizer, a supervisory position, or any other position of management, such person may be sentenced to an additional term of imprisonment of not more than 5 consecutive years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H588736AB31B641EDA7D14676364711F0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conspiracy</header><text>Any person who conspires to commit an offense described in this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D550337CEE7431F89E252B2253E9E20"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7484EFFFFA245068EFF849631188592" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">932. Trafficking in firearms.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H30057230A95D4A669FCF1A34AAC24CB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Directive to the sentencing commission</header>
 <paragraph id="H08317E2F4B4848FAAE2A02A7A694B2CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pursuant to its authority under section 994(p) of title 28, United States Code, the United States Sentencing Commission shall review and, if appropriate, amend the Federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to persons convicted of offenses under section 932 of title 18, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5E4FDADB5D64E34BD954D2C687FDF32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Commission shall review the penalty structure that the guidelines currently provide based on the number of firearms involved in the offense and determine whether any changes to that penalty structure are appropriate in order to reflect the intent of Congress that such penalties reflect the gravity of the offense.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


