<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H46DE7BF3486F4040A274897A9E904B68" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2385 IH: Stop Blood Tomatoes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2385</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150515">May 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require certain large companies to submit to an independent annual audit of their supply chains
			 to verify that their supply chains are free of child and forced labor.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCDE55C4B7F9242A1B411ACC773B675B7" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDACBF6A9237C45808C428DA2EF2CBABD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Blood Tomatoes Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAD3551C8C1A342E68AC929461714C545"><enum>2.</enum><header>Audit of supply chain required</header> <subsection id="H9AFC1293858B4385867A2915E7F0A9EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each public or private company that produces or sells products in interstate commerce that has gross annual revenues in excess of $1,000,000,000 shall annually submit to an audit of its supply chains by an independent auditor for the purpose of determining if such company’s supply chains are free of child labor and forced labor.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7EDC5F2566CC4A06A39AC71B6A5B6C32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing of audit</header><text>The audit required by subsection (a) shall be conducted during the first quarter of the company’s fiscal year and shall be a complete audit of the companies supply chains during the previous fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9E498E2D11BA478C815DBFEF033A3BDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination by auditor</header><text>In addition to any specific information regarding a company’s supply chain, the independent auditor shall make a determination in each audit that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H24EDCE6B33344D19AAA616543F4C18D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the company’s products are produced without the use of child labor or forced labor; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA15644C741A348CABC8B536E43036AFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the independent auditor cannot be certain that child labor or forced labor was used, that the company’s products may have been produced with the use of child labor or forced labor.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0210433288B44757A94AAE4B0630314B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting of audit determination</header><text>Each company required to submit to an audit under this section shall, within 60 days of the completion of the audit—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3B4D1DE0E10640CF8EC0C6AA53617553"><enum>(1)</enum><text>report the determination made pursuant to subsection (c) to the Department of Labor and the Securities and Exchange Commission; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A174EF3D73A4CB986AD8EA52F71514D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>post a clear and conspicuous notice on the primary homepage of the company’s Internet website, based on such determination, that states either of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9ED40AD8F15046DBA89661FDFD1C9DC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>Products are free of child labor and forced labor.</quote>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62391AE9CA8541B1A593B78B6961E33D"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>Products may have been produced using child labor or forced labor.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CF79F960D8B4931BA1ED7938B65E85F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this Act and for purposes of the audit required under this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HCABBF5F7A2324E12896D8E3B1F12B204"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>child labor</term> means any labor practice relating to work performed by a minor in violation of national and international standards, including International Labor Organization Convention No. 182;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF82DED5E447843E28CF728B16DCB60A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>forced labor</term> means any forced labor practice in violation of national and international standards, including International Labor Organization Convention No. 29;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82A24B09B910484BABF0BDB01565FFAC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>independent auditor</term> means an entity that is unrelated to and fully independent of any company for which it performs audit services required by this Act that has demonstrated experience with examining international supply chains and familiarity with international labor standards;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H091D0320AE5540668B175F61B6C8FC57"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>product</term> includes a manufactured product, agricultural commodity, and oil, natural gas, and minerals; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA441E1D337E54C9A81B90DC2E4A16C0D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>supply chain</term> means all labor recruiters, suppliers of products, component parts of products, and raw materials used by a company and its subsidiary and suppliers in the manufacturing of such company’s products, whether or not such company has a direct relationship with the supplier.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


