<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE42B9F43DE6E4B43B5FCCE20A9F41B4C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1791 IH: Grace Period Restoration Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1791</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150414">April 14, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the patent law to promote basic research, to stimulate publication of scientific
			 documents, to encourage collaboration in scientific endeavors, to improve
			 the transfer of technology to the private sector, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0F845A5A974F4F13A330ABEE3F4E9673" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0B2F8312C0774145A23BBD10D46F41FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grace Period Restoration Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H232A02EF3F994FAA848DC9E5718F3162"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header> <subsection id="H39CE80DC642A4C3688800917C0C7543E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6A5AA134A4E14C97A3F74C85B51EB94F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Language in the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/29">Public Law 112–29</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 284) and regulations and examination guidelines issued by the United States Patent and Trademark Office implementing provisions of that Act have created uncertainty regarding the scope of the 1-year grace period during which an inventor who discloses an invention to the public may decide whether to file a patent application for the invention (referred to in this Act as the <quote>grace period</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA0AAD58AAD74205A194E49A087C872A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The regulatory reading of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act does not comport with the intent of the sponsors of that Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20E4762B73C647AEBA95FE137495EAB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In performing more than 50 percent of all basic research in the United States and pursuing the transfer of research results to the private sector for the benefit of the public under the auspices of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/35/18">chapter 18</external-xref> of title 35, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Bayh-Dole Act</quote>), institutions of higher education and government laboratories face a difficult and expensive challenge in gaining and utilizing the full scope of patent rights.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8DB06F8967E4F198B224F87167EEB5A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The uncertainty relating to the grace period created by the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act adds to the challenge faced by institutions of higher education and government laboratories in gaining and utilizing the full scope of patent rights.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0869D0D890A346219E99185A1C1BF6BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Job growth and the creation of start-up companies and small businesses are thwarted by uncertainty as to the scope of the grace period and by the difficulty and expense of gaining and utilizing patent rights, which hinders the economy of the United States and the technological leadership of the United States in a competitive global economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2291F9469F5648BEBFFDE43B3B5FEA89"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Ambiguity and uncertainty in statutory text and government regulations breed abusive and expensive patent litigation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8934468BFE444AABD66B981E2E38FC7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Discouragement of scientific research publication—</text> <subparagraph id="H74198045D86E4B6CA757DA3A5FEF3D26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>delays the disclosure of scientific advances to the public;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF63FFDC60B114F89A813CA5EE0609CAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>thwarts scientific advances;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D562A5D4319408DA4A8D9B914CB4C2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>chills collaborative research activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DEBE780EBD44B44AF076054D98554D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>delays, if not denies, the opportunity for the public to realize the benefits of research results.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H246B8E4116754AA5BEFD2D139F7CD007"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Misappropriation by third parties of disclosed inventions is likely to increase, especially in countries that take advantage of the technological prowess of the United States without appropriately compensating inventors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC44180B48330498CA4A88880693D13AB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Secrecy is anathema to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF5E60D1605C14E13A29934099C81136B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maintenance of a viable United States patent system;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43ABD831B70E4C96AB6DEDBFBF0497D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the constitutional purpose of the United States patent system; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2DACC31384748D899BFD38FA3038224"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the goal of the United States patent system of promoting scientific progress.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H333F7CAE249E42F0955F9A2567F35863"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In the words of David J. Kappos, who served as the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office during the enactment of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act, the grace period before the enactment of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act was <quote>the gold standard of best practices</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14D1483869F346B48C3C0C417EA3FDE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="HD94A82E14CCA48C98C9D828AB5EDD37D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to correct the drafting problem in the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act relating to the grace period; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC30752DCEB1C4A6C922D9C073C2AA6F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to maintain the position of leadership of the United States in educational, technological, and scientific progress.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H799F67C712B94E9F9F76B1594DAC5F6F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disclosures following a public disclosure of a claimed invention by an inventor</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(b) of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94DA5175A8F94306ACDBF0BEF84FC131" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H9A10FACC40894166A277DF1567327058"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosures by any person after public disclosure of a claimed invention by an inventor</header> <subparagraph id="HB879179E0C8D4CEDAC4783C8D228EEAB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph—</text>
 <clause id="H29E595C6DB384951974F27C5B52320AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>covered person</term>, with respect to a claimed invention, means—</text> <subclause id="H966E64A3820C4226B3F118B18563B00E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the inventor;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9260CCE8F33C40ACB7B55D6D2986DA75"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a joint inventor; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF80A7146ADB9444C9704A788D77BBE77"><enum>(III)</enum><text>another who obtained the claimed invention directly or indirectly from the inventor or a joint inventor; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H5D62A77C1CCF4FDF9E7C84522B12D82A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>relevant section 112(a) requirements</term> means the requirements for a specification under section 112(a) other than the requirement to set forth the best mode of carrying out the invention.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBDE121A2BAE49F3813FE092301357D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public disclosure</header><text>A disclosure by any person shall not be prior art to a claimed invention under subsection (a) or section 103 if—</text>
 <clause id="HB020B157A7E04DE58A2FC5C81D231235"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the disclosure is made under subsection (a)(1) or effectively filed under subsection (a)(2) 1 year or less before the effective filing date of the claimed invention; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H17363B98B1BD42ADAD16D109DE7564DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>before the disclosure described in clause (i) is made or filed, and 1 year or less before the effective filing date of the claimed invention, the claimed invention is publicly disclosed in a printed publication by a covered person in a manner that satisfies the relevant section 112(a) requirements.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD18EAAE49E9D4761A7971144BB4DF175"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination that public disclosure would have satisfied specification requirements</header><text>In determining under subparagraph (B) whether a claimed invention was publicly disclosed in a printed publication by a covered person in a manner that satisfied the relevant section 112(a) requirements—</text>
 <clause id="H25F0352672104C90AD5931A8FAC49AE0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>only the state of the art known on and before the date of the disclosure may be considered; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD10DC93501474E9B837407A4B8E6C1CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>satisfaction of the relevant section 112(a) requirements may be—</text>
 <subclause id="H9F356E340A834C8691043D3AC0011615"><enum>(I)</enum><text>established by 1 or more public disclosures in printed publications made by a covered person during the period of 1 year or less between—</text>
 <item id="H7248702DE7314EE78530743045F6A2EC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the disclosure by the covered person described in subparagraph (B)(ii); and</text> </item><item id="H3E47565D58B94CFE859CB3ADCEA7EF49"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the effective filing date of the claimed invention; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H0A37048AC13545C9BD0370033223131D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>supported by statements under declaration or oath relating to the existence and content of the public disclosure or disclosures in printed publications described in subclause (I).</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7110AD4B4732486696C8E71330C57544"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Presumption of validity</header><text>An applicant for a patent shall present to the Patent and Trademark Office, before the Patent and Trademark Office issues a notice of allowance of the application for the patent, each disclosure under subparagraph (C)(ii)(I) and any statement under subparagraph (C)(ii)(II) in order for the section 112(a) support provided by each such disclosure or statement under subparagraph (C)(ii) to be taken into account under the section 282(a) presumption of validity of an issued patent.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2000E1CCCC1645B2AC31DFD86D7BD67D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Certain disclosures not prior art</header><text>A disclosure described in paragraph (1)(A), (2)(A), or (2)(C) shall not be prior art to a claimed invention under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE60397F2C54942109BD858DEAB83ED8F"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Patent and Trademark Office may establish procedures to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="H878A4A959D1E469B90E9CCDCADEEC369"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect as if enacted as part of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/29">Public Law 112–29</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 284).</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


