<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3FFBEC316B194C1B825E843591E0D5EF" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 702 : To adapt to changing crude oil market conditions.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 702</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20151019">October 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To adapt to changing crude oil market conditions.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H94C532084D584B029CD4DBE765C4EA02" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA6F26ECBE8E44A278B279C273EF47ABF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HB262F78DC72346C4AAC2B7F99609EDA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has enjoyed a renaissance in energy production, establishing the United States as the world’s leading oil producer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF2388EB9124F08B9DDA3B47656DD38"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By authorizing crude oil exports, the Congress can spur domestic energy production, create and preserve jobs, help maintain and strengthen our independent shipping fleet that is essential to national defense, and generate State and Federal revenues.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6C47165D3704544A105D4A3D349B5B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An energy-secure United States that is a net exporter of energy has the potential to transform the security environment around the world, notably in Europe and the Middle East.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C7450F3D63445958B557F1297D8046B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For our European allies and Israel, the presence of more United States oil in the market will offer more secure supply options, which will strengthen United States strategic alliances and help curtail the use of energy as a political weapon.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE617DBECAAF41C690FD2C86638180B6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The 60-ship Maritime Security Fleet is a vital element of our military’s strategic sealift and global response capability. It assures United States-flag ships and United States crews will be available to support the United States military when it needs to mobilize to protect our allies, and is the most prudent and economical solution to meet current and projected sealift requirements for the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6D4FADB5F204A5AB74C7BF8FC1EEEF6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Maritime Security Fleet program provides a labor base of skilled American mariners who are available to crew the United States Government-owned strategic sealift fleet, as well as the United States commercial fleet, in both peace and war.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF350BDF8D21A4515BB8112FDFA762C64"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has reduced its oil consumption over the past decade, and increasing investment in clean energy technology and energy efficiency will lower energy prices, reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and increase national security.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HB966876D6FA140D891D7154019979057"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6212">42 U.S.C. 6212</external-xref>) and the item relating thereto in the table of contents of that Act are repealed.</text>
 </section><section id="H11196292FF764FD39252188C2CB4CFF5"><enum>3.</enum><header>National policy on oil export restriction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, to promote the efficient exploration, production, storage, supply, marketing, pricing, and regulation of energy resources, including fossil fuels, no official of the Federal Government shall impose or enforce any restriction on the export of crude oil.</text>
		</section><section id="HCECFE516A97544588C0788C8C02FC463"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study and recommendations</header>
 <subsection id="H68BCEC85CCF64CA1A8BEA4E11DD91158"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategic Petroleum Reserve</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall conduct a study and transmit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate recommendations on the appropriate size, composition, and purpose of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF91C3A45426144EF90874D48ACBB0E8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas emissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall conduct, and transmit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate the results of, a study on the net greenhouse gas emissions that will result from the repeal of the crude oil export ban under section 2.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H982FFBC43D0E4D66A5A42B814107D55B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategic Petroleum Reserve Study</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall conduct a study and transmit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate recommendations on the appropriate size, composition, and purpose of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H549BB9879AC84EBFB388ED0E8345CD9F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Crude oil export study</header>
 <paragraph id="H6A865C9231DE47D58EDF10097360760B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Department of Commerce, in consultation with the Department of Energy, and other departments as appropriate, shall conduct a study of the State and national implications of lifting the crude oil export ban with respect to consumers and the economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H494884706500466D9B6AEEF6881BE9CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall include an analysis of—</text> <subparagraph id="HCFDE41A966C0451BB368F93B0BE5D567"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the economic impact that exporting crude oil will have on the economy of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AF1291D71D245C59808AE18459B5253"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the economic impact that exporting crude oil will have on consumers, taking into account impacts on energy prices;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF40EEBB86D6B42D894505289CA9D004B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the economic impact that exporting crude oil will have on domestic manufacturing, taking into account impacts on employment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A3CAACF4A3E43A9942E72C0EBA738FE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the economic impact that exporting crude oil will have on the refining sector, taking into account impacts on employment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86A046C9532049A1B1FF99393F267080"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Bureau of Industry and Security shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB23EE9B26694476CB52254399EC84F6B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act limits the authority of the President under the Constitution, the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1601">50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), part B of title II of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6271">42 U.S.C. 6271 et seq.</external-xref>), the Trading With the Enemy Act (50 U.S.C. App. 1 et seq.), or any other provision of law that imposes sanctions on a foreign person or foreign government (including any provision of law that prohibits or restricts United States persons from engaging in a transaction with a sanctioned person or government), including a foreign government that is designated as a state sponsor of terrorism, to prohibit exports.</text>
		</section><section id="H2883468105634652AA17906361282DCE"><enum>6.</enum><header>National Defense Sealift Enhancement</header>
 <subsection id="H74AF991E6D5B4FF6B15CA4BDEEC6090D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 53106(a)(1) of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H631CB20F70D54F8DB327821DC101E8B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the comma before <quote>for each</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD929B29590644B41B47CA010FEF3A9AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>2016, 2017, and 2018;</quote> and inserting <quote>and 2016</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD477F64B54848839816B771DB02B033"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (G); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85F72D0B259C4B28B7C55CB32F2D2632"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (D) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H350E6FDC1F834662B31ECA2D8A780C26" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1097370643B4486DA1761F46AB1F387E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$4,999,950 for fiscal year 2017;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E725F67A922442C906157A0CEED1FC6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018, 2019, and 2020;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3E2FE1EEE814EF1BB050FD70E2B9CAB"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,233,463 for fiscal year 2021; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5706252484754F75B051A37513F638E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 53111 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDA224D73767E4A91842F128EB9605ED6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>2016, 2017, and 2018;</quote> and inserting <quote>and 2016</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96060A5711C94AFBA7633E658A9639A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (7); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E1117A48901412585201CC00C2EA3C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FBD97E9E95D48B1B12EBC285B352701" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="HD9E6F73465D6401AADBEF92C45640BEF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$299,997,000 for fiscal year 2017;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8083250591D4ADCBB8A565842CB313B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$300,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018, 2019, and 2020;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15A6745450F44F9DA9819D7F5DC4AC52"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$314,007,780 for fiscal year 2021; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H44EEB4B9EA0041DEBC3EB2424CA7B8B2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Partnerships with minority serving institutions</header> <subsection id="HB09C90AA39134035B8DF8F7E1F1277EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Department of Energy shall continue to develop and broaden partnerships with minority serving institutions, including Hispanic Serving Institutions (HSI) and Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) in the areas of oil and gas exploration, production, midstream, and refining.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD26FF6257D174C6A91B62FC4515CA2A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public-Private partnerships</header><text>The Department of Energy shall encourage public-private partnerships between the energy sector and minority serving institutions, including Hispanic Serving Institutions and Historically Black Colleges and Universities.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H364AE8AB2D1849F4BFBD638F7E222F18"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Commerce shall jointly transmit to Congress a report that reviews the impact of lifting the oil export ban under this Act as it relates to promoting United States energy and national security.</text>
 </section><section id="H8C9A11B695EA49FB8B2903BD485C2343"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Commerce shall jointly transmit to Congress a report analyzing how lifting the ban on crude oil exports will help create opportunities for veterans and women in the United States, while promoting energy and national security.</text>
		</section><section id="HDF7F0A3014AE44A0AF1BB02616FAC33E"><enum>10.</enum><header>Prohibition on exports of crude oil, refined petroleum products, and petrochemical products to the
 Islamic Republic of Iran</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize the export of crude oil, refined petroleum products, and petrochemical products by or through any entity or person, wherever located, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to any entity or person located in, subject to the jurisdiction of, or sponsored by the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20151009">Passed the House of Representatives October 9, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


