<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBFF2B8C0FACE4950A93B288C0FB03A08" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 847 IH: Investing in Innovation for Education Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 847</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to invest in innovation for education.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H49452A3DCD6044A3A05126B97BE64930" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB5829FD07F6848AA85DCE276D00AE0BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investing in Innovation for Education Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H29A865CF6ED24167BD0C880D2A3C5B73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Investing in innovation</header> <subsection id="H1AD686525E70420B80FAD9B61B6E38DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82C3EAF5A67D40268CA8322D8BAC0582" style="OLC"> 
<part id="H7BE4962EFF21454BBDBD33F5B250025F"><enum>D</enum><header>Investing in innovation</header> 
<section id="H5385C4F48FBD4D11B20AC6A3D6FEF875"><enum>4401.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this part are to—</text> <paragraph id="HA6275C8ABC5A4D47B4BC24F068166FBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fund the identification, development, evaluation, and expansion of innovative, evidence-based practices, programs, and strategies in order to significantly—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H47272AEC805946C09189B36798DA9CCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase student academic achievement and decrease achievement gaps;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5251E0DEA0B24F2EBD6946B5FC687351"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase secondary school graduation rates;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H126A9640BE634D5FB1A34FA364C70BF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase college enrollment rates, rates of college persistence, and rates of attainment of other post-secondary credentials;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA21CCEA21F540E4BDA8D39E3B646F82"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve teacher and principal effectiveness or retention of highly effective teachers or principals; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE792B424E98B4BD899E716A568A2F948"><enum>(E)</enum><text>increase the identification and dissemination of innovative educational strategies in rural areas; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF91E367063D44A75A477DD3C0E4A37C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the rapid development, expansion, and adoption of tools and resources that improve the efficiency, effectiveness, or pace of adoption of such educational practices, programs, and strategies.</text> </paragraph></section>
<section id="H0657213C2E0F4ED6AE5B68B3992B043D"><enum>4402.</enum><header>National activities</header> 
<subsection id="HF74D9A9720C44094A0CD78B11AE7F557"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b), from the amounts appropriated under section 4408, the Secretary shall reserve not more than 10 percent for each fiscal year to carry out activities of national significance, which may include—</text> <paragraph id="HD60844E34D3D4C05A2C09E92E47028BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">technical assistance, including to applicants from rural areas;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC5F5DF44548B4A57AFDDAC4EDB7B282D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pre-application workshops or web-based seminars for potential applicants, including applicants from rural areas;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF8CE79B4A334974A376C90AF83460F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recruitment of peer reviewers, including individuals with a background in rural education and individuals with expertise in education technology, to participate in the review of applications submitted under section 4404;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H48BA8C71DAFB4CFBACA69E25533DC1BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dissemination of best practices, in consultation with the regional educational laboratories established under part D of the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9561">20 U.S.C. 9561 et seq.</external-xref>) and comprehensive centers established under section 203 of the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9602">20 U.S.C. 9602</external-xref>), developed with grant funds provided under this part, including best practices developed with grant funds in rural areas;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDED5CAA1F5124983A72232346993B8AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>entering into partnerships with other agencies, nonprofits, and the private sector to carry out advanced research and development activities, including research and activities in rural areas; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H73093BE609344EC6A008517AB24294D7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>carrying out prize awards, in a manner consistent with section 24 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3719">15 U.S.C. 3719</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB97B71F28A4C4E9EA6771F16D1D87250"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservation of funds for dissemination</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve not less than 50 percent of the funds reserved under this section to carry out the dissemination activities described in subsection (a)(4).</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="H5AC94E308DC5408FA6A68A4549E188FB"><enum>4403.</enum><header>Program authorized; length of grants; priorities</header> 
<subsection id="H29FAE3AD5A684D54ACC430308BC16BDC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program Authorization</header><text>From the amounts appropriated under section 4408 and not reserved under section 4402, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to carry out the activities described in section 4405.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H80143C48FB114BAD8A574CE99B402B52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration of Grants</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities under this section for a period of not more than 3 years, and may extend such grants for an additional 2-year period if the eligible entity demonstrates to the Secretary that it is making significant progress on the program performance measures identified in section 4406.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H48738A374AFD47A494B43310349E612B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rural areas</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that not less than 25 percent of the funds awarded under this section for any fiscal year are for projects that meet both of the following requirements:</text> <paragraph id="H64701050FD4D4AF1B5CE0B714D5921AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The eligible entity is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HABDE756CA6F04895812287F5C7116188"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local educational agency with an urban-centric district locale code of 32, 33, 41, 42, or 43, as determined by the Secretary;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDFBABE381AF248648BDDC47EE8A971BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a consortium of such local educational agencies; or</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC6135112719E4D93A07CBC865D0373CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an educational service agency or a nonprofit organization with demonstrated expertise in serving students from rural areas.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63EFC122E7A84A89851869327ADF9A51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A majority of the schools to be served by the project are designated with a school locale code of 41, 42, or 43, or a combination of such codes, as determined by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD056564BBA5F47FDBFBBDA050BBD6675"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Support for New Practices, Strategies, or Programs</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that not less than one-half of the funds awarded under this section for any fiscal year are for projects that—</text> <paragraph id="HC3F7755EE36C462FA8D07070038009A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>meet an evidence standard described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (f); and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC9AA964660414C2881D4B3AC83624E81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>do not meet the evidence standard described in paragraph (1) of subsection (f).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8AA2ECB6D6C54C0189DABE5C0C084C8C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priorities</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary may give priority to an eligible entity that includes, in its application under section 4404, a plan to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H68662AC7195348DEAA3F643AE800B9F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve early learning outcomes and academic connections between early learning and elementary school;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H89E94A693EF64B6499EB4923E23BD54D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support college access, persistence, and success;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H521165B6307D444FBA8EAB7C1BC1A781"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support family and community engagement;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H84E378AAFB914B65ADDBE12AC1C0FBA8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>address the unique learning needs of students with disabilities or English language learners;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD7B6E20B3AF41979B5101406D570A88"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support the effective use of education technology to improve teaching and learning;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D403377B7384F85B4F7E467BA0201A6"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the teaching and learning of science, technology, engineering, computing, or mathematics;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F8B7C12694942479ED3ED66A861CC50"><enum>(7)</enum><text>serve schools in rural local educational agencies;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA51B32C03774248912C97BC9E9C0FDD"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train teachers or principals to adopt and implement college and career ready standards;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3906E139F7F4AB2BD780DFE341D1B61"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop alternative career pathways or differentiated school staffing models for effective teachers or principals to expand their impact on student learning;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3252EFAA4A3E4CA78B2627C811C2DE71"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train or support principals or teacher leaders, including teacher leaders preparing for principal roles;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H589CFABBEDA84B9D9AA2D2C8D2052E28"><enum>(11)</enum><text>support, improve, or develop any other area of school innovation, as determined by the Secretary; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H69FA35DCE87E47E8A7FD9233A9FB027B"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address the learning needs of Indian, Native American, Alaska Native, or migrant children in school.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBB5EE7D1B0C04065B2EC4A72D8731220"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Standards of Evidence</header><text>The Secretary shall set standards for the quality of evidence that an eligible entity shall provide to demonstrate that the activities the eligible entity proposes to carry out with grant funds under this section are likely to succeed in improving student outcomes or outcomes on other performance measures. These standards may include any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H4CA854CAF88540C08A01A10B29CD7252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Strong evidence that the activities proposed by the eligible entity will have a statistically significant effect on student academic achievement, student growth, graduation rates, or outcomes on other performance measures.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H26E5680972414B9BB9452B49F57701CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Moderate evidence that the activities proposed by the eligible entity will improve student academic achievement, student growth, graduation rates, or outcomes on other performance measures.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1ECD09B39BB42A09D07C6B3B898E8C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Evidence of promise or a strong theory that the activities proposed by the eligible entity will improve student academic achievement, student growth, graduation rates, or outcomes on other performance measures.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H32561E02BBD1412190C2FEA04E067AEB"><enum>4404.</enum><header>Applications</header> 
<subsection id="H03C200976F5F4AD0A1B4DECCD74A7C9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity that desires to receive a grant under section 4403 shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H7EF0563262684C26A9C037F292131185"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application submitted by an eligible entity under subsection (a) shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H11127BCC56CF45C89AF9B1CAAF00297C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describe the project for which the eligible entity is seeking a grant and how the evidence supporting that project meets the standards of evidence established by the Secretary under section 4403(f);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5D04B0775644CEEA091A8D5A7661904"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe how the eligible entity will address at least one of the areas described in section 4405(a)(1);</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFC6848DAA9334B98AD35A1D20CB99AF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide an estimate of the number of students that the eligible entity plans to serve under the proposed project, including the percentage of those students who are from low-income families, and the number of students to be served through additional expansion after the grant ends;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H650F354741BD47FA97F1E90A8724480A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>demonstrate that the eligible entity has established one or more partnerships with the private sector, which may include philanthropic organizations, and that the partner or partners will provide matching funds, except that the Secretary may waive, on a case-by-case basis, the matching funds requirement under this paragraph upon a showing of exceptional circumstances, such as the difficulty of raising matching funds for a project to serve a rural area;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7504EE8271CE4CF090832512682155B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the eligible entity’s plan for continuing the proposed project after the grant funding under section 4403 ends, including a plan for dissemination of best practices and collaboration with other local educational agencies;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A6FC7CEC5FC4319A76568307ACEB5EF"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate that the proposed project has incorporated input and feedback from educators working in the area to be served;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC185BA0AF51D477D840C3BF4CFB85563"><enum>(7)</enum><text>if the eligible entity is a local educational agency—</text> <subparagraph id="H14B065BEE1AD49338BF2AC0E6CF80D68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>document the local educational agency’s record in—</text> 
<clause id="HFE042919043940FCBB72FD74297FCF39"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increasing student achievement, including achievement for each subgroup described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v); or</text> </clause> <clause id="HDECB2DE498C44EF0B61FE13AAC240A64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>decreasing achievement gaps; and</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9CCA73FDD0B2420380C25D53240882AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate how the local educational agency has made significant improvements in other outcomes, as applicable, on the performance measures described in section 4406;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2326792AE1D54166A55FE77E557F2FA8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>if the eligible entity is a nonprofit organization—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H02FFD92E90E34AA99B56C767A219BAAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide evidence that the nonprofit organization has helped at least one high-need school or high-need local educational agency significantly—</text> <clause id="H395BC4770B314698B59536067DF6A604"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increase student achievement, including achievement for each subgroup described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v);</text> </clause>
<clause id="H59AB88BE6CDF459A8BE87C63C18BA657"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce achievement gaps; or</text> </clause> <clause id="H6A3D025FE47B4F6392517A64BB7F1820"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increase graduation rates; and</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC7F430A33A9443D4B015C3C959A54190"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe how the nonprofit organization has helped at least 1 school or local educational agency make a significant improvement, as applicable, in other outcomes on the performance measures described in section 4406;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC18F7057644E4775A9453F059907E634"><enum>(9)</enum><text>if the eligible entity is an educational service agency—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD392D5EDC6A34805A852828269747323"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide evidence that the agency has helped at least one high-need school or high-need local educational agency significantly—</text> <clause id="H92B42019D2E547878619CDF86724BE19"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increase student achievement, including achievement for each subgroup described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v);</text> </clause>
<clause id="HFB2C9E0192504AF68173052DD0F04202"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce achievement gaps; or</text> </clause> <clause id="H218C21842F184853A5ADAC887C324448"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increase graduation rates; and</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA188B73424994F2BA390501B5C12F941"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe how the agency has helped at least 1 school or local educational agency make a significant improvement, as applicable, in other outcomes on the performance measures described in section 4406;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE740F3FC60344878B301CE0C027D809D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>provide a description of the eligible entity’s plan for independently evaluating the effectiveness of activities carried out with funds under section 4403;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB1075110168C4E5A84D0AC5D2A04F0CA"><enum>(11)</enum><text>provide an assurance that the eligible entity will—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9EA320240BF4F5CA105487E732BCEC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cooperate with cross-cutting evaluations;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H11AB1D19209144258D2C14CB7EDA4C6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make evaluation data available to third parties for validation and further study consistent with protections established by applicable Federal, State, and local privacy requirements and other on provisions on the protection of personally identifiable information; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF910F5980E8E4337BCDD5D0BCFE059A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>participate in communities of practice; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9D6F95C2C14447BA815F0BCA7FBE1889"><enum>(12)</enum><text>if the eligible entity is a nonprofit organization that intends to make subgrants, consistent with section 4405(b), provide an assurance that the eligible entity will apply paragraphs (1) through (10), as appropriate, in the eligible entity’s selection of subgrantees and in the oversight of such subgrants.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8F89E765B7A44DCDA953BF407A5221B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria for evaluating applications</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under section 4403 on a competitive basis, based on the quality of the applications under this section submitted and, consistent with the standards established under section 4403(f), each eligible entity’s likelihood of achieving success in improving student outcomes or outcomes on other performance measures.</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="H87CC3F1B0FF14B94BC6829015D24F7C9"><enum>4405.</enum><header>Uses of funds</header> 
<subsection id="HE35B60A2F58A45A89DE34703C3050FE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under section 4403—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8F68CA0100684C6AB81FED8C3F83BFED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall use the grant funds to address, at a minimum, one of the following areas of school innovations:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H27F202C019664A58841A4EC2920ACB3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improving the effectiveness and distribution of teachers or principals.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2827E46BA78D4F63A17888F00657439E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Strengthening the use of data to improve teaching and learning.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HD8A859213889434EB0C30F2113BBCAEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Providing high-quality instruction based on rigorous standards that build toward college and career readiness and measuring students' mastery using high-quality assessments aligned to those standards.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBD45F7DF418C4A7CB610CC1079490ADA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Turning around the lowest-performing schools.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H34D8A958304E476EA30757997F234CEB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supporting the effective use of technology to improve teaching or principals and learning, including training teachers or principals in the innovative use of technology.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE847717565A24B72AE9BD1E692195A6F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other area of school innovation, as determined by the Secretary.;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6E9A564AFC5042EFA78EB3A5922F8DAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall use those funds to develop or expand strategies to improve the performance of high-need students on the performance measures described in section 4406; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCCBC75CDF36C438E9D1B0A5F62D8B8ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may use the grant funds for an independent evaluation, as required by section 4404(b)(9), of the innovative practices carried out with the grant.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6F4D41D1C0984904B878BD1FCE83E61B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority to subgrant</header><text>In the case of an eligible entity receiving a grant under section 4403 that is nonprofit organization such eligible entity may use the grant funds to make subgrants to other entities to provide support to one or more high-need schools or high-need local educational agencies. Any entity receiving a subgrant under this subsection shall comply with the requirements of this part for eligible entities, as appropriate.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H016D1A24182543E5AC843F9CCF377BD2"><enum>4406.</enum><header>Performance measures</header> <subsection id="H131F34761D8A4E4F821C273FC3228854"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish performance measures for the projects carried out under this part. These measures, at a minimum, shall track an eligible entity’s progress in—</text> 
<paragraph id="H93A7F848905049F1809527A9D0AC5F90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improving outcomes for each subgroup described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v) that is served by the grantee on measures, including, as applicable, by—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2523682DA454C2D8A1F79C8AF3948F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing student achievement and decreasing achievement gaps;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB553E1BE21A7441FAA40881BAB7D293B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing secondary school graduation rates;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95A6D539E5584811B40104553D166C70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increasing college enrollment rates and rates of college persistence;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB92699D22C79432986CC2AA96C7733DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving teacher and principal effectiveness or the retention of highly effective teachers or principals;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H291446C1622347F0801B3857EF59C676"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improving school readiness; or</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2EF33DACD4BF4F2C821E4D58CAE2F5F7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other indicator as the Secretary or grantee may determine; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H596D569D4ED842A2856007863CAFA843"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementing the eligible entity’s project in rural schools, as applicable.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD503AC91FFD94FF39C4D258CA4502F58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data collection period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated under section 4408, the Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="HD14D0BC31A9A44CDAE8A881302C3BCE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>approve, for an eligible entity receiving a grant under section 4403, a data collection period of not more than 72 months beginning after the end of the eligible entity’s grant period; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6FE123A24E2249E2B4F6F570301F5E91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide the eligible entity with funding during such period for the sole purpose of collecting, analyzing, and reporting performance information under this subsection on the project carried out during the grant period.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H29BA5B915A67464AB85EB216C1C9EBA9"><enum>4407.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under section 4403 shall submit to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, an annual report that includes information on—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB56DF950536D407F8591388D10CD5275"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the eligible entity’s progress on the performance measures established under section 4406; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C510D1E2CD342DC836555FE02C41A97"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the data supporting such progress.</text> </paragraph></section>
<section id="H6BB84BFA47E64E97B385D2F273114AC1"><enum>4408.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $500,000,000 for fiscal year 2016 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years.</text> </section> <section id="H84F29A1E7CB44DB7AB112C1DCC729DAE"><enum>4409.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE453630470124B258D3DA8500C3F897E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H1668C92E6B8A41F4BE4DEF189F769F67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5BD4B6B16817465A918FCEEE906C416F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an educational service agencies; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2FB1CBE91C245C4B851AEC8584AB416"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonprofit organization in partnership with a local educational agency or consortium of schools.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7CA73F4311BB483087E5F8F412F0D3EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High-need local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high-need local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency—</text> <subparagraph id="H556C561F68644D9EB69C9AC216CEE597"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that serves not fewer than 10,000 children from families with incomes below the poverty line;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA5FC35B75D694B19A055B9B8FD259697"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which not less than 20 percent of the children served by the agency are from families with incomes below the poverty line; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H149036222D804ABABB08312322ADFD2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that is in the highest quartile of local educational agencies in the State, based on student poverty.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6E013469667C486AA96C57CD352979F8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High-need school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high-need school’</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H426DA4812E374CB68415E5ACEB52642B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an elementary school or middle school in which not less than 50 percent of the enrolled students are children eligible for free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD0DAEC2B32414DD781C7BF6BA4EFEEB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a high school in which not less than 40 percent of the enrolled students are children eligible for free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>), which may be calculated using comparable data from feeder schools.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HDE2DBC2BF5E34709A76D46BC254E389A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Principal</header><text>The term <term>principal</term> includes an assistant principal.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H89C6B6D108454187A4EEFADA0EB24B70"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Teacher</header><text>The term <term>teacher</term> includes teacher leaders.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC81B584A993D4C959C3E8B4574C1A67D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Teacher leader</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>teacher leader</term> means a teacher who has demonstrated effectiveness and assumes leadership responsibilities to work with other teachers to raise student achievement in multiple classrooms.</text></paragraph></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection>
<subsection id="HDC27852683CF4F44A45B48551AC4BA77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4304 the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H20C4B260AC084248BAF8C9E81F332972" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry idref="H7BE4962EFF21454BBDBD33F5B250025F" level="part">Part D—Investing in Innovation</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5385C4F48FBD4D11B20AC6A3D6FEF875" level="section">Sec. 4401. Purposes.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H0657213C2E0F4ED6AE5B68B3992B043D" level="section">Sec. 4402. National activities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5AC94E308DC5408FA6A68A4549E188FB" level="section">Sec. 4403. Program authorized; length of grants; priorities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H32561E02BBD1412190C2FEA04E067AEB" level="section">Sec. 4404. Applications.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H87CC3F1B0FF14B94BC6829015D24F7C9" level="section">Sec. 4405. Uses of funds.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H016D1A24182543E5AC843F9CCF377BD2" level="section">Sec. 4406. Performance measures.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H29BA5B915A67464AB85EB216C1C9EBA9" level="section">Sec. 4407. Reporting; annual report.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H6BB84BFA47E64E97B385D2F273114AC1" level="section">Sec. 4408. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

