<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1E9A80453D124AAB9DCB1A6B3DB16166" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3599 IH: Eastern Band Cherokee Historic Lands Reacquisition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3599</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150924">September 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To take certain Federal lands in Tennessee into trust for the benefit of the Eastern Band of
			 Cherokee Indians, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H844B572362B14E03906DDD870FD2448C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H487DE83BE3694903B0FB1878E3F09B6E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eastern Band Cherokee Historic Lands Reacquisition Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3B289F999C934E2FA39CA08992E4DE5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Land taken into trust for the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians</header> <subsection id="H7198EC9FBFFB4E30A804BB286C2CEC81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Lands into trust</header><text>Subject to such rights of record as may be vested in third parties to rights-of-way or other easements or rights-of-record for roads, utilities, or other purposes, the following Federal lands on or above the 820-foot (MSL) contour elevation in Monroe County, Tennessee, on the shores of Tellico Reservoir, are taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians:</text>
 <paragraph id="H22C124D39C3F4033A40164020A74C1D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sequoyah Museum Property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 46.0 acres of land generally depicted as <quote>Sequoyah Museum</quote>, <quote>Parcel 1</quote>, and <quote>Parcel 2</quote> on the map titled <quote>Eastern Band of Cherokee Historic Lands Reacquisition Map 1</quote> and dated April 30, 2015.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4A0A69ECDDD49A6B9CC8746E130B713"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Support Property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 11.9 acres of land generally depicted as <quote>Support Parcel</quote> on the map titled <quote>Eastern Band of Cherokee Historic Lands Reacquisition Map 2</quote> and dated April 30, 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86DC1E91D4D041D1BB5B693811000F04"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chota Memorial Property and Tanasi Memorial Property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 18.2 acres of land generally depicted as <quote>Chota Memorial 1</quote> and <quote>Tanasi Memorial</quote> on the map titled <quote>Eastern Band of Cherokee Historic Lands Reacquisition Map 3</quote> and dated April 30, 2015, and including the Chota Memorial and all land within a circle with a radius of 86 feet measured from the center of the Chota Memorial without regard to the elevation of the land within the circle.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F508BE86B194B25BD282A6A208640EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Property on lands</header><text>In addition to the land taken into trust by subsection (a), the improvements on and appurtenances thereto, including memorials, are and shall remain the property of the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7C565CA7155F4512A7889538978E3672"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional lands into trust</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians may identify additional Federal lands on or above the 820-foot (MSL) contour elevation managed by the Tennessee Valley Authority that are of significant historical and cultural importance to the Cherokee and such lands shall be taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians, if the Tennessee Valley Authority, Secretary of the Interior, and Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians agree to such lands being taken into trust.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5066E0FD3E124615947773FF74253C26"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Revised Maps</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of a land transaction made pursuant to this section, the Secretary of the Interior, after consultation with the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians and the Tennessee Valley Authority, shall submit revised maps that depict the land taken into trust under this section, including any corrections made to the maps described in this section to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E29869B395747538300C7F855A71AEB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contour elevation clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The contour elevations referred to in this Act are based on MSL Datum as established by the NGS Southeastern Supplementary Adjustment of 1936 (NGVD29).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H27CB3C0D8BC94D1B9FCA04E5F7E23FC5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The lands taken into trust under this section shall be subject to the conditions described in section 5.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H601CF7CB87A1449E96037202BB88764A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Permanent easements taken into trust for the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians</header>
 <subsection id="H1311AD5B66F44466865DA79ABFF34C52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permanent easements</header><text>The following permanent easements for land below the 820-foot (MSL) contour elevation for the following Federal lands in Monroe County, Tennessee, on the shores of Tellico Reservoir, are hereby taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians:</text>
 <paragraph id="H94FBEA10F26945D8820B34C7A8DC8A0A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chota Peninsula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 8.5 acres of land generally depicted as <quote>Chota Memorial 2</quote> on the map titled <quote>Eastern Band of Cherokee Historic Lands Reacquisition Map 3</quote> and dated April 30, 2015.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6A61B29A69441709B44175F2D61B427"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chota-Tanasi Trail</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 11.4 acres of land generally depicted as <quote>Chota-Tanasi Trail</quote> on the map titled <quote>Eastern Band of Cherokee Historic Lands Reacquisition Map 3</quote> and dated April 30, 2015.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H429E2ED7D7A04F8AA6BD6B54786531CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional easements</header><text>The Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians may identify additional Federal lands below the 820-foot (MSL) contour elevation managed by the Tennessee Valley Authority that are, or are appurtenant to, lands of significant historical and cultural importance to the Cherokee and a permanent easement for such lands shall be taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians, if the Tennessee Valley Authority, Secretary of the Interior, and Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians agree to such grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H601D5968564A45E78905E56A0AE2743D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revised Maps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of a land transaction made pursuant to this section, the Secretary of the Interior, after consultation with the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians and the Tennessee Valley Authority, shall submit to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate revised maps that depict the lands subject to easements taken into trust under this section, including any corrections necessary to the maps described in this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5200DB067E4C4FA7B089B28BFE47773C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The lands subject to easements taken into trust under this section shall be subject to the use rights and conditions described in section 5.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HAB366CC4EF5E4DC78B6375552FEED9FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Trust administration and purposes</header>
 <subsection id="H9B2FF8DA2C54429D94D06B1E7FA5C506"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicable laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as described in section 5, the lands subject to this Act shall be administered under the laws and regulations generally applicable to lands and interests in lands held in trust on behalf of Indian Tribes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAFB0E5D4E963498F9B87BEA915869710"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except the lands described in section 2(a)(2), the lands subject to this Act shall be used principally for memorializing and interpreting the history and culture of Indians and recreational activities, including management, operation, and conduct of programs of and for—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4FE449AE3A3E47849F0C1FCE67D1D306"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Sequoyah birthplace memorial and museum;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC5EFB4700114888B813A34A349EE8E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the memorials to Chota and Tanasi as former capitals of the Cherokees;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H23C4D4E7B6754C18ACB545AC380CB67F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the memorial and place of reinterment for remains of the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians and other Cherokee tribes, including those human remains and cultural items that are repatriated by the Tennessee Valley Authority to those Cherokee tribes under the National Graves Protection and Repatriation Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H334CBA4AF3984829A4FAFFC20B8DB2A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>interpreting the Trail of Tears National Historic Trail.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54ACB82E61DA4BA888EC2323A906759F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of support property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The land described in section 2(a)(2) shall be used principally for the support of lands subject to this Act and the programs offered by the Tribe relating to such lands and their purposes including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9C23099129A04FE1B90D6E127F4BEB5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>classrooms and conference rooms;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H98E158AB9D2B43A8BAE81C9EF8C09316"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cultural interpretation and education programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DE656194E9A4D6C9FBE4C24256A33A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>temporary housing of guests participating in such programs or the management of the properties and programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BD4B21F40794FC5B8BC4CEF7DAEC029"><enum>(4)</enum><text>headquarters offices and support space for the trust properties and programs.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60BB0524E3184DD6AC71E4E7DB7B6CC9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Land use</header><text>The principal purposes of the use of the land described in section 3(a)—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB36EEDE9663E48F7BEBC779C09DBC9B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>paragraph (1), shall be for a recreational trail from the general vicinity of the parking lot to the area of the Chota Memorial and beyond to the southern portion of the peninsula, including interpretive signs, benches, and other compatible improvements; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H523D0EB8377048E0B304FF7610C97C10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>paragraph (2), shall be for a recreational trail between the Chota and Tanasi Memorials, including interpretive signs, benches, and other compatible improvements.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA2393D9EE5154BB5B9D71DA4DB14C4D6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Use rights, conditions</header>
 <subsection id="H040E8E8170E049FD9E1FFF3D46B8A02B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Flooding of land and roads</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tennessee Valley Authority may temporarily and intermittently flood the lands subject to this Act that lie below the 824-foot (MSL) contour elevation and the road access to such lands that lie below the 824-foot (MSL) contour elevation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54AC19C9D0F141E6B3A7F57B47228DA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Facilities and structures</header><text>The Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians may construct, own, operate, and maintain—</text> <paragraph id="H2B5D7EE56AD24D838F1DB8F4D2121774"><enum>(1)</enum><text>water use facilities and nonhabitable structures, facilities, and improvements not subject to serious damage if temporarily flooded on the land adjoining the Tellico Reservoir side of the lands subject to this Act that lie between the 815-foot and 820-foot (MSL) contour elevations, but only after having received written consent from the Tennessee Valley Authority and subject to the terms of such approval; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2A1A952D9234DF4995DF08D7CC9D2C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>water use facilities between the 815-foot (MSL) contour elevations on the Tellico Reservoir side of the lands subject to this Act and the adjacent waters of Tellico Reservoir and in and on such waters after having received written consent from the Tennessee Valley Authority and subject to the terms of such approval, but may not construct, own, operate, or maintain other nonhabitable structures, facilities, and improvements on such lands.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC9FEAAA52FF45E189BD9A48FF6E6B86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ingress and egress</header><text>The Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians may use the lands subject to this Act and Tellico Reservoir for ingress and egress to and from such land and the waters of the Tellico Reservoir and to and from all structures, facilities, and improvements maintained in, on, or over such land or waters.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5BD3CA568764477593579CFEF52FCE73"><enum>(d)</enum><header>River control and development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use rights under this section may not be exercised so as to interfere in any way with the Tennessee Valley Authority’s statutory program for river control and development.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H46E4668231234D4986434A76F68AEFC1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>TVA authorities</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the right of the Tennessee Valley Authority to—</text> <paragraph id="H20357291D0914FB394ABF21933E9026A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>draw down Tellico Reservoir;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC4A4249E76F4207ACAF20A40DCA1B71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fluctuate the water level thereof as may be necessary for its management of the Reservoir; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H45A2F58CF9694E5EACA616E6C44E645B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>permanently flood lands adjacent to lands subject to this Act that lie below the 815-foot (MSL) contour elevation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CB2DBA1DA524F918609F1BF697F458B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Right of entry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The lands subject to this Act shall be subject to a reasonable right of entry by the personnel of the Tennessee Valley Authority and agents of the Tennessee Valley Authority operating in their official capacities as necessary for purposes of carrying out the Tennessee Valley Authority’s statutory program for river control and development.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H471F9C30F1E641C1AE7DED9DC91C5CD9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Entry onto land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that the Tennessee Valley Authority’s operations on the lands subject to this Act do not unreasonably interfere with the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians’ maintenance of an appropriate setting for the memorialization of Cherokee history or culture on the lands and its operations on the lands, the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians shall allow the Tennessee Valley Authority to enter the lands to clear, ditch, dredge, and drain said lands and apply larvicides and chemicals thereon or to conduct bank protection work and erect structures necessary in the promotion and furtherance of public health, flood control, and navigation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5E05314A3A074ED2A442E9D77ABE6C02"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Loss of hydropower capacity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All future development of the lands subject to this Act shall be subject to compensation to the Tennessee Valley Authority for loss of hydropower capacity as provided in the Tennessee Valley Authority Flood Control Storage Loss Guideline, unless agreed to otherwise by the Tennessee Valley Authority.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H905C4BC57D8449A6B8209A601F764ACA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Protection from liability</header><text>The Tennessee Valley Authority shall not be liable for any loss or damage resulting from—</text> <paragraph id="H840B4710709A4E998BFF2E2EA8D55494"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the temporary and intermittent flooding of lands subject to this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C61A0D26BC445F79C6B6E9931AD9DBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the permanent flooding of adjacent lands as provided in this section;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EF4FABE29164A7F9842C97614F5B8FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>wave action in Tellico Reservoir; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF046D04AA4D9482B948F7A53307C2660"><enum>(4)</enum><text>fluctuation of water levels for purposes of managing Tellico Reservoir.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H74FC1582CB334E47A0F655FE7D7CBB31"><enum>6.</enum><header>Lands Subject to the Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act, the term <term>lands subject to this Act</term> means lands and interests in lands (including easements) taken into trust for the benefit of the Eastern Band of Cherokee Indians pursuant to or under this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="HFBAE4212FE1A4CFEAF34E72AACA5B056"><enum>7.</enum><header>Gaming Prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No class II or class III gaming, as defined in the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>), shall be conducted on lands subject to this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


