<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H15D446B01A704D4C8C103B3BA995D5F4" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3710 IH: Safe Agriculture Production Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3710</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000458">Mr. Fincher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Plant Protection Act with respect to authorized uses of methyl bromide, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCF5C2D8AA2724AB990BB48C93CA90325" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2FCCEDD3E8AE45E4A100BCBF0CA64950" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Agriculture Production Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD0EBDF16FAEC4B53AB208AE9F4FC874A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Methyl bromide</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 419 of the Plant Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7719">7 U.S.C. 7719</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H87A68301EC8D44CB99795A2359848EF5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HB6B0ACDF98A2474DA3273F9B26D02FC8"><enum>419.</enum><header>Methyl bromide</header> 
<subsection id="H4116823DDE5B4DA18DDC581F23D75DC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header> 
<paragraph id="HFC45BA8E05C541A5BF7F9706A5CDFE89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), a State, local, or tribal authority may authorize the use of methyl bromide for a qualified use if the authority determines the use is required to respond to an emergency event. The Secretary may authorize such a use if the Secretary determines such a use is required to respond to an emergency event.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4364B88AA0214DB484AE1B268CBE7D53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 5 days after the date on which a State, local, or tribal authority makes the determination described in paragraph (1), the State, local, or tribal authority intending to authorize the use of methyl bromide for a qualified use shall submit to the Secretary a notification that contains the information described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA59F962AD58D48DBB0EFD3AEB0AE2E4A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Objection</header><text>A State, local, or tribal authority may not authorize the use of methyl bromide under paragraph (1) if the Secretary objects to such use under subsection (c) within the 5-day period specified in such subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB8A797198574419FB11C2ED86EAF66A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification contents</header><text>A notification submitted under subsection (a)(2) by a State, local, or tribal authority shall contain—</text> 
<paragraph id="H67B1012D0BF14402A393C7221F639CB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a certification that the State, local, or tribal authority requires the use of methyl bromide to respond to an emergency event;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F056EE3A50348929CA99D2EB2DB06A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the emergency event and the economic loss that would result from such emergency event;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE338062D48AE4EDB81A4361B2F17F006"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the identity and contact information for the responsible individual of the authority; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H997F2572045542F7865EE95E7EA8D4F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the qualified use of methyl bromide that is the subject of the notification—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H19AC7C25E4574801A7CBE9B5BFED7E45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the specific location in which the methyl bromide is to be used and the total acreage of such location;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88495681DC9B410690AA70E3DC6374EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the identity of the pest or pests to be controlled by such use;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD1749E71CF3424CA764D4CF6E10E420"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total volume of methyl bromide to be used; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF10D14DBDC0B4B1A8777C329C2347D6B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the anticipated date of such use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F5514540D3944B198C96A3F6DA2F3CF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Objection</header> 
<paragraph id="H5C850894E01F45DE84F620EBCD52B566"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, not later than 5 days after the receipt of a notification submitted under paragraph (2) of subsection (a), may object to the authorization of the use of methyl bromide under such subsection by a State, local, or tribal authority by sending the State, local, or tribal authority a notification in writing of such objection that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD3CA5FEFCA73482CA7B2279401EF4EB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>states the reasons for such objection; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74A72C8E5A9C489D9B820DF0800E1969"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifies any additional information that the Secretary would require to withdraw the objection. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BDD7A2FCEEA4A65A6FB87DD5C6BBA9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reasons for objection</header><text>The Secretary may object to an authorization described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H834D1A46058F42B8BCB657E111414465"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the notification submitted under subsection (a)(2) does not— </text> <clause id="HAD8BC1C2F9024E0B9DB624AC51BA7E43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contain all of the information specified in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC0D55344F9E5454E82630B43C2861897"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrate the existence of an emergency event; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64B8A69009C54A2E954DA16B359CDCF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the qualified use specified in the notification does not comply with the limitations specified in subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A961EDB5F144BFCAB14C51E548A051E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Withdrawal of objection</header><text>The Secretary shall withdraw an objection under this subsection if—</text> <subparagraph id="HA08833CC0F414C6BBCBF2F1D77B0120E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 14 days after the date on which the Secretary sends the notification under paragraph (1) to the State, local, or tribal authority involved, the State, local, or tribal authority submits to the Secretary the additional information specified in such notification; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C5D72C019FE4D56A1853270702D3793"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such additional information is submitted to the satisfaction of the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFBEB6F9CB964AF992821A7E353A0010"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect of withdrawal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the issuance of a withdrawal under paragraph (3), the State, local, or tribal authority involved may authorize the use of methyl bromide for the qualified use specified in the notification submitted under subsection (a)(2). </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE2585B5B76334DE6AE6AF0F525AFE89F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use for emergency events consistent with FIFRA</header><text>The production, distribution, sale, shipment, application, or use of a pesticide product containing methyl bromide in accordance with an authorization for a use under subsection (a) shall be deemed an authorized production, distribution, sale, shipment, application, or use of such product under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, regardless of whether the intended use is registered and included in the label approved for the product by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under such Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H670C036C1A054715A025E32933562C5B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitations on use</header> <paragraph id="H9085A84985594936A4C88594EEE9A5A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitations on use per emergency event</header><text>The amount of methyl bromide that may be used per emergency event at a specific location shall not exceed 20 metric tons.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FFEAABA84E844D894F3EB27EDEEDEEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limits on aggregate amount</header><text>The aggregate amount of methyl bromide allowed pursuant to this section for use in the United States in a calendar year shall not exceed the total amount authorized by the Parties to the Montreal Protocol pursuant to the Montreal Protocol process for critical uses in the United States in calendar year 2011.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9CC23C4934434AC79A6052A3A7170AC1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Ensuring adequate supply of methyl bromide</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, it shall not be unlawful for any person or entity to produce or import methyl bromide, or otherwise supply methyl bromide from inventories (produced or imported pursuant to the Clean Air Act for other purposes) in response to an emergency event in accordance with subsection (a). </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7996DD45495049E084B6441EE17D4238"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exclusive authority of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall have the exclusive Federal authority with respect to determining which species are considered quarantine pests (as defined in section 319.37–1 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Safe Agriculture Production Act of 2015</short-title>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1F72EA8381A344CCA2851478BA46DFD0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="H9588639EB4DA4EF8BC71432220258AAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emergency event</header><text>The term <quote>emergency event</quote> means a situation—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6CF83A96A3A841B5A8C3878CD7222A39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that occurs at a location on which a plant or commodity is grown or produced or a facility providing for the storage of, or other services with respect to, a plant or commodity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22FF6AA7E0874EE387538434C5078F45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which the lack of availability of methyl bromide for a particular use would result in significant economic loss to the owner, lessee, or operator of such a location or facility or the owner, grower, or purchaser of such a plant or commodity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF7194C71EC645CD89BF5BF556B9DFFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, in light of the specific agricultural, meteorological, or other conditions presented, requires the use of methyl bromide to control a pest or disease in such location or facility because there are no technically or economically feasible alternatives to methyl bromide easily accessible by an entity referred to in subparagraph (B) at the time and location of the event that—</text> <clause id="HDE75D733C05F41F891C714947111341B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are registered under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136">7 U.S.C. 136 et seq.</external-xref>) for the intended use or pest to be so controlled; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H851A000790E24896ABBD4325F4A8D8EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would adequately control the pest or disease presented at such location or facility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B32620ACAB148B0BE6BB93BB82ABBDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pest</header><text>The term <quote>pest</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136">7 U.S.C. 136</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D0E83E763E7481F91C0056724468315"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified use</quote> means, with respect to methyl bromide, a methyl bromide treatment or application in an amount not to exceed the limitations specified in subsection (e) in response to an emergency event.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

