<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H91A50453398B4DED92C6FE4F41C23AC6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2869 IH: Local and Municipal Health Care Choice Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2869</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150624">June 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000238">Mr. Thornberry</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to permit cooperative governing of public
			 entity health benefits through local governments in secondary States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3A429A88C43B459DAABD1732088A0777" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB1D8225435BD40ACB41F4B21AE003256" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local and Municipal Health Care Choice Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE18C41C3F703400F80FC2DAD0DC462AD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cooperative governing of public entity group health coverage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4420E48DD3CF4EE386BE55E30F9B00A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the section 2794 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-95">42 U.S.C. 300gg–95</external-xref>) relating to uniform fraud and abuse referral format as section 2795; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H077E757580B644FC87519BBB00173C2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="HACE7D18DB5544FA18918628911DC08B0" style="OLC"> <section id="H892A0C5829C14D03A002611424E3A929"><enum>2796.</enum><header>Authority to offer public entity group health coverage to local governments in a secondary State</header> <subsection id="H4E49928C3B12474DB01788352F7E5E2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A local government in a secondary State (as defined in subsection (i)(7)) may provide group health coverage to its officers, employees, or retirees (and their dependents) through a local government employee health benefits pool or program authorized under the laws of a primary State, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H972A007E188D46B9A13EDA754411860F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility for multistate activity</header><text>A local government employee health benefits pool or program shall be eligible to offer group health coverage to officials, employees, and retirees (and their dependents) of a local government located in a secondary State through an interlocal agreement with such local government, or as approved by an applicable State authority in such secondary State, unless—</text>
 <paragraph id="H128A64416ADB492B8201E8E41C012A43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a pool or program that primarily serves municipal officers, employees, or retirees (and their dependents), an objection is made to the offering of such coverage by the municipal league or association located in the secondary State within 90 days of the date on which the authority is granted or an interlocal agreement is executed; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2878874E57FA402EB56C98060EDC8C4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a pool or program that primarily serves county officers, employees, retirees (and their dependents), an objection is made to the offering of such coverage by the county association located in the secondary State within 90 days of the date on which the authority is granted or an interlocal agreement is executed.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA60552FA1B04F8FB97A5B47744F3ED1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of covered laws of primary State</header><text>The covered laws (as defined in subsection (i)(2)) of the primary State shall apply to group health coverage offered by a local government employee health benefits pool or program in the primary State and in any secondary State, but only if the coverage and the pool or program comply with the conditions of this section with respect to the offering of coverage in any secondary State.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H52E202A89DA64C11857017E2CEE3F8F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limited application of secondary State laws</header>
 <paragraph id="HE68433AD655F45068DA44BF2ACF94C05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this section, a local government employee health benefits pool or program that offers group health coverage in a secondary State to the officers, employees, or retirees (and their dependents) of a local government located in such secondary State, is exempt from any covered laws of the secondary State (and any rules, regulations, agreements, or orders sought or issued by such State under or related to such covered laws).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E4FEE8540074BB28CBEB1BD13EBB0A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secondary State authority</header><text>A secondary State may require a local government employee health benefits pool or program to do any or all of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H045B396BC0B84506B86DA7A5D3296CEE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Registration</header><text>To register with an applicable State authority in such State with jurisdiction over local government employee health benefits pools or programs and designate such authority as its agent solely for the purpose of receiving service of legal documents or process.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H052CA5C1EC27498CB675AA64EC8CF29D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>To file with an applicable state authority in such State—</text> <clause id="H825A1B1A947A4A4FBB701AFCE16ABD9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a written intent to do business in that State;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H37A1E7C2FDD24A10A78A7C76F4DEFFEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>copies of the membership or interlocal agreements entered into between the local government employee health benefits pool or program and a local government of that State; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H88A9F5DB5E5C45598904B1BA01086204"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>copies of annual audited financial statements of the local government employee health benefits pool or program filed with the primary State.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4713DB99673E42398F3B753E6B465614"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Compliance with injunctions</header><text>To comply with an injunction issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, upon a petition by an applicable State authority in such State alleging that the pool or program is in hazardous financial condition.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FECC50E6A524B9E9CE5EC658948A41B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Compliance with State fraud and abuse laws</header><text>To comply with any State law regarding fraud and abuse, except that if the State seeks an injunction regarding the conduct described in this subparagraph, such injunction must be obtained from a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72FDE798585249299FA146192A06A01F"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Compliance with State unfair claims settlement practices laws</header><text>To comply with any State law regarding unfair claims settlement practices.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69815890D33D47D0A508287882168875"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on secondary State authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a local government employee health benefits pool or program offers group health insurance coverage to officials, employees, and retirees (and their dependents) of a local government located in a secondary State pursuant to subsection (b), such secondary State may not do any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03CD13512134485FA1FE8DF3C2FFB7C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Countersigned by local agent or broker</header><text>Require any group health coverage issued by the pool or program to be countersigned by an insurance agent or broker residing in that secondary State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA48E08B6A924CF5AC4F05FDB83C7837"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submit to duplicative financial examinations</header><text>Require the pool or program to submit to an examination of its financial condition by an applicable State authority in such State, unless—</text>
 <clause id="H2B66E4A8D4AA4BAEAEF68047F1991120"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an applicable State authority of the primary State has not done an examination within the period recommended by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE496EBAC93BA4298B74985E2457A8FD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any such examination by the secondary State is conducted in accordance with the examiners’ handbook of the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and is coordinated to avoid unjustified duplication and unjustified repetition.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C26E96EED9940BE81F72086F0E0D69F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Discriminate against pool or program</header><text>Otherwise discriminate against the pool or program issuing group health coverage in both the primary State and in any secondary State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E3EC27EAA0744F0BC335A52745E7EF3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Benefit requirements</header><text>Group health coverage offered by a local government employee health benefits pool or program shall be at least as comprehensive as the coverage of the essential health benefits under section 1302(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18022">42 U.S.C. 18022(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3A6D7E7BD489450888FD063E1AE16ED0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Disclosure requirement</header><text>Prior to providing group health coverage to the officers, employees, or retirees (and their dependents) of a local government located in a secondary State, a local government employee health benefits pool or program shall provide notice to such individuals that the health coverage is governed by the covered laws and regulations of the primary State, as well as by any applicable Federal laws and regulations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H951B255F4C7048E5BA41C6401D3BDB0D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Status of group health coverage in secondary State</header><text>A local government employee health benefits pool or program that is not regulated as an insurer in its primary State, and whose group health plans are not regulated as insurance in its primary State, shall not be subject to the jurisdiction of a State insurance regulatory agency in any secondary State.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H622D2B8AF9C0482191B74AAE3E0F145A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Designation of primary State</header>
 <paragraph id="H58FD849695A542CB8813F9F1E233890C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of a single State</header><text>A local government employee health benefits pool or program may only designate one State as its primary State with respect to all such coverage it offers under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC66A01DA214906B7282344D48C91D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial operations in primary State</header><text>Such pool or program may not offer group health coverage in a secondary State until it is deemed to be doing business in the primary State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC26B092D833C49A896DEB0E4945DBEB6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H03A7FD24FEB0436BADE330AA7D81E71E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable State authority</header><text>The term <term>applicable State authority</term> means, with respect to a local government employee health benefits pool or program in a State, any official or officials designated by the State to administer the requirements of this section for the State with respect to such pool or program, including the official or officials with authority to approve interlocal agreements under applicable State law, but shall not include any State insurance regulatory agency.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HF93807229933434286F824A89DB52FC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered laws</header>
 <subparagraph id="H224B7628F1874185B095A958A0B0BB27"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered laws</term> means the laws, rules, regulations, agreements, and orders pertaining to any of the following:</text> <clause id="HAE91631BA92549D6A8FC5D5971DF1211"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Group health coverage issued by a local government employee health benefits pool or program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H214FFEC60B244544849C0ACBAA87F6A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The offer, sale, rating (including medical underwriting), renewal, and issuance of group health coverage to local government officials, employees, and retirees or their dependents.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC58532F7550545BA8EE73F19920DAB59"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The management, operations, and investment activities of a local government employee health benefits pool or program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC0003B51DEE54B15A86990EDFA75D3F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Loss control and claims administration for a local government employee health benefits pool or program with respect to liability for which the pool or program provides coverage.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2EE651AA2B2C4756B56D96294FD3B40A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The payment, on a nondiscriminatory basis, of applicable premium and other taxes (including high risk pool assessments) which are levied on health insurance issuers, brokers, or policyholders under the laws of the State.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD067CE25B754892900FDB9BEEF05887"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Such term does not include any law, rule, regulation, agreement, or order governing the use of care or cost management techniques, including any requirement related to provider contracting, network access or adequacy, health care data collection, or quality assurance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D89A714F199416F8ACB7C49AD04B045"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Group health coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>group health coverage</term> means medical care expense reimbursement provided under a group health plan.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F83C1D7C9C8435C93575717F8716DEB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>The term <term>local government</term> means a county, municipality, special district, school district, junior college district, housing authority, or other political subdivision or public entity defined under State law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE3E634CA01C4EB4B52D032238088604"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Local government employee health benefits pool or program</header><text>The term <term>local government employee health benefits pool or program</term> means a risk pool authorized or permitted by State statute or otherwise regulated by a State agency under which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H89AE09A2E8DE4E0A8D50420BC18E49BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local government or group of local governments, directly or through a pool, provide health care benefits primarily for local government officials, employees, and retirees and their dependents; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED308E487AD44A209621A0EEBA843E99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such pool may provide health care benefits from the assets of the pool or its member local governments through any combination of self-funded arrangements or fully insured products;</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and includes any other State authorized program designed to provide health benefits to local
 government officials, employees, and retirees and their dependents.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FB9026670EF4B87874EB9A5D108BF15"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Primary State</header><text>The term <term>primary State</term> means, with respect to group health coverage offered by a local government employee health benefits pool or program, the State designated by the pool or program as the State whose covered laws shall govern the pool or program in the issuance of such coverage under this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE55D3125C46C471688DEC83BF4FFA348"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secondary State</header><text>The term <term>secondary State</term> means, with respect to group health coverage offered by a local government employee health benefits pool or program, any State that is not the primary State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


