<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB1234FDB43F1488F8518F6C924CEDCFA" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2755 IH: American Worker Mobility Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2755</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150612">June 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide relocation subsidies for the long-term unemployed, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA6470C2867C5480E801715CCEE766F0E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB1FC3A57F4074F0E98CA7490E65D9BC2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Worker Mobility Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD652E61347BF4D4DBCC32926D980F10C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Relocation subsidies for the long-term unemployed</header> <subsection id="HE9A0797F52C84B44BFC64A9EC1B1D2B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may grant a relocation subsidy to an eligible individual who meets the requirements of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H87A5630A1D6147198A203F1034544866"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meaning of eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of this section, an eligible individual is an individual who, as of the date of the application for a relocation subsidy under this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD1A7279D4A824185A1601B16BF90306F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is totally unemployed and has been totally unemployed for at least 26 consecutive weeks;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1CCDF8EFCC843848719EA6A28642A0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has exhausted all rights to regular compensation under the law of a State or under Federal law with respect to a benefit year (excluding any benefit year ending before July 1, 2008);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD38CC2FA7A8843B3BB64A75302F16C77"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has not received a relocation subsidy under this section in the 2-year period preceding such date of application; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H090ED106A332418093A6664BE11765E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is able to work, available to work, and actively seeking work.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEEFB4F3D6EA64E8AB153B72F67B1778D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for grant</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may not grant a relocation subsidy to an eligible individual under this section unless the Secretary determines that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H11B1415B0320489FA24AEA145CA5A601"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the relocation subsidy will assist such individual in relocating within the United States, at least 60 miles from the individual’s current residence, for the purpose of attaining employment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98773ADC15D64029AD6C044C3FF18380"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such individual filed an application with the Secretary not later than January 1, 2020; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H69A8103F3C254B04BC49C2FF7E4C4AC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such individual—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0C50D9D5399245C38DA1717811F4DE5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has obtained a bona fide offer of suitable employment affording a reasonable expectation of long-term duration in the area in which the individual wishes to relocate; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H158D53931A0E47F1B596A7A5BF19CF60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>wishes to relocate to an area that has an unemployment rate that is at least 2 percentage points less than the unemployment rate of the area of the individual’s initial residence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H112D86915EA749DD85039057EA7C2734"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount of subsidy</header><text>A relocation subsidy granted to an eligible individual under this section shall be equal to the lesser of $10,000 or the amount that any contribution by a potential employer of the individual to the individual’s relocation expenses is exceeded by the sum of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB5931FEEB60B47EB9875F42F78A5551C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>90 percent of the reasonable and necessary expenses incurred in transporting the worker, the worker’s family, and household effects, plus</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E2712F2A4847C185E6B95BA0CD11AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a lump sum equivalent to 3 times the individual’s weekly benefit amount for the most recent benefit year (as such terms are defined in the State law), up to a maximum payment of $1,250.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EA5FA11E74C4A408F43326690131BEC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Prior to granting any relocation subsidies under subsection (a), the Secretary of Labor shall issue regulations designed to prevent fraud or abuse relating to the program established under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59876AD9C37D4139AC82B416BB2020C9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text>No additional appropriations are authorized for any fiscal year to carry out this Act.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H530CFE559D194C24B1176FC28D00A8FD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7A4123764F6448E89D37CBFB993EB0BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>regular compensation</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 205(2) of the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3304">26 U.S.C. 3304</external-xref> note), as in effect prior to January 1, 2014; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FDD7A9336D64DCD9FA0089BD308F3B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>suitable work</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="HC92DF8B35F3A45D1A7E56AD8E8BEE601"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means suitable work as defined in the applicable State law for claimants for regular compensation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2ABE3D206CD349A595D145F09E74BFBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include self-employment or employment as an independent contractor.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H800479E9BAD54F0499003D5F1387F436"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than March 15 of each of calendar years 2016 and 2018, the Secretary of Labor shall submit a report to Congress that identifies, by geographic region—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD8B459E038CA4350B727DB083C1498DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total number of relocation subsidies granted to individuals under this section during the calendar year preceding each such calendar year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AE01AC092D6445CA83A405CF9A690B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total number of relocation subsidies granted to individuals pursuant to subsection (c)(3)(A) during such calendar year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE365E138B95F474D9C221004D5EAF7D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total number of relocation subsidies granted to individuals pursuant to subsection (c)(3)(B) during such calendar year, and the number of such individuals who obtained employment within 1 month, 3 months, and 6 months, respectively, after the individual’s relocation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D098EC8AD6B4AC3B575A9AAE93B3733"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the average amount of a relocation subsidy granted during such calendar year;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H41916C6FBA124CB19899C38D1ACF7323"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the average distance traveled for relocation by each individual receiving a relocation subsidy during such calendar year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A9D47D6DDD419CBD690D8D1A2283D2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the number of individuals who received a relocation subsidy under this section during such calendar year and subsequently applied for unemployment benefits.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


