<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4305749FDB114FC39A66DBEA1D7DBBD7" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4117 IH: TRUST Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 4117</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20151119">November 19, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require statistics relating to community trust in law enforcement in the National Crime Victim’s Survey, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE218D11BAD604BAC8FFEA1AC73AC3FDC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB56E5919438648E39320DB0E90CE3C6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tracking Reputations Upgrades Societal Trust Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>TRUST Act of 2015</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0432EC6D46054D6AB04A3B007EBD2F6E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Required inclusion in the National Crime Victim's Survey of statistics relating to community trust in law enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, as part of each National Crime Victim's Survey, the Attorney General shall include statistics relating to the level of trust by the residents of a State or unit of local government in each law enforcement agency that serves that jurisdiction.</text> </section> 
<section id="H4068F81656DE4381A8EEF519C04A120F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report that includes recommendations of the Attorney General on actions that may be taken to improve the level of trust by residents of a State or unit of local government in law enforcement agencies serving that jurisdiction, if the results of the statistics required to be included in the National Crime Victim's Survey by section 2 of this Act indicate that such level of trust is, in the determination of the Attorney General, problematically low.</text> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

