<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H936674EFB07A4F0E84C8D15FB72B06F7" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4108 IH: To prohibit the use of funds for the provision of assistance to Syrian opposition groups and individuals.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 4108</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20151119">November 19, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="">Select Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit the use of funds for the provision of assistance to Syrian opposition groups and individuals.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB908A839A3144B6587C484FAB54EE0A8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H54121F5A574D4E7DB80E0CCA0D930627" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on provision of assistance to Syrian opposition groups and individuals</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds available to the Central Intelligence Agency, the Department of Defense, or any other agency or entity of the United States involved in intelligence activities, or to the National Security Council or its staff may not be obligated or expended to provide assistance, including training, equipment, supplies, stipends, construction of training and associated facilities, and sustainment, to any element of the Syrian opposition or to any other Syrian group or individual seeking to overthrow the government of the Syrian Arab Republic, unless, after the date of the enactment of this Act, funds are specifically authorized to be appropriated and appropriated by law for such purpose.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

