<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H041AC270B6E8407682044B48957BED35" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3911 IH: To make technical amendments to the Act of December 22, 1974, relating to lands of the Navajo Tribe, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3911</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151103">November 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To make technical amendments to the Act of December 22, 1974, relating to lands of the Navajo
			 Tribe, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HDCC7E3FA1DC44DE9877A5AC10A964389" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9D6FFACF75B042ECA31116BDF372E7B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Navajo reservation boundary clarification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 11 of the Act of December 22, 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d-10">25 U.S.C. 640d–10(b)</external-xref>), is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1F32870E1C8449A990234C6E614ED863"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>present boundary of the Navajo Reservation</quote> and inserting <quote>trust lands of the Navajo Tribe, including the bands of the Navajo Tribe, as of January 1, 2015</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCB3B9A771D1477D8EF4740A3EC14182"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>present boundary of the reservation</quote> and inserting <quote>trust lands of the Navajo Tribe, including the bands of the Navajo Tribe, as of January 1, 2015</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H8E768173075942A196A3F414ED8108CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reselection of lands to correct surveying error</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the Act of December 22, 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d-10">25 U.S.C. 640d–10</external-xref>), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H8698E5BD070C40C58EA616A8F39A9043" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H71C8D7E3EEA6415A9910AAA4B76B7A0B"><enum>(j)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1AAD703FAB8D408BBBDA1F37BACBFB7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Navajo Tribe may—</text> <subparagraph id="HA31126E04FD34252918F9E8FB7A7D5F5" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deselect not more than 757 acres of the land selected under this section as of January 1, 2014; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C30F3B7043649FD9DCDE02870EA8EAD" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reselect, accordance with this section, the same amount of acres of the land that is deselected under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDFB1E6DC3974FADA9AC8B0A41520A78" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any lands deselected under paragraph (1)(A) that were held in trust shall be taken out of trust and administered by the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H1296C8F33AF341628816B638E9E0A377"><enum>3.</enum><header>Fair rental value payments report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall submit a report to the Committee on Natural Resources in the House of Representatives and the Committee on Indian Affairs in the Senate a report that contains the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5F4477C4C5684184A5529462FBAD0751"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The dates that the Secretary rendered initial rental decisions on annual rents owed by the Navajo Tribe to the Hopi Tribe pursuant to section 16(a) of the Act of December 22, 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d-15">25 U.S.C. 640d–15(a)</external-xref>), for each of years 2001 through 2014, including an explanation for any delay longer than 12 months after the end of any year during that period.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4697ED3A58134D579D4D76BE4B5DE6D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The current status of all rental determinations for each of years 2001 through 2014, and, to the extent appeals are pending, where these appeals are pending, and how long such appeals have been pending at that locale.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB59B3B4BC2745D39384AF20A9FAE65B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that rental determinations have been delayed, the role, if any, in the delay that has been the result of contracts with the Bureau of Indian Affairs related to a contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450f">25 U.S.C. 450f</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D662FF443B54C259C2C1C70E9F46C51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whether contracts to perform those functions which are otherwise the obligations of the Bureau of Indian Affairs to carry out the requirements of section 16(a) of the Act of December 22, 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640-15">25 U.S.C. 640–15(a)</external-xref>), have been funded at the level necessary to ensure that these functions are properly performed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CB0BEE760184117BC5D42B091AED9E2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">What contract provisions, if any, have been included in any contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450f">25 U.S.C. 450f</external-xref>) between the Bureau of Indian Affairs and any contractor to ensure that the contractor’s performance of those functions which are otherwise the obligations of the Bureau of Indian Affairs to carry out the requirements of section 16(a) of the Act of December 22, 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d-15">25 U.S.C. 640d–15(a)</external-xref>), is free from conflicts of interest as required by part 900.231 through part .236 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB39B8A255AD2447CB97AE75A2BBD567E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The total amount that the Navajo Tribe has paid as rent and interest pursuant to section 16(a) of the Act of December 22, 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d-15">25 U.S.C. 640d–15(a)</external-xref>), including the amount of prejudgment interest paid by the Navajo Tribe and the amount of post-judgment interest paid by the Navajo Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A185E05B1014871AC6ABBE33F3E9CA4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A plan to bring initial rental determinations current through the 2015 year as of April 1, 2016.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D4B8E7CDF0A4058859D14F248E61434"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A plan to ensure that, beginning on April 1, 2017, all annual rental determinations are completed and delivered to the Navajo Tribe and the Hopi Tribe on or before April 1 of each year.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H250AA97AF656443D9A1BC13975FCDFED"><enum>4.</enum><header>Navajo tribe sovereignty empowerment demonstration project</header>
 <subsection id="HEAED52AE2C2C4106A765E4ADD6CE80BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Navajo sovereignty empowerment zones</header><text>The Navajo Tribe shall have the authority to designate up to 150,000 acres within one or more of the following, which shall be designated as Navajo Sovereignty Empowerment Zones:</text>
 <paragraph id="H586E1BC5073E44F7ACBBC3EEB068470D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Lands selected by the Navajo Tribe pursuant to section 11 of the Act of December 22, 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d-10">25 U.S.C. 640d–10</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H409D57D9B4D844CC925BC4646385821C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Lands within that portion of the Navajo Reservation lying west of the Executive Order Reservation of 1882 and bounded on the north and south by westerly extensions, to the reservation line, of the northern and southern boundaries of said Executive Order Reservation (formerly known as the <quote>Bennett Freeze</quote> area).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4ECADDCBB9E8422C8542DE04AB389113"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lands partitioned to the Navajo Tribe pursuant to sections 3 and 4 of the Act of December 22, 1974 (25 U.S.C. 640d–2 and 640d–3).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB47073F28D564233AEDFC5EEF25283F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of certain laws</header>
 <paragraph id="H46165FE0A46449FAB8634CD715EA7F1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to approval by the appropriate regulatory bodies under Navajo law, such as the Navajo Nation Environmental Protection Agency, the Navajo Nation Historic Preservation Department, and the Navajo Nation Department of Fish and Wildlife, within the Navajo Sovereignty Empowerment Zones, the Navajo Tribe may choose to waive any or all of the laws in paragraph (2) with regard to renewable energy development, housing development, public and community facilities, infrastructure development (including water and wastewater development, roads, transmission lines, gas lines, and rights-of-way), and related economic development.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FC3E537ECC34AD2A4836A7287C30FF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Law Eligible for Waiver</header><text>The laws referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFE7762F4184D4C6E9C1B203B63F70008"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F6A7B76408D4CB89393F14E513E3A47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDD276D4A2884CE4BD6554750FB2666B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E05BE9CFDCD4A92BADD0778E519BB34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5A76D1EC9E94E66A3AD2DB1F695B600"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/668dd">16 U.S.C. 668dd et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF842D07D86E43C188F58DD46AAAF98E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/742a">16 U.S.C. 742a et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CEF69DB4EE44FBA80E881CD7C676FF8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/661">16 U.S.C. 661 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ABD4F1C33AD4C3EB131405945D749BB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1EA933565A19472B9AF897A72C67EAFE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of title 54, United States Code, derived from the Act of August 25, 1916 (commonly known as the <quote>National Park Service Organic Act</quote>), <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/86/523">Public Law 86–523</external-xref>, and <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/383">Public Law 91–383</external-xref>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91DD346802DA497B8E051E1A664E09DD"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Sections 401(7), 403, and 404 of the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/625">Public Law 95–625</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77C01DDCB3664FCA8AAE6EFC5EA9853C"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The Arizona Desert Wilderness Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/628">Public Law 101–628</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E18E9BD944C42EBAFFC048B68D2F56E"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8442BB174B14A3AB4F0A384A4A4C99E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grand Canyon exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to projects within the rim of the natural formation commonly referred to as the Grand Canyon.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2D29ED64A55480A89E258C252431E00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of savings to the navajo tribe</header>
 <paragraph id="H885167047EBC4C9F9CDF7533C384D482"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Federal agencies responsible for implementation of the laws listed in subsection (b)(2) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H533A31620D9D426197188D212D05D5D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult in good faith with the Navajo Tribe to determine the cost that the Federal agency would have otherwise expended on implementation of the laws or regulations described in subsection (b) in the Navajo Empowerment Zones, and this amount shall not be less than the agency would have otherwise provided for the operation of programs or portions thereof, without regard to any organizational level within the agency at which the program, function, service, or activity or portion thereof, including supportive administrative functions and including indirect costs that are provided in support of the operation of the program, function, service or activity or portion thereof, is operated; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D8D57CF10E14B47A3292A54C745FEDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later the 90 days after the beginning of each applicable fiscal year, transfer to the Navajo Tribe the amount of funds identified under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8AE6BACDD3C408386FD6A34FAB8F1FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The Navajo Tribe shall use all monies that it receives under this subsection to implement tribal law in the Navajo Sovereignty Empowerment Zones.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFE01106AB24003B0905444BF184592"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final agency action</header><text>Federal agency decisions made pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be final agency action for the purposes of appeal to the appropriate Federal district court pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC82D86CBC12D43A6BC7073E23DB7339B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil jurisdiction</header>
 <paragraph id="H4FA05870B9164A5DA6C3B05F0F3D1333"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all individuals and entities operating within a Navajo Sovereignty Empowerment Zone shall be subject to the full civil and regulatory jurisdiction of the Navajo Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE61D77A9DB9D4B6096E8A151B9FAEF0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Full faith and credit</header><text>Any judgment issued by the Navajo Tribe consistent with this section shall be accorded full faith and credit by the court of another State, Indian tribe, or territory and by Federal district courts.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DC06F9E2DD84B50BBA61C4634E8E7AD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tribal sovereignty</header><text>Nothing in this section supersedes, replaces, negates, or diminishes—</text> <paragraph id="HB54A2AA80C8F4FACB0FF578BD996C079"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the laws and regulations of the Navajo Nation, which shall remain in full force and effect within the Navajo Sovereignty Empowerment Zones; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72BFC30D1B2B45108B74232316B07028"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the treaties or other agreements between the United States and the Navajo Tribe.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H403F23E3ECB3409EA62AC9B1C5F0929F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Navajo-Hopi dispute Settlement Act</header><text>Nothing in this section waives the provisions of the Navajo-Hopi Dispute Settlement Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d">25 U.S.C. 640d</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE315120992DE422E9016D4C2E018CB1C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding and grants</header><text>Nothing in this section negates or diminishes the eligibility of the Navajo Tribe to receive or continue to receive funding and grants under the Navajo-Hopi Dispute Settlement Act of 1996 or any other laws of the United States.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H54FDDA25D7454422899DCAD81597D69D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Relinquishment of accommodation agreement and eligibility for relocation benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Navajo-Hopi Land Dispute Settlement Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d">25 U.S.C. 640d</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H98FD6DDEE23E462190285E8EB2E595FB" style="OLC">
				<section id="HD13505E8676440E6BBC1AED6896DB401"><enum>13.</enum><header>Relinquishment of accommodation agreement and eligibility for relocation benefits</header>
 <subsection id="HC205B9187C9B41D284F7E1DD14317BCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Settlement Agreement, or the Accommodation Agreement, any Navajo head of household, or the successor thereto if such person is no longer the head of household, who has entered into an Accommodation Agreement shall have the following rights:</text>
 <paragraph id="H23E6E00206AD4306B524476C950861F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To relinquish that Agreement for up to two years after the effective date of this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H638C25AC6AC44810958FC004676F4708"><enum>(2)</enum><text>After a relinquishment under paragraph (1), to receive the full relocation benefits to which the Navajo head of household would otherwise have been entitled had the head of household not signed the Accommodation Agreement, including relocation housing, counseling, and other services. In the event that the Navajo head of household is no longer the head of household, the successor thereto shall be entitled to receive the full relocation benefits.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H662C003A1B9043A3B6F4C0560CDA60BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>A relinquishment under subsection (a) shall not go into effect until the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation provides the full relocation benefits to the Navajo head of household, or successor thereto.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H79A78C1AC45F4F05A0B3530B40EE4625"><enum>6.</enum><header>Navajo rehabilitation trust fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 32 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/531">Public Law 93–531</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640d-30">25 U.S.C. 640d–30</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5932D29C0CC94E9B9AAEE3D5B12B8CFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA8F88EC77D784F87B8394158699F8941"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9E09E9EE1E14A1E85DE880621B6B10E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40D1DED7C25640BFB22DFAF68F75AC8F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HDEF8959F78A5428FA3B3AEB9C87398D0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HEFFBF3E4F2C6480FACE8C4BA68E61D8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>at the discretion of the Navajo Tribe, to use for development in the Navajo Sovereignty Empowerment Zones established pursuant to section 104.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9759414D5F324357AE3BA4F14B68807D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the first sentence of subsection (f), by striking <quote>and the United States has been reimbursed for funds appropriated under subsection (f) of this section</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7A5D8B89544EF394B39BC7B04EB70B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> <subparagraph id="H163434FB29EA490A9E8D11089BFB625E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>1990, 1991, 1992, 1993, and 1994</quote> and all that follows through the final period and inserting <quote>2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, and 2019.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87527C3AB5AC4D9891901509EB7A4BEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

