<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE876BB97FA3A4B3B9C6778E62FE23858" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4287 IH: Wireless Tax Fairness Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4287</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151217">December 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000445">Mr. Forbes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000413">Mr. Whitfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001045">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000213">Mr. Barton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To restrict any State or local jurisdiction from imposing a new discriminatory tax on cell phone
			 services, providers, or property.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF44512D3C59341E2930CD659F1F7270F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6AC9D6C689864523AD5136F1FBA8262C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wireless Tax Fairness Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB083E18051B343EB9D4C5E4F338B06DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8B212FB0F90840C18B11659B1AADAC60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It is appropriate to exercise congressional enforcement authority under section 5 of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and Congress’ plenary power under article I, section 8, clause 3 of the Constitution of the United States (commonly known as the <term>commerce clause</term>) in order to ensure that States and political subdivisions thereof do not discriminate against providers and consumers of mobile services by imposing new selective and excessive taxes and other burdens on such providers and consumers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBE8C26BF75049D7A9C00671836D9D29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In light of the history and pattern of discriminatory taxation faced by providers and consumers of mobile services, the prohibitions against and remedies to correct discriminatory State and local taxation in section 306 of the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/11501">49 U.S.C. 11501</external-xref>) provide an appropriate analogy for congressional action, and similar Federal legislative measures are warranted that will prohibit imposing new discriminatory taxes on providers and consumers of mobile services and that will assure an effective, uniform remedy.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H69E2C8B1DDD74206AB5C841428BA11DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Moratorium</header>
 <subsection id="H97F4D5CE5D0E497F9C7C350D81A4BF87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No State or local jurisdiction shall impose a new discriminatory tax on or with respect to mobile services, mobile service providers, or mobile service property, during the 5-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5255FF71F5954760A2CE5DD1C74E06C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HEF244E9DFAAD4FE08DB110BA4AB82995"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mobile service</header><text>The term <term>mobile service</term> means commercial mobile radio service, as such term is defined in section 20.3 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, or any other service that is primarily intended for receipt on, transmission from, or use with a mobile telephone or other mobile device, including but not limited to the receipt of a digital good.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB779C0EFD5D94B75A05E50B12FD6105B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mobile service property</header><text>The term <term>mobile service property</term> means all property used by a mobile service provider in connection with its business of providing mobile services, whether real, personal, tangible, or intangible (including goodwill, licenses, customer lists, and other similar intangible property associated with such business).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H956F823061F5464DAB3698E7F9F8C881"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mobile service provider</header><text>The term <term>mobile service provider</term> means any entity that sells or provides mobile services, but only to the extent that such entity sells or provides mobile services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA36713812DAC45AE9F8B470316C985D5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>New discriminatory tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>new discriminatory tax</term> means a tax imposed by a State or local jurisdiction that is imposed on or with respect to, or is measured by, the charges, receipts, or revenues from or value of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0F4C345271B248758887D84967E07D62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a mobile service and is not generally imposed, or is generally imposed at a lower rate, on or with respect to, or measured by, the charges, receipts, or revenues from other services or transactions involving tangible personal property;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EFD828AD39D4D81BCB87794E60861F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a mobile service provider and is not generally imposed, or is generally imposed at a lower rate, on other persons that are engaged in businesses other than the provision of mobile services; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A1D0CF41BC24F56A5931A43EFBE0680"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a mobile service property and is not generally imposed, or is generally imposed at a lower rate, on or with respect to, or measured by the value of, other property that is devoted to a commercial or industrial use and subject to a property tax levy, except public utility property owned by a public utility subject to rate of return regulation by a State or Federal regulatory authority;</text>
					</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">unless such tax was imposed and actually enforced on mobile services, mobile service providers, or
 mobile service property prior to the date of enactment of this Act.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD93AE12754DA471084BA89A07763B051"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State or local jurisdiction</header><text>The term <term>State or local jurisdiction</term> means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, any territory or possession of the United States, a political subdivision of any State, territory, or possession, or any governmental entity or person acting on behalf of such State, territory, possession, or subdivision that has the authority to assess, impose, levy, or collect taxes or fees.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H1EAF8C093D2647DDB60933834CF0BDCD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tax</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3A81386FD18645E1A91C318AF1FEA754"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>tax</term> means a charge imposed by a governmental entity for the purpose of generating revenues for governmental purposes, and excludes a fee imposed on a particular entity or class of entities for a specific privilege, service, or benefit conferred exclusively on such entity or class of entities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H532B9BFEC70C42F086A286D23BBCCEEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>tax</term> does not include any fee or charge—</text> <clause id="H9AD3CE379B7A4994AF6A72FDA863DF27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>used to preserve and advance Federal universal service or similar State programs authorized by section 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5DAA4C0CA11A42A180E60C0895890198"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specifically dedicated by a State or local jurisdiction for the support of E–911 communications systems; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDC87034AB1CC48E4BED68DE9DF563FA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used to preserve and advance Federal telecommunications relay services or State programs implementing this Federal mandate pursuant to title IV of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/336">Public Law 101–336</external-xref>; 104 Stat. 327) and codified in section 225 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/225">47 U.S.C. 225</external-xref>).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14934A81840D463EA24ABC1292BFC1D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header>
 <paragraph id="H7F1C39C31B744DEFAEA5433282EFA4C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(4), all taxes, tax rates, exemptions, deductions, credits, incentives, exclusions, and other similar factors shall be taken into account in determining whether a tax is a new discriminatory tax.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7019A513CC2B4330B3DF93FE67E7F82D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of principles</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, in determining whether a tax on mobile service property is a new discriminatory tax for purposes of subsection (b)(4)(C), principles similar to those set forth in section 306 of the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/11501">49 U.S.C. 11501</external-xref>) shall apply.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4E3A31D53F7450799C44E2457DFE780"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="HB7C03ABA5D7C4C4A910281AB245F36EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>generally imposed</term> as used in subsection (b)(4) shall not apply to any tax imposed only on—</text>
 <clause id="H9B8D562CD7974FA7A2D42D0187AB8225"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specific services;</text> </clause><clause id="H2525D59266A04EA1BA04806C33481459"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specific industries or business segments; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H638E212060DA455D83645F75B9544B75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>specific types of property; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H46945A8132DE4B21BF90188C910B2AF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>new discriminatory tax</term> shall not include a new tax or the modification of an existing tax that either—</text>
						<clause commented="no" id="H78AF14432122432382929C01DB00B07C"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD892E10ED30B49F8871951D3F61EA6BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>replaces one or more taxes that had been imposed on mobile services, mobile service providers, or mobile service property; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HCD2EE41F04C94D47B8A375B70E71AE2F" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is designed so that, based on information available at the time of the enactment of such new tax or such modification, the amount of tax revenues generated thereby with respect to such mobile services, mobile service providers, or mobile service property is reasonably expected to not exceed the amount of tax revenues that would have been generated by the respective replaced tax or taxes with respect to such mobile services, mobile service providers, or mobile service property; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEE9F4F8FBC445848EDA9D3177FEB348"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a local jurisdiction tax that may not be imposed without voter approval, provides for at least 90 days’ prior notice to mobile service providers, and is required by law to be collected from mobile service customers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4A31549E7C4D4E1789BC660B156A3638"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of section 1341 of title 28, United States Code, or the constitution or laws of any State, the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, without regard to amount in controversy or citizenship of the parties, to grant such mandatory or prohibitive injunctive relief, interim equitable relief, and declaratory judgments as may be necessary to prevent, restrain, or terminate any acts in violation of this Act.</text>
 <paragraph id="H34BCD1D17B314834A3946733AFC8B802"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>Such jurisdiction shall not be exclusive of the jurisdiction which any Federal or State court may have in the absence of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF724010C3B6F45C7AAAFBFC962329962"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>The burden of proof in any proceeding brought under this Act shall be upon the party seeking relief and shall be by a preponderance of the evidence on all issues of fact.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA170F3F4B3DE4FF0B5AC18BFB31C5B32"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In granting relief against a tax which is discriminatory or excessive under this Act with respect to tax rate or amount only, the court shall prevent, restrain, or terminate the imposition, levy, or collection of not more than the discriminatory or excessive portion of the tax as determined by the court.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HBEFA3B48185343DC9A995A419AA1083F"><enum>5.</enum><header>GAO study</header>
 <subsection id="H13ED17944D2A49E8B15471A75A8F6618"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study, throughout the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, to determine—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF5BFF9BB8C024CDEAF75DC85C5223E59"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how, and the extent to which, taxes imposed by local and State jurisdictions on mobile services, mobile service providers, or mobile property, impact the costs consumers pay for mobile services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H555ACA1EC6EC440CB53771511E1224EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the moratorium on discriminatory mobile services taxes established in this Act has any impact on the costs consumers pay for mobile services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC4F6054492A42C7B12CDF80EB817DE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit, to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, a report containing the results of the study required under subsection (a) and shall include in such report recommendations for any changes to laws and regulations relating to such results.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


