<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H536E47BA4D99499A9FA7B7D683E4F963" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3033 IH: Research Excellence and Advancements for Dyslexia Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3033</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150713">July 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the President’s annual budget request to Congress each year to include a line item for
			 the Research in Disabilities Education program of the National Science
			 Foundation and to require the National Science Foundation to conduct
			 research on dyslexia.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE7DD07B99EF74628870085F5BE65E3F4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1054ABD685384A7DA02B9AFA9D304692" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title<editorial></editorial></header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Research Excellence and Advancements for Dyslexia Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>READ Act</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="HF359F7BAD8BB4E35946EF0E8AE33FC0D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD226BE89FE3A4E2A808CAC5845A13601"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dyslexia is defined as an unexpected difficulty in reading by an individual who has the intelligence to be a much better reader.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H281A91B5B27F44FBBBD707870273CB09"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As many as one out of six, or 8,500,000, American school children may have dyslexia.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H56042CEB5C8F4442B3A45E1B21F7063E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since 1975, dyslexia has been included in the list of qualifying learning disabilities under the Education for All Handicapped Children Act of 1975 and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HEA41A138B66442B3ABDE55DF6504A733"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research in Disabilities Education</header>
 <subsection id="HE093511DC67B4ECB816098D0BE019C6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act alters the National Science Foundation’s Research in Disabilities Education program for fundamental and implementation research about learners (of all ages) with disabilities, including dyslexia, in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM). The National Science Foundation shall continue to encourage efforts to understand and address disability-based differences in STEM education and workforce participation, including differences for dyslexic learners.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3BBA8F58F00141B695F8566D088FF767"><enum>(b)</enum><header> Line item</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall include the amount requested for the Research in Disabilities Education program in the Foundation’s annual congressional budget justification.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HFA90CD0D0A6841A3A8B449F332DDCC23"><enum>4.</enum><header>Dyslexia</header>
 <subsection id="H01FEE48D31334D77A19F81068E457FCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Science Foundation shall support multi-directorate, merit-reviewed, and competitively awarded research on the science of dyslexia, including the early identification of children and students with dyslexia, professional development for teachers and administrators of students with dyslexia, and curricula and educational tools needed for children with dyslexia. Research supported under this subsection shall be conducted with the goal of practical application.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7D5967C6EFAA4C95A925B009FA1233FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Science Foundation shall devote at least $5,000,000 annually to research described in subsection (a), to come from amounts made available for the Research and Related Activities account or the Education and Human Resources Directorate. No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated under this section. This Act shall be carried out using funds otherwise appropriated by law.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


