<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H25957904C0B44E98A77069165E056924" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2641 IH: Horseracing Integrity and Safety Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2641</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150603">June 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve the integrity and safety of interstate horseracing, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4669F0DD4D6A42F281935FB3A5383438" style="OLC">
 <section id="H085DA609DEC34E98A2135093B0A73730" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Horseracing Integrity and Safety Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1DD05D5C5BCA4E239E1BA95E231EA509"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H05BBED7A54AB49F7AD06BA071D9AC9B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act prohibits the adulteration or misbranding of any food, drug, or device in interstate commerce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5102F9CE49A5436F8978FFE066B28511"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The manufacture, delivery, and use of certain performance enhancing drugs in horseracing can constitute violations of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H844C9A430D934363A59618A195C39F3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to a Food and Drug Administration Import Alert titled <quote>Animal Drug Imported For Use By Racetrack Veterinarians</quote>, the Food and Drug Administration routinely receives complaints from State racetrack authorities about the illegal use of clenbuterol, detomidine hydrochloride, glu­co­sa­minoglycan polysulfuric acid ester, hyaluronic acid, and isoxsuprine hydrochloride.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DAE703EA49E4B6D852B74EA18D2F1C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Currently, nearly every horse participating in interstate horseracing is injected shortly before racing with furosemide, a drug that is approved by the Food and Drug Administration for use in horses only for the treatment of edema.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A72C4743CD94A399D1474B330250241"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress enacted the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978 to regulate interstate commerce with respect to parimutuel wagering on horseracing in order to further the horseracing industry of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD47580D4B94467791063345B0050797"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The use of performance-enhancing drugs in horseracing is widespread in the United States, where no uniform regulations exist with respect to the use of, and testing for, performance-enhancing drugs in interstate horseracing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01DCD775C8294857B9F2EDD9B3CE4B2D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A 2012 New York Times investigation found that, on average, every week 24 horses die racing, a high equine fatality rate likely caused by the misuse of permitted medication and abuse of illegal drugs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16669AE600214ABFB3D07E75E47490A8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A 2013 horseracing industry study found that a large majority of parimutuel wagering participants avoid wagering at certain tracks and when certain trainers compete because they assume illegal drug use affects race results.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H346715FE82954018A7EBF157F7420D29"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Total parimutuel wagering on Thoroughbred horseracing in the United States declined 30 percent from 2002 to 2014.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HE7095B05EA7A4F83A394BA6D2091C3C0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE1F45A3A956544F5AC857A6BF39297E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interstate off-track wager; horsemen's group; host racing association; off-track betting system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>interstate off-track wager</term>, <term>horsemen's group</term>, <term>host racing association</term>, and <term>off-track betting system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3002">15 U.S.C. 3002</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D47618489B042839D1BE8A408DCDE47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Veterinarian-client-patient relationship</header><text>The term <term>veterinarian-client-patient relationship</term> has the meaning of that term as used in the Principles of Veterinary Medical Ethics of the American Veterinary Medical Association (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HFCDC87A0261242E38BFEA117A96F7882"><enum>4.</enum><header>Independent anti-doping organization for interstate horseracing</header>
 <subsection id="HB77AD666730547B18C758DF8A1D897DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be an independent anti-doping organization with responsibility for ensuring the integrity and safety of horseraces that are the subject of interstate off-track wagers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4ED10DE3EF1D4585BA4ECC79C5B98D0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the independent anti-doping organization referred to in subsection (a) with respect to horseraces described in that subsection are the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF61DC857664A4DEFADC39C1771F00DB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing, publishing, and maintaining rules with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H4E6428EB80F246B79AC1B1FB5D297BCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substances, methods, and treatments that may not be administered to a horse participating in such a horserace;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07B0789B0D664687A7F672C8FDE59744"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substances, methods, and treatments that may be administered to a horse participating in such a horserace in the context of a veterinarian-client-patient relationship; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93A56A2FEA634D6CB7A4760B9576D868"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of substances, methods, and treatments permitted under subparagraph (B), including rules with respect to the period before a horserace (which may not be less than 24 hours before a horserace) during which a horse may no longer receive such substances, methods, and treatments.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H240358352E2F4A1CA7DAC07405EA80A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Implementing programs relating to anti-doping education, research, testing, and adjudication to prevent any horse participating in a horserace described in subsection (a) from racing under the effect of any substance, method, or treatment that could affect the performance of the horse (other than a substance, method, or treatment described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) administered during a time period that is permitted under subparagraph (C) of that paragraph).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H225CF29896524DA3B02B3D36E8140F42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Excluding from participating in any horserace described in subsection (a) any person that the independent anti-doping organization or a State racing commission determines—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9BB2B5F4D6634C789AEFE9D9873A234F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has violated a rule with respect to a substance, method, or treatment that may not be administered to a horse participating in such a horserace under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDF6FAC5D6754C62A6E18B7F8D316022"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has violated 3 or more times a rule with respect to a substance, method, or treatment permitted under subparagraphs (B) and (C) of that paragraph that has the ability to affect the performance of a horse; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4379663B806E4CB4B21C273ABAB94642"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is subject to a suspension from horseracing activities by any State racing commission.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6894B8274154974B1865045385367ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The independent anti-doping organization referred to in subsection (a) shall publish the rules required by subsection (b) not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF5559603EEDC4017874D2252ABCCFCBB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Suspension of exclusion period</header><text>The independent anti-doping organization referred to in subsection (a) may—</text> <paragraph id="H2B6967C0B8C840CB83F0EB66C9A170B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>suspend a period of exclusion from participating in a horserace imposed on a person pursuant to subsection (b)(3) if the person provides substantial assistance to the organization or other persons that results in the discovery of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H77EDAFEBCEEE462CB768B66168E6FF95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a violation of a rule published under subsection (b) by another person; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94ED6DF73FC8429BAED0A8DE8A90755E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a violation of Federal or State law by another person; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BBFCEAC698B4EA5BF71A5EA8BC3EFCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may reinstate all or part of a period of exclusion imposed on a person and suspended under paragraph (1) if the person fails to provide substantial assistance described in that paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9677C7A5719745E8A998BF21FA38718E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing, publishing, and maintaining rules under subsection (b)(1), the independent anti-doping organization referred to in subsection (a) shall consult with State racing commissions, host racing associations, horsemen's groups, and other interested persons.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H771002D2DD104FEBAE7C7EE88B056390"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Transition rule with respect to furosemide</header><text>During the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the independent anti-doping organization referred to in subsection (a) shall permit the use of furosemide in a horse participating in a horserace described in subsection (a) if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H415B0B64EE8D4A858B00166E564D79F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the horse is 3 years old or older; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H850B3322F93C4CAC91A079ABD03B270C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the use of furosemide—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA22E06C590A0457F886B9A1148E4FB83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complies with the requirements of the document entitled <term>ARCI–011–020 Medications and Prohibited Substances</term> published by the Association of Racing Commissioners International, Inc.; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H278FF7B8F4434C188BAAFE56379DE749"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is within the context of a veterinarian-client-patient relationship.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84AA54FF46814F9EBC8B3202C8390311"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Designation of organization</header><text>The independent anti-doping organization designated pursuant to section 701 of the Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/2001">21 U.S.C. 2001</external-xref>) shall serve as the independent anti-doping organization referred to in subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE8533DEAAD774630A82EF80F3BDD441B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Consent required for acceptance of interstate off-track wagers</header>
 <subsection id="HE8A0EDA6DF5F48F29B92E72A2D416950"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, a host racing association may conduct a horserace that is the subject of an interstate off-track wager, and an interstate off-track wager may be accepted by an off-track betting system, only if consent is obtained from the independent anti-doping organization referred to in section 4(a).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD5C0332D77CC4818B59F26707D7F361C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for agreement</header>
 <paragraph id="H460E2AECA70C44B0BBBC4DBCCE8DDB48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A host racing association shall obtain the consent required by subsection (a) of the independent anti-doping organization referred to in section 4(a) pursuant to an agreement entered into between the association and the organization that specifies the terms and conditions relating to such consent, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEF32731FAD6E4C6C97E15837E45375CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>compliance with the rules published under section 4(b); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB77B1DC428045A59868BFC9CD095C68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>payments to the organization to defray the costs of carrying out the duties of the organization under this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC418DD8684C45DEBA4E55637AB4734B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defrayal of costs</header><text>The independent anti-doping organization referred to in section 4(a) shall ensure that all of the costs incurred by the organization in carrying out the duties of the organization under this Act are defrayed pursuant to agreements entered into under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


