<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD3D551C81614B5698774424E0A347ED" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3090 IH: Alzheimer’s Caregiver Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3090</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150716">July 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000030">Ms. Loretta Sanchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants for training and support services for
			 Alzheimer’s patients and their families.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA42E96AFF8A04F84841B0F16B3B01807" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4844DA6BEB94A84BB669F472218C6F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alzheimer’s Caregiver Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE17DF0BDE0644F4A8054AB0903CE0540"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants regarding training and support services for Alzheimer’s patients and their families</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title III of the <act-name parsable-cite="PHSA">Public Health Service Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 330L the following:</text>
			<quoted-block act-name="Public Health Service Act" id="HFD5DE5FFA76848A48FE0BACC7B240D3F">
				<section id="HEA429E52979C488094CF6AB7EDE246A4"><enum>330M.</enum><header>Grants regarding training and support services for Alzheimer’s patients and their families</header>
 <subsection id="H766E701165F84082A08DD3471B8FE545"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may make grants to public and nonprofit private health care providers for the purpose of expanding training and support services for families and caregivers of patients with Alzheimer’s disease.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC0EB954146184731B0B011C30D24A490"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recipients of grants</header><text>The public and nonprofit private health care providers to whom grants may be made under subsection (a) include health care organizations, community health centers, nursing homes, senior centers, Area Agencies on Aging, community-based organizations, and State, local, and tribal health agencies and social service agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0CE006027BB84EDE84540025D0DD38BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Integration of treatment, training, and support services</header><text>A condition for the receipt of a grant under subsection (a) is that the applicant involved agrees to employ a comprehensive approach to Alzheimer’s care that integrates treatment of patients with Alzheimer’s disease with training and support services for the patients’ families and caregivers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H65B8A5514C2B46F0AF618E591AB57F27"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate with the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Women’s Health and the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health in order to ensure that women, minorities, and patients who live in medically underserved communities (as defined in section 799B(6)) are able to benefit from the training and support services funded through grants under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H458AC0191237431DBC891EAD45EFE84F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate cultural context</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition for the receipt of a grant under subsection (a) is that the applicant involved agrees that, in any program to be funded by such grant, services will be provided in the languages most appropriate for, and with consideration for the cultural backgrounds of, the individuals for whom the services are provided.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBAE229D747A84543B100FD9E80D92A1A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Outreach services</header><text>A condition for the receipt of a grant under subsection (a) is that the applicant involved agrees to provide outreach activities to inform the public of the services of the program, and to provide information on Alzheimer’s disease.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H560A898A1EE74B2C9000F0BF90E59A1B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application for grant</header><text>A grant may be made under subsection (a) only if an application for the grant is submitted to the Secretary and the application is in such form, is made in such manner, and contains such agreements, assurances, and information as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H43516E8080574FA1BB76D444F519B129"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="H77F2BE853FF54145ACB736CAF59C892C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2021.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D8389C389AD45E28016BAC98CD29EA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation for medically underserved communities</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall make available not less than 10 percent for grants under subsection (a) to applicants that primarily serve medically underserved communities, as defined in section 799B(6).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


