<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5BA23200607C4BD3B6051C83C644961C" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 415 IH: Stop Corporate Inversions Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 415</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150120">January 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the rules relating to inverted corporations.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6AEFD8B91AF04AF083710F772AA1FCC1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDD8346C0661146988EE34C4B442F4B65" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Corporate Inversions Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAD53CDA4843149699847014834B7F5A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modifications to rules relating to inverted corporations</header> <subsection id="H877859AA595C48BE9DD1B48D83522D7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7874">section 7874</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB75C15EFCFCD4F90AA232E4EDE08A118" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H9311E24A4176452292245B5BC6425CD4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inverted corporations treated as domestic corporations</header> 
<paragraph id="HBACA65D01C8F43B6BF130842088C0557"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 7701(a)(4), a foreign corporation shall be treated for purposes of this title as a domestic corporation if—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C5C1F313ABE48A4B4AFEB4E1F2CE2D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such corporation would be a surrogate foreign corporation if subsection (a)(2) were applied by substituting <quote>80 percent</quote> for <quote>60 percent</quote>, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3A0148C1F324C16A58FCDA3526538F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such corporation is an inverted domestic corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7AFBB757532F4D40B5F1786803261A5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inverted domestic corporation</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a foreign corporation shall be treated as an inverted domestic corporation if, pursuant to a plan (or a series of related transactions)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H562B5302E2C74F82ACBE1D4F58307FF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the entity completes after May 8, 2014, the direct or indirect acquisition of—</text> <clause id="H289FC62D0B8642BFBD6DF3D48E36F8E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>substantially all of the properties held directly or indirectly by a domestic corporation, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6EAF861C187D42AA990979F14D84BFB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>substantially all of the assets of, or substantially all of the properties constituting a trade or business of, a domestic partnership, and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H736F1D1D2C4B437B9A4121E1F5DC31C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after the acquisition, either—</text> 
<clause id="H36FF9877A3B14263AD7CC3BCDF7628E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 50 percent of the stock (by vote or value) of the entity is held—</text> <subclause id="H8DAF0C7BA1E94A5190A0B1E5DB92998D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of an acquisition with respect to a domestic corporation, by former shareholders of the domestic corporation by reason of holding stock in the domestic corporation, or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H702C3CCEA3A54A44AA9948BA29DC82C5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an acquisition with respect to a domestic partnership, by former partners of the domestic partnership by reason of holding a capital or profits interest in the domestic partnership, or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF55C9977F479449B89AA84EC9134736E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the management and control of the expanded affiliated group which includes the entity occurs, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States, and such expanded affiliated group has significant domestic business activities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5F06A7D2B94413A97142225DEFEB30C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for corporations with substantial business activities in foreign country of organization</header><text>A foreign corporation described in paragraph (2) shall not be treated as an inverted domestic corporation if after the acquisition the expanded affiliated group which includes the entity has substantial business activities in the foreign country in which or under the law of which the entity is created or organized when compared to the total business activities of such expanded affiliated group. For purposes of subsection (a)(2)(B)(iii) and the preceding sentence, the term <term>substantial business activities</term> shall have the meaning given such term under regulations in effect on May 8, 2014, except that the Secretary may issue regulations increasing the threshold percent in any of the tests under such regulations for determining if business activities constitute substantial business activities for purposes of this paragraph.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD97B8A5EBA9148E89429DADC81E36EC8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Management and control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (2)(B)(ii)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H117B739ED2174D0C97303EFF4C75B2F3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for purposes of determining cases in which the management and control of an expanded affiliated group is to be treated as occurring, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States. The regulations prescribed under the preceding sentence shall apply to periods after May 8, 2014.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95064408521841BEA0008157C03BD747"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Executive officers and senior management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such regulations shall provide that the management and control of an expanded affiliated group shall be treated as occurring, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States if substantially all of the executive officers and senior management of the expanded affiliated group who exercise day-to-day responsibility for making decisions involving strategic, financial, and operational policies of the expanded affiliated group are based or primarily located within the United States. Individuals who in fact exercise such day-to-day responsibilities shall be treated as executive officers and senior management regardless of their title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20C5E17BA6414C859FF47321EEB3781B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Significant domestic business activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (2)(B)(ii), an expanded affiliated group has significant domestic business activities if at least 25 percent of—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B2E2E6BD26649DF87A31A2A2B58D3CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employees of the group are based in the United States,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE39E3DE6B76146369E7EC0FF19CB1282"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employee compensation incurred by the group is incurred with respect to employees based in the United States,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A177218D9D04CC0A5508FA049B0A835"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the assets of the group are located in the United States, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB53032576E840DBA0CABC7C25CFCF3D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the income of the group is derived in the United States,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">determined in the same manner as such determinations are made for purposes of determining substantial business activities under regulations referred to in paragraph (3) as in effect on May 8, 2014, but applied by treating all references in such regulations to <quote>foreign country</quote> and <quote>relevant foreign country</quote> as references to <quote>the United States</quote>. The Secretary may issue regulations decreasing the threshold percent in any of the tests under such regulations for determining if business activities constitute significant domestic business activities for purposes of this paragraph.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H18F5B3EDD0EA44E7AE038541EEBDB1AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="H5C045271BD204B74937899949889DEBF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Clause (i) of section 7874(a)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>after March 4, 2003,</quote> and inserting <quote>after March 4, 2003, and before May 9, 2014,</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C7FA9BE185A4B80BB361487FF51EE53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsection (c) of section 7874 of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H23D00544DE504B869836EACC98D61B7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="H93B51CADCE4E4C018A109217942C8363"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (a)(2)(B)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (a)(2)(B)(ii) and (b)(2)(B)(i)</quote>, and</text></clause> <clause id="H18A2F985BD3241978C22B38724288030"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or (b)(2)(A)</quote> after <quote>(a)(2)(B)(i)</quote> in subparagraph (B),</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9AF8DED6C964ED28790C5EDBC6C70FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>or (b)(2)(B)(i), as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>(a)(2)(B)(ii)</quote>,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82DDA189BF2347208D5CABB2597A864F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>subsection (a)(2)(B)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (a)(2)(B)(ii) and (b)(2)(B)(i)</quote>, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA0E687BDCFC4DA3B9AF1DE64D1BDC56"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by inserting <quote>or inverted domestic corporation, as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>surrogate foreign corporation</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H44D796CCCCAA403C860A7C3EFE0488B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after May 8, 2014.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


