<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE8796ADA43B44821920C62E52E81FC78" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3602 IH: Gold King Mine Spill Recovery Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3602</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150924">September 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide compensation to injured persons relating to the Gold King Mine spill, to amend the
			 Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of
			 1980 to address mining-related issues, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9A095A2C81604552A2ABC3A34C428B9F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAFCF170F24AE4C9C947A8A099A8BE6E0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gold King Mine Spill Recovery Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4A1E59C614CF4D7A95BE1CD87257FE46"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD725702B3F8A48D7B4DA9166B61F2E0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on August 5, 2015, approximately 3,000,000 gallons of contaminated water was discharged from the Gold King Mine north of Silverton, Colorado, into Cement Creek, a tributary of the Animas River, while contractors of the Environmental Protection Agency were conducting an investigation of the mine—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF8196425697D4847B7145CB205C49AAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to assess the ongoing water releases from the mine;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB1A33ADFE4D4170937A0902268C37C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to treat mine water; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6332F5DDE6474C2796031C9AF48E5842"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to assess the feasibility of further mine remediation;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE137B750A0D9491D9CFE77A846DFAFA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the plume of contaminated water resulting from the discharge described in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE6EDC067511A486F92D7D0830BAC2C88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was found to contain high levels of heavy metals, including aluminum, arsenic, cadmium, cobalt, copper, iron, lead, manganese, mercury, molybdenum, nickel, and zinc; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A7765641DAF419081ECEB40C47803A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>flowed through the Animas River, the San Juan River, and Lake Powell;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87045529EE38480D8F9DD79C9CF56137"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of this Act, with respect to the discharge described in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H11A77D6C36E4476493C9B91FAC957A96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>state of emergency declarations have been made by—</text> <clause id="H4C7DC4E0110F45B68652A44ACE4FAFBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the States of Colorado, New Mexico, and Utah; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9242F8DD71C34B8088F9DFB987EB5E9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Navajo Nation; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H86CF49801A5B4F92B9D46518D3D7AB36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a declaration of disaster has been issued by the Southern Ute Indian Tribe; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H130BB01BFDFA4416ABFD056CE65EA1D0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on August 11, 2015, Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency Gina McCarthy stated that the Environmental Protection Agency will take full responsibility for the discharge described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1F04397C00B744969089F58ABE71A28E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD9CA400F79304ACF8D9C87A04C3AB262"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB60432CD1EDC46CD9479BD257766BDA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gold King Mine spill</header><text>The term <term>Gold King Mine spill</term> means the discharge on August 5, 2015, of approximately 3,000,000 gallons of contaminated water from the Gold King Mine north of Silverton, Colorado, into Cement Creek that occurred while contractors of the Environmental Protection Agency were conducting an investigation of the Gold King Mine.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB3D472EE9154BC59E20E63AD4C7CC59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Injured person</header><text>The term <term>injured person</term> means a person that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF56B92A10C31409E8B7E12A3E422D64B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>suffered injury resulting from the Gold King Mine spill; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9E2351BF4EA41389582BEFC5465A791"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is—</text> <clause id="HEAB6941C343B45E9BAA50292DBF501CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual, regardless of the citizenship or alien status of the individual;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDD5E2687B714DD6884CF86FF589A700"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an Indian tribe, tribal corporation, or other tribal organization;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6BC7739CC8347A392689DF907674EE1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a corporation, business, partnership, company, association, insurer, county, township, city, State or political subdivision of a State, school district, ditch company, special district, water district, water company, the Animas-La Plata Operation, Maintenance and Replacement Association, or other non-Federal entity; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76AB5F2AF40B41FA95F918571E921494"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a legal representative of an individual or entity described in any of clauses (i) through (iii).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4D2D0DDDBC4C959AEF4034AE308DB5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Injury</header><text>The term <term>injury</term> means any damage to, or loss of, property, or a personal injury or death, caused by a negligent or wrongful act or omission of a Federal officer, employee, contractor, or subcontractor while acting within the scope of office, employment, or contract, under circumstances in which the Federal officer, employee, contractor, or subcontractor, if a private person, would be liable to the claimant in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction in which the act or omission occurred.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA7FC8A7943948418BB6B5CA364ECE6C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Gold King Mine Spill Claims established by section 4(b)(1).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HA555353B5082422389CA003931809094"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compensation for victims of Gold King Mine spill</header> <subsection id="HB0A97D9A27CF4AB6A2D7CE17E550CBF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal tort claims</header> <paragraph id="H69692AA2855842F5A7C46B886B9B9AD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), each injured person shall be entitled to receive from the United States compensation for a claim filed, or civil action brought, under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Tort Claims Act</quote>), arising out of or relating to an injury resulting from the Gold King Mine spill.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4E6A03BF888E476EA222B91885F897ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of acceptance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The acceptance by an injured person of compensation under paragraph (1) shall have the same effect as acceptance of compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Tort Claims Act</quote>), or any other Federal or State law, arising out of or relating to the Gold King Mine spill.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBB51F047EE94DA597C6E3183BF7F54E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Administrator and the Attorney General shall process a claim filed, or civil action brought, pursuant to paragraph (1) as expeditiously as practicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25FB143FC5C24BEC9DC9E5CF0AFAD3E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any claim under this Act arising out of, or relating to, an injury resulting from the Gold King Mine spill—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAAABED9BFDCD40B1BA01A245A1B6967B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the maximum amount limitation on claims described in the proviso of the first sentence of section 2672 of title 28, United States Code, shall be waived; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB151C6F8B15342008D778C712FFEE432"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator may provide compensation for the claim in an amount greater than $25,000 without prior written approval of the Attorney General (or a designee), as the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44E23DBDA3954F4C8455868C256B14CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Gold King Mine Spill Claims</header>
 <paragraph id="HC56089B451DC4C62A7A0D49907B5FEA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Environmental Protection Agency an Office of Gold King Mine Spill Claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6A6D8D831AF4B7BA2DD3CD3D8CD06EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Office shall receive, process, and pay claims in accordance with this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BE52B685C1F44DE904B8430E43A26CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text>The establishment of the Office by this subsection shall not diminish the ability of the Administrator to carry out the responsibilities of the Environmental Protection Agency under any other provision of law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0623B6C656D4E9BA4D6CA7B71733526"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>On request of the Administrator, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any personnel of that department or agency to the Office to assist in carrying out the duties under this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99C21922AA6E43F78B14554E42CB5C89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allowable damages</header>
 <paragraph id="H9D6C2A3F4F7E49CCAADB467811669BAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Property loss</header><text>A claim that is paid for loss of property under this section may include otherwise-uncompensated damages resulting from the Gold King Mine spill for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H80C96BAB1A1E46439DB7595C9C569E09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a cost resulting from lost tribal subsistence from hunting, fishing, firewood gathering, timbering, grazing, or agricultural activities, or from lost use for traditional or ceremonial uses, conducted on land or water damaged by the Gold King Mine spill;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA110D37B4D07475AA1AF3EC8D91FEFDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a cost of reforestation or revegetation on tribal or non-Federal land, to the extent that the cost of reforestation or revegetation is not covered by any other Federal program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE34AFACF79D42DC8C91FA186CC36072"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any costs borne by any injured person to determine the extent of—</text> <clause id="H9A778BDF14344C45AEDDA9E9294D697B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the damages to agricultural land; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4200192715344C43BAFFA5E0BC02D40F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other damages covered by this Act;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77DBBCCDB7884582B2E3270786D6E3FD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any costs borne by an injured person who had to pay for water supplies or equipment to treat water during the period for which a water supply of the injured person was compromised by the Gold King Mine spill; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CB7F805C4E94461858F2EAAE5B985B4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other loss that the Administrator determines to be appropriate for inclusion as loss of property.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9811823EBD614A17A871FBA2EC8AC304"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Business loss</header><text>A claim that is paid for an injury under this section may include damages resulting from the Gold King Mine spill for the following types of otherwise uncompensated business loss:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3A9332A4241D42C7B07563F6C7C4C2F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Damage to tangible assets or inventory.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9599D8FA86464D4F9E9D861EB58467D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Business interruption losses.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6CE690C77734CD6AD27C1103A058955"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Overhead costs.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F030E876EFE482DA161E5CE1339062C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Employee wages for work not performed.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0650D042BC548E1BC7225BA4B98EED3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other loss that the Administrator determines to be appropriate for inclusion as a business loss.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20C842BC9AB1419A95744C1282D2640A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial loss</header><text>A claim that is paid for an injury under this section may include damages resulting from the Gold King Mine spill for the following types of otherwise uncompensated financial loss:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0331BAB3EB3548EEADF930AE661AF35D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An insurance deductible.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H496123784C8D4262B605CC5BBE88EDEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Lost wages or personal income.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88AA4AA0F1894956BE717377B434B643"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Emergency staffing expenses.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF51F0FFDE7AB40A38100AA4D3D1E1004"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Debris removal and other cleanup costs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA3C4C348B2A475BA29359453D12A68E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other loss that the Administrator determines to be appropriate for inclusion as a financial loss.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA76ADB40E57A4B68A81A5BB6D885B865"><enum>5.</enum><header>Long-term water quality monitoring program; designation as Superfund site<editorial></editorial><editorial></editorial></header>
			<subsection id="H715FD031188C429E8E04BA976FBBC4D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gold King Mine Spill Response Program</header>
 <paragraph id="H28F86AA8E24340539A90637EEDA3C84B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall work with affected States and Indian tribes to develop, fund, and implement a long-term monitoring program for water quality of the Animas and San Juan Rivers in response to the Gold King Mine spill.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9985A9E373104A449E6549094DFFB382"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program under paragraph (1) shall provide—</text> <subparagraph id="H1D67C602C72447C482CAF323277A6A8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>full disclosure to the public of applicable water quality and sediment data; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B3838B424684D649A31308534573012"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a clear and meaningful comparison between those data and all relevant water quality standards.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63763EADD4024EB0BD40337750E2A1FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Administrator should—</text>
 <paragraph id="H875875DFDBBC40A080D72D72599D929E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with all local communities along the Animas and San Juan Rivers affected by the Gold King Mine spill, the Navajo Nation, the Southern Ute Indian Tribe, and the States of Colorado and New Mexico to determine whether it is appropriate to seek a designation for the Upper Animas River watershed on the National Priorities List under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA51C6344F5404B44ACFB5D0C31F47AE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritize the construction of a water treatment plant in the Upper Animas River basin to significantly reduce the ongoing heavy metal discharge into the Animas River from Cement Creek.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6A845F3400C842899E1514A4A29204A8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Amendment to CERCLA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59F6E6E2742942D0B3BC3AEC3E732073" style="OLC">
				<section id="H7A4109852BF747B58DF3F755078946B5"><enum>129.</enum><header>Mining-related provisions</header>
 <subsection id="H3A41CF88B4F941FD933CE7CA40AD8D99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of the Interior, in coordination with the Governors of affected States, the heads of appropriate research universities, and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC9D493732CB6409F8811E829AC7C727E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, review known, existing abandoned and inactive mines—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC8DF72811DBB47C89387F49DB9E61495"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify the most dangerous abandoned and inactive mines on public land and private land with respect to the existence of pollution and the potential to release any hazardous substance or other pollutant, particularly with respect to contamination of water; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7B0D472DF774B95A4D20058504DC79A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to establish a priority plan for activities for removal and remediation of the hazardous substances and other pollutants;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83946D4263C64456934D2EE944B3869A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>periodically thereafter, as appropriate, update the priority plan established under paragraph (1)(B) as new information becomes available; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9475361C1339405F91FC8031044D69DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a long-term research initiative to evaluate the physical, chemical, and geological attributes of closed, abandoned, and inactive mines and pursue technological developments to aid in the cleanup of such mines.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF436C9D7F0E64BA3818483F10EB7F04E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions prior to certain activities</header><text>Before conducting any activity at a mine that presents the significant potential for accidental discharge of a hazardous substance or other pollutant, the Administrator or the head of any other Federal department or agency carrying out an activity for mine remediation shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4AC5E28C9D0A477D9CDCD62F09D31DAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide to each tribal, State, and local unit of government the resources or residents of which may be affected by such a discharge notice regarding the activity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H831A28B2361E40B58FC488BC070E7667"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a spill prevention, control, and countermeasures plan to avoid and mitigate the impacts of such a discharge.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HE792B0CD69154FD18B272481EA7BB19F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effect of Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act (or an amendment made by this Act) provides for compensation of any injured person pursuant to this Act (or an amendment made by this Act) from the Hazardous Substances Superfund established by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9507">section 9507(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


