<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H07C48D1A0741474D918A7AC656500A85" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1929 IH: International Conflicts of Concern Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1929</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To restrict United States nationals from traveling to countries in which foreign governments or
			 anti-government forces allow foreign terrorist organizations to engage in
			 armed conflict for purposes of participating in such armed conflict or
			 from providing material support to entities that are engaged in such armed
			 conflict, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HEB4C130332724DB5BB1F84422DF58422" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC1CA74A4214842F9910385B09C495780" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Conflicts of Concern Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF64FD1DA960F4145966B848F9932A8CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identification of Countries of Conflict Concern</header> <subsection id="HCFA6B3882ACB4EAA80A27B714166B44E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to Congress a report that identifies each country the government of which or anti-government forces in which the President believes, based on all information available to the President, is allowing one or more foreign terrorist organizations to engage in armed conflict that is occurring in such country.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3C363DF10DAB43929566B1374DFE90B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The President shall update the report required under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="HE6188734C3BC44B2A8FABC916C54E8B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as new information becomes available; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H649300D9F1934B21963D2F0092AB0CCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less frequently than semi-annually.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6603ED1933742F2BC695963E613505F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) and the updates required under subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3B50BD42092547949682837B16A21321"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of Countries of Conflict Concern</header>
			<subsection id="H77F2161025D94B2982C838C507831997"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header>
 <paragraph id="HB2174D1221394D5397AB256A98C282AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall designate a country as a <quote>Country of Conflict Concern</quote> if the President determines that—</text> <subparagraph id="H056107AA54A14F2794463A0A6EEAC9E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the government of such country or anti-government forces in the country is allowing one or more foreign terrorist organizations to engage in armed conflict that is occurring in such country as identified in the report required under section 2(a) or any update to the report required under section 2(b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FFA10299CFD434CADCA1C973181E1F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>it is in the national security interest of the United States to restrict travel by any United States national to such country and to restrict material support provided by United States nationals to entities that are engaged in armed conflict in such country.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H057366AB89094220A8A5167A08ED0937"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Syria shall be deemed to have been designated by the President under paragraph (1) as of the date of the enactment of this Act and the President is not required to notify Congress of such designation of Syria under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4E60D10068D4255892DEDDAB32DA7E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on designation</header><text>Upon designating a country as a Country of Conflict Concern under subsection (a), the President shall submit to Congress a report notifying Congress of the designation of the country.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD4FCD78D6D964AE09F7C7B3BB5E37C0A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Licensing requirement</header>
 <paragraph id="H450D1679DF9740AEAF102868323713DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to any country designated as a Country of Conflict Concern under subsection (a), the President shall exercise the authorities of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705 et seq.</external-xref>) without regard to section 202 of such Act to require a United States national to obtain a license—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5C694299E6044DF98D44941C63D49FDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to travel to such country; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AF62927A603416AAB399351EE9DC0CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide material support to entities that are engaged in armed conflict in such country.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25C31711AA6A4210BA3749204FA38423"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to obtain a license under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to United States national who is a full-time officer or employee of the United States Government for purposes of carrying out official business of the United States Government.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD470E534421C41EB8A48F6128314D611"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person who violates paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (c), or a regulation prescribed under this Act, to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3E2646448DCD435CA1D1DBD4EF68D196"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination of designation</header><text>The designation of a country as a Country of Conflict Concern under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date on which the President submits to Congress a report that contains—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1447324E61454FB7B0D2E87D356516FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a determination and certification that subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) (as the case may be), or both, no longer applies with respect to the country; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B3354C9E1BE45BEA04E56391E0530ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a justification for the determination and certification.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H258DB1E1AD2146C894211F756E22B5DE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President is authorized to promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act, including the promulgation of such regulations under the authority of section 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1704">50 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="HAA8EAE9E6B824BC693CFC39F9E0C5923"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HBD91AA0BB42E41CAA204A2A7C417AC61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign terrorist organization</header><text>The term <term>foreign terrorist organization</term> means any organization so designated by the Secretary of State under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C5FBB0D48E450F9E4E98A9AA8A7A97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States national</header><text>The term <term>United States national</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H626E24B41FB0401EAE5DAE6A89AEF03B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a national of the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC51AD18C44F49CC93FCE78015968BCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an alien who is lawfully present in the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

