<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB13C44C0275441099ED1062DDB6E5CBB" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3563 IH: Milk Freedom Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3563</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150918">September 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000589">Mr. Rigell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000367">Mr. Amash</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the interstate traffic of unpasteurized milk and milk products that are packaged for
			 direct human consumption.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4EE3599DE85F471C9A6768C8DEB5C078" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBFE9BDF1EED847FDB21605FD61174AD6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Milk Freedom Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBE79C2E6861D4A84BAFF632740D76565"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interstate traffic of unpasteurized milk and milk products</header> <subsection id="H131FF859A1C046628BECC548ABD92F60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale allowed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>), section 361 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/264">42 U.S.C. 264</external-xref>), and any regulations or other guidance issued under such Act or section, a Federal department, agency, or court may not take any action (such as administrative, civil, criminal, or other actions) that would prohibit, interfere with, regulate, or otherwise restrict the interstate traffic of milk, or a milk product, that is unpasteurized and packaged for direct human consumption, if such prohibition, interference, regulation, or restriction is based on the determination that, solely because such milk or milk product is unpasteurized, such milk or milk product is adulterated, misbranded, or otherwise in violation of Federal law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE2578EF6214543AE9066E3D465F148AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HA7D5ECD41837406082AAB036B2528ACC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>milk</term> means the lacteal secretion, practically free from colostrum, obtained by the milking of one or more healthy animals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE5E277FE93546AC904D0FC8EFBE4219"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>milk product</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H9CF1973417324B6C9FB3DDE8561F3FB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a food product made from milk; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48CCD376878342C8B938484A3EC945F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes low-fat milk, skim milk, cream, half and half, dry milk, nonfat milk, dry cream, condensed or concentrated milk products, cultured or acidified milk or milk products, kefir, eggnog, yogurt, butter, cheese, whey, condensed or dry whey or whey products, ice cream, ice milk, and other frozen dairy desserts.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC44FCE640C943E9B870188B1F10DBAD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>packaged for direct human consumption</term> means milk and milk products that are packaged for the final consumer and intended for human consumption. Such term does not include milk and milk products that are packaged for additional processing, including pasteurization, before being consumed by humans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC64571D8C5FD42898B237E99CDE1E85C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pasteurized</term> means the process of heating milk and milk products to the applicable temperature specified in the tables contained in section 1240.61 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), and held continuously at or above that temperature for at least the corresponding specified time in such tables.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C9B14BFE0144727BF8F542FC9696D84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>unpasteurized</quote> means not pasteurized.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

