<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72BB0478DAFF41DF801BFC3D7D79A9D9" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2492 IH: To direct the Secretary of the Army to provide for modification of certain Federal water resources development projects on the Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint Rivers, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2492</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000575">Ms. Graham</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Army to provide for modification of certain Federal water resources development projects on the Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint Rivers, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HFCEBD673784F46988381BE97937C025D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA17C9644755E45159E4F8FDE95E25233" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint River projects</header> 
<subsection id="HFDC4CDBCF40944BDB3E68343095118AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H508AB17534794B12BA08EA03BA8DF2CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint projects</header><text>The term <term>Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint projects</term> means the Federal water resources projects on the Apalachicola, Chattahoochee, and Flint Rivers in the States of Alabama, Florida, and Georgia authorized by section 2 of the Act of March 2, 1945 (59 Stat. 17, chapter 19; 60 Stat. 635, chapter 595) and section 203 of the Flood Control Act of 1962 (76 Stat. 1182), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H477492B4E19A49E3B8768D3F5C0120DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Buford Dam and Reservoir;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF692DF967804BE3BB2CD69F88324814"><enum>(B)</enum><text>West Point Dam and Reservoir;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD60BC1A3FAE9485996713327145339F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>George W. Andrews Dam and Reservoir;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7244C680EA244C0E9E92802A14997441"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Walter F. George Dam and Reservoir; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82D7DC558CCD4A16ABEB545DBA76A45E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Jim Woodruff Dam and Reservoir.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H306C1FC453054B69A4E55776B0D3A785"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Freshwater Flows</header><text>The term <term>freshwater flows</term> means the quality, quantity, timing, and variability of freshwater flows required—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F14068F40C7403F9670227399A1EBD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to support and reestablish—</text> <clause id="HCB97D8E00C664DEAB45AACE0636F5F8B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the physical, chemical, biological, and overall ecological integrity of the components, functions, and natural processes required for a thriving and resilient Chattahoochee River, Apalachicola River, Apalachicola River floodplain, and Apalachicola Bay;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6AA6B762FF084348BF4F906A91C400F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commercial and recreational fisheries dependent on freshwater flows into Apalachicola Bay and adjacent waters, including the Gulf of Mexico; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7B0F11ACD43B4753B3D0AEEBA2F6166C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">thriving and diverse fish, wildlife, and plant populations having species composition, diversity, adaptability, and functional organization similar to those found in the Chattahoochee River and Apalachicola River ecosystems prior to construction of the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint projects;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4B2FDB097254DE9822107C9F3C78160"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to restore and recover species that are endangered, threatened, or at risk; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC58D12DF050475EBDE65CD425437097"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent significantly harmful adverse impacts to the Chattahoochee River and Apalachicola River ecosystems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54E811908CE345AF991A4E9503BCE945"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project modification</header><text>Notwithstanding any authorized purpose of the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint projects, the Secretary shall operate the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint projects in a manner that ensures the maintenance of freshwater flows.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDC2CCB3A51714B429D4B9D07DF7DD5BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revision of water control manuals</header> <paragraph id="H9F372A97F63844A1BD0DCAB02696BF54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall complete the ongoing revision of the water control manuals for the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint projects and issue revised water control manuals for those projects that ensure the maintenance of freshwater flows.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAD0A7F69B604477A3B9E37B761D95D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Operational modifications</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that operational modifications needed to maintain freshwater flows are achieved, to the maximum extent practicable, while providing system-wide balance in conservation storage through the maintenance of water levels within the same action zone for each of the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint project reservoirs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00D7EF428B8149ED832F1F3EDCF5A951"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent peer review of water control manuals</header> <subparagraph id="H28BB8AB2FF194B0895435D30EA04A0DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences under which the National Academy of Sciences shall carry out an independent peer review of each revised water control manual, as required under section 2034 of the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2343">33 U.S.C. 2343</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41A34116D83046C58F4DB587211F088A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>Each independent peer review under this paragraph shall comply with section 2034 of the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2343">33 U.S.C. 2343</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H353051AAB10E4BB090929790125F7C4C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Final approval</header><text>Before a final water control manual may be issued, the Secretary shall obtain written approval of each water control manual developed under this subsection from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H96E28C714B3D470FB2BFA6CC109ED1C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2DD12C5187D45E5896CD4F3940BD4B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE158E077ADBA4F82B5892165CB6B5E19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Director of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60FC95A6C0CF4CFD9CCA5524D1FCF435"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Geological Survey.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H33CF50D0C3F24E869EF490B71F17DA52"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability of other Federal and State laws</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), nothing in this section waives, limits, or otherwise affects the applicability of any provision of Federal or State law that would otherwise apply to the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint projects.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

