<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H98C986A2CB6A47BEA3C68A401F227AD2" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1408 IH: Mortgage Servicing Asset Capital Requirements Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1408</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150317">March 17, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require certain Federal banking agencies to conduct a study of the appropriate capital requirements for mortgage servicing assets for nonsystemic banking institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC31240AB889E40DCA3BB4A26FE552107" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1985B14D0C674AF58B5176FF59EC64D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mortgage Servicing Asset Capital Requirements Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBA5C0CD712E7457C8B17397D699BFD53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community financial institution mortgage servicing asset capital requirements study</header> <subsection id="H2ED0444E2DB14C39856878893E65B1D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9E4D972F3241491A832FEE9B3E6135D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Banking institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>banking institution</term> means an insured depository institution, Federal credit union, State credit union, bank holding company, or savings and loan holding company.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F0E1F6E472D4F7A81D7546F83DC7D6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basel III capital requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Basel III capital requirements</term> means the Global Regulatory Framework for More Resilient Banks and Banking Systems issued by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision on December 16, 2010, as revised on June 1, 2011.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB117EB0309B145E097842C548E9A2D7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal banking agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal banking agencies</term> means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD079577D65A4809B9FF27A464CEE187"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mortgage servicing asset</header><text>The term <term>mortgage servicing asset</term> means those assets that result from contracts to service loans secured by real estate, where such loans are owned by third parties.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CE794B05B68436E93646806E634D2AE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>NCUA capital requirements</header><text>The term <term>NCUA capital requirements </term> means the proposed rule of the National Credit Union Administration titled <quote>Risk-Based Capital</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 4340; January 27, 2015).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2816AC131E714BF3AFFD735A70773A8B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nonsystemic banking institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nonsystemic banking institution</term> means any banking institution other than an institution identified by the Financial Stability Board as a <quote>global systemically important bank</quote>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23CD5AA9B88B4C349749C61E46CFBAC6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Other definitions</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD417019B98454F5696A88E7ACCC92D6F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Banking definitions</header><text>The terms <term>bank holding company</term>, <term>insured depository institution</term>, and <term>savings and loan holding company</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H825D981669B841E6965270FE81569782"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Credit union definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Federal credit union</term> and <term>State credit union</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, under section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAA22EC9B8BA04FBCA7772467B09A3445"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study of the appropriate capital for mortgage servicing assets</header> 
<paragraph id="H8C5475A63D60460CADBA8D34A680D468"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal banking agencies shall, jointly, conduct a study of the appropriate capital requirements for mortgage servicing assets for nonsystemic banking institutions.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA29772C3042446CA8C8353EE7AD0EA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Issues to be studied</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study required by this subsection shall include, with a specific focus on nonsystemic banking institutions—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE4AF13B2FBE1439182AA4A55917F96B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the risk to banking institutions of holding mortgage servicing assets;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA9FBB499F2B4C34B6F81149236D6255"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the history of the market for mortgage servicing assets, including particularly the market for such assets in the period of the financial crisis;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF8AA77BF0EF420CBF71FEB809E9F247"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of banking institutions to establish a value for their mortgage servicing assets through periodic sales or other means;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD20300E34FD44850A5682ECAEE69D505"><enum>(D)</enum><text>regulatory approaches to mortgage servicing assets in addition to capital requirements that could be used to address concerns about the value of and ability to sell mortgage servicing assets;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0FF9B4687A649B5B3B58A94927062FC"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of imposing the Basel III capital requirements and the NCUA capital requirements on nonsystemic banking institutions on their ability to compete in the mortgage servicing business, including the need for economies of scale to compete in that business, and on their ability to provide service to consumers to whom they have made a mortgage loan;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65D3537CE2F4457C82C2E3A81B6422C6"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of what the mortgage servicing marketplace would look like if the Basel III capital requirements and the NCUA capital requirements on mortgage servicing assets—</text> 
<clause id="H045D0FC39CB44B15A936B7B6A4F8C4C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>were fully implemented; and</text></clause> <clause id="H320D4F77941A4049B98850FCF284397E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applied to both banking institutions and nondepository residential mortgage loan servicers;</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H957CFFBAEDE643D1AB9963FCD15946FE"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the significance of problems with mortgage servicing assets, if any, in banking institution failures and problem banking institutions, including specifically identifying failed banking institutions where mortgage servicing assets contributed to the failure; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H346B0CE7F32844E89B8B6A326EBB4CB6"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the relevance of the Basel III capital requirements and the NCUA capital requirements on mortgage servicing assets to the banking systems of other significant developed countries.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30CFED4CE08448C9B4AB583D4F418D0F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal banking agencies shall issue a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives containing—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE8ADF47864542E9AB6BC79BF9F178FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the study required under paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E650F85B6064B76A1CB558DE26C3099"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any analysis on the specific issue of mortgage servicing assets undertaken by the Federal banking agencies prior to finalizing regulations implementing the Basel III capital requirements and the NCUA capital requirements.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H48D054DF05DC4E6E8B051C22ECA13167"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Delay of rulemaking</header> <paragraph id="H9487A9CCC35042D8B57930534EE8B553"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rules on mortgage servicing assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no regulation to implement the Basel III capital requirements or the NCUA capital requirements with respect to mortgage servicing assets for nonsystemic banking institutions shall take effect before the end of the 3-month period beginning on the date the report is issued under subsection (b)(3).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC002D235AF14F8095FAAFB3BEECED12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final rule requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before any final rule is issued by a Federal banking agency with respect to capital requirements on mortgage servicing assets for nonsystemic banking institutions, the Federal banking agency shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H1E75AF7F964E48D5959932519ECEF71C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the related proposed rule was issued before the date on which the report is issued under subsection (b)(3), issue a new proposed rule for public comment; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4880263B166045A4A8E31F54CC29491C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider regulatory approaches to mortgage servicing assets that could address concerns about the value of and ability to sell mortgage servicing assets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

