<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA6243481053B4C49A75DDC009DE86F14" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 596 EH: To repeal the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and health care-related provisions in the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 596</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To repeal the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and health care-related provisions in the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9B6AA31A880341F1AC8C8A07C63B8937" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB893199FE2834720A09F19E2335FF0D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Repeal of PPACA and health care-related provisions in the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010</header> 
<subsection id="H36657A5A409544248566D9457FEE85D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>PPACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) is repealed, and the provisions of law amended or repealed by such Act are restored or revived as if such Act had not been enacted.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H0672DE88E3C440FC8D85AB230BB59C3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Health care-Related provisions in the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, title I and subtitle B of title II of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/152">Public Law 111–152</external-xref>) are repealed, and the provisions of law amended or repealed by such title or subtitle, respectively, are restored or revived as if such title and subtitle had not been enacted.</text> </subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEE8ADD9942944CBA538079949EFF4D8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act shall not be entered on either PAYGO scorecard maintained pursuant to section 4(d) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</text> </section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85C947221D7C400BA1CEB6B767B9A15F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reporting replacement legislation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Education and the Workforce, the Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00"> the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives</committee-name> shall each report to the House of Representatives legislation proposing changes to existing law within each committee’s jurisdiction with provisions that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H316700D283D2489B8C44296461F04966"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foster economic growth and private sector job creation by eliminating job-killing policies and regulations;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H36BED0F99E6B4C0C82AB844347A69684"><enum>(2)</enum><text>lower health care premiums through increased competition and choice;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64EE7A5BCAA94F4F85FE642DAA343982"><enum>(3)</enum><text>preserve a patient’s ability to keep his or her health plan if he or she likes it;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H844A51CFD7A14A799C9EBBCD50A24A2C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide people with pre-existing conditions access to affordable health coverage;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC47B83D7518047D18C8E2246A6861046"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reform the medical liability system to reduce unnecessary and wasteful health care spending;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2CB80910CC84CACA115C462140CB008"><enum>(6)</enum><text>increase the number of insured Americans;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF293A99A230A4DDFB81A7A792AC0A07C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>protect the doctor-patient relationship;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5878917A24CF449E983ABDF385B8FA49"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the States greater flexibility to administer Medicaid programs while reducing costs under such programs;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E7BC82EC13F4D0DA3B150D78FB5A2B0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>expand incentives to encourage personal responsibility for health care coverage and costs;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD2D941CD2CB40EDB8B626BCB160FBD2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>prohibit taxpayer funding of abortions and provide conscience protections for health care providers;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64A4C92F2C0B46A6979AAB14358D060D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>eliminate duplicative government programs and wasteful spending; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5079D1A5FFA7430B99E7DBB978899294"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">do not accelerate the growth of entitlement programs or increase the tax burden on Americans.</text> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20150203" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives February 3, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


