<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB3CDBA6CDE774422A9306BBF6B1BB6ED" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3769 IH: James K. Polk Presidential Home Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3769</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151020">October 20, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to study the suitability and feasibility of designating the
			 James K. Polk Home in Columbia, Tennessee, as a unit of the National Park
			 System, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HAD339F08C21F42B58D50433794ECC560">
 <section id="HCEBC8E09CED541FB990D75C947EBBB0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>James K. Polk Presidential Home Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H59ED2223D1FA4D74B390FD33DB645BB2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7BD40AE942C241E88894FBB8A5E20708"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in 1961, the James K. Polk Home was designated as a National Historic Landmark; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FDCE2D57EA34A409712913C1951919C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in April 2015, the National Park Service completed a reconnaissance survey of the James K. Polk Home, in which the National Park Service—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HADE59D0DF9904D0481C107D9798B9046"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determined that—</text> <clause id="H41D884DBE9984769BF9D72D044B12D34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the James K. Polk Home is conclusively nationally significant; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9CF21AF3B57E49BBABD8F3E8AD15BD86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a special resource study is needed to fully analyze the suitability, feasibility, and need for management of the James K. Polk Home by the National Park Service; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCEBB5E2972140F2AC06219ADF49DF12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommended that Congress consider authorizing a special resource study for the James K. Polk Home and associated properties.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H2043EA2EDAC241E7879EEAEF08D07373"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study</header>
 <subsection id="HD9F37922CE1B421BA92371D4DA35480B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct a special resource study of the site of the James K. Polk Home in Columbia, Tennessee, and adjacent property (referred to in this Act as the <quote>site</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8974CB274C524339B96FEB6640FB1CDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct the study under subsection (a) in accordance with section 100507 of title 54, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC2BAF55AF651472A83A5996DB792A29D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8EAC7D6740BC4DDDB01B94D21CDA775B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the national significance of the site;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA120A29CA0134495BA441D41322A2C27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the site as a unit of the National Park System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0D73D42569040DCBC2DA7F4CF337E7A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include cost estimates for any necessary acquisition, development, operation, and maintenance of the site;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69D8B17D829C4F23BB36B692B88D86EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with interested Federal, State, or local governmental entities, private and nonprofit organizations, or other interested individuals; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H7715D506B2C6497C95E4D724CB0FAEF2"><enum>
 (5)</enum><text>identify alternatives for the management, administration, and protection of the site.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C63B5B760EC4A158FC26303FA950BD9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are made available to carry out the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5AE62DA7532F40E482BFD80713A287F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions of the study; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AA84CF389C54B50B780AA01F33FB90A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


