<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H357DBDC3446B400DB9A98447503DB962" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2670 : Microloan Modernization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2670</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20150714">July 14, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to provide for expanded participation in the microloan program, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFFFA903E27294DD19435D783F45AEFF5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3662430F051C4AB0BA9B23FB119CA051" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Microloan Modernization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1182E5BF683F4C389567D9AF1FD9367F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waivers of 25/75 rule</header> <subsection id="H87AF4056A6B94D51B299A27B7D914FE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(m)(4)(E)(i) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(m)(4)(E)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Administrator shall by rule establish a process by which intermediaries may apply for and the Administrator may grant a waiver from the requirements of this clause.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H99B52A3CE1BA4A6AADD45915F39BCDC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the rule required by the amendment made by subsection (a), the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall require any applicant for a waiver to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0094394AF9AF4409858AB16408F41FEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to specify how such applicant will use the additional technical assistance; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDB5A2DB9900467381BAC48080DC09D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide assurance in a form provided for by the Administrator in the rule that the intermediary will have sufficient funds to provide technical assistance to all of the intermediary’s borrowers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7436B61F11D048C2BEA1085D10C49AE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rule required by subsection (a) shall be promulgated after notice and the opportunity for comment of not less than 60 days. Such regulation shall be codified in the Code of Federal Regulations and shall incorporate any delegation of the Administrator’s authority to approve waivers to any appropriate subsidiary official.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H8A0F476EA602490583C8E49983C3D264"><enum>3.</enum><header>Microloan intermediary lending limit increased</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(m)(3)(C) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(m)(3)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$5,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$6,000,000</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H380C3FABB7834704AC951C7BE9ED0305"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extended repayment terms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(m)(6) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(m)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AC98826F47F4293BC7878033FEA0B79" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H24CA0982D14842AEACD282FCA95DB7EA"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Repayment terms for loans to small businesses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may not impose limitations on the term for repayment of a loan made by an intermediary to a small business concern or entrepreneur, except that—</text>
 <clause id="H437225B6350948F8977F9C2A02C76372"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a loan made by an intermediary of $10,000 or less, the repayment term shall be not more than 6 years; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6B9E650F9A8F4318B1AD0831A796D741"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a loan greater than $10,000, the repayment term shall be not more than 10 years.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="HC4827D5BEABA4252A199AC006C2ABCEC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Lines of credit authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(m)(6)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(m)(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>short-term</quote> insert <quote>(including lines of credit)</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="HACF036703C8F47DDA1E1A6CC2584A7CE"><enum>6.</enum><header>GAO study of microenterprise participation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall complete a study on and report to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H387C2037464247B7B00389208F0BEBB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The operations (including services provided, structure, size, and area of operation) of a representative sample of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H42CBF182A5A641BCBDC13ED1F3284D46"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intermediaries that are eligible for participation in the microloan program under section 7(m) of the Small Business Act and that do participate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H610CB63456AD4CECB3E7111BBC9F823C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intermediaries (including those operated for profit, operated as nonprofits, and those affiliated with a United States institution of higher learning) that are so eligible and that do not participate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D5A20E3B4A44ADDB11A16D27C10E920"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The reasons why intermediaries described in paragraph (1)(B) choose not to participate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H28F9A7F4BCD1459ABCCB04AD2A0C4FD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations on how to encourage increased participation in the microloan program by intermediaries described in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE232338FE40413E942BFA8B855B2C40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations on how to decrease the costs associated with participation in the microloan program for eligible intermediaries.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HE2304760B51D457185CBBAF7ACC47E2C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Office of Advocacy economic study of mandatory savings requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration shall submit to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report on the economic impact of a mandatory savings requirement on business concerns eligible to participate in the microloan program under section 7(m) of the Small Business Act, including on the benefits and costs of such a requirement and recommendations on implementation of such a requirement.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20150713">Passed the House of Representatives July 13, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


