<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6A89CC0385E542BC87B76A3F0E4F4172" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3561 IH: Fair Access to Education Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3561</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150918">September 18, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the section 484(r) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to exclude certain marijuana-related offenses from the drug-related offenses that result in students being barred from receiving Federal educational loans, grants, and work assistance, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5ADAE9BA09F94ECFB5BC053509423689" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7D0C9020E1C140F6B51AE716DF555AC6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Access to Education Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCAB43508356A422FAC71DCF790719E6C"><enum>2.</enum><header> Exclusion of misdemeanor marijuana possession offenses from drug-related offenses resulting in suspension of eligibility for financial assistance for higher education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 484(r) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1091">20 U.S.C. 1091(r)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>controlled substance</quote> the following: <quote>, but not including any misdemeanor offense for possession of marihuana (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>)),</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H2724B140AC744495AB463678CAFBC252"><enum>3.</enum><header>Applicability; resumption of eligibility</header> 
<subsection id="H66DF4D32409E42A4AC05A3065A409956"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by section 2 shall apply to convictions for offenses described in the matter inserted by such amendment occurring before, on, and after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1B759CD54F2E453D852517BD473FFD21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Resumption of eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any student whose eligibility for grants, loans, and work assistance under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) was suspended under paragraph (1) of section 484(r) of such Act by reason of a conviction, before the enactment of this Act, for an offense described in the matter inserted by the amendment made by section 2 of this Act shall, unless otherwise ineligible for such assistance, resume eligibility upon such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

