<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H489B921921B74EDAB1E8A6B25EAD48EA" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4234 IH: Primary Care Physician Reentry Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4234</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151210">December 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a demonstration program to facilitate physician reentry into clinical practice to
			 provide primary health services.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H53234B9AA950485DAA59772856A8A789" style="OLC">
 <section id="H757A0FAE90F64E0E96AC6E453B863809" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Primary Care Physician Reentry Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" id="H5E850257294D49299C6406D4BFCB4EFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H22CF86617C334B7CA4A28FFCB4A055D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the Association of American Medical Colleges—</text> <subparagraph id="H9AB79E5DF51744F1BEBE7800A432C3AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the shortage of primary care physicians will reach 45,000 by the year 2020, as fewer than 20 percent of medical students choose to enter primary care medicine; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2AAAEAE7B2904E6CB89E0910654BFFAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the overall shortage of physicians in the United States is expected to surpass 130,000 by 2025.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H071A92A8D42249A09D51403B5C114463"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Medical schools in the United States train only approximately 18,000 new physicians every year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H816C6E3EEC6141ECA62A606EE062561D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services estimates that the United States needs at least 16,000 more primary care physicians.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7BA5A72E728644F4BEC47B02B181336F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to a survey of 1,600 pediatricians over the age of 50 conducted by the Association of American Medical Colleges and the American Academy of Pediatrics, 22 percent of female pediatricians took extended leave (6 months or more) from medicine, compared to only 6.5 percent of male pediatricians. Seventy-one percent of the female pediatricians who took extended leave did so to care for a child or family member.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HC3F1D75DED5843C08B4099D471C9AAD7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reentry program for physicians</header>
			<subsection id="HF177322BE2A24D9E9480E2E91AE3486A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Activities of the Secretary</header>
 <paragraph id="H8C595B96A0AC4C04ADEB3B7EC942FFED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of demonstration program</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a demonstration program to assist the development of innovative programs that facilitate physician reentry into clinical practice to provide primary health services. Under such demonstration program, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDBCF653B63B749649BEBE48FAC5D2476"><enum>(A)</enum><text>award one grant, on a competitive basis, to an eligible entity described in subsection (b) in each of the 10 regions served by a regional office of the Department of Health and Human Services to carry out physician reentry projects to assist reentering physicians participating in such projects through any of the activities described in subsection (d); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6889D5414A8412A9ACC867775036CC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in consultation with key stakeholders and subject to paragraph (2)(B), carry out the administrative activities described in paragraph (2)(A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD43B58696366428AAE58D87A68B1831C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE9D6CAD7E5D14075A4CD99137D5ECE7D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), the administrative activities described in this subparagraph are the following:</text>
 <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DB69680325441CC904B2D4E2D1CBC5E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conduct a national needs assessment with regard to the supply of physicians who provide primary health services, using, to the extent feasible, information collected for use in other similar completed or forthcoming studies, such as studies conducted by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality and the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5819CA5A9BF44F08A77B9DA24BD5B33A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop a database that contains a directory of programs that help physicians reenter clinical practice.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H84A9841891FB41C98FCB76CAE9A4C9B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disseminate evidence-based assessments and evaluation tools as such assessments and tools become available to measure the basic core competencies of physicians reentering clinical practice that are consistent with the guidelines published by the Federation of State Medical Boards for such physicians.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H719F1E503A6343A691799EF6D0AF9C04"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Assist State regulatory authorities and hospital credentialing committees to structure requirements for physicians to return to clinical practice in a manner that ensures patient safety while addressing the burdens on such reentering physicians.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H254D13A169604B77B0F01A4545F45FEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use not more than 15 percent of the funds appropriated to carry out this section to carry out the activities described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86C73DF281BE4A2CA9E67EEEF5A5BE4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Entities eligible to receive a grant under this section are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2CB68551195F41A4B8CD824B09F83F8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A State (as defined in section 2(f) of the Public Health Service Act, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201(f)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC436CCA620B14DF5AE79087DB5E84DC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A hospital.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H40B480106E644F8D9F7150E5991CECEE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An academic medical center.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE44022C5DC84764B0DD61C194160D25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A medical school.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB79C850C02174068AA4350924E91231E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A health center (as defined in section 330(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b(a)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DBAB7E7C4F9425B8DF7665A73D7B3E7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A teaching health center.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0999F38D42CF440AADD5712FF323C5CB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization with a demonstrated history or expertise in providing physician education and with the ability to offer programs specifically targeted at reentering physicians.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CD4A733188B4149AB9372ABFA23C78F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>In order to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F3A33E9A1A34E659351AFA402EB6252"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Uses of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives funds under this section shall use such funds to carry out a physician reentry project to assist reentering physicians participating in the project through any of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA30EF0BE7B64448EBAD354FB12E89E87"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training such reentering physicians to reenter clinical practice.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H66EF2FA34E254CEB893FE7010238A8D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paying credentialing fees and other fees that are necessary for such reentering physicians to reenter clinical practice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H068291A248F34FF48A5BAE9FF8492D1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Paying the salaries of such reentering physicians who are so eligible to reenter clinical practice during the period for which such physicians provide primary health services at a center described in subsection (e)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1F6D8FF5FE647DE9993B0BD6F441EEF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing loan repayment assistance and other financial assistance, including scholarships and grants for education and training, to such reentering physicians.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7565DE6F6D57456080A5897E22597666"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements of reentry physicians To participate in projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to participate in a physician reentry project carried out by an eligible entity under this section, a reentering physician shall provide assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the physician will comply with the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H49034386DB314AECBB92B075D6A55E02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Service locations</header><text>The reentering physician shall provide primary health services at—</text> <subparagraph id="H3472B6AE0FA742D1B44499D848904596"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a health center (as defined in section 330(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b(a)</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA982DDD7E3CC413DBBCAF4932D685ED5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Veterans Administration Medical Center if the Secretary of Veterans Affairs certifies that there is a shortage of physicians at such medical center; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA3759F053E947DBB743471DF397F8E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a school-based health center (as defined in section 2110(c)(9) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397jj">42 U.S.C. 1397jj(c)(9)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1F9BCE4FF8E43A3A6375618BC7414B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Length of service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reentering physician shall provide such services at such a center, consistent with paragraph (1), for not less than 2 years.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H685D2416167446A7981B8F24914391CD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Liability protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 224 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/233">42 U.S.C. 233</external-xref>), a reentering physician participating in a physician reentry project under this section shall be deemed to be an employee of the Public Health Service working within the scope of such employment with respect to primary health services provided by such reentering physician at a center described in subsection (e)(1) under the terms of such participation in such project. The remedy against the United States for a physician described in paragraph (2) who is deemed to be an employee of the Public Health Service pursuant to the previous sentence shall be exclusive of any other civil action or proceeding to the same extent as the remedy against the United States is exclusive pursuant to subsection (a) of such section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF8AAAC6831D64A49AA0B022913793068"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual review and report</header><text>For any year during which the demonstration program under this section is carried out, the Secretary shall conduct a review and comprehensive evaluation of such program and shall prepare and submit to Congress a report assessing such program, including an assessment of the performance of the reentering physicians who participate in physician reentry projects under such program.</text>
			</subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06208709AE8948588D2D9C64FBB09E7C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reentering physicians</header>
 <paragraph id="HF8E466906A1744B189F0559033FE5FB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Subject to <internal-xref idref="HD6B88063F6514447A06526C22E375E37" legis-path="3.(c)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>, for purposes of this section, the term <term>reentering physician</term> means an individual—</text> <subparagraph id="H66F9E873F78D43E29A1E7A46BDC1D908"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is a physician (as defined in section 1861(r)(1) of the Social Security Act, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(r)(1)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F07D08B460E400789263FEB36250C21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who received training in primary care or primary health services, including family medicine, internal medicine, pediatrics, obstetrics and gynecology, dentistry, and mental health.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H64490AE002944970AF02648EE5D87D2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who was previously (and may currently be) legally authorized to practice medicine and surgery by a State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD40F5C16C6CC4948A3AA21D20D8387AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>who previously engaged in the clinical practice of medicine, but who is not currently engaged in the clinical practice of medicine and has not been engaged in such practice for a period of 2 years or such longer period determined to be sufficient by the Secretary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E38FBB59A514E6485C8D1574A3192BD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who provides assurances satisfactory to the Secretary and the respective State licensing board that the individual will return to clinical practice in the discipline in which such individual was trained or certified, including, if applicable, by regaining necessary training and certification for legal authorization to practice medicine and surgery by a State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6B88063F6514447A06526C22E375E37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>reentering physician</term> does not include an individual if—</text> <subparagraph id="H305AEF36D6344693AA703124A301AEFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such individual has failed to complete an obligation to provide health care services under a Federal, State, or local program (including any period of obligated service under subpart III of part D of title III of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 254<italic>l</italic> et seq.)); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H478499E3E5944FA29E17D1D9D09FDFA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individual has a debt due to the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E44140EADDB47A494412FCB4EE70759"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Primary health services defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>primary health services</term> has the meaning given such term in section 331(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254d">42 U.S.C. 254d(a)(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF610363A27384C0699516EFE456282FE"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2016.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


