<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H48B75F45792B46E1A4BF84430EDE10CF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4018 IH: Consumer Protection and Choice Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4018</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151116">November 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish deferred presentment transaction requirements, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7ABDC00DEC5E42A6A28B82A07C3439D3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB3DB4824E911462CAE79A4EA31D33A7A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Protection and Choice Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6C4A1E7B448E410C8822837480820A68"><enum>2.</enum><header>Deferred presentment transaction requirements</header> <subsection id="HD8DED04C83E249D9B177771E67A7A488"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 2 of the Truth in Lending Act is amended by inserting after section 128A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638A">15 U.S.C. 1638A</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D659FCC23984BC6B7D09455AE1B879A" style="USC">
					<section id="H8B5DE9EF32974A299A33BA67F647442B"><enum>128B.</enum><header>Deferred presentment transaction requirements</header>
 <subsection id="H87B1EB8F2952464A8CB5AE5BC22DDD67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on deferred presentment transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A deferred presentment transaction is prohibited except as authorized by this section.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HCF732A91F30148AFA91812074C4A8E79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulation of deferred presentment transactions and deferred presentment providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Director of the Bureau determines that a State has in effect a covered deferred presentment law, any regulations of the Bureau with respect to deferred presentment transactions and deferred presentment providers shall not apply in such State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2E7E8AFE92A747349EDCA1AACA0DDD1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered deferred presentment law defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>covered deferred presentment law</term> means a law or regulation of a State that provides for the licensing of deferred presentment providers and the regulation of deferred presentment transactions, which may be accomplished through existing State authority, and that meets the following requirements:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2B2C59B4956041EE94B1E1913A780889"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The law or regulation must establish a database of deferred presentment transactions to assist deferred presentment providers with complying with the requirements of this section, which may be operated by a private company selected by the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85F77684D648458399976DCE5643478C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deferred presentment provider requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The law or regulation must require a deferred presentment provider to—</text> <subparagraph id="H92988D60E57642CC9640ECCB3A418F3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be licensed by the State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2890379268254C22B06066429BF883A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to the State the results of a background check, including fingerprinting, of each officer and principal of the deferred presentment provider;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C02317008654B098E8C8088080CB036"><enum>(C)</enum><text>secure a copy of a valid State-issued form of identification from a consumer before entering into a deferred presentment transaction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96AAF0875B25407BA5BB6F4294CC43C4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>verify through the State deferred presentment transaction database that a consumer entering into a deferred presentment transaction with the deferred presentment provider—</text>
 <clause id="H03F45019D0E3451986AC63311058E99B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not have an outstanding deferred presentment transaction; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6ABEB14F42624BB28F7DE47921C302D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>did not have an outstanding deferred presentment transaction within the previous 24-hour period; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H411D8BEF1C4E411FABBB62F7A8D6DD75"><enum>(E)</enum><text>report to the State deferred presentment transaction database operator immediately—</text> <clause id="H96787A359356487AAC4006A5503892BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>upon entering into a deferred presentment transaction agreement—</text>
 <subclause id="H8D98881D0A5141208745EF8B6F72F9A6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name of the consumer that provided a check or other payment instrument for deferred presentment;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2516ACD58AFC4104967825162F0FEFCF"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the consumer’s social security number or employment authorization alien number;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H823E1E8F3F97460384DFE79AA0403B33"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the consumer’s address;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H24D1520476F34752B49135083DEC8A90"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the consumer’s driver’s license number or identifier from other valid State-issued form of identification;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3FC17623FAD84498ACA36E03B8112875"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of the deferred presentment transaction;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H747CD6FFB32D42A1AC41CAB8575DBB18"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date such deferred presentment transaction is made and the date on which repayment of the deferred presentment transaction is due; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H840AE4AFB6F04776909AF31B3494561A"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other information as the State determines appropriate; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H1968CE0D1DFB4A3895A6755467C7ED5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon repayment by the consumer of the amount owed under a deferred presentment transaction agreement or after such deferred presentment transaction agreement is otherwise settled, the date and time on which the amount owed under such deferred presentment transaction agreement is satisfied.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC39478E0E24785BA89959DAFE70FF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deferred presentment transaction agreement requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The law or regulation must require that the terms of a deferred presentment transaction agreement—</text> <subparagraph id="H48DB1BF5917F422BBE4647F33824C770"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit the total amount of all interest and fees that may be charged to a consumer by a deferred presentment provider with respect to a deferred presentment transaction to no more than 10 percent of the amount of such a deferred presentment transaction and no more than a $5 processing fee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE2DA01C078F44C891D1C52C211766B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit the duration of the deferred presentment transaction to a period no longer than 31 days or less than 7 days;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H436A31F02E0841979F59E58BB35C96B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>limit the amount of the deferred presentment transaction to no more than $500, exclusive of allowed fees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB10366ED23534C8DB646F0F2CC725FEF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>be in writing;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H643F2321AD6344C98BAF8475C5F74523"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that the consumer shall—</text>
 <clause id="H23AA9BB6683A431FA8475CD345F8C6C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have the right to rescind any deferred presentment transaction agreement within the first 24 hours of the deferment period; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAA1F35FEFEB14D898B572D00F2A4FD76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pay any allowable processing fee regardless of such rescission; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97E48259DAE143CC9B0C441588788B58"><enum>(F)</enum><text>include such other information as the State determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA42A45F0C86C4BD5946D9038C03F79E2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of past-due amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The law or regulation must require that if a consumer fails to repay the amount due pursuant to a deferred presentment transaction agreement by the contractual repayment date, a deferred presentment provider shall provide an additional 60-day grace period, without any additional charge, for the consumer to repay such amount before the deferred presentment provider may request payment for the check or other payment instrument or pursue other civil remedies, subject to the conditions that the grace period will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDA014F12232C440BB413041AC5E8706C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>terminate immediately if, before the end of the 7-day period beginning on the date of the contractual repayment date, the consumer failed to make an appointment to attend a course with a consumer credit counseling agency and inform the deferred presentment provider of such appointment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6377A350FEB493ABE2CA14931EE7E7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be deemed to have terminated at the end of the 7-day period beginning on the date of the contractual repayment date if, before the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date of the contractual repayment date, the consumer failed to complete a course with a consumer credit counseling agency and inform the deferred presentment provider of the completion of such course.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H576FDB8B051143EB81BF093DF979A2B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>A deferred presentment transaction that complies with the requirements of this section and applicable State law shall not be considered to be an unfair, deceptive, or abusive act or practice.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAD360A7E4CF746F0BCAD87BF742663FC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The requirements of this section shall take effect on the date that is 24 months after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D8D1D00B60443AFAB57C2ED3218295A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H562E3A3C187847F19B25E40D4075CB7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deferment period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>deferment period</term> means the number of days a deferred presentment provider agrees to wait before depositing, presenting, or redeeming a consumer’s check or other payment instrument under a deferred presentment transaction agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD283E421FA44818F72834CD7698061"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deferred presentment provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>deferred presentment provider</term> means a person who holds a license to be a deferred presentment provider in the State in which a deferred presentment transaction agreement is entered into and who provides currency or other payment instrument to a consumer as part of a deferred presentment transaction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H390DB80CBD2B4283B6CF1CF2197A5E55"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deferred presentment transaction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>deferred presentment transaction</term> means a transaction in which currency or other payment instrument is provided to a consumer in exchange for a consumer’s check or other payment instrument and an agreement that such consumer’s check or other payment instrument shall be held for a deferment period prior to presentment, deposit, or redemption.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A584114249C4EF3918FDFF5121B3634"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deferred presentment transaction agreement</header><text>The term <term>deferred presentment transaction agreement</term> means the underlying agreement establishing a deferred presentment transaction.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA8030C2F7EC4D1F995C8B82CE15BB53"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Other payment instrument</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>other payment instrument</term> means a draft, warrant, money order, traveler's check, or electronic instrument (other than currency).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54FED53586DC4EEBA9A027E773F1C5C6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory and possession of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD87D9DF0822242BBA43D9C82B63BB57B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State deferred presentment transaction database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State deferred presentment transaction database</term> means the database established by the State that issued the consumer’s form of identification.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HD7E28F8A721A4A4A8F54C7A00C99A4F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents at the beginning of chapter 2 of the Truth in Lending Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 128A the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62D00C8FAAE34F08BA7D33CDC6B31777" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">128B. Deferred presentment transaction requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9C9B9F5AF6354822A204FEBF9EF18343"><enum>3.</enum><header>Moratorium and safe harbor</header>
 <subsection id="HC72C88E22E464C7DB9DD37C40A981B2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Moratorium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection may not promulgate or enforce any regulation related to deferred presentment providers with respect to deferred presentment transactions during the 24-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDCB8EF1E59AA4E468B3CCF918444D521"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection may not impose any additional requirements related to deferred presentment providers with respect to deferred presentment transactions in a State if such State has enacted a covered deferred presentment law by the effective date in subsection (e) of section 128B of the Truth in Lending Act, as added by section 2(a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H609F767C7D864B9983B10D4A6CE67391"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payday loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection—</text> <paragraph id="H8FE8FF1B72F54DA19A16F88AE2193D40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not regulate payday loans during the 24-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07284871874A48E58EFC9A9A3C6B01DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may regulate payday loans in a State after such period only if such State has not enacted a covered deferred presentment law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H637DB65827274A9FAEE155CEFC62E537"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H396018853FD94858B1ECF39E6D7743DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>TILA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>covered deferred presentment law</term>, <term>deferred presentment provider</term>, <term>deferred presentment transaction</term>, and <term>State</term> shall have the meanings given such terms under section 128B of the Truth in Lending Act, as added by section 2(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BC78E93E2E94AC1A733CECE0F733068"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payday loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>payday loan</term> means a loan described under section 1024(a)(1)(E) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5514">12 U.S.C. 5514(a)(1)(E)</external-xref>), except that such term does not include a deferred presentment transaction.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


