<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1FBDD54BC21B4013B5C5F113D5F372F6" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3494 IH: Protecting Infants Born Alive Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3494</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150911">September 11, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide greater clarity for States with respect to excluding providers whose actions a State suspects causes termination of fetuses born alive, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H79C8D6F860FE43FBBF10C59B3DD97208" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9F680954FBAD4F0D8D0DA9A1CCD44417" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Infants Born Alive Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H55D44B238D3A4AD48E30A076DD96770A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarifying States’ ability to exclude providers whose actions States suspect causes termination of fetuses born alive</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1902(a)(23) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(23)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, or as requiring a State to provide medical assistance for such services furnished by a person or entity whose services or actions are suspected by the State of causing the termination of a human fetus who would be classified as an infant that is born alive under section 8 of title 1, United States Code</quote>. </text></section> 
<section id="H98C709D9CF13431DB877288FDE15C5CE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protecting patients by not providing Federal funding to providers who terminate fetuses born alive</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1903(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (11) the following new paragraph: </text> <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H0D01831ABC3C4A5CB600EA9E1E14EEEA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H2859DE1F447A4EF09B0FAF42A1069048"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to amounts expended for medical assistance for items and services furnished by a person or entity who has terminated a human fetus who would be classified as an infant that is born alive under section 8 of title 1, United States Code;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H0ED0A10118AC4076927744177CBD3379"><enum>4.</enum><header>Termination from participation in Federal health care programs of providers who terminate fetuses born alive</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1128(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3B54AEF5AFD448CAA7F3A319E28E85D6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HEE0C4452E7B4476CAA44E2782FD6AF19"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Termination of born alive infant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual or entity that has terminated a human fetus who would be classified as an infant that is born alive under section 8 of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H08563C20BDE140A5844904D9BF4FEC6A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to terminations occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

