<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F9D99ABFF5B4176BAE62ABFB947D7A8" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2285 IH: Prevent Trafficking in Cultural Property Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2285</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150513">May 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To improve enforcement against trafficking in cultural property and prevent stolen or illicit cultural property from financing terrorist and criminal networks, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9AAC82EB74FB4F72A341DB973F3B9C55" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H160FC5930ACD40AAA7E62D0F2DAB141E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prevent Trafficking in Cultural Property Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAA3C2302C49644BF9FEDC1A0B8937145"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>cultural property</quote> includes property covered under—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4239840D2E314C10BEADEF2BB3066E1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Article 1 of the Hague Convention for the Protection of Cultural Property in the Event of Armed Conflict, adopted at the Hague on May 14, 1954 (Treaty 13 Doc. 106–1(A)); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D750549621944CD905FF2803B484CFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Article 1 of the Convention on the Means of Prohibiting and Preventing the Illicit Import, Export, and Transfer of Ownership of Cultural Property, adopted by the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (<quote>UNESCO</quote>) on November 14, 1970.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF7D1DB7ABD404DAAB6192BF942A327A6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="H27DC003DCACC4B80AC6DB3D76400DEEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure the Department of Homeland Security, specifically U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), enhances and unifies its efforts to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB608487BC763450E9CB08A3D5A01449D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interdict, detain, seize, and investigate cultural property illegally imported into the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38691A86E60746EEA767C836A152F622"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disrupt and dismantle smuggling and trafficking networks engaged in, conspiring to engage in, or facilitating illegal trade in cultural property, including stolen antiquities used to finance terrorism; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92F66D0FAD9E4CC990D5F76CD2A1063F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support Offices of United States Attorneys in prosecuting persons engaged in, conspiring to engage in, or facilitating illegal trade in cultural property; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H381B63A50999414F8D00D458BA7D7044"><enum>(2)</enum><text>protect cultural property pursuant to its obligations under the 1954 Hague Convention for the Protection of Cultural Property in the Event of Armed Conflict, the 1970 UNESCO Convention on the Means of Prohibiting and Preventing the Illicit Import, Export, and Transfer of Ownership of Cultural Property, and the Convention on Cultural Property Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2601">19 U.S.C. 2601–2613</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H63597CB18235445BBD8F505D060FCCE3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Activities of the Department of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Commissioner of CBP and the Director of ICE, as applicable, shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC8624C05825F493D87B372F092151041"><enum>(1)</enum><text>direct CBP and ICE to each designate a principal coordinator or group of personnel to direct, manage, coordinate, and update their respective policies and procedures, as well as conduct interagency communications, regarding illegally imported cultural property;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC9B9A0B65A140CFACFA02937EBECAA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>direct CBP and ICE to each update existing directives, regulations, rules, and memoranda of understanding, and, if necessary, devise additional directives, regulations, rules, and memoranda of understanding, relating to policies and procedures on the illegal importation of cultural property in order to—</text> <subparagraph id="H63AE6ACE2A75424FB852E92BA133AA83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflect changes in cultural property law, including changes and updates to relevant treaties, bilateral agreements, statutes, regulations, and case law that occurred subsequent to Customs Directive No. 5230–015, <quote>Customs Directive on Detention and Seizure of Cultural Property</quote>, dated April 18, 1991;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BBE83C8568C481BA032E9417CE3E22B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emphasize investigating, and providing support for investigations and prosecutions, of persons engaged in, conspiring to engage in, or facilitating the illegal importation of cultural property, including smugglers, dealers, buyers, money launderers, and any other parties, facilitators, and enablers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE723559198D146AC830B6D4A16BA316F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide for communication, coordination, and unity of effort between relevant CBP and ICE offices in investigating and supporting prosecutions of persons engaged in, conspiring to engage in, or facilitating the illegal importation of cultural property; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31C38C2137D24AD5A8B713C9A3CA104B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure all personnel within CBP and ICE involved in interdicting and investigating the illegal importation of cultural property receive sufficient training in—</text> <subparagraph id="H84BC34140E8F4DC39C96052F361C6D28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant cultural property laws;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4DADC51452E4B86AA1F92ED4E0E4EF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the identification of cultural property from regions that are at greatest risk of looting and trafficking; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4A1F35006FA4923825D3C7C68A41720"><enum>(C)</enum><text>methods of interdiction and investigative techniques specifically related to illegal trade in cultural property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H53CB3C2E10CF40BEB2ECDCCC28F14EC8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Role of the Smithsonian Institution</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the heads of all components of the Department of Homeland Security involved in cultural property protection activities are authorized to enter into agreements or memoranda of understanding with the Smithsonian Institution to temporarily engage personnel from the Smithsonian Institution for the purposes of furthering such cultural property protection activities.</text></section> <section id="HC446778C7AC1400E9478243280A97D51"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and three years thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4556AC1C88074BA78E547F578FAA06DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the progress of the implementation of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B8829ED09F84A75925A20EAAB8963A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department’s other actions to enhance and unify its efforts to interdict, detain, seize, and investigate cultural property illegally imported into the United States, and investigate, disrupt, and dismantle smuggling and trafficking networks engaged in, conspiring to engage in, or facilitating the illegal importation of cultural property.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

