<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0215F113D1A9421B8471A3C9DEA82A17" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1300 IH: First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1300</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to make anthrax vaccines and antimicrobials available to emergency response providers, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD8A123D56ADB4123AD59A38CB018EA19" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE952A7AEE3C44ECC99BDEFD6727CC998" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Responder Anthrax Preparedness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC89F9BE7427C4533A8CC12FD26F3B558"><enum>2.</enum><header>Anthrax vaccination program for first responders</header> <subsection id="H95AE17A5AFA4413C98EAB3D81C8DB1A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Anthrax preparedness</header> <paragraph id="H02042B915C974DCA87973B74435DABB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title V of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/311">6 U.S.C. 311 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H4DCD0E274B564B7798E8E513539C529B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HC8E2CC0A661A49E0992FD11F97579A8F"><enum>526.</enum><header>Anthrax preparedness</header> 
<subsection id="HD32CDAEAC3DC47838FEFFABE2B103E8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vaccination program for first emergency response providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of domestic preparedness for and collective response to terrorism, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall make available surplus vaccines and antimicrobials and vaccines and antimicrobials with short shelf lives, from the strategic national stockpile under section 319F–2(a) of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 247d–6b(a)) to emergency response providers for administration to such providers who voluntarily consent to such administration, and shall—</text> <paragraph id="H71287B29D23E4CAE96AA39A749D1CCB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish any necessary logistical and tracking systems to facilitate making such vaccines and antimicrobials so available; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0738BB9AF1BE4F00A74506EAE9E02129"><enum>(2)</enum><text>distribute disclosures regarding associated risks to end users.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE24DBF82EB4C42C2A568E45B0ABF10C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Threat assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0918E6FF41EB41EB8AEF6B75F9F4EB72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support homeland security-focused risk analysis and risk assessments of the threats posed by anthrax from an act of terror;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDD85432BF8F490DA93D054952586655"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leverage existing and emerging homeland security intelligence capabilities and structures to enhance prevention, protection, response, and recovery efforts with respect to an anthrax terror attack; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3EDB2DE9648422095894639CDBB0982"><enum>(3)</enum><text>share information and provide tailored analytical support on threats posed by anthrax to State, local, and tribal authorities, as well as other national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F93599917B749F2BC6DAA48C4C6183F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections in section 1(b) of such Act is amended by inserting at the end of the items relating to title V the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2C8369A0182B4B9AA6902ED55A87A42E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 526. Anthrax preparedness.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H63C09BAC36F74C7893D047133C94D5F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot program</header> 
<paragraph id="H6481BF87BFFC4B6C8F67F415118E77A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the vaccination program authorized in section 526(a) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a), the Secretary shall carry out a pilot program to administer vaccines and antimicrobials to emergency response providers as so authorized. The duration of the pilot program shall be at least 18 months.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93BCE091CBA8464FA25AC0FB059803DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preliminary requirements</header><text>By not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and prior to implementing the pilot program under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H302B3EA03766450DB42B907B7B000239"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a communication platform for the pilot program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27AB9558DEC2454ABC2A9E6796922DC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish education and training modules for the pilot program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H44826B3AF54E4128B1A1D68CB0856190"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct economic analysis of the pilot program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE44DAB4E4A84B95AFAA1E753049A4B6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create a logistical platform for the anthrax vaccine request process under the pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF59EAF06C43495B862AFE7CC515462B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Location</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program under this subsection, the Secretary shall select emergency response providers based in at least two States for participation in the pilot program. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EA14250A7BA474B9FFAB973AAE77EA3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Distribution of information</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to each emergency response provider who participates in the pilot program under this subsection disclosures and educational materials regarding the associated risks of any vaccine or antimicrobial administered under the pilot program and of exposure to anthrax.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H472CED2F026C4162ABADEB1A002A4682"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the completion of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the progress and results of the pilot program. The report shall include a plan under which the Secretary plans to continue to make vaccines and antimicrobials available to emergency response providers under section 526(a) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AEDD87B7339472DA7A031B68A88C1C5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Deadline for implementation</header><text>The Secretary shall begin implementing the pilot program under this subsection by not later than the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

