<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0EBC45927AE64F9DA5053AF8B1391199" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1829 IH: DHS Communication Enhancement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1829</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150415">April 15, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to assess and submit to Congress a report on the ability of the Department of Homeland Security to convey information to, collect information from, and serve individuals with limited English proficiency.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H375DA997F8F947E6B3D838DBCA772908" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H64140B6448FF4E7B9472B17857A40732" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Communication Enhancement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H82A083BFE2B44C9884638C53836AE77D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessing and developing a plan to improve DHS communication with and service of individuals with limited English proficiency</header> <subsection id="H898405D1F1304D4DB67F11601E8CBAB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Under Secretary for Management, shall complete an assessment of the ability of the Department of Homeland Security to convey information to, collect information from, and serve individuals with limited English proficiency. With respect to each component in the Department, the assessment shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4E7965A071D1486E871D3F0B89DCEBE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify the languages spoken fluently and read by individuals with limited English proficiency commonly encountered by personnel of the component;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED06DF20394941738F230170B75E4EE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review the public materials of the component to assess the extent to which the materials are available in the languages identified under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBED5657FAEB4114BEE8716C07D599FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess the ability of personnel of the component to communicate with and serve individuals with limited English proficiency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEE6717A00D0541938E8D904A4D5CE46D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report; implementation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate concerning the assessment under subsection (a). Such report shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H402A643ECECC49B088343B5DD925FD75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the findings of such assessment for each component of the Department; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66322FC221A5405082F11838DADD20E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan, including a timeline for implementation, developed in consultation with the head of each component, to improve the ability of each component to convey information to, collect information from, and serve individuals with limited English proficiency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

