<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H41B743909F89476197774706C5141941" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1913 IH: Protecting American Taxpayers from Fraud Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1913</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150421">April 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to develop guidance and procedures for the recovery of refunds relating to tax return preparer fraud.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HF769BE75EEC0432F8C4F775FF9822759" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H466D33ECAA32432D81CC7068DACC6A26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting American Taxpayers from Fraud Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCDEA12985FB343B5ACFCF77A25682345"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to address predatory practices in low income communities by some tax return preparers.</text></section>
<section id="H5D7D721291B94D19BEC4E150AE267256" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Referral procedures for recovery of refunds for taxpayers defrauded by employees or agents of tax preparation firms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall develop referral procedures for, and establish a liaison to, tax preparation firms to seek recovery of refunds for taxpayers defrauded by employees or agents of tax preparation firms. In developing such procedures, the Secretary (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall ensure that there is coordination among the following entities within the Internal Revenue Service: Taxpayer Advocate Service, Wage &amp; Investment Division, Criminal Investigation, Office of the Chief Counsel, Return Preparer Office, and Office of Professional Responsibility.</text></section> <section id="H3FCA10408E4C483BB5AF3F6643D3A89F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Comprehensive guidance for the treatment of all claims for refunds relating to tax return preparer fraud</header> <subsection id="H7CA7DD144A9742DF9CFAC2F7BD96B9BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall develop comprehensive guidance for the treatment by the Internal Revenue Service of all claims for refunds relating to tax return preparer fraud. Such guidance shall provide a clear description the rights and responsibilities of taxpayers, including the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H837224A758E44CD981E119FB6300FC4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mitigation</header><text>Actions taken by the taxpayer to prevent the preparer fraud or to minimize the loss.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9714DDCF34D640E49045F833D9EFFB53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restitution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Actions taken by the taxpayer to receive restitution relating to tax return preparer fraud and whether the taxpayer has received any restitution.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H57A4728F28CB4C77846DABD1B693B522"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Substantiation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Actions taken by the taxpayer to substantiate a claim of fraud, including one or more of the following, if available:</text> <subparagraph id="H536FA70D31B340DC84FB92E29D572101"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing a copy of the unaltered return of tax (if provided by the preparer).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H40B2C367EF834AD2ABE92B65567BA958"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing a business card, flyer, or other advertisement with the preparer’s contact information.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6320907A8EC64161B46F259812A3F719"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing a copy of any refund traces requested.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDAAE06A59D9B4CB68D9F29A0DD2DB1D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing a copy of bank statements showing the expected refund was not deposited into the victim’s account.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBEAC8A1150CC4C248830E6BB9C08A7C3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing a taxpayer statement regarding the fraud, which shall be signed under penalties of perjury.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7EB4DD0EAD8B4C62B04791D04740C37D"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Filing a report or complaint with local law enforcement authorities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H081EA6FE0DD341F9B55F9741D84116DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance relating to restitution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in the guidance developed for restitution—</text>
<paragraph id="H5D3F114CF2E840F0A6BC8DD689FA046B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>place the emphasis on restitution received by the taxpayer and making the taxpayer whole relative to the cash value of assets that have already been transferred to the taxpayer,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF04D533426F740408AA4BADA727222A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not reduce restitution on the basis of either anticipated or court mandated (but not yet collected) payments, and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9E1E8A8635B34D9EAA392046824CFAE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for a claw-back procedure to ensure that restitution ultimately paid to the taxpayer, subsequent to the restitution provided by the Internal Revenue Service, would be remitted to the Internal Revenue Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

