<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDD2A524E83F94D5AA10F66C622722805" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4143 IH: Terrorist Refugee Infiltration Prevention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4143</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151201">December 1, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To temporarily restrict the admission to the United States of refugees from countries containing
			 terrorist-controlled territory.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8C299A4E0ECB4D97BBFA3C148BDAECE2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88E1E2C695F640D18C8F55715A9F1D77" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terrorist Refugee Infiltration Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H967B883908D14ACAAEB0BCA59403D217"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2CF331E6C8E449E1ADFE2949058375BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Country containing terrorist-controlled territory</header><text>The phrase <term>country containing terrorist-controlled territory</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5175070E71FF42BF89B139BA51379FDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Iraq, Libya, Somalia, Syria, and Yemen; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB8F42935D704A2CAD762DCF11EF61D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other country designated by the Secretary of State pursuant to section 4(a).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED0C9EFDB3C2482781AA6EDD57B8C674"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Refugee</header><text>The term <term>refugee</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a)(42) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(42)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39BC791DC12045CCA8960B627F22AD20"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Substantial assistance</header><text>The phrase <term>substantial assistance</term> means a level of assistance without which the United States could not achieve the purposes for which the assistance was provided or sought.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1150B8C4E77A4005A5AF9175C45CE673"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Victim of genocide</header><text>The term <term>victim of genocide</term> has the meaning given the term in Article II of the United Nations Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide, opened for signature in Paris on December 9, 1948.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H5CAE054451484613B04BF99F2E51B987"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on refugees from terrorist-controlled territories</header>
 <subsection id="HE87230BC4ACE4A6DA8AEE1D1039246CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, an alien may not be admitted to the United States under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) if the alien is a national of, has habitually resided in, or is claiming refugee status due to events in any country containing terrorist-controlled territory.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H5C92C35620F142CA8858732F3251F24D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header>
 <paragraph id="H3C4FA766A3294FF3816D67FC86253395"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien otherwise prohibited from admission to the United States under subsection (a) may be admitted to the United States under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) if the alien clearly proves, beyond doubt, that he or she—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE14A3E1E291F46B0855ABD623D1CEB37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>satisfies the requirements for admission as a refugee; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02491F6011AA43268C0950C49C236F92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a member of a group that has been designated by the Secretary of State or by an Act of Congress as a victim of genocide.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F706051E4B44C01AAE75EAD99A0A4CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National security threat</header><text>An alien may not be admitted under paragraph (1) unless—</text> <subparagraph id="H97C712A3BE264A609A59C078A7E8F560"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the alien has undergone the highest level of security screening of any category of traveler to the United States, including assessments by the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the Federal Bureau of Investigation Terrorist Screening Center, and the National Counterterrorism Center;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2A2117B06CF472CB2AC6839833D46AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>full multi-modal biometrics of the alien have been taken, including face, iris, and all fingerprints; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA23E37C309D5430AA05C75351ED1497E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of National Intelligence certify that such alien is not a threat to the national security of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2CE7EED4B074CC6B8A36D60D671840A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to any alien seeking admission under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) if the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of National Intelligence certify that the alien—</text>
 <paragraph id="H64F13BE23E80444C8A61081A922F0AE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provided substantial assistance to the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H368BE0A674754EF4AF7B878DFC379D78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>would face a substantial risk of death or serious bodily injury because of that assistance if not admitted to the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7030B9F4CB3743FCAD8253C71025CECB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Secretary of State</header>
 <subsection id="H490D18E4618948A886492CF0EA7524E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of other countries</header><text>In addition to the countries listed in section 2(1)(A), the Secretary of State may designate, as a <quote>country containing terrorist-controlled territory</quote>, any country containing territory that is controlled, in substantial part, by a Foreign Terrorist Organization, as designated by the Secretary of State under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>), to the exclusion of that country’s recognized government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H050AA9D124A3421786F2EF44BDDB6270"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of countries containing terrorist-Controlled territory</header><text>The Secretary of State shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD14B29FB05824B5196264FC2ABCBFF4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain and continually update a list of the countries containing terrorist-controlled territory; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9979F20054E4942952CE5E4E0114432"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continuously make available the list described in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0B603BE6687045B492518F81B5DCC06A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the Secretary’s Web site;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F6AF68DA4504215BE421B599556189D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CCC5DB52D3A477F823D653472E7C053"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to Congress; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3526016E5BD458783752FBB033B0153"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to the public.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE3EA442110E4E4EBDCECCE5DD27EB5B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Victims of genocide</header><text>The Secretary of State shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD68A2793209C4E77AEC023F801C8E3FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify all groups that are victims of genocide;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA436DA1AF6BD4CE1978FBDA87B6F33FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain and continually update a list of the groups that the Secretary or Congress has identified as victims of genocide; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA63401E1BC474428BB1D7B4EA043645C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continuously make available the list described in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE703A443BF2459FA8A2AA2EFD85FCBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the Secretary’s Web site;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A5EAB00D12247648BCE53182410EA24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ED8F5D409CD4D368E83DFD2A1F8FF44"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to Congress; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C02974CD3EE42A38AD7429AB0AB2B64"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to the public.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC7260C556524749B86D5B56BD084877"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National security threat</header><text>The Secretary of State may refuse to designate a group for the exception under section 3(b)(1)(B) if the Secretary determines that the group poses a substantial security risk to the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HABF448D4DD524C9B9787EAEF13C4DF8B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Secretary of Homeland Security</header>
 <subsection id="H26EA96C9B18A4979B05F512CF5594D48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue regulations to implement section 3 as soon as practicable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE26FCCC3C496486C898DBD41DA00A543"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limit of alien assertions</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not admit any alien into the United States under this Act solely based on the assertions of such alien.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA23F84D2B2AE40E2AFF132D61029F0E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall coordinate with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of National Intelligence to substantiate, as much as reasonably practicable, the assertions made by aliens seeking admission to the United States.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H7397EB049C97449C980C7558C64D6903"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective period</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall be effective during the 3-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


