<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E33FDA2C52945B695367ED8F06EB409" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1034 IH: To provide for an accounting of total United States contributions to the United Nations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1034</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150224">February 24, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for an accounting of total United States contributions to the United Nations.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0AF6C1B26CAF45739B6B0FD31060F160" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEC6F431D03104451B547039F72508545" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Report on United States contributions to the United Nations</header>
<subsection id="HC948F7F75AC145EA8AD2E714CF622E9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to Congress a report on all assessed and voluntary contributions, including in-kind, of the United States Government to the United Nations and its affiliated agencies and related bodies during the previous fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCA3B65B77B0A49F080D268A5BD60FADB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text>
<paragraph id="H54C43D36CDC3449E9BEB92312B54A6D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total amount of all assessed and voluntary contributions, including in-kind, of the United States Government to the United Nations and its affiliated agencies and related bodies during the previous fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H360772C7CB6A4FF2884262DF0EF8199C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The approximate percentage of United States Government contributions to each United Nations affiliated agency or body in such fiscal year when compared with all contributions to each such agency or body from any source in such fiscal year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H36F81E236E2E48D4BFEFB9B172A181B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For each such United States Government contribution—</text> <subparagraph id="H950D9CC3B5F44CBF950C54C085B4E2B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of each such contribution;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6328ACC1996A4B91943EE49BDB02BD86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of each such contribution (including whether assessed or voluntary);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H255BD2ED51934CAA87AE2C41EE381120"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the department or agency of the United States Government responsible for each such contribution;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE71C17FF3F5D4C208655A686ADA37D81"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the purpose of each such contribution; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7768EAC047345A4A30D76A810EACE5E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the United Nations or its affiliated agency or related body receiving the contribution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF96C6C3A030B43D4BA1839D593572CCD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of initial report</header><text>The first report required under subsection (a) shall include the information required under this section for the previous three fiscal years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0695C76BAFA44A1E9DD047FCAE340217"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public availability of information</header><text>Not later than 14 days after submitting a report required under subsection (a), the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall post a public version of the report on a text-based, searchable, and publicly available Internet Web site.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


