<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2C1F7B91A302431A8BDA283AAD32538A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2896 IH: TAILOR Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2896</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies to take risk profiles and
			 business models of institutions into account when taking regulatory
			 actions, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB03394A6D94F418A8C13796D71C4D85A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9F42F799800649869311DF6C9FF5AC7A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taking Account of Institutions with Low Operation Risk Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>TAILOR Act of 2015</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H739B866CD3614AEA950253BB4C65A5EE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulations appropriate to business models</header> <subsection id="HD4243C17AC414D29A6E8BF7D4D935087"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any regulatory action occurring subsequent to enactment of this section, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H65B2B036AB644C688594491CAAA7488B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take into consideration the risk profile and business models of the various institutions or classes of institutions subject to the regulatory action;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE22631817F7549E88C2B081205224420"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the necessity, appropriateness, and impact of applying such regulatory action to such institutions or classes of institutions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04F22EB26A1442A282C4F89CDF42E9F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>tailor such regulatory action applicable to such institutions or class of institutions in a manner that limits the regulatory compliance impact, cost, liability risk, and other burdens as is appropriate for the risk profile and business model involved.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79E11A74A3DD49E99C6D995BF98A7555"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other considerations</header><text>In satisfying the requirements of subsection (a) and when implementing such regulatory action, the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall also consider—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBF9D9C7A76484E3686DEFF23DF9C9CBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the impact that such regulatory action, both by itself and in conjunction with the aggregate effect of other regulations, has on the ability of the institution or class of institutions to flexibly serve evolving and diverse customer needs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5C3A0631C3D4972BE8C643C4E0A66DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the potential unintended impact of examination manuals or other regulatory directives that work in conflict with the tailoring of such regulatory action described in subsection (a)(3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44AD6B6B9BEE4A96A590760EAB6D65A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the underlying policy objectives of the regulatory action and statutory scheme involved.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45A4DFDADF834B30814FC61297BF5709"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of proposed and final rulemaking</header><text>The Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall disclose in every notice of proposed rulemaking and in any final rulemaking for a regulatory action how the agency has applied subsections (a) and (b).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB39991DBA39741AAAFA04E14CBC3FAA8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
				<paragraph id="H9F7BDFCEB18140128294017753BB2F73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individual agency reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="H105476B7E6B7438A98ACDA6F51D32FA6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall individually report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, within twelve months of enactment of this section and annually thereafter, on the specific actions taken to tailor the agency’s regulatory actions pursuant to the requirements of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C3CC892FD3D4388AA63CD296C3887B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appearance before the Committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Federal financial institution regulatory agency shall appear before the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate after each report is made pursuant to subparagraph (A), to testify on the contents of such report.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D6197EEB50C4592BEA5A553F1A9F758"><enum>(2)</enum><header>FIEC reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4280E8F703F947E898E879DDA3ABA0A9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Financial Institutions Examination Council shall report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, within three months after the reports required under paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="HDE59026EBF1646B6B3B161EAD76A608A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on the extent to which regulatory actions tailored pursuant to this section result in differential regulation of similarly-situated institutions of diverse charter types with respect to comparable regulations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1555A78D44FC4D538FE07750FACF88BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reasons for such differential treatment.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D17EF8319D74EF2A75682D72B13B997"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appearance before the Committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Financial Institutions Examination Council shall appear before the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate after each report is made pursuant to subparagraph (A), to testify on the contents of such report.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H017CF70AE369488199A630CD20EDBB57"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limited look-Back application</header><text>The Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies shall conduct a review of all regulations adopted during the period beginning on the date that is five years before the date of the introduction of this Act in the House of Representatives and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply the requirements of this section to such regulations. If the application of the requirements of this section to any such regulation requires such regulation to be revised, the agency shall revise such regulation within three years of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D03C8D992144129BF46A0DE48C07787"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="HCDB45C2B80DC4613AED6044A5CC5873B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies</header><text>The term <quote>Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies</quote> means the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F5DEEE267CF4CEBAAF85EDDFBC02D39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulatory action</header><text>The term <quote>regulatory action</quote> means any proposed, interim, or final rule or regulation, guidance, or published interpretation.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

