<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0ED0578DEC4E47DF8D59CC239F13A1CF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 476 IH: GI Bill Education Quality Enhancement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 476</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to clarify the process of approving courses of education
			 pursued using educational benefits administered by the Secretary of
			 Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H21DA4EE137ED47999582B61D96CF7B37" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9F2FECDA1D55473B9584C10A68EE0F19" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>GI Bill Education Quality Enhancement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H27EECCF69A3C4289826EEBB6CE729E32" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Role of State approving agencies</header> <subsection id="HCBBFD8C44CC541438CA80A8904D66242"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Approval of certain courses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3672(b)(2)(A) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the following</quote> and all that follows through the colon and inserting the following: <quote>a program of education is deemed to be approved for purposes of this chapter if a State approving agency determines that the program is one of the following programs:</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0CD5A6E4B5164FA7B0A5832CFB40AEE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval of other courses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3675 of such title amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB6564A8F19914176B2B954E5CEA31DC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H42FE7CC5800B431D9D23DD0CE96F67B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary or a State approving agency</quote> and inserting <quote>A State approving agency, or the Secretary when acting in the role of a State approving agency,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7EF62A256C4424C86292B8D15012B09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>offered by proprietary for-profit educational institutions</quote> and inserting <quote>not covered by section 3672 of this title</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9DB4ABA0F1A40B587C47A2F407F7F91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>the Secretary or the State approving agency</quote> and inserting <quote>the State approving agency, or the Secretary when acting in the role of a State approving agency,</quote> each place it appears.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB0215C7C55204803B49D6C0D13EA0016"><enum>3.</enum><header>Criteria used to approve nonaccredited courses</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H30342C3EEBD24CB3A910002C6FFEE881"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3676(c)(14) of such title is amended by inserting before the period the following: <quote>if the Secretary, in consultation with the State approving agency and pursuant to regulations prescribed to carry out this paragraph, determines such criteria are necessary and treat public, private, and proprietary for-profit educational institutions equitably</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD2A20834BAD6416F8EE2025D031F0FD2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to an investigation conducted under section 3676(c) of title 38, United States Code, that is covered by a reimbursement of expenses paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to a State pursuant to section 3674 of such title on or after the first day of the first fiscal year following the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H155EEE01CF1F487092FE54ACAB4B32CB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Clarification of assistance provided for certain flight training</header>
 <subsection id="HC918E5AE913E48CAAC95A3431B18F63E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c)(1)(A) of section 3313 of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8E872A40985141A6BD6D74D1630AEC8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F8ECD96E2444384802DEB1CB656A4BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE84ABD245854D60B7D59E815F7F8791"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>In the case of a program of education pursued at a public institution of higher learning</quote> and inserting <quote>(I) Subject to subclause (II), in the case of a program of education pursued at a public institution of higher learning not described in clause (ii)(II)(bb)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37C92E4D8E794821BF266C1978B81E1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C223C83325A4533A78A0AC25D56EA70" style="USC"> <subclause id="H78D231995A514E7DBBAA595D78DC894B" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the actual net cost for in-State tuition and fees pursuant to subclause (I), the Secretary may not pay for fees relating to flight training.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H947779D59C194E49BF8D9668EDC71964"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9B77E57427E2402696D819F8B78EC185"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by redesignating items (aa) and (bb) as subitems (AA) and (BB), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDD2F6643660451C8CDDBEBB242C6FF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (II), by redesignating items (aa) and (bb) as subitems (AA) and (BB), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87B08E306436413A891F3F2CE15B1483"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7387A5796B644A159C8AA8CD3768E02C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In the case of a program of education pursued at a non-public or foreign institution of higher learning</quote> and inserting <quote>(I) In the case of a program of education described in subclause (II)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01BC87962697498AABC5C95846C383B5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE944705EF3344AA6A0E65EDB8F1B0C74" style="USC"> <subclause id="HE783ABB179DC4D16A5109CED078676ED" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program of education described in this subclause is any of the following:</text>
 <item id="H0FCDDBF75136442D9138607F27679E13"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program of education pursued at a non-public or foreign institution of higher learning.</text> </item><item id="H2B260287058043ECBBC292658122656E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>A program of education pursued at a public institution of higher learning in which flight training is required to earn the degree being pursued (including with respect to a dual major, concentration, or other element of such a degree).</text>
								</item></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H597BE3235ADA4F0882386182D15996B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to a quarter, semester, or term, as applicable, commencing on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H19B80786ADC84CCEB19C5F833F4C6A7F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Compliance surveys</header>
 <subsection id="H8F3151FD558C4A129675CF4378545C43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3693 of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8252F6C805D64E59BCAA2ADD9CB5E5B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following new subsection (a):</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H364621C3CFB144CE9489DA3D96E118C5" style="USC">
						<subsection id="H94DE7B8AF77A46CBB5EBA1BE450977D1"><enum>(a)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF3B462F42A44496A8ABBA1FA33F56A81"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary shall conduct an annual compliance survey of educational institutions and training establishments offering one or more courses approved for the enrollment of eligible veterans or persons if at least 20 such veterans or persons are enrolled in any such course. The Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H52A63067479E4F88B596A518D71C8C9E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>design the compliance surveys to ensure that such institutions or establishments, as the case may be, and approved courses are in compliance with all applicable provisions of chapters 30 through 36 of this title;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A7799DD15884A618B2CDFBFAABB9284" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">survey each such educational institution and training establishment not less than once during every two-year period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F8F7F3E204E4D998CC4D5ACD039D1EF" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assign not fewer than one education compliance specialist to work on compliance surveys in any year for each 40 compliance surveys required to be made under this section for such year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC298D2CCF02E4AD6985288F8DA50D810" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the State approving agencies, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF0CAE0FE50E4EAF96DBD091F697BDF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>annually determine the parameters of the surveys required under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B45F402B7A54425BA45CA5A4648A9FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than September 1 of each year, make available to the State approving agencies a list of the educational institutions and training establishments that will be surveyed during the fiscal year following the date of making such list available.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB86A75BE25504D299FD6B3680ED5A530"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40754EF0573A44728AA7BE776FD348E4" style="USC"> <subsection id="H135D01BC9CF541EF8742AD09BCB763F1"><enum>(c)</enum><text>In this section, the terms <term>educational institution</term> and <term>training establishment</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 3452 of this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H991BA0C3AB7F4DA9ACBB5830E24F5619"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of such section is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDFC66AAA29504F34AE89285E6ACC39C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (a) of this section for an annual compliance survey</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(1) for a compliance survey</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50C5EBF64E0E4A0D9F4ADE9435B0153C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>institution</quote> and inserting <quote>educational institution or training establishment</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H72E8FB0DEC6F431EA2D24F5A34DC9950"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>institution's demonstrated record of compliance</quote> and inserting <quote>record of compliance of such institution or establishment</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


