<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC9A27A3B62744B798FBF2BB5BA533539" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2155 IH: Community STEM Learning Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2155</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to
			 award grants for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics
			 education programs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H034D26E8C8514DF2AD40D8A6C7AE5079" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF7D66A3147D5451797644294CB671044" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community STEM Learning Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFFFB344F0FA0475CB5A3E999A1019695"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and Purpose</header> <subsection id="H6DE91A12FE334F35A5415A298A0DFF9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9676CBCB08B0470CBDF2884BE96D2CF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employment projections forecast a 17-percent growth in the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (<quote>STEM)</quote> fields over the next decade.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A354C240E904654B081466699AE17F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ninety-two percent of STEM occupations will require at least some post-secondary education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H206DCAFC54624600AF7D037FAD662AA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>While the number of degrees awarded in STEM fields has increased steadily since the 1960s, the overall share of STEM degrees awarded has actually shrunk in comparison to all degrees conferred.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H987A95BF03D04AA684B2A56C86A19C54"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Internationally, a larger proportion of all degrees awarded are in the STEM fields. While 16 percent of degrees awarded in the United States are in STEM fields, nearly 50 percent of degrees awarded in China, 38 percent in South Korea, and 28 percent in Germany are in STEM fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3D4EA11709B4CC5AA6080D176C44688"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Minorities are seriously underrepresented in the science and engineering workforce in the United States, with just under 6 percent of Blacks and over 5 percent of Hispanics participating in the STEM workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AE1A07DBA5348DDAAC7E15D43EE833C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Twenty-one percent of Black college students enter college with STEM majors, but only 16 percent actually receive a bachelor’s degree in a STEM major.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB5B9AE5D47E4637A8E62B65B9A31C0E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Over <fraction>½</fraction> of Black students that enroll in a 4-year university are interested in STEM, but are not proficient in math.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE20CF4C9ABE942869682E7C599AB1C3C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Since 1990, mathematic scores on the assessments conducted by the National Assessment of Education Progress have increased for all students, but White students have average scores 27 points higher than Black and Hispanic students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A3C9360E2FB464AAE57AF0F6BFE353C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>After school programs play an important role in addressing the achievement gap in underserved communities. Studies demonstrate that STEM learning during the school day is necessary but not sufficient for life-long STEM literacy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3CB489E9BC2433AA105FE07A6684CDA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>As many as 8,400,000 students are enrolled in after school programs. Ethnic minority children are more likely than non-minority children to participate in after school programs. While 15 percent of all students are enrolled in after school programs, 24 percent of Black students and 21 percent of Hispanic students are enrolled in such programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H218899A7D8DE43248EFDA8ECF14C3273"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to prepare middle school and secondary school students to be ready for opportunities in the STEM fields in college and in careers through strong after school, summer, and weekend programs that focus on STEM education.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H3666F821B61C424F95C981E06F528D5E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendment to ESEA for STEM grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6661">20 U.S.C. 6661 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC13145416B454088BB6BF36A58190496"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the part heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="part" style="OLC">and Stem Grants</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="part" style="OLC">Partnerships</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA5BB40BCAD049208F629272EAE21C09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the part heading the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CAC5A7EF4CD4829BD2C562D24F48403" style="OLC">
					<subpart id="H0F82D7C8D6E649D5B2B139D5FC0F9AB5"><enum>1</enum><header>Math and Science Partnerships</header></subpart><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC79FD9807930466E98123B1BD1A61828"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 2203 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D326C324ED646B79667F6100F5DF873" style="OLC"> <subpart id="H8A04160D4B0449F89541D3A115131151"><enum>2</enum><header>STEM Grants</header> <section id="H4C2CABD827D14439A5E4479D9D6DD6EC"><enum>2211.</enum><header>Informal STEM learning program</header> <subsection id="H0515230930A64B399886812A387F1560"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to award grants, to be known as <quote>informal STEM learning program</quote> grants, to national and regional intermediaries to establish informal STEM learning in-school, after school, summer, and weekend programs that focus on science, technology, engineering, and math (referred to in this section as <term>STEM</term>) education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H663747C258D24BC6A55A962F0454B212"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A national or regional intermediary seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8E92910995584230927ACAADDA909C11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amount requested and the proposed use of the funds.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H173838E810F74905AB2E2D68EA2BAF2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the national or regional intermediary will require a community-based affiliate operating an informal STEM learning program to provide the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2A95677FB5084CD2BA4C30CBF726C488"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A program description, including a description of—</text> <clause id="HC40380B82CD24A99903C6638111E3D61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the project-based learning that the program will use and the applicability of such projects to students’ lives after graduation from secondary school;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD85AB0C513B2408B962AAA690F967B38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the academic instruction, research model, or curriculum that the program will use; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE717FCD7E6234B7DB6CFF5D139A114FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any service-learning opportunities that will be available to students.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F727C825CE64025B842E04C38C80E90"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evidence that the informal STEM learning program will primarily serve students who are traditionally underrepresented in STEM field careers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04AD7F3C8A724B5FAA87947E7F94EDBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the student recruitment plan, student retention plan, and parental engagement plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FF2053CB57B412E9885A9AE5BCB5A1C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the professional development and training that the community-based affiliate will provide to its informal STEM learning program staff.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H893626769E0C43719FCA51466FD23FE7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of the community-based affiliate’s collaboration with an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/10001">20 U.S.C. 10001</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93579BB04D0A45BCB186A898396DD3A9"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the community-based affiliate will enable students who participate in the program to achieve the goals in subsection (c).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H171B00BC05A94B4D9C723A7579486EDC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The goals of the Informal STEM learning program grants are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA190754FC0B241209837956B6ACA340B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To increase awareness of and exposure to current science content, scientific processes, and tools for students who are traditionally underrepresented in STEM field careers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H915A583E51434AF1ADFC390EF57518F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To provide STEM learning that is connected to workforce skills that are essential in the 21st century.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E9F9B22188345AAA56A4B3FE0B6EB69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To increase on time grade promotion, the number of students who graduate high school, and the number of students who pursue opportunities in STEM fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E17BD31D79C497D87DB8AFEECE71056"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To increase enrollment in and completion of more STEM related coursework in school for students who are traditionally underrepresented in STEM field careers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67F568E127454FA5A02E98A34868F8AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To increase awareness of students who are traditionally underrepresented in STEM field careers of the opportunities after graduation from secondary school in STEM fields, including college majors in STEM and careers in STEM.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73ADBE8D504348E0BFD8E5BA6C5D5D38"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For students to have the experience of interacting with staff who demonstrate a positive attitude toward STEM fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B83674076424B68A5C7672422766ED5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To facilitate project-based learning and service-learning.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA09053A7C507413C912977129287C3B5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A national or regional intermediary that receives a grant under this section shall reserve—</text>
 <paragraph id="H96635E53273B4C12BA12F95141BFBD51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 25 percent to provide technical and administrative assistance to and collect data from its community-based affiliates to which it makes subgrants;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04282BD6E4A046E283ED8A9A0FA1B0E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less than 50 percent for subgrants to community-based affiliates that have demonstrated effectiveness in operating STEM programs in order for such affiliates to expand such STEM programs to reach more students who are traditionally underrepresented in STEM field careers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54DC6CF0C92D4889BA5B8EF1CE452C55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not less than 25 percent for subgrants to community-based affiliates that do not operate STEM programs in order for such affiliates that seek to develop new STEM programs that are consistent with the goals of this section to develop and establish such new STEM programs.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA644AA1F53049BB8A4C9487A3E4127A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subgrants to community-Based affiliates</header>
 <paragraph id="HF20CC31D81E042D4BFC3A9412ADE3935"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community-based affiliate seeking a subgrant shall submit an application to its national or regional intermediary at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the national or regional intermediary may reasonably require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB036FD4D7BC343BBB37937F3AB8F33AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community-based affiliate that receives a subgrant under this section to operate an informal STEM learning program shall operate an in-school, after school, summer, or weekend program that focuses on STEM education and primarily serves students who are traditionally underrepresented in STEM field careers. Such program shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D378DE6810444159BEEA8FE74EF6DC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Educational services that include—</text> <clause id="HD74997D262314F5892096C010FF370A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an initial assessment of students’ progress in math, science, and reading;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA76692E864B64FC89E2C82E60AA06099"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remediation and educational enrichment services; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF7DA7E6FAA5846A6BD126643FFA86022"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">helping students to improve their study skills.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8DFD94EA76848D690BE83B3CD23CE9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Project-based learning opportunities.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0660DC6D39F347B99524E45E37FE0861"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Individualized instruction and tracking of student progress that is aligned with in-school performance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7123DA88847F49DAA39DA1ACCFC1268E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>A community-based affiliate that receives a subgrant under this section shall collaborate with an institution of higher education to provide the services described in paragraph (2).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB677700F54746569D960D8C3030FEF2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H2443A09B71D34864A14DFA31774AF16C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit a report annually to the Committee on Education and the Workforce in the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions in the Senate on the progress that national and regional intermediaries and their community-based affiliates operating informal STEM learning programs have made toward achieving the goals in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7963E3B0796D4623B84BAF078EE97557"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National or regional intermediary report to the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A national or regional intermediary receiving a grant under this section shall submit a report annually to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including the progress that its community-based affiliates operating informal STEM learning programs have made toward achieving the goals in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE789FEF05FC74AB6A0546FE5F825458C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community-based affiliate report to its national or regional intermediary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community-based affiliate that receives a subgrant under this section shall submit a report annually to the national or regional intermediary that awarded such subgrant at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the intermediary may require, including the progress its informal STEM learning program has made toward achieving the goals in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H677C101FD7CC430D96F5EE60A57F7B35"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H85A025EDD7D3433F89E27EF9B2F940C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community-based affiliate</header><text>The term <term>community-based affiliate</term> means a community-based organization (as defined in section 9101) that is an affiliate of a national or regional intermediary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABB80A989BD74E638AE608364B2BC1D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Informal STEM learning education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>informal STEM learning education</quote> is education related to science that occurs in informal, out-of-school contexts, such as participating in structured afterschool programs and visiting science centers and engaging with the exhibits and programs offered at such centers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA15DCD97C5094A82AABCE6C1B7581D2D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National intermediary</header><text>The term <term>national intermediary</term> means a national private nonprofit organization that—</text> <subparagraph id="H482DA6B49DD147BFA53109EE3C8ED341"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a network comprised of community-based affiliates in not less than 50 regional communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63136388CA8743D8A4E8064F09C648EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has demonstrated expertise and effectiveness in overseeing programs to help middle school and secondary school students succeed, including programs to help such students become college-ready and career-ready; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D51FFA2F9924596AFAF4F82A7B70DCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has operated in not less than 25 States continuously for not less than 20 years.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97250FFCB4FD487B8BBE9EE33486123F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Project-based learning</header><text>The term <term>project-based learning</term> means learning through a broad project that includes instruction, substantive content, and reflection, with the goal that students who participate in the project will achieve a concrete goal or complete a project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H615A325EA96040D29ACF69B2AD50FA12"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regional intermediary</header><text>The term <term>regional intermediary</term> means a private nonprofit community-based organization that—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E6E47873D604C87A270AD8FDCA2C485"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a network comprised of community-based affiliates in a prescribed region; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC044EF29B152418AAA7D237B9F1F57E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has demonstrated expertise and effectiveness in conducting outreach and providing education activities to middle school and secondary school students.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B960414CBCE400CBDF8D07621E5C719"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section—</text> <paragraph id="HB62AF5DF31804FED9D22E43A71DE3936"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$20,000,000 for fiscal year 2016;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2021427BDB274A67832D559A6193FF19"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$30,000,000 for fiscal year 2017;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC759DD29B91B46B8A72D8F86CA143EFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$40,000,000 for fiscal year 2018; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14EF5C7A1C0041A89E705F3D4B6C2B0B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for fiscal year 2019.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

