<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBA994FE482B44BB69F57DC46429790E0" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 819 IH: To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to use the definitions in section 40125 of title 49, United States Code, in determining whether an unmanned aircraft conducting aeronautical research flights qualifies for public aircraft status under that section, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 819</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150209">February 9, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to use the definitions in section 40125 of title 49, United States Code, in determining whether an unmanned aircraft conducting aeronautical research flights qualifies for public aircraft status under that section, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HF03F8DBC36AE484D8155F8A0D1A9BD38" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB392AB2CD20F4857BD0234F1B44D7424" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Public aircraft operating status of unmanned aircraft used in aeronautical research flights; safety procedures for such flights</header> 
<subsection id="H83904F5937AA452BA6E364DF8B2145BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public aircraft operating status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether an unmanned aircraft used in the conduct of aeronautical research qualifies as a public aircraft under section 40125 of title 49, United States Code, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall—</text> <paragraph id="H04255745E2B7438490ABCBEEB7EF826D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of determining whether the aircraft is used for a commercial purpose, use only the definition given that term in subsection (a) of such section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63F20DF92E9247DFA4462C10439EDC2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for purposes of determining whether the aircraft, including airborne platforms and systems, is used for aeronautical research and platform-based research, include atmospheric and natural resources research, meteorological observation, and airborne astronomy as aeronautical research.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4EB4D820F5D44DAAAE18A4907C79FF43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures for beyond-Line-of-Sight operations</header> <paragraph id="H7176D0C0EB334446B05435796CA40751"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall develop and implement procedures for safe, beyond-line-of-sight operations in the national airspace system by unmanned aircraft conducting aeronautical research.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E48B84CD78345B8821D65C90A441A0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations for approval</header><text>In developing the procedures required by paragraph (1) relating to beyond-line-of-sight operations by unmanned aircraft described in that paragraph, the Administrator shall ensure that a decision to approve such an operation takes into consideration the safety of the entire operation, including whether any provisions required to be included in the certificate of authorization for the operation result in additional safety risk to any individual associated with the operation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFCE97724304D4DAC89C753FD58FB3D94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>unmanned aircraft</term> has the meaning given that term in section 331 of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/95">Public Law 112–95</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


