<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H296CC231FCDB4F64AB6D931603A56CA5" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1732 RH: Regulatory Integrity Protection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 66</calendar>
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1732</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 114–93]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150413">April 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001154">Mr. Shuster</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001150">Mrs. Miller of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000810">Mr. Woodall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001070">Mr. Hardy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20150427">April 27, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000373">Mr. Ashford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001057">Mr. Huelskamp</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000363">Mr. Kline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000458">Mr. Fincher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000051">Mr. Sanford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000689">Mr. Mica</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-desc><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20150427">April 27, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on April 13, 2015</action-instruction>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To preserve existing rights and responsibilities with respect to waters of the United States, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HPW00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HBE3F3AC63BC54338B93E67BC67CD544C">
<section commented="no" id="HC7DA209639304B98925A9D7DF21DAE55" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulatory Integrity Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H49B10D27C78F45D6A4F158CFDAC1189D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Withdrawal of existing proposed rule</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall withdraw the proposed rule described in the notice of proposed rule published in the Federal Register entitled <quote>Definition of <quote>Waters of the United States</quote> Under the Clean Water Act</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 22188 (April 21, 2014)) and any final rule based on such proposed rule (including RIN 2040–AF30).</text></section>
<section id="H4B996B283F9E4A2FA83D6F3AF187588B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Development of new proposed rule</header>
<subsection id="H33D3BAC238D942D6A818DA78D34620BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Army and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall develop a new proposed rule to define the term <quote>waters of the United States</quote> as used in the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8437D4D5DB784571962708061C0F9368"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of new proposed rule</header><text>In developing the new proposed rule under subsection (a), the Secretary and the Administrator shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H4C48778DE3B349BD836FDC7D86670251"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take into consideration the public comments received on—</text> <subparagraph id="H72EC6EEDB58749D3A3F0118D07171D26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposed rule referred to in section 2;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0D37437F93D64BECAE90B612CBA6FCE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the accompanying economic analysis of the proposed rule entitled <quote>Economic Analysis of Proposed Revised Definition of Waters of the United States</quote> (dated March 2014); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42E74F2E332641BFBB2833BB09B4AC35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the report entitled <quote>Connectivity of Streams &amp; Wetlands to Downstream Waters: A Review &amp; Synthesis of Scientific Evidence</quote> (EPA/600/R–14/475F; dated January 2015);</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4D5539B63AFC4D8CBBE5515203170605"><enum>(2)</enum><text>jointly consult with and solicit advice and recommendations from representative State and local officials, stakeholders, and other interested parties on how to define the term <quote>waters of the United States</quote> as used in the Federal Water Pollution Control Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAEC7A599FC84E04A52B550EAEED9919"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prepare a regulatory proposal that will, consistent with applicable rulings of the United States Supreme Court, specifically identify those waters covered under, and those waters not covered under, the Federal Water Pollution Control Act—</text>
<subparagraph id="H11357299E068430B848C57C658CC88ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>taking into consideration—</text> <clause id="H05BD81E4CD1845DFAAB328684E1D6FF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the public comments referred to in paragraph (1); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HF01B3FE6F5FD4BBF83D1A455FA4ED261"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the advice and recommendations made by the State and local officials, stakeholders, and other interested parties consulted under this section; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H681E232001F7452D8990F359402C3E40"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporating the areas and issues where consensus was reached with the parties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1583771D119340F798B869A7C9F4A5C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federalism consultation requirements</header><text>As part of consulting with and soliciting advice and recommendations from State and local officials under subsection (b), the Secretary and the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2D0936F7BC2544BCB72DCD239649EA8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to reach consensus with the State and local officials on how to define the term <quote>waters of the United States</quote> as used in the Federal Water Pollution Control Act;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H637528DA765A46B5B2839B2B394CEB7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide the State and local officials with notice and an opportunity to participate in the consultation process under subsection (b);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2A707DD3E61408E988A216213DF5E18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult with State and local officials that represent a broad cross-section of regional, economic, policy, and geographic perspectives in the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H098E090BE3464A32A1F28F2A871A4172"><enum>(4)</enum><text>emphasize the importance of collaboration with and among the State and local officials;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC5129F3C2AB4006B803448F5812CECB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>allow for meaningful and timely input by the State and local officials;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5ACAAA1E1DA542FCB26FECD966D6DE9E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognize, preserve, and protect the primary rights and responsibilities of the States to protect water quality under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and to plan and control the development and use of land and water resources in the States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H723A45B3B5294AC68B76B3926D8968ED"><enum>(7)</enum><text>protect the authorities of State and local governments and rights of private property owners over natural and manmade water features, including the continued recognition of Federal deference to State primacy in the development of water law, the governance of water rights, and the establishment of the legal system by which States mediate disputes over water use;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFD05754F806F4E1D99C1DC04F74528FF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>incorporate the advice and recommendations of the State and local officials regarding matters involving differences in State and local geography, hydrology, climate, legal frameworks, economies, priorities, and needs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H091C4E2F4F0C4617A8DF184690C222F8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure transparency in the consultation process, including promptly making accessible to the public all communications, records, and other documents of all meetings that are part of the consultation process.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD8508B5888A64F55BF3AF480B6DD631A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Stakeholder consultation requirements</header><text>As part of consulting with and soliciting recommendations from stakeholders and other interested parties under subsection (b), the Secretary and the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H342F78F8DC5E4AE794B2964639EA82DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify representatives of public and private stakeholders and other interested parties, including small entities (as defined in section 601 of title 5, United States Code), representing a broad cross-section of regional, economic, and geographic perspectives in the United States, which could potentially be affected, directly or indirectly, by the new proposed rule under subsection (a), for the purpose of obtaining advice and recommendations from those representatives about the potential adverse impacts of the new proposed rule and means for reducing such impacts in the new proposed rule; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H06BD3AA9318F46C28637186499A48773"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure transparency in the consultation process, including promptly making accessible to the public all communications, records, and other documents of all meetings that are part of the consultation process.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC1DE13494A074EACB8413761ABC338FD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Timing of federalism and stakeholder consultation</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Administrator shall initiate consultations with State and local officials, stakeholders, and other interested parties under subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF60687405EB34B87AE5D52F1878400DB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall prepare a report that—</text> <paragraph id="H2206EA71F5FF4F9AB215F427049C616C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies and responds to each of the public comments filed on—</text>
<subparagraph id="H30A948049A0B4E8983287EF9A52156AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposed rule referred to in section 2;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83F197B3471542E4B991AA8670CED918"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the accompanying economic analysis of the proposed rule entitled <quote>Economic Analysis of Proposed Revised Definition of Waters of the United States</quote> (dated March 2014); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7B443E5278284784894A870A5CC38DAE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the report entitled <quote>Connectivity of Streams &amp; Wetlands to Downstream Waters: A Review &amp; Synthesis of Scientific Evidence</quote> (EPA/600/R–14/475F; dated January 2015);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0651AA38762645B0B3E74788FF2AF43D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides a detailed explanation of how the new proposed rule under subsection (a) addresses the public comments referred to in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A948D3648DD484CA38C36093C66A4E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describes in detail—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C8582F988AA4FE08DCA6C2CC7CCDAC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the advice and recommendations obtained from the State and local officials consulted under this section;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3A56A83AB843498380BE3EDCDDF037BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the areas and issues where consensus was reached with the State and local officials consulted under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H94D047AE188449F0BC7279CE372A47C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the areas and issues of continuing disagreement that resulted in the failure to reach consensus; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B41893239FE4000A51339870B2ECD63"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the reasons for the continuing disagreements;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H888F17D7ED21459EBFCDC61CE5702D50"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides a detailed explanation of how the new proposed rule addresses the advice and recommendations provided by the State and local officials consulted under this section, including the areas and issues where consensus was reached with the State and local officials;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA65CF2BAD0644183AEC41DB75B89679C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>describes in detail—</text> <subparagraph id="H963BC55A3FD345A1BA67238DE69642BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the advice and recommendations obtained from the stakeholders and other interested parties, including small entities, consulted under this section about the potential adverse impacts of the new proposed rule and means for reducing such impacts in the new proposed rule; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H69CB9F5DEC444170B794236CAF47B643"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the new proposed rule addresses such advice and recommendations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAE96C2A93494641A0F3D79530486DD3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provides a detailed explanation of how the new proposed rule—</text>
<subparagraph id="H88DA4C17466748CFB7A580275CA06563"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognizes, preserves, and protects the primary rights and responsibilities of the States to protect water quality and to plan and control the development and use of land and water resources in the States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H971A7EEAC8B649D4BC338005E661028F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is consistent with the applicable rulings of the United States Supreme Court regarding the scope of waters to be covered under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF4C77CD44803496AAEFA07F93D7D8E6C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provides comprehensive regulatory and economic impact analyses, utilizing the latest data and other information, on how definitional changes in the new proposed rule will impact, directly or indirectly—</text> <subparagraph id="HB03EECA67D9F4F95B360A693D5BA61FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each program under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act for Federal, State, and local government agencies; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H623CF56FAFD74931A4344666ADCBF4A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public and private stakeholders and other interested parties, including small entities, regulated under each such program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBC70792EEE224935A1C828B129E7A530"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Publication</header> <paragraph id="HC090F0AEF3314E0BB68D6829AE21530E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal Register notice</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the completion of consultations with and solicitation of recommendations from State and local officials, stakeholders, and other interested parties under subsection (b), the Secretary and the Administrator shall publish for comment in the Federal Register—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEC1BED8B615847AA8014EF64EF6040E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the new proposed rule under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H790D2EC0CF2742A8AF12174455EECA49"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the areas and issues where consensus was reached with the State and local officials consulted under this section; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7B807658B9D44CC093BEB1DF63F5EFD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the report described in subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C78B9C06F354F98923EA510D67E12D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration of review</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall provide not fewer than 180 days for the public to review and comment on—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCF87932BFF194030939BA232C5B7E3DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the new proposed rule under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DEB78936EDC44239C2964F488978548"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the accompanying economic analysis for the new proposed rule; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8D4678B7F5534DD7B5D1BF8398D058D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the report described in subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCF8E115A45CF41318A14E834D685D66C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Procedural requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>) shall apply to the development and review of the new proposed rule under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HCAC6A65A498943A090FE021DF8518D85"><enum>(i)</enum><header>State and local officials defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>State and local officials</quote> means elected or professional State and local government officials or their representative regional or national organizations.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20150427">April 27, 2015</action-date> <action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

