<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87A43575E86B441A994499E80998D8FB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2810 IH: Stay in Place, Cut the Waste Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2810</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150617">June 17, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for a review of efforts to reduce Federal agency travel expenses through the use of video conferencing and a plan to achieve additional reductions in such expenses through the use of video conferencing, to implement such plan through rescissions of appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD6BDEE53A8234DF49263D7DCB5D8EFC4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD6B9110D10964B97A3C9A13823F2C6B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stay in Place, Cut the Waste Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE8FE2A8BEA18496F847BFD7D8903AD8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAF4C1807BA50476FA3A7C70930C7E93B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government spends billions of dollars per year on travel to conferences, training programs, business meetings, court and administrative hearings, and other related activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F7FF34A788E449DAB404A993D1A333E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On November 9, 2011, President Barack Obama issued Executive Order 13589 (76 Fed. Reg. 70863; relating to promoting efficient spending). Section 2 of such Executive order directs the head of each executive department or agency to establish a plan for fiscal year 2013 to reduce the combined expenses associated with a variety of activities, including travel, by not less than 20 percent below fiscal year 2010 levels.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B7E8E010480483D8DB1FA5E17121586"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 3 of Executive Order 13589 addresses travel spending and provides, in part, for the use of video conferencing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H393FBCD740EA4962894ED28409896C07"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In May 2012, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget instructed the heads of executive departments and agencies to reduce their travel budgets in fiscal year 2013 to 30 percent below fiscal year 2010 levels.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27AF2289F2F84E22958D3C42A042C244"><enum>(5)</enum><text>While the Administration has made efforts to utilize video conferencing and reduce travel expenses, such practices are still a largely untapped means of saving taxpayer dollars.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74FBD242C0B6410AA57034A68A3BFE38"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Telework Enhancement Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/292">Public Law 111–292</external-xref>) requires the head of each executive agency to establish a policy under which eligible employees of such agency may be authorized to telework.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE399F1280359402AA5E368945D8DA2B4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The video conferencing industry has shifted from a hardware-based model to a browser-based model, leading to reduced expenses and increased efficiency in a system that is able to meet the needs in daily commerce for full-featured conferencing using off-the-shelf equipment present in most every Government office, business, and home.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5575B4D78F744637B0661545CFE8C8D5"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Video conferencing can be used by Federal employees instead of or in addition to telephones and email to enhance communication and problem solving, to reduce associated carbon footprints, to facilitate staff training and interagency meetings, and to increase employee productivity, thereby helping shorten project timelines, promote efficiency, improve collaboration among coworkers across the country, and improve work-life balance.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H392F3570DC6D43959B566D102AD79CED"><enum>3.</enum><header>Review, plan, and report on using video conferencing to reduce Federal agency travel expenses</header> 
<subsection id="HC64D9B2A802E411CA7B748B9D8EE64A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall review the extent to which Federal agencies have reduced travel expenses by the use of video conferencing pursuant to Executive Order 13589 (76 Fed. Reg. 70863; relating to promoting efficient spending) and OMB Memorandum 12–12–12.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCAD9A7B195C04CB3994CE66B33A8E8DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall develop a plan for fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 2019 to use video conferencing to achieve the lesser of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7E386FF536B64244B7348F5324BD9B7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a 50 percent reduction in Federal agency travel expenses below fiscal year 2015 levels; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF52A1286E96C4A44A350BCEA9E983810"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the greatest reduction in such expenses the Director considers feasible.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDE989305B0AD499A90B04DF3EFBC8747"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the review required by subsection (a) and the plan required by subsection (b).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H92C23CB306F8478BAE99D98D35B44231"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation of plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the amounts made available to Federal agencies to fund travel expenses for fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 2019, the Director shall rescind the amounts that are proposed for reduction by the plan developed under section 3(b).</text></section> 
<section id="HBE4CE4C5CF2E4593A0172E69F14DEB5C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H3552FFEE42334BCB801436C3BB390CF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC28A5557B49A4E379BBF20F8B1E20FB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <quote>Federal agency</quote> means any agency listed in section 901(b) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32DED23D8C784250A3B00CF127F5E725"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>travel expenses</quote> means the total amount a Federal agency pays or reimburses under subchapter I or subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


