<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H112DD9B3A6574B0EBE0864BCACEC0BAE" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1194 IH: Family Engagement in Education Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1194</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150302">March 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To strengthen families’ engagement in the education of their children.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC8148E9C457641B4801F8C78185331C3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF6BADA73CFFF497D9C2C8BCD9A17E94C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family Engagement in Education Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4D65E8382C7D4420BDFD8C0CFFE617C5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc>
<toc-entry idref="HF6BADA73CFFF497D9C2C8BCD9A17E94C" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H4D65E8382C7D4420BDFD8C0CFFE617C5" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H3F021D70F8F44D4C9F57017E5064F573" level="section">Sec. 3. Findings; purpose.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H016221711F2342BB873EC4F9AB60DE79" level="section">Sec. 4. Amendment references.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H10DDD495323D4CE1828CB54BA9F36E2B" level="section">Sec. 5. Family engagement in education.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE1255386ACF444A7868876AE1699131D" level="section">Sec. 6. State plans.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H2990C3DE05DA443BABDAE52096F7BF91" level="section">Sec. 7. Local educational agency plans.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H4F5E8622B4E9426D824E813BC93B326F" level="section">Sec. 8. Family engagement in education policy.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H084469550BBE411493B189578D7F46EE" level="section">Sec. 9. Prevention and intervention programs for children and youth who are neglected, delinquent, or at risk.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H77DF3E904F0D4C02BFAFB89487D3D067" level="section">Sec. 10. Research and evaluation for family engagement in education.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H53DCA6E7CE3E4BC3AA10F4B91639E6FE" level="section">Sec. 11. High-quality teachers and principals.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H2162CC41E10E4A7DA2C783E4E4807A1B" level="section">Sec. 12. Definitions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H14D9B55503E84CF08DB9B858D573B6C6" level="section">Sec. 13. Repeal of Parental Assistance and Local Family Information Centers.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HC831435D439B4F7CAF1F2CF2254FFA7A" level="section">Sec. 14. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HBEC975F4EF3D44A199CF5463096FF515" level="section">Sec. 15. Government Accountability Office study and report.</toc-entry></toc></section>
<section id="H3F021D70F8F44D4C9F57017E5064F573"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header>
<subsection id="H0DB33C38C7834DD68CBF12C0FD521B4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD7ACA9DC39ED47B1AF29B78FB0A130FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Family engagement in a child's education raises student achievement, improves behavior and attendance, decreases drop-out rates, and improves the emotional and physical well-being of children.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA8B35E8A1E7144DC908535A805C3AAC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Families are critical determinants of children's school readiness as well as of students' decision to pursue higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5F0E467DEB04C54BFD327993C302E74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Effective family engagement is a great equalizer for students, contributing to their increased academic achievement, regardless of parents' education level, ethnicity, or socioeconomic background.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7B8BBC135D3F414CA4578C0E8070A3A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Research on school improvement has identified meaningful partnerships with families and communities as 1 of 5 critical ingredients necessary to turnaround chronically low-performing schools.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06E3162081DE48F9B8982A066B7A66C4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Positive benefits for children, youth, families, and schools are maximized through effective family engagement that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE19D8B47C40946E3ACB6EF2BB1B460D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a shared responsibility in which schools and other community agencies and organizations are committed to reaching out to engage families in meaningful ways and families are committed to actively supporting their children's learning and development;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0E6DBC98FAF4721B9C34CB70EEFBE56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is continuous across a child's life from birth to young adulthood; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAB654DA982F349C6B02D38CA667879FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reinforces learning that takes place in all settings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H302A4AB0DBC2482ABCA39F3B2888AAA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to increase student success and foster school improvement by strengthening families’ engagement in the education of their children.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H016221711F2342BB873EC4F9AB60DE79"><enum>4.</enum><header>Amendment references</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> <section id="H10DDD495323D4CE1828CB54BA9F36E2B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Family engagement in education</header> <subsection id="H1C34B27C52EC454C8910887865940673"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Family engagement and responsibility fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding after section 1004 the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76ED1100D5B148F7ADF2D93645792711" style="OLC">
<section id="HF3EEAFD7043C4E4C8A68A72D34D61204"><enum>1005.</enum><header>Family engagement and responsibility fund</header>
<subsection id="H27B34707830A40769C24AC6AD0E6E9CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State educational agency shall reserve not less than 0.3 percent and not more than 1 percent of such agency's allocated funds under section 1122 for each fiscal year for use as provided in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8281675EDFB345AB9D97F2BBE6D04A00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of reserved funds</header><text>From the amounts reserved for each fiscal year under subsection (a), each State educational agency—</text>
<paragraph id="H8B523FA2D56041D18C2B8362EE54C493"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall establish a Statewide Family Engagement Center under section 1006;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4AC3D79091E4BCEBD4C2DF5984A5B9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall establish at least 1 Local Family Engagement Center under section 1007; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H06F77BD33B824410A678D20CDAC758C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may allocate any funds remaining after carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2) for building State educational agency capacity for family engagement activities under section 1008.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H87855846BA48452CA5CA0789AB919D87"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>If a State's allocation under section 1122 for a fiscal year is less than $60,000,000, and such State determines that such allocation is insufficient to establish a center of sufficient size and scope to meet the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b), such State may use its allocation for activities under section 1008.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HAACF2BBE158B487B890AFD73603117D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statewide Family Engagement Centers Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding after section 1005, as added by subsection (a), the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5810C50D11314F3EBF2BD22E9A9080D0" style="OLC"> <section id="HA844A95AD9094309B49DD104BE5937C0"><enum>1006.</enum><header>Statewide Family Engagement Centers</header> <subsection id="H4F53F0EFE118464193A42567B7F41839"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>From the funds reserved under section 1005, each State shall award a grant or contract to a statewide nonprofit organization to establish a Statewide Family Engagement Center to provide comprehensive training, technical assistance, and capacity-building to local educational agencies, organizations that support family-school partnerships, and other organizations that carry out parent education and family engagement in education programs.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF4CFEA1C534C45B09EB46C4FC3772F3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header>
<paragraph id="HFD493734DCE543DB96FE27A29999F189"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each statewide nonprofit organization that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the State at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the State may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3183DCB1E0642E78E014A83098815AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H26C204E4E38F403586C038B251017FD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the applicant's approach to family engagement in education, including the use of strength-based strategies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31412C2AAB1546E4AF84365163A893AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the applicant's plan for improving statewide capacity for family engagement in education, that includes—</text>
<clause id="H6E3CF722DFAB4B06B21B4C485313070A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>management capacity and governance;</text></clause> <clause id="H6B2A7B69EF094DEAB05033B905403A80"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>statewide leadership;</text></clause>
<clause id="H43FE36A1CB504E47BF91F284388E783B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>systemic services for family engagement in education;</text></clause> <clause id="H04D6201A8AB74998A9DDEA6B87F46379"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>capacity-building for local educational agencies, and schools served under this title; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HFD6A15F4D57441859B959BE49C00AB82"><enum>(v)</enum><text>student learning and school improvement.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FF8B243C6554323840FD3AB4BB78937"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the applicant's experience in providing training, information, and support to local educational agencies, schools, and nonprofit organizations on family engagement in education policies and practices that are effective for low-income parents and families, limited English proficient individuals, minorities, parents of students with disabilities, parents of homeless students, foster parents and students, parents of migrant students, and parents of Indian and Native Hawaiian students, where applicable.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC0EAC4B6BE24439DB350D7322510D4E9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assurance that the Statewide Family Engagement Center will—</text> <clause id="H672E144A200B46FCA3F9B9E4CCD665E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be governed by a board of directors, the membership of which includes parents of school-aged children;</text></clause>
<clause id="H416086311E6A4164BCFB17602E87E9C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have a process for outreach and consultation with—</text> <subclause id="HF18FA96083A94561B59CBFC9EFB58F8C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>parents of children from birth through young adulthood;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HF63D752FAFB9482F8C507FF1DB97F34F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>representatives of the State parent-teacher association;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD8D39671F475460FB6850A1AF9A3E45D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>representatives of education professionals with expertise in improving services for disadvantaged children;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HA6DCCC2A134F4491B7FCAF254A4CD2A6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>representatives of local elementary schools and secondary schools, including students, disadvantaged youth, and representatives from local youth organizations; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H72F56089B8334D0F95703D63133F879D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>representatives of a State educational agency, a local educational agency, and an Indian tribe or organization;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H759D411486BA4DED999A50376C94CF91"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>operate a center of sufficient size, scope, and quality to ensure that the center is adequate to serve the State educational agency, local educational agencies, and community-based organizations;</text></clause> <clause id="HEE676DB2E0DA46FEA9272F6DD239C166"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>serve urban, suburban, and rural local educational agencies and schools;</text></clause>
<clause id="H33EA2EED295F4032BE4831F536838869"><enum>(v)</enum><text>work with—</text> <subclause id="H11111C56CADA426DA9BA3CD749EB1CA5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the State educational agency, local educational agencies (including local educational agencies receiving funds under section 7113), and schools;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H36E259C161F74687ADF7A4D41FC69C5E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Local Family Engagement Centers assisted under section 1007;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0D3E941583AF4E1A9B4B90FBAFD21C6B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>parent training and information centers and community parent resource centers assisted under sections 671 and 672 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HB6EA9914AA854136B40A23D012AB5AE9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other organizations and agencies;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC4C7160A29E840CABB4891B60A7E0EAB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>use not less than 20 percent of the funds received under this section in each fiscal year to establish or expand technical assistance for evidence-based early childhood parent education programs that focus on successful transition to school;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF84B7CA4E40947E589481F5E60521381"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>provide assistance to the State educational agency, local educational agencies, Indian tribes and organizations, and community-based organizations that support family members in areas such as assistance in understanding State and local standards and measures of student and school academic achievement and strategies for supporting school academic achievement;</text></clause> <clause id="H91F17F5876A64B8BA2C7B42CD86BFECA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>work with the State educational agency, local educational agencies, Indian tribes and organizations, and schools to determine parental needs and the best means for delivery of services to address such needs; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HD6F4EC3421954597BC019D02A6925AC3"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>meet the requirements for matching funds under subsection (d).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H02274D301F1C4454AD523FF6EF94AB0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A statewide nonprofit organization that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to provide training, technical assistance, and capacity-building in coordination with the State educational agency, local educational agencies, Indian tribes and organizations, and organizations that support family-school partnerships to—</text>
<paragraph id="H374E4E3E9FFD4A3AB522198DBA0EB64C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist parents in participating effectively in their children's education and to help their children meet State and local standards, such as assisting parents—</text> <subparagraph id="HB6BC270B91974F55A82754FA77A97249"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to engage in activities that will improve student academic achievement, including understanding how they can support learning in the classroom with activities at home and in afterschool and extracurricular programs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H68BA35491C034FB89C13430ED5E3394B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to communicate effectively with their children, teachers, principals, counselors, administrators, and other school personnel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC533F69E65D748EAA6FE3AE33789DA39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to become active participants in the development, implementation, and review of school-parent compacts, family engagement in education policies, and school planning and improvement;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4484D86C057B489B972A172E9A4FB6AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to participate in the design and provision of assistance to students who are not making adequate academic progress;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H200D569A559D4C75A7C1CFA4B94446A4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to participate in State and local decisionmaking;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H054376052951435BAC9E1FB71916EE0E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to train other parents; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0B299A80E134285895F9524CD36AA9F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to help the parents learn and use technology applied in their children's education;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H54A39D46D58D403C9FFEEC340F35A53A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist the State educational agency in developing and implementing a statewide family engagement in education policy and systemic initiatives that will provide for a continuum of services to remove barriers for family engagement in education and support school reform efforts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0DA1E7C04DE4A9EB4C9013A216121E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assist in the development, implementation, and assessment of family engagement in education policies and plans under sections 1112 and 1118; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H12C519D6D81B413483332E1957C677D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supplement the family engagement activities under section 7115 and coordinate with the Bureau of Indian Education and Indian tribes and organizations to improve family engagement in education policies and programs, where applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9990052CCB184A7E891E5EB452772274"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Matching funds for grant renewal</header><text>For each fiscal year after the first fiscal year for which a statewide nonprofit organization receives a grant under this section, the organization shall demonstrate in the application that a portion of the services provided by the organization, as determined by the State, is supported through non-Federal contributions, which may be in cash or in-kind.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6E169A72F75B4464912976075C3F344A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Submission of information</header><text>Each statewide nonprofit organization that receives a grant under this section shall submit to the State, on an annual basis, information on the activities it has carried out using grant funds received under this section, including reporting on metrics developed under section 1505 and reporting on the recommendations provided by the special advisory committee and the actions taken in response to such recommendations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEAC3987A333347E38D487DB19EEE4F05"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a Statewide Family Engagement Center from—</text>
<paragraph id="H18429DA588CD41D9867464BDB06ACB5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>having its employees or agents meet with a parent at a site that is not on school grounds; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2008E3632D9496BA1EE521BEF44C933"><enum>(2)</enum><text>working with another agency that serves children.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF09242082B4347528430C51770C699F7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Parental rights</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HE846C274A89242958264585219E861D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>no person (including a parent who educates a child at home, a public school parent, or a private school parent) shall be required to participate in any program of parent education or developmental screening under this section; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD49B96C1DCA140E9A5E635F49582A3C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no program or center assisted under this section shall take any action that infringes in any manner on the right of a parent to direct the education of their children.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H040D7A1FD6A0480185A209189648C7AA"><enum>1007.</enum><header>Local Family Engagement Centers Program</header> <subsection id="H7F46013C52FE46468BA4F0F24E335649"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to establish and operate Local Family Engagement Centers and to evaluate the usefulness and effectiveness of innovative approaches demonstrated by these centers in engaging families in their children’s education by providing training, services, supports, and opportunities that meet families' needs and remove barriers to their engagement in their children’s education to improve student achievement.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5666FEC8111041E2ABDF87821E1E84AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>From the funds reserved to carry out this section under section 1005(b)(2), a State educational agency shall award grants or enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with eligible entities to establish and operate Local Family Engagement Centers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4B57A911B02948C69B7AB64172D613CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this section, the State shall give priority to eligible entities that propose to serve communities with the greatest need, as determined by the State.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC07AB6CF5127432D9D97CBEB993020F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible Entity</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means a private, nonprofit organization or Indian tribe or organization that—</text> <paragraph id="H588D33FBA1F84F28BCA33860B8DAB028"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a demonstrated record of working with low-income parents and families in the community;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFCAA506AE01946B998C45F07F455D26B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is located in a community with elementary schools and secondary schools that receive funds under part A and is accessible to families of students in those schools; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14FA2FC2B3574417B0F3D030E2FE1A60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is partnering with 1 or more local educational agencies or 1 or more schools that receive funds under part A.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA597377C6ED548D0ACA25BACFB43AC58"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application for grants</header><text>To receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the State educational agency may require, including—</text> <paragraph id="H916C5CB7C69E49F890A9F7926AAC7B83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the entity's approach on family engagement in education, including its use of strength-based strategies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H742E4C510E7D423AAE4D8A42438FC8BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information demonstrating that the applicant meets the definition of an eligible entity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0218B2D7FBB41378ED0492784355CF5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information that the applicant has the capacity to structure and operate a center of sufficient scope and quality adequate to serve the needs of the local area in which it is located;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A4D48F826BB426EBCA67BFF6C75292F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the entity’s experience in providing training, services, and support to low-income parents and families, English language learners, minorities, parents of students with disabilities, parents of homeless students, foster parents, parents of Indian and Native Hawaiian students, and parents of migrant students;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DBDCF438FEB4881AF82F02488B84F48"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of the collaboration with the local educational agency or school personnel in the area to be served by the center;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H5237CAD4B6944160A47A166AAB89BA99"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a description of the steering committee, a majority of whose members are parents of students in schools that receive funds under part A, who will be targeted for services by the Local Family Engagement Center, that will direct and implement the activities of the Local Family Engagement Center;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4927C38E6D284F928E89467B272B84B1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of how the entity will coordinate its efforts with the Statewide Family Engagement Center;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H36EDD776434A4A97B9F79ABDD99BB4E0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>information that the applicant is capable of meeting milestones or deadlines as the State educational agency may prescribe; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33FE706ABDCD4F98B2B5CEF34325A1BB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>such other information as the State educational agency determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC7CF72E9F2B34689BDCDF8D2433CEC95"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall establish and operate a Local Family Engagement Center and use the grant funds to provide training, services, and supports to engage families in their children’s education and to build the school-family partnerships necessary to ensure that all children are on track to graduate from high school ready for college and careers, such as through—</text> <paragraph id="HFFBB66DB500740F586757DC3F325ECA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assisting parents and families in understanding how they can improve student achievement, including how to access ongoing student performance data and related information to support learning in the classroom with activities at home, and in afterschool and extracurricular activities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9AE4787BEEE24D2EA1BECAF75B7C92A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assisting parents and families in supporting on-time graduation, including understanding early warning indicators that a student is at risk of not graduating on time;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE17CA3CA9BAB45278BC55AB5D1F3373D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assisting parents and families in understanding how they can prepare their children academically, socially, and financially for postsecondary education, including early awareness of the availability of student financial assistance and career and technical education opportunities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF8BA05D5C994B878B7C251671D72548"><enum>(4)</enum><text>training parents and families on effective ongoing communication with their children, teachers, principals, counselors, administrators, and other school personnel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDF1A13311E641EBBE11F419195834FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing direct services to families, such as home visitation, family literacy programs, and health and behavioral health services to meet the needs of families and remove barriers for engaging in the education of their children;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAEBE268F54ED446185416196970454E3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>providing advocacy services to ensure that families can fully participate in their children’s education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4FE22944B074349B3EF74F07BC66CF2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>providing supports such as transportation, childcare, and meals to facilitate family engagement in education in programs implemented or assisted by the Center; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5CBCE7323A7A422F8F4819B61A0B1814"><enum>(8)</enum><text>improving the coordination, availability, and effectiveness of integrated services and comprehensive supports for children and families.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9DC51B03B29B418DAB567BF3F476B064"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation and annual report</header><text>A State educational agency shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H2FB19F4F4E4D4887A636272914849082"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of the grants funded under this section and section 1006; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA573D4F1EDF410DAE2BBA1DCF7D0AFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue an annual report on the implementation of such grants, describing any practices the State determines to be most effective or innovative for fulfilling the purposes of the Local Family Engagement Centers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H05E862EA5C114E44A3015B61E75C487E"><enum>1008.</enum><header>State educational agency capacity for family engagement activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each State may use funds reserved under section 1005(b)(3) to support the development and implementation of the statewide family engagement in education plan described in section 1111(d) through activities such as—</text> <paragraph id="HD69216ADF82C45178367DEC1737C7324"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting an office or staff positions within the agency dedicated to family engagement in education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB2E9585734D64844B7D9D791CCE0F56B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carrying out the State’s responsibilities under sections 1006 and 1007;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF24DB8B585814E9B905F82DEDA1EFC0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>developing and implementing a statewide data collection and evaluation system on family engagement in education metrics to identify schools that would benefit from training and support related to family engagement in education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27CD970B15F94E48B18DD533D642C0E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reviewing local educational agencies’ family engagement in education policies and practices as provided by sections 1112(b)(1)(P) and 1118(i), and evaluating the use of funds under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FA3AC45A52F4888BB667B77E7D6D9DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordinating technical assistance and support to local educational agencies, including local educational agencies receiving funds under section 7113, with schools that would benefit from training and support related to family engagement in education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD8C5FBBE377456CB769524D10277DA8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>developing curricula for professional development for teachers, principals, school librarians, and other school leaders on improving family engagement in education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09B09DF2F11C49FF86A88B667E5A5017"><enum>(7)</enum><text>developing standards and curricula for family engagement in education in partnership with teacher and principal preparation programs; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2FA84B9CACD4BAFB18ECF3E9CFF53C8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>coordinating statewide services related to early education, higher education, child health and welfare, after-school programs, community service-learning programs, and other programs to develop coordinated family engagement in education policies, practices, and services.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC664D51B3C9148DFBAC5C6F0E0054A1D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1004 the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HFD2254B24530430295474747559CB9F2" style="OLC">
<toc>
<toc-entry idref="HF3EEAFD7043C4E4C8A68A72D34D61204" level="section">Sec. 1005. Family engagement and responsibility fund.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 1006. Statewide Family Engagement Centers.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H040D7A1FD6A0480185A209189648C7AA" level="section">Sec. 1007. Local Family Engagement Centers Program.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1008. State educational agency capacity for family engagement activities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="HE1255386ACF444A7868876AE1699131D"><enum>6.</enum><header>State plans</header>
<subsection id="HD98ADD6D11294C89A88B3AEC96C3C798"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1111(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EF5AFAA3BF5443FBCB6750BC6F3A63C" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H331784071B164F7781BF1CBFD85E0A1B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Family engagement</header><text>Each State plan shall include a plan for strengthening family engagement in education. Each such plan shall, at a minimum, include—</text>
<paragraph id="H6F05DFB4ABEC47CF94F60013DB69CDE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the State's criteria and schedule for review and approval of local educational agency family engagement in education policies and practices pursuant to sections 1112(e)(3) and 1118(i);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB244ADB26EBA48AD98B75C1EE39504E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the State's system and process for assessing local educational agency implementation of section 1118 responsibilities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65C8DFC0EA0D465EBCA4226207E05E3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the State's criteria for identifying local educational agencies that would benefit from training and support related to family engagement in education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30A6BE7005CA4908A04A49D7C48F4B99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the State's statewide system of technical assistance and support for local educational agencies and schools on family engagement in education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H077875E43F40455CA5B2357CF254C68E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assurance that the State will, when applicable, refer to the Statewide Family Engagement Center and the applicable Local Family Engagement Center those local educational agencies that would benefit from training and support related to family engagement in education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4F37FE522A147CEBA9DAF67097E16EE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an assurance that the State will communicate with Indian tribes and organizations and Native Hawaiian organizations to improve implementation of family engagement in education programs and services for parents of Indian and Native Hawaiian students;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H516C61B09BD8470886BF82F99B85F1C6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a plan for using funds reserved under section 1005; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39D6011D3FDE4A6FB4E5971B83048CEC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of the relationship, as applicable, between the State educational agency and Statewide and Local Family Engagement Centers, parent training and information centers, and community parent resource centers in the State established under sections 671 and 672 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H9545A126D0084F339529887C45FCD6C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header>
<paragraph id="HA9E6C498DEFB40F1A0B1165A3AAC4A3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual State report</header><text>Section 1111(h)(4) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(h)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H9AE82BAA44784397B54217ABC649F11B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H29F43ADDED1647058D25BCC15802FF51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2029895A48934535B6B4F8EBBAECE3AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8365366F6984426785636BF5290DE350" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H96B446C854644A77BD15FB0CAB4B2837"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the number of schools and the name of each school that would benefit from training and support related to family engagement in education, the reason why such school was so identified, and the measures taken to address the need for training and support; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4698F1053FF745959E60D75F8C962D86"><enum>(I)</enum><text>information on the State educational agency's family engagement in education programs and activities.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H167A4CF4C5DF4224810F4FD596F50D1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>Section 1111(j) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(j)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>the development and implementation of policies and procedures for family engagement in education,</quote> after <quote>reliable,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H2990C3DE05DA443BABDAE52096F7BF91"><enum>7.</enum><header>Local educational agency plans</header> <subsection id="HE72357AE7B2742EFABDEAAE8510F4F7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1112(b)(1)(P) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6312">20 U.S.C. 6312(b)(1)(P)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62A1FD572848497DAA913D1A94987FEC" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="HB644F0F9C70E422788422B33D523B815"><enum>(P)</enum><text>a description of the strategy the local educational agency will use to implement and assess family engagement in education under section 1118;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H2E60E4A1687D40CABCAB1728D7E72DD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Engagement in developing plans</header><text>Section 1112(b)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6312">20 U.S.C. 6312(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HE0B6A54317F14C1687E61E013CE870D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (Q) as subparagraph (S); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H371B5DF18EE24BDAB76953F1F45F071F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (P) the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CA09DD17A6146858B0F8D0E454BFE61" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H0AEC39251CB4489A95665691D51DCD44"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>a description of how the local educational agency will engage families in the development, implementation, and assessment of local educational agency plans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60280D84604A4721BFBC663EDA211B6F"><enum>(R)</enum><text>a description of how the local education agency will improve teacher and principal knowledge and skills in effectively engaging parents in their children’s education; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H4F5E8622B4E9426D824E813BC93B326F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Family engagement in education policy</header>
<subsection id="HBECEC4482E1E44C3A34CFE4244271791"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Local educational agency development of policies and practices</header><text>Section 1118 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6318">20 U.S.C. 6318</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9EBC9C9884DC4A6C93F545DFEBF39769"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (a) through (h) as subsections (b) through (i), respectively; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A6998EA5A574FEEA13EFCBE54559446"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before subsection (b), as redesignated by paragraph (1), the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03CD0C6492F24B88A9CFC24B795F70A8" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H2468EC47117D4DB485EA6A1EA2953B06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each local educational agency and each school receiving funds under this part shall develop policies and practices for family engagement in education that meet the following principles and standards for family-school partnerships:</text>
<paragraph id="HA0A00121EE1A48AB936D75081BA6FB40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Welcome all families to be active participants in the life of the school, so that they feel valued and connected to each other, school staff, and what students are learning in class.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE552DE81A324369A4E3B1ADBBD68ECA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Communicate effectively by ensuring regular two-way, meaningful communication between family members and local educational agency and school staff in a manner, language, and with technology that family members can understand and access.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3F6B551E27F4E0CA2F54C26A7BEF973"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Support student success by fostering continuous collaboration between family members and local educational agency and school staff to support student learning and healthy development at school and at home.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCBF710E33B74E398249006B34B8F611"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Speak up for every child and empower family members to be advocates for all students within the school.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H68CFF652AFB24CEA9CF5D1FB5236B02F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Ensure that family members, local educational agencies, and school staff are equal partners in family engagement in education decisionmaking.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1242021EB0E849ACA28F8F5BB4E9B6CA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Collaborate with community organizations and groups to turn the school into a hub of community life.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H10A36CECA7434139843CDE0C5E8275B9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Create a continuum of family engagement in education in student learning and development from birth to young adulthood.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H868CE32E10284CD59EA96A1EAD03C553"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Train and support superintendents, principals, and teachers to fully engage families in the education of their children.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H06B166C81DE24EB7A0234EEDC5E78A97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Written policy</header><text>Section 1118(b)(2), as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBD37B7C7E3E2490395329668A914EEE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (f)</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA05C7A029B6443449F282B4B3EC9F08B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69727FA3FE1E4F20AACDFC62FCBECA7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H78FD3DBE72D34427B956670B792A57C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E54F9C55D8E49B18008BACE335B6E37" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE9AC201D2ABC4D8998A47848C035AD1A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>participate in evaluations of the effectiveness of family engagement in education strategies and policies; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A31667554A340D7813E9CAB3DB43865"><enum>(H)</enum><text>participate in developing recommendations for creating a positive school climate and safe and healthy schools.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCEA20783BEF4549BBE4C99B8C3F15E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>Section 1118(b)(3)(A), as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CE742581CD74FE08CFA979D1F5A8D37" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H78470FD3FAD242F29FDBE386659DCE6F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each local educational agency shall reserve not less than 2 percent of its allocation under subpart 2 to carry out this section, except that this subparagraph shall not apply if 2 percent of such agency’s allocation under subpart 2 for the fiscal year for which the determination is made is $10,000 or less.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H3C82B82CC47941198CCF3C83831D06A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Section 1118(b)(3)(C), as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H820E1FD218C643A997BC54654CE25642" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H8ADE933F2BBB4A7EAD0310ABA98DDAB6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Not less than 75 percent of the funds reserved under subparagraph (A) shall be distributed to schools served under this part.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HE67A75083C164B6286EC09A17ECF5048"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reserved funds</header><text>Section 1118(b)(3), as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H3D37219630DA4AB5A34CC92E3CC85DB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as subparagraphs (C) and (D), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB99699293DE487D9133F394D4ED7C75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02B9460B546546F6936CEA0D33B53C61" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H8131AF9A13754F6D97749046DE6FCFEF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds reserved under subparagraph (A) may be used for the following:</text> <clause id="H433845A1D2BC4D9392DF4A5B58543055"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Increasing capacity through establishment of a dedicated office or dedicated personnel within the local educational agency or at the school level for family engagement in education.</text></clause>
<clause id="HA119149B328A48A796522182E4C17F96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Supporting schools and nonprofit organizations in providing professional development on family engagement in education for school staff, parent leadership training, family literacy and numeracy programs, home visitation programs, family volunteerism programs, and other innovative programs that meaningfully engage families.</text></clause> <clause id="H948963AF10344B309EFD9D35F47F4774"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Developing and implementing local educational agency family engagement in education data-collection systems and indicators.</text></clause>
<clause id="H5A1FF7BEC41948F2BE47C54F7410DE3D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance and training to schools on the implementation and assessment of family engagement in education policies and practices.</text></clause> <clause id="HEB8FE109E4E44B77ADDAD0839F85636A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Providing additional support to schools that have been identified for improvement under section 1116(b) to assist in their implementation of family engagement in education, including the hiring and maintenance of family engagement in education coordinators.</text></clause>
<clause id="HEBCBCB676AA04577BE48EEA8DA2BF334"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Partnering with the Statewide Family Engagement Center and the applicable Local Family Engagement Centers or community-based organizations to identify community resources, services, and supports to remove economic obstacles to family engagement in education by meeting families’ needs.</text></clause> <clause id="H42FBFB5EDD0D402486CC046217414253"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Supporting schools and eligible entities in the development and implementation of research-based family practices in programs that emphasize the importance of family engagement in education, including—</text>
<subclause id="H11CE989AA4AD4131960B4CBE83FEE7B9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>successful transitions from early learning to kindergarten through grade 12 settings;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H058B566DCD0644B189B7EEF64118005A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>improved understanding of and shared responsibility for student success;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HCC9CE57E180B4DB2952CAB273DAED28A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>use of student and school data;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4C70D22E079F4C50BD7E3558E9CC8F28"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>importance of open, effective communication between schools and families;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H8D6732547FE941FAB4BF50577ADC9212"><enum>(V)</enum><text>early warning indicators that a student is at risk of not graduating on time;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD9B6929743AA4CAC920311AD778457EE"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>parent and community advocacy to increase parent participation; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE6CA3604DA454B499FC45B61283537B1"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>improved understanding of the parents’ role in academic, social, and financial preparation for postsecondary education, including career and technical education.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB18D05E0164642B6B925C79A6A1BD3FA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Assisting schools in the development, implementation, and assessment of family engagement in education plans.</text></clause>
<clause id="H30C49A3C3CD04D0CB7D0DBD19EE28452"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Monitoring and evaluating the family engagement in education policies and practices funded under this section.</text></clause> <clause id="HBA44559386534C38A2EBEECDC83CFC41"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Supporting other activities approved in the local education agency’s plan for improving family engagement in education.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1DAC305929EA4CC198BA2FEA14D10FEF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>School parental involvement policy</header><text>Section 1118(c)(1), as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended in the first sentence by striking <quote>subsections (c) through (f)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (d) through (g)</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFE60AC8B23B844CEA32225AED88B8B1A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Shared responsibility for high student academic achievement</header><text>Section 1118(e), as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HFF51539AA6454EC885F964F49BB83FD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>subsection (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (c)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6588B65E7C2C4290BADF96EA388146E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA2F7FBC1A3D4841B14D417953B8CB39" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HD0D271ACB0414DBC88C82706FCC517FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describe the school’s responsibility to—</text> <subparagraph id="H03E41C9A1A31417785412CFF918FAFD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide high-quality curriculum and instruction in a supportive and effective learning environment that enables the children served under this part to meet the State’s student academic achievement standards, and the ways in which each parent will support their children’s learning, such as—</text>
<clause id="H66B7EB686FD446B2AF4F05C9DAB683BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>monitoring attendance and homework completion;</text></clause> <clause id="H98B4326441914A70A88589F8C1D244E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>volunteering in their child’s classroom or school; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9EA71123484840A5B3109D164EB70623"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>participating, as appropriate, in decisions relating to the education of their children and positive use of extracurricular time; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DDBB4039B404DC9BE366840B767A757"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engage family members in the development of recommendations for student attendance, expectations, behavior, and school safety, including the development of reasonable disciplinary policies and behavioral interventions, such as the implementation of school-wide positive behavior interventions and supports and the phase-out of out-of-school suspension and expulsion; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H084469550BBE411493B189578D7F46EE"><enum>9.</enum><header>Prevention and intervention programs for children and youth who are neglected, delinquent, or at risk</header>
<subsection id="HB14E7EACE01947BCB07460304BE0D12E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plan and state agency applications</header><text>Section 1414 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6434">20 U.S.C. 6434</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H434A005C018641CF89FE33990583F6CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFB68AD9977C84951A3D36CC9A78D9641"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41E9D99280764550AA3E20EC82EDDE81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3A8526FA469E4939AD63825A7B6567C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC064D13130A7431E939E3827F7DFC5E2" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H025F57A22644414DA66CF5E3A1C460C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that contains an assurance that each child or youth serviced by the program will have a transition plan developed in partnership with families and aftercare providers that will place the child or youth on a path to career and college readiness; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5D3E7C42697F43A19EE3FF1ED24EE15C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H2471DF6917B44598AC9FE6928A9DC8FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (15) through (19) as paragraphs (17) through (21), respectively; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCCBC581A7A1244739500344AD8F91CA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (14) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4B30DFC1FEC4B7183E8336FBEF6F5FF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H45CAEAD6192140B8BEC39CA23B293897"><enum>(15)</enum><text>describes how the State agency will implement family engagement in education policies and practices that align with section 1118;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1499518858E841D4BDA86997C9BB69EB"><enum>(16)</enum><text>includes an assurance that the State agency will establish, for each child or youth served under this subpart, an educational services and transition plan that is developed in consultation with the child or youth, family members of the child or youth, and the local educational agency or alternative education program that will receive the child or youth following their period of service under this subpart;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H10DE3C33E06E4569A1799500F3436093"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Local educational agency applications</header><text>Section 1423 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6453">20 U.S.C. 6453</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H7447C616DBFB41E59E2C767F16ECBA22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (9) through (13) as paragraphs (11) through (15), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB441525107646C2B1147E20525C67D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (8) the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE58BF04EDB8C493ABA23AAC26E4E1731" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H58B231998C9E4177B0072C68B6DD17E3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a description of how schools will implement family engagement in education policies and practices that align with the provisions of section 1118;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA95B15F5FDA4FD8B18CAFB9AFD5D008"><enum>(10)</enum><text>an assurance that the local educational agency will establish for each child or youth served under this subpart an educational services plan that is developed in consultation with the child or youth, family members of the child or youth, and the local educational agency or alternative education program receiving the child or youth following their period of service under this subpart;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEFBA5DF3B8524676B03443EF75C773BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program requirements for correctional facilities receiving funds under this section</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1425 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6455">20 U.S.C. 6455</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD0B003807D2D45A48825D49271A7F7B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC7499EEA3C56446E8EE33DF214629BC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (11) and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F86912D59D74151A51A43E85C2F97A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H207E63C0EA15413BAAFA3F5A9F341E5F" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H758F2A2887EE401C840D52347A49018C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>prepare an educational services and transition plan for each child or youth served by the program, in partnership with families and aftercare providers, consistent with section 1414(a)(1)(C); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C1EC24F606B44448D0D6D7347A634F1"><enum>(13)</enum><text>establish for each child or youth residing in the facility and serviced by this subpart an educational services and transition plan that is developed in consultation with the child or youth, family members of the child or youth, and the local educational agency or alternative education program receiving the child or youth following their period of service under this subpart.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H77DF3E904F0D4C02BFAFB89487D3D067"><enum>10.</enum><header>Research and evaluation for family engagement in education</header>
<subsection id="H2D9472B35B9F47D2837864C1269E97EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part E of title I (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6491">20 U.S.C. 6491 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10BE2E5E7BBB44778A2E8EB167066C78" style="OLC"> <section id="H80196545DD5A45DA953B55A0201E806E"><enum>1505.</enum><header>Research and evaluation for family engagement in education</header> <subsection id="H86C7C9918E32488787F454119383CE5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of metrics for family engagement</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Family Engagement in Education Act of 2015</short-title>, the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, after consultation with the advisory committee established under subsection (b), shall develop recommended metrics on family engagement in education for State educational agencies that reserve funds under section 1005 and local educational agencies that reserve funds under section 1118 and provide recommendations on the integration of metrics into State accountability and longitudinal data systems.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H29DFD656B7664973B3CB4E76C44BDE40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall appoint an advisory committee, including researchers and representatives from national nonprofit organizations with expertise in family engagement in education, to make data-driven recommendations regarding metrics required under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H66A4CC0B10BD488982A9B6FD42C3F23A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Research for effective family engagement in education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From funds appropriated to carry out this subpart, the Secretary shall conduct research on effective family engagement in education, including through awarding grants and entering into contracts with eligible entities. Such research may include—</text>
<paragraph id="H6689595A482647B297750A0ACE222A89"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exploratory research to discover the underlying processes or components of family engagement in education programs that are associated with improved education outcomes for students;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF6B016834704E95B1C3BD90C00B12BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBE35959D00D04C5A93022754BD999F00"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop culturally sensitive strategies or programs for improving family engagement in education; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1243B5231EF4071A10AD4B19709A127"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rigorously evaluate the impact of such strategies or programs on students' education outcomes; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7FCCDEB6634C41B4A2074258D5119EAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research to—</text> <subparagraph id="H610AC0200CD7413CB2D8F6FFFF4D5E13"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop professional development programs intended to enable school personnel to support parental involvement in education; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEDA03ECC344547DD8FD744AE9852D6D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rigorously evaluate the impact of such programs on students' education outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HEC8AE128D1034554803FC2FC98CFA7A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1504 the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8705129DAD2F46CE88AA8A2FB2D09C3C" style="OLC">
<toc>
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 1505. Research and evaluation for family engagement in education.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="H53DCA6E7CE3E4BC3AA10F4B91639E6FE"><enum>11.</enum><header>High-quality teachers and principals</header>
<subsection id="HB7FAD7608FB24EA8B6134444943A6C19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State application contents</header><text>Section 2112(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6612">20 U.S.C. 6612(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC13C6D7DEC574AD2B6CEFA5207575C9C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD1BB2496DA3F4298B166CE68C54CF38A"><enum>(13)</enum><text>A description of how the State educational agency will improve teacher and principal knowledge and skill in effectively engaging families in their children’s education.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HA94FBE716CC9426E94469E3C4D98A883"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State activities</header><text>Section 2113(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6613">20 U.S.C. 6613(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB540C5E695064A679166FCA75950BD2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (12) through (18) as paragraphs (13) through (19), respectively; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA5B960C775D943BAAD771EB263832A38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (11) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA26F31F84004795B33DA0785ED52B74" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB427EA4D1AF346AEAFED5B726C23A6D2"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Training of teachers and principals on how to effectively engage families in their children's education.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H2162CC41E10E4A7DA2C783E4E4807A1B"><enum>12.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9101 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H67CDBDD8CCCC4B92847B69E1F293F7C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (32);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33D27956A1864D2DA0C7D25CCE3E7333"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (20) through (31) as paragraphs (21) through (32), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H712799C9A3DC4C40A212E18A7207FCF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (19) the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE417B3486FF64BD49B4F1BFDACE9E926" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H6CE33E7B023F43B4BBD85297808D9413"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Family engagement in education</header><text>The term <term>family engagement in education</term> means a shared responsibility—</text> <subparagraph id="HBCA92D0B84684D40BF3D85948CA4D284"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of families and schools for student success, in which schools and community-based organizations are committed to reaching out to engage families in meaningful ways and families are committed to actively supporting their children’s learning and development; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H873DC68AC55E46D0AC7C2FD5EBDE74AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is continuous from birth through young adulthood and reinforces learning that takes place in the home, school, and community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H14D9B55503E84CF08DB9B858D573B6C6"><enum>13.</enum><header>Repeal of Parental Assistance and Local Family Information Centers</header> <subsection id="H6579F22BA29C47099ADA38230409B1FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part D of title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7241">20 U.S.C. 7241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H2B2DE5E2DA194DFFA182355C4B09B8F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subpart 16; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE778F66D397A4168A3D829D5A65805D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparts 17, 18, 19, 20, and 21, as subparts 16, 17, 18, 19, and 20, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5846E4B2F78E4C97B7C68F4CF7A02F86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC6F6267331274714A679A37B93FE3157"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to subpart 16 of part D of title V;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF4378C563A8E486D8B94921BDC4878F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the items relating to sections 5561, 5562, 5563, 5564, 5565, and 5566; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13FD78A2C7134AA3A7B2D866453DA415"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating the items relating to subparts 17, 18, 19, 20, and 21 of part D of title V, as subparts 16, 17, 18, 19, and 20 of part D of title V, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HC831435D439B4F7CAF1F2CF2254FFA7A"><enum>14.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by striking—</text> <paragraph id="H4ECEA4EA40BC49E9943A52888A7DA199"><enum>(1)</enum><text><quote>parental involvement</quote> and <quote>parent involvement</quote> each place the terms appear and inserting <quote>family engagement in education</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3D2F47C41C084B11BCB6DB9F6D3E1ABF"><enum>(2)</enum><text><quote>involvement of parents</quote> each place the term appears and inserting <quote>engagement of families</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51A10812982D4A8395579B1AD2B4D812"><enum>(3)</enum><text><quote>parental information and resource center</quote> each place the term appears and inserting <quote>Statewide Family Engagement Center</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA236D6691565430B91BC54D2C7A00AF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text><quote>parental information and resource centers</quote> each place the term appears and inserting <quote>Statewide Family Engagement Centers</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42EFC1E87BE14547B9750B10BFEA3C06"><enum>(5)</enum><text><quote>involve parents</quote> each place the term appears and inserting <quote>engage families</quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HBEC975F4EF3D44A199CF5463096FF515"><enum>15.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office study and report</header>
<subsection id="H90494595A4BD47D686DB1B4C2556B9B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header>
<paragraph id="H4FBAADB200CC459D9FBC3B80007B344F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study, and make findings and recommendations relating to compliance with, and use of funds made available for, section 1118 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6318">20 U.S.C. 6318</external-xref>), including matters specified in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD31DAD3185F440FF90975ECE17AF2840"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The study shall include a review and analysis of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1BE301B57C064EC3827300377533C57B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of funds reserved by local educational agencies for family engagement in education under such section 1118;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C80E18004164458BA976220B40C40F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the innovative, effective, replicable, or model family engagement in education policies, practices, and uses of funds of State educational agencies and local educational agencies determined by the Secretary of Education to be in alignment with section 1118;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H773BB343E57E4B8B91DE4C370AC598C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any barriers to State educational agencies and local educational agencies in implementing section 1118;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H66D2E25DECF94FA1B202C80AB502535C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any barriers to Indian tribes and organizations, Native Hawaiian organizations, and Alaska Native organizations in developing, implementing, and assessing family engagement in education policies and practices; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC1F4DB146FFD4DFFB63BE2A65C831846"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the use of data collection and reporting and outcome and assessment systems of State educational agencies and local educational agencies to determine the extent to which family engagement in education is implemented as described in section 1118.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAE617146854441D89B6E4EBC199DCF21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives a report containing the findings and recommendations resulting from the study conducted under this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


