<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1371F8D1E6A94678B585970EFC7AD61A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 49 IH: To make 2 percent across-the-board rescissions in non-defense, non-homeland-security, and non-veterans-affairs discretionary spending for each of the fiscal years 2015 and 2016.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 49</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To make 2 percent across-the-board rescissions in non-defense, non-homeland-security, and
			 non-veterans-affairs discretionary spending for each of the fiscal years
			 2015 and 2016.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H954BD707EAE64DF191F06331BFFA6B39" style="OLC">
		<section id="H5B10BD6A2A8D4392A8EE0A7BC93415BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Across-the-board rescissions in non-defense, non-homeland-security, and non-veterans-affairs
			 discretionary spending for each of fiscal years 2015 and 2016</header>
			<subsection id="HE2BF6A3306424B7C9E7D8D066A23BCF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Across-the-Board Rescissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby rescinded an amount equal to 2 percent of—</text>
				<paragraph id="H7AED3AA3DA56419A83FB3ECA72D6901B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the budget authority provided (or obligation limitation imposed) in each of the fiscal years 2015
			 and 2016 for any non-defense, non-homeland-security, and
			 non-veterans-affairs discretionary account in any fiscal year 2015 or 2016
			 appropriation Act;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H59B3869F6C314E89A2AF7A7699F308F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the budget authority provided in any advance appropriation for each of the fiscal years 2015 and
			 2016 for any non-defense, non-homeland-security, and non-veterans-affairs
			 discretionary account in any prior fiscal year appropriation Act; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H09D4CDF742C54996859FDCF2E5ECEA2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the contract authority provided in each of the fiscal years 2015 and 2016 for any program that is
			 subject to a limitation contained in any fiscal year 2015 or 2016
			 appropriation Act for any non-defense, non-homeland-security, and
			 non-veterans-affairs discretionary account.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC462255E844D4705B86D97816C2AC58F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Non-Defense, Non-Homeland-Security, and Non-Veterans-Affairs discretionary account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), the term <quote>non-defense, non-homeland-security, and non-veterans-affairs discretionary account</quote> means any discretionary account, other than—</text>
				<paragraph id="HF1ECC2D733144688A2683DE7FD7AC42C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any account included in a Department of Defense Appropriations Act;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H29BCE5911C7840668A008842B2868F88"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any account included in a Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H85D32C4B6DBD424CB78EE9DF9552B7DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any account of the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs included in a
			 Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies
			 Appropriations Act; or</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB12E97A843E745128F0021F1973D0C9F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any account for Department of Energy defense activities included in an Energy and Water Development
			 and Related Agencies Appropriations Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21DA46AD4E3E4D44B9DEC8B6D5CE3664"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Proportionate application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any rescission made by subsection (a) shall be applied proportionately—</text>
				<paragraph id="H8FDB223566A64B76B798696DBFBE5C21"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to each discretionary account and each item of budget authority described in such subsection; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H302891D7076A4ABEBDBBC39B1FAC3801"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within each such account and item, to each program, project, and activity (with programs, projects,
			 and activities as delineated in the appropriation Act or accompanying
			 reports for the relevant fiscal year covering such account or item, or for
			 accounts and items not included in appropriation Acts, as delineated in
			 the most recently submitted President's budget).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85B14485368345EDB31F80565CE50D9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subsequent appropriation laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any fiscal year 2015 or 2016 appropriation Act enacted after the date of enactment
			 of this section, any rescission required by subsection (a) shall take
			 effect immediately after the enactment of such Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD9975D8AF61440A384DD553BDFB2849E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>OMB report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 30 days after the date of enactment of this section (or, if later, 30 days after the
			 enactment of any fiscal year 2015 or 2016 appropriation Act), the Director
			 of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to the Committees on
			 Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report
			 specifying the account and amount of each rescission made pursuant to
			 subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


