<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H47FB446643E6474BA2CF935659B7FDBA" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2142 IH: Capitalizing on American Methane Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2142</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against income tax for facilities using a qualified methane conversion technology to provide transportation fuels and chemicals.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HFCD702C27B0D4B75802D52F5AD08BE36" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H40CAFADACE134EFDA34ADB89CCED320C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Capitalizing on American Methane Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF7B52F2742914101A341D84A92A9C86B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Incentives for innovative fuel production through qualified methane conversion technology</header> <subsection id="HAB34C81F509B4387BEA665C864BD6558"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion of qualified methane conversion technology in gasification project credit</header> <paragraph id="HDE0153C1005B49D69AC3E64000535EDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48B">section 48B(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1E70D2CEF3244E3DBE9DADBD2807AD4C" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HCC733B0DF51E44AFB4972F459BC0E3FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gasification technology</header><text>The term <quote>gasification technology</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H61F5846567DE4E80A3CB51FFE86B34FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any process which converts a solid or liquid product from coal, petroleum residue, biomass, or other materials which are recovered for their energy or feedstock value into a synthesis gas composed primarily of carbon monoxide and hydrogen for direct use or subsequent chemical or physical conversion, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H87F45BB5225A48D79D8F9CC357207A53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any qualified methane conversion technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H319D96BABD2747079A02EC898D332C07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified methane conversion technology</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 48B of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC6E9B6D5A47C4CF5A620D9E487EE8A93" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HABEA6FA29CB34E38AD4F21991DD21894"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualified methane conversion technology</header> 
<subparagraph id="H483D5BCE184A4ABDB25ABF8335051698"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified methane conversion technology</quote> means a process consisting of the molecular conversion of a fuel consisting principally of methane into hydrocarbons, and the subsequent use of such hydrocarbons, if such hydrocarbons are principally intended to be used—</text> <clause id="H83AAEF5E70DC437EBD7E4BB4E587DFE5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to replace or reduce the quantity of petroleum present in a fuel used in motor vehicles, motor vehicle engines, nonroad vehicles, nonroad engines, or aircraft if—</text> 
<subclause id="H1312752DA2B04554B71D3D3B5807BC1F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions associated with the production and combustion is, on an ongoing basis, not more than such emissions from the equivalent conventional fuel produced from conventional petroleum sources,</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC8623DE7C68941BE99C22ED57452BC0A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the sulfur concentration is not more than 2 parts per million, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H07118ABF58A448DA8F60315DB500BC7B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such production is at a facility which, during the taxable year, has an annual total production capacity of not more than 150,000,000 gallons of liquid transportation fuel, or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA0576F329F524E47A85F596589F61417"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for the production of chemicals (within the meaning of paragraph (7)(A)).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5A08F154A0E4240A894B0933FB6A41B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Primary purpose of facility</header><text>If a facility uses qualified methane conversion technology to produce both fuels and chemicals, the requirements described in subparagraph (A)(i) shall apply only if the primary use of the facility is to produce fuels.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0533362BF98448CEA188EBA697BCDC6D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <quote>qualified methane conversion technology</quote> does not include technology that is part of a facility the construction of which begins after September 30, 2025.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block></after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F3BE6DBA526455CB8B9D01B279A50D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Increase in credit available for methane conversion projects</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7A9928A43C2B424BB1394A8E758C3BB8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 48B(d) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H734DB5DC4EBC43AD9B91A590BEE62C18" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HB41682380872490BA3BA09C563508B81"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$500,000,000 for qualifying gasification projects that rely primarily on qualified methane conversion technology.</text></subparagraph> 
<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="paragraph">No qualifying gasification project shall receive more than $100,000,000 under the program.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E8AD2CA37604732AACBF5F09F7B1A32"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Period of issuance</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 48B(d) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HB1EAF23E2AFA48079463518AABC6F6A9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0C288EA0CF4942A0805154FF733E8201"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of issuance</header> <subparagraph id="H090036D824DC4ED6B00AA40544363A99"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A certificate of eligibility under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) may be issued only before October 1, 2025.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6875932A9AD4D1AA40C02FCDF824D3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified methane conversion technology</header><text>A certificate of eligibility under subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1) may be issued only during the 10-fiscal year period beginning on the first October 1 which is on or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D7EF4CE29AB442E92291B2CE142155E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Selection priorities</header><text>Paragraph (4) of section 48B(d) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HA0BF35EE193A4A10A183428799814696" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HA9C32059A0AE4A488BB42ECD99DB1AC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selection priorities</header> 
<subparagraph id="HBB1FF189708E450ABD7FC6EBB2097C78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining which qualifying gasification projects, other than projects using qualified methane conversion technology, to certify under this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HC16F49FEA40945558538963593690A8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>give highest priority to projects with the greatest separation and sequestration percentage of total carbon dioxide emissions, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1E350ED83CD047F5BD40F15D94A55E21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>give high priority to applicant participants who have a research partnership with an eligible educational institution (as defined in section 529(e)(5)).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E11029B37C84F089B49FF82404ECF5A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chemicals projects using qualified methane conversion technology</header><text>In determining which qualifying gasification projects that produce chemicals using qualified methane conversion technology to certify under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to projects involving a production process that has significant environmental benefits over the production of the same chemical from petroleum products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDEA1CE5C3F3D43D08D5628B918010D93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of qualified methane conversion technology in alternative fuel credit</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6426">section 6426(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (F), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (G) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H735411E1C92B470B83C0E44F39C27669" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H85047F7DB5D44F7FB512E1EAED79CE8B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>liquid fuel produced through qualified methane conversion technology (as defined in section 48B(c)(9)(A)) at a facility the construction of which begins before October 1, 2025.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H161FD7422A29456A966B4DF7FA4EF6D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

