<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBAFBD8B1B56344DDB9687029872CA80A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3066 IH: Federal Disaster Assistance Nonprofit Fairness Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3066</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150715">July 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to clarify that houses
			 of worship are eligible for certain disaster relief and emergency
			 assistance on terms equal to other eligible private nonprofit facilities,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HDF5DACC31DAB4D9BA4EC8AABF8CFF96B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA86FED4A9D034958B7B629E1CB816672" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Disaster Assistance Nonprofit Fairness Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8C768CACD392400AB348ADC65300AE88"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC3EB9467FA8A469BAD4AF230C21FC7CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Churches, synagogues, mosques, temples, and other houses of worship throughout communities nationwide play an essential role in the daily lives of the communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAA024791B1E4C60AC54AB511716804A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Federal Emergency Management Agency’s (FEMA) public assistance program provides financial grants for the repair of various types of private nonprofit facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H007F2F619F844489875D87F1111947FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Among the types of nonprofits to which FEMA provides such grants are those in which citizens gather and engage in a variety of educational, enrichment, and social activities. These activities are essential to community building and occur in houses of worship.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64DDB13785E8473CBF7BF472F88DDC7B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>), FEMA’s disaster relief program is a general government program under which assistance is provided in the wake of a natural disaster using criteria that are neutral with regard to religion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4A23D44342E40B49FA8F54492E940B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Congress has previously enacted legislation providing financial assistance to religious nonprofit institutions, including houses of worship, on terms equal to other eligible nonprofit institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D4FC244A14D405588B05A6103A6ED09"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Such legislation is consistent with recent precedents of the Supreme Court of the United States and legal opinions issued by the Office of Legal Counsel of the Department of Justice.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HA6FD899D63164A0593D0A0923D453028"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of houses of worship as private nonprofit facilities eligible for disaster relief</header>
 <subsection id="H464AA535EC5D451884D35F3E83F981C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of private nonprofit facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102(10)(B) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(10)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80CFD4000A544FC5816F8BD5BD87B6FB" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H0B8862C5BAF441A2BAC11598E5947F80"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the facilities described in subparagraph (A), the term <quote>private nonprofit facility</quote> includes any private nonprofit facility that provides essential services of a governmental nature to the general public (including museums, zoos, performing arts facilities, community arts centers, community centers, including houses of worship exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, libraries, homeless shelters, senior citizen centers, rehabilitation facilities, shelter workshops, and facilities that provide health and safety services of a governmental nature), as defined by the President.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H89C68DDF87ED414A9691ACBD993EE958"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities</header><text>Section 406(a)(3) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE69AEE3C23A042429A6804EAB7076A99" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HBD2CDBAAECEA44B28F7A5A8A609489E5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Houses of worship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A church, synagogue, mosque, temple, or other house of worship, and a private nonprofit facility operated by a religious organization, shall be eligible for contributions under paragraph (1)(B), without regard to the religious character of the facility or the primary religious use of the facility.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6DC63C65CBB746AD91198A3BE0E999CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply to the provision of assistance in response to a major disaster or emergency declared on or after October 28, 2012.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


