<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC2073EE8CD91418FABCC9161301FD3D0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3836 IH: FAIR Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3836</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151027">October 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require a report on diversity recruitment, employment, retention, and promotion at the
			 Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HEAED93F26CCE4E79A0ED291C6609827C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4420C8CB8D814C36BAC370B650F8973F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Affairs Inclusion Reporting Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>FAIR Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H04B1D2FFE9394014B8EFEDC8A46F44D7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on diversity recruitment, employment, retention, and promotion at the Department of State</header> <subsection id="H0CF29A12D29548A3AF00B3FBA6549EE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and quadrennially thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5425574EC139454E903555F3211B7B0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the efforts, consistent with existing law, including procedures, effects, and results since the period covered by the prior such report, to promote in the Department of State equal opportunity and inclusion for all United States employees in direct hire and personal service contractors status, particularly employees of the Foreign Service, including equal opportunity for all races, ethnicities, ages, genders, and service-disabled veterans, with a focus on traditionally underrepresented minority groups;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66F77BA75E084C219B9DDF1DF48DF1F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes a section on—</text> <subparagraph id="H4203B6D0213E4876A5C0C71A900C203F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the diversity of selection boards;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H921092CCF3D64672A67C40C87B002B40"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the employment of minority and service-disabled veterans during the most recent 10-year period, including—</text>
 <clause id="H8EDEDDCC5C6143D096F0B87774BA995C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number hired through direct hires, internships, and fellowship programs;</text> </clause><clause id="HF49595E8408A444CA90B8BE501187851"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number promoted to senior positions, including FS–01, GS–15, Senior Executive Service, and Senior Foreign Service; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA5BCE5FE9C3A4F2180FB8BE4EDA262EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>attrition rates by grade, civil and foreign services, and the senior level ranks specified in clause (ii);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3C7E05108DE49789DC150F2308CCCB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mentorship and retention programs; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29EEC8E2DE7B4A51AE9A6B20C45ECD7E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is organized in terms of real numbers and percentages at all levels.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H067AD4C25ED64B4C938803770D2A19C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall describe the efforts of the Department of State to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H10B39E819F234E75ADFA134EC89B886F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>propagate fairness, impartiality, and inclusion in the work environment domestically and abroad;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H445FFB06AABF4091B5D809DEB6F9783C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>eradicate harassment, intolerance, and discrimination;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA71517FED62A4453B2391E8A5F15E5C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>refrain from engaging in unlawful discrimination in any phase of the employment process, including recruitment, hiring, evaluation, assignments, promotion, retention, and training;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE1CFE3CCF6340418F779793767FFFC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>eliminate illegal retaliation against employees for participating in a protected equal employment opportunity activity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB10D6CD250E244B0A8C527A055C14D17"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide reasonable accommodation for qualified employees and applicants with disabilities;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H40A10991E264409E8E0DE58ADB654694"><enum>(6)</enum><text>resolve workplace conflicts, confrontations, and complaints in a prompt, impartial, constructive, and timely manner;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5013D0AC7404D2A8ACA0CF40BB28401"><enum>(7)</enum><text>improve demographic data availability and analysis regarding recruitment, hiring, promotion, training, length in service, assignment restrictions, and pass-through programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90382906BE74461F87A938F55B177849"><enum>(8)</enum><text>recruit a diverse staff by—</text> <subparagraph id="HA386A8F99C704E37B7405F8BF33EB432"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recruiting women, minorities, veterans, and undergraduate and graduate students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0EABC52B02B4D12A90469A03074D317"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recruiting at historically Black colleges and universities, Hispanic serving institutions, women’s colleges, and colleges that typically serve majority minority populations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F959048868442088EDA3889C95C46EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sponsoring and recruiting at job fairs in urban communities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4425F94A2103436F8276462B5468F864"><enum>(D)</enum><text>placing job advertisements in newspapers, magazines, and job sites oriented toward women and people of color;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86D544F58F3A42FF8BF82C7E188DEE5F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing opportunities through the Foreign Service Internship Program and other hiring initiatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF308CC271C0643498324EAA3FAF0FD03"><enum>(F)</enum><text>recruiting mid- and senior-level professionals through programs such as—</text> <clause id="HD32C30BE3FC144D09073F5FC5B2259EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the International Career Advancement Program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8EA35F247CA444B99B2A9103FB4668E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Public Policy and International Affairs Fellowship Program;</text> </clause><clause id="HB9A1A9F7C71142A6AC6486BAF7ABF56F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Institute for International Public Policy Fellowship Program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC992CA4E2CE34AEF845EA659F64C1D70"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Seminar XXI at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology’s Center for International Studies; and</text> </clause><clause id="H14822C10E3814D54A9C41F84E6E8CEB0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other similar, highly respected, international leadership programs; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07315001A70E4FFF8A784D046EA1574A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>provide opportunities through—</text> <subparagraph id="H3CA4F4F66C4743F78E9128C5D2AFDBB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Charles B. Rangel International Affairs Fellowship Program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12E637189C494DB5A5982C8955A540F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Thomas R. Pickering Foreign Affairs Fellowship Program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66B4F8C10EDF4225BF1E94A7F4E354E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of initial report</header><text>The first report submitted to Congress under subsection (a) shall include the information described in subsection (b) for the three fiscal years immediately preceding the fiscal year in which such first report is submitted.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HEAF2E01469404047B8C660C30E84D302"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion of the Charles B. Rangel International Affairs Program and the Thomas R. Pickering
			 Foreign Affairs Fellowship Program</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning in fiscal year 2016, the Secretary of State shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4D0D79F658B04C34AB8E3A23EA510A98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase by ten the number of fellows selected for the Charles B. Rangel International Affairs Program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A46A80F9AB43058A1B3BC8F6915356"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase by ten the number of fellows selected for the Thomas R. Pickering Foreign Affairs Fellowship Program.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HD461B4A3CFD4463F9CA948D5465E62C8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Retention of mid- and senior-level professionals from underrepresented groups at the Department of
			 State</header>
 <subsection id="H8EC2479ADFEA453EBA381B5B1C6FCC96"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State should provide attention and oversight to the employment, retention, and promotion of underrepresented groups to promote a diverse ethnic representation among mid- and senior-level career professionals through programs, such as—</text>
 <paragraph id="H80DA6768D8FB49A391DBD4E4D753AFB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the International Career Advancement Program;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H83BD36347DA849FEA0D928C82A82D374"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Seminar XXI at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology’s Center for International Studies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20D64C1730704141B858666E17BFDA13"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other highly respected international leadership programs.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE49445368594998A822CC3407B64F80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of past programs</header><text>The Secretary of State should review past programs designed to increase minority representation in international affairs positions, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1812C332274D424C8C3845624DAF7ACC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Public Policy and International Affairs Fellowship Program; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H91D8AABE910744779E5C104092889140"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Institute for International Public Policy Fellowship Program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


