<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H491E611F005042DC9EFB4D8EF62872C2" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3125 IH: Accidental Firearms Transfers Reporting Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3125</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150721">July 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to report to the Congress
			 semiannually on the number of firearms transfers resulting from the
			 failure to complete a background check within 3 business days, and the
			 procedures followed after it is discovered that a firearm transfer has
			 been made to a transferee who is ineligible to receive a firearm.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0E936D2C7E314BB9A803FD9F5960290E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA0234500FE034AD2A5AFF77323E7C3B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accidental Firearms Transfers Reporting Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H340D124911B142969105F3AEB0363F44"><enum>2.</enum><header>FBI report on firearms transfers resulting from the failure to complete a background check within <enum-in-header>3</enum-in-header> business days, and the procedures followed after it is discovered that a firearm transfer has been made to a transferee who is ineligible to receive a firearm</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 6 months thereafter, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a written report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC637173C17264F99A9D094E08C70F6DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of proposed firearm transfers—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E950AA80F7248FC907BCC81D729F71D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>about which a person licensed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, contacted the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FC8F1081AE54056BCFBF983F49DA744"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to which the system failed to respond to the licensee within 3 business days; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H260C6391FAC54334939594AB6F3BA0A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which were completed in the period covered by the report; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE09CFFC2F6704BEABD347295501CB32B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the procedures followed after it is discovered that a firearm transfer has been made to a transferee who is ineligible to receive a firearm.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


