<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2D9517CFA34947D78A5DBCC2A6AC9746" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1962 IH: Investing for Tomorrow’s Schools Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1962</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish State infrastructure banks for education.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H56F4870C3F9646A0A3C4FAF214ACD308" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA73007111D554077A4052435C9236FF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investing for Tomorrow’s Schools Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H39B2BEC4FDE3422C9DE600423C458851"><enum>2.</enum><header>State infrastructure bank pilot program</header> <subsection id="H17E074CCFF3B4195B867964EE45B6B2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H50469D8DF0FF4F04B44630C67D3DF147"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>Subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may enter into cooperative agreements with States for the establishment of State infrastructure banks and multistate infrastructure banks for making loans—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBB0C6FB6E1504BB9B4A14B0C737DDE76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to local educational agencies for building or repairing elementary or secondary schools which provide free public education (as such terms are defined in section 14101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/8801">20 U.S.C. 8801</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4C3A4E4F37F402B960EF480076E3ADE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to public libraries for building or repairing library facilities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC51805B31E7B4129BAEFBEF0401014B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to eligible charter school entities for use for the objective described in section 5224(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7223c">20 U.S.C. 7223c(2)</external-xref>) consistent with subpart 2 of part B of title V of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7223">20 U.S.C. 7223 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CAA8F2AB23647DCA1996980962374A3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to community learning centers to connect and improve broadband services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE51039D2544D4C10A132022480AF5BF0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to educational service agencies for building or repairing elementary schools, secondary schools, or other school facilities that provide free public education.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C47098F9DBB4F598FAA5848D369B9CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interstate compacts</header><text>Congress grants consent to two or more of the States, entering into a cooperative agreement under paragraph (1) with the Secretary of the Treasury for the establishment of a multistate infrastructure bank, to enter into an interstate compact establishing such bank in accordance with this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F538A8A01194832BBDAFF8E9C6CC994"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall make grants to State infrastructure banks and multistate infrastructure banks in a State in a cooperative agreement under subsection (a)(1) to provide initial capital for loans provided under this section. Each bank shall apply repayments of principal and interest on loans to the making of additional loans. The Secretary shall take final action on an application for a grant under this subsection within 90 days of the date of the submission of such application.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7428AE1ED4944CDD8E34713CACF280B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Infrastructure bank requirements</header><text>In order to establish an infrastructure bank under this section, each State establishing the bank shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H34527C6859D84EB08276F3C06AD5A99F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contribute, at a minimum, in each account of the bank from non-Federal sources an amount equal to 25 percent of the amount of each capitalization grant made to the State and contributed to the bank under subsection (b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE802BF2B00641718A273F94124AE378"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify an operating entity of the State as recipient of the grant if the entity has the capacity to manage loan funds and issue debt instruments of the State for purposes of leveraging the funds;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C728DE343424431944C19F6D486A62E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>allow such funds to be used as reserve for debt issued by the State so long as proceeds are deposited in the fund for loan purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64FAB902D1374CB5880E3B31E06B3547"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that investment income generated by funds contributed to an account of the bank will be—</text> <subparagraph id="H4D5C6A7FC2464DEC9C457AB9A4B33213"><enum>(A)</enum><text>credited to the account;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CBB89EB6A404B2BA98C768498C492AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>available for use in providing loans to projects eligible for assistance from the account; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB11276923A2B46CD80DC80FC80A449C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>invested in United States Treasury securities, bank deposits, or such other financing instruments as the Secretary may approve to earn interest to enhance the leveraging of projects assisted by the bank;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAE24A83CADB45C481F02FBD4C0A026B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure that any loan from the bank to an eligible charter school entity, local educational agency, public library, or community learning center will bear interest at or below the lowest interest rates being offered for bonds the income from which is exempt from Federal taxation, as determined by the State, to make the project that is the subject of the loan feasible;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H167840F0E6FA48399DA3C42B81C06960"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that repayment of any loan from the bank to an eligible charter school entity, local educational agency, public library, or community learning center will commence not later than 1 year after the project has been completed;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD08771C6CD64AD58F36598BDF5CEF7B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the term for repaying any loan to an eligible charter school entity, local educational agency, public library, or community learning center will not exceed 30 years after the date of the first payment on the loan under paragraph (5);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HECDCA5EE20B347FBA40FB6C62F5F4C7A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>ensure that the funds loaned annually that are used under subsection (a)(1)(C) are limited to a percentage of the total funds loaned that does not exceed the percentage of elementary and secondary school students in the State enrolled in charter schools during the most recent school year for which enrollment data are available;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42049F93B67D4BB0AE46ED3CBBB1C574"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the funds loaned annually under subsection (a)(1)(D) are used exclusively to connect and improve broadband services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3BA80CB97EE4AA8B511B41232173F18"><enum>(10)</enum><text>require the bank to make an annual report to the Secretary on its status and make such other reports as the Secretary may require by guidelines.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB66FDE192A843968C0FAED6FF6744EB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Forms of assistance from infrastructure banks</header>
 <paragraph id="H9CF838BE8F1E47BF9F2444028C9F8F89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An infrastructure bank established under this section may make loans in an amount equal to all or part of the cost of carrying out a project eligible for assistance under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DE9C8A9DA9F4414AB11A990D576EDDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications for loans</header><text>An application to an infrastructure bank for a loan shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H334F07869CDF42EB97779210C7F451B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a renovation project, a description of each architectural, civil, structural, mechanical, or electrical deficiency to be corrected with funds under a loan and the priorities to be applied;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88A0F42D6C514A8AAC1F63E640F0934F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the criteria used by the applicant to determine the type of corrective action necessary for the renovation of a facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31958E94773E48F4BD7A2DCCB0F29951"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of improvements to be made and a cost estimate for the improvements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5A30CC4EE6B4457930F6DBB3EFF39C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how work undertaken with the loan will promote the conservation of energy, water, or waste; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36BDD1396D57487999DB267171E67E58"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other information as the infrastructure bank may require.</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">An infrastructure bank shall take final action on a completed application submitted to it within 90 days after the date of its submission.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H214AEC3E61A94459B5D54C3DA2CCFEB6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criteria for loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In considering applications for a loan to an eligible charter school entity, local educational agency, public library, or community learning center, an infrastructure bank shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H19232B388088422AA39E887B856169E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the eligible charter school entity, local educational agency, public library, or community learning center involved lacks the fiscal capacity, including the ability to raise funds through the full use of such agency’s bonding capacity and otherwise, to undertake the project for which the loan would be used without the loan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FDBEEB9A1FD4A72A52B6AFF3FCAD47F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a local educational agency, the threat that the condition of the physical plant in the project poses to the safety and well-being of students;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B4A2B13DA6149629DBBAC32B49F79F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the demonstrated need for the construction, reconstruction, or renovation based on the condition of the facility in the project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8578A0C2CAB44ACB8DA707DB05E94607"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the age of such facility; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2C07670E2A794A038D320B93E2D6494B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrated need to connect and improve broadband services in the local community.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29FAD231A1934FCA8085BD6BA6EBB7DC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualifying projects</header>
 <paragraph id="HFAFC044033314E16AC0B68E799715A12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (a)(1), a project is eligible for a loan from an infrastructure bank if it is a project that consists of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6A99C8F3FD3A4827AB905E4499D74AE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the construction of new elementary or secondary schools to meet the needs imposed by enrollment growth;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2E4E0794CB2446C8EB3B99C12ABD626"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the repair, rebuilding, or upgrading of classrooms or structures related to academic learning, including the repair of leaking roofs, crumbling walls, inadequate plumbing, poor ventilation equipment, and inadequate heating or lighting equipment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BA93179AADA42E794CEB7E25C4C2B91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an activity to increase physical safety at the educational facility involved;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE31E6AEEAF342C5BB42BBF0BE0728F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an activity to enhance the educational facility involved to provide access for students, teachers, and other individuals with disabilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9F9E25F121149B69D45BB25446F2266"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an activity to address environmental or health hazards at the educational facility involved, such as poor ventilation, indoor air quality, or lighting;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB5ED81AD55945D3A3557D60B9C3B1C9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the provision of basic infrastructure that facilitates educational technology, such as communications outlets, electrical systems, power outlets, or a communication closet;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H598375AB3FA04F36A14ADEDE97A575FF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>work that will bring an educational facility into conformity with the requirements of—</text> <clause id="H6401A4CCC3CF49238C39EE7BC255A019"><enum>(i)</enum><text>environmental protection or health and safety programs mandated by Federal, State, or local law if such requirements were not in effect when the facility was initially constructed; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H365C062B726748F48BF6CC94B299EBFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>hazardous waste disposal, treatment, and storage requirements mandated by the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act of 1976 or similar State laws;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H487D6C14F7F9461EA393AE386D1CB96F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>work that will enable efficient use of available energy resources;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2E2E33A9A2040C8A731F0C8B7DB6D28"><enum>(I)</enum><text>work that will reduce reliance on fossil fuels and expand use of solar power, wind power, and other renewable energy resources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE66D1B16E644FDFA3614377E239F67E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>work to detect, remove, or otherwise contain asbestos hazards in educational facilities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H118331C0D92E4B22A5517A048AC8369A"><enum>(K)</enum><text>work to construct new public library facilities or repair or upgrade existing public library facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2E2CEA3DC5D40D6BC32A37A7AB76088"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work to connect entities described in subsection (a)(1) to broadband services, and to improve such connections for such entities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE30654FC8ED942499BC4D5894B761C20"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measures designed to reduce or eliminate human exposure to classroom noise and environmental noise pollution; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73EB9A2165F54F048369CACA6075EBA0"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the repair, replacement, or upgrade of kitchen equipment, kitchen appliances, and kitchen facilities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H577A5287B1444056A411CD748B1E2497"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Davis-Bacon</header><text>The wage requirements of the Act of March 3, 1931 (referred to as the <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/276a">40 U.S.C. 276a et seq.</external-xref>), shall apply with respect to individuals employed on the projects described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8498A7DDD1DB487BA48CE714A4F1E35D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Green practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity using a loan under this section to fund a new construction or renovation project described in paragraph (1) shall ensure that the project is certified, verified, or consistent with State laws, regulations, and any applicable provisions of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H61D732FFDEBD4347B4DC5606050EF4C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the LEED Green Building Rating System;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62B6429F90FB422490B5B58FBA1E99AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Living Building Challenge;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A9408128FE344EB932792397A71F240"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the CHPS green building rating program developed by the Collaborative for High Performance Schools; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H143952AA2C734D09A703BF84AF1E5BF2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a program that—</text> <clause id="HDD49041B42F14273B3D36B8859291C9B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has equivalent or more stringent standards;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8EA07ED8180D463AB87ADB4E84199612"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is adopted by the State or another jurisdiction with authority over the entity; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCA93616A3FE448D7A15B45F4BEE25CF8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>includes a verifiable method to demonstrate compliance with such program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF99435651A724231BE7E9A9DD4E27E39"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplementation</header><text>Any loan made by an infrastructure bank shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, and local funds available.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6042128A035C467BB22B51B7F662E73E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation on repayments</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the repayment of a loan from an infrastructure bank under this section may not be credited towards the non-Federal share of the cost of any project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H69DED1B6A10146ED897FFDF7C9E8899B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Secretarial requirements</header><text>In administering this section, the Secretary of the Treasury shall specify procedures and guidelines for establishing, operating, and providing assistance from an infrastructure bank.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA87E60AE5B784C68B32CE76484AA57ED"><enum>(i)</enum><header>United States not obligated</header><text>The contribution of Federal funds into an infrastructure bank established under this section shall not be construed as a commitment, guarantee, or obligation on the part of the United States to any third party, nor shall any third party have any right against the United States for payment solely by virtue of the contribution. Any security or debt financing instrument issued by the infrastructure bank shall expressly state that the security or instrument does not constitute a commitment, guarantee, or obligation of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2765BB6A030042CA9588BE13AB7BBE9A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Management of Federal funds</header><text>Sections 3335 and 6503 of title 31, United States Code, shall not apply to funds contributed under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA9AED02EEF3145759C74086028A9C622"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Program administration</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2015 through 2019, a State may expend not to exceed 2 percent of the Federal funds contributed to an infrastructure bank established by the State under this section to pay the reasonable costs of administering the bank.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1192D12F8B5448959CB69B67CB6D5E7B"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Secretarial review</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall review the financial condition of each infrastructure bank established under this section and transmit to Congress a report on the results of such review not later than 90 days after the completion of the review.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE84AE43B770462F9AC1C3021B734292"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For grants to States for the initial capitalization of infrastructure banks there are authorized to be appropriated $500,000,000 for fiscal year 2015 and for each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HE6027C37153242C2A7C5FEAFBFB8015F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H6306225680344D268EBBD6BFCEE891C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community learning center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community learning center</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4201(b)(1) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7171">20 U.S.C. 7171(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BD5534456AB485F8710B9781DFCAFF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Educational service agency</header><text>The term <quote>educational service agency</quote> means a regional public multiservice agency authorized by State statute to develop, manage, and provide services or programs to local educational agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE78BD5E137F04FB4BA786E2CAD494FEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible charter school entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible charter school entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H61BF3E4CBF0849E6AE9B62427E6052DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a charter school (as defined in section 5210 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221i">20 U.S.C. 7221i</external-xref>)); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD9B5B4F57634DF0A35B538E9F7794D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a developer (as so defined) that has applied to an authorized public chartering agency (as so defined) to operate a charter school.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B1AC162A1C64CEEB5D2B242F76C61AF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAADB250DB3BE46A894CE59BA23B82F99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> means a public board of education or other public authority legally constituted within a State for either administrative control or direction of, or to perform a service function for, public elementary or secondary schools in a city, county, township, school district, or other political subdivision of a State, or for such combination of school districts or counties as are recognized in a State as an administrative agency for its public elementary or secondary schools.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28D79D8927A04A00A0F772C29EF788DF" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term includes any other public institution or agency having administrative control and direction of a public elementary or secondary school.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H746C40BF2BE7424899598AFC05C61C43" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term includes an elementary or secondary school funded by the Bureau of Indian Affairs but only to the extent that such inclusion makes such school eligible for programs for which specific eligibility is not provided to such school in another provision of law and such school does not have a student population that is smaller than the student population of the local educational agency receiving assistance under this Act with the smallest student population, except that such school shall not be subject to the jurisdiction of any State educational agency other than the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BD88240C64244F1AA93353F20372107"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Outlying area</header><text>The term <term>outlying area</term> means the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3375D0640EE4D7CA8AA1EE6C7F5EF56"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public library</header><text>The term <term>public library</term> means a library that serves free of charge all residents of a community, district, or region, and receives its financial support in whole or in part from public funds. Such term also includes a research library, which, for the purposes of this sentence, means a library that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC10E903DEF8C403D9F790748264E26D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>makes its services available to the public free of charge;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14B680CA03284FB686A9E59330426254"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has extensive collections of books, manuscripts, and other materials suitable for scholarly research which are not available to the public through public libraries;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57CF09E4BB3746808F3E8AC9A050C3A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engages in the dissemination of humanistic knowledge through services to readers, fellowships, educational and cultural programs, publication of significant research, and other activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B584850AED745EF98E1A34956E662A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not an integral part of an institution of higher education.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD93B80F1D7946D7A4A4EFA6B3F78D46"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each of the outlying areas.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


