<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA6EBE23D8AA04AEF9821343EC2E641F2" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 404 IH: To authorize early repayment of obligations to the Bureau of Reclamation within the Northport Irrigation District in the State of Nebraska.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 404</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150116">January 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize early repayment of obligations to the Bureau of Reclamation within the Northport
			 Irrigation District in the State of Nebraska.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H27A5521FAED346DD88E5534E26AA6BF7" style="OLC">
		<section id="H4CFD4304EF0B4F05AEA95D3B8FDEC3FF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Early repayment of construction costs</header>
 <subsection id="H379A83E19671464FB570DF29F4867E95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 213 of the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/390mm">43 U.S.C. 390mm</external-xref>), any landowner within the Northport Irrigation District in the State of Nebraska (referred to in this section as the <quote>District</quote>) may repay, at any time, the construction costs of project facilities allocated to the landowner’s land within the District.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC03BD1AC156E4D9CB276D71FE27F1EEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of full-Cost pricing limitations</header><text>On discharge, in full, of the obligation for repayment of all construction costs described in subsection (a) that are allocated to all land the landowner owns in the District in question, the parcels of land shall not be subject to the ownership and full-cost pricing limitations under Federal reclamation law (the Act of June 17, 1902, 32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093), and Acts supplemental to and amendatory of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/371">43 U.S.C. 371 et seq.</external-xref>), including the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/13/390aa">13 U.S.C. 390aa et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEA02B4D7F9C649CE82036930C0575250"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>On request of a landowner that has repaid, in full, the construction costs described in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior shall provide to the landowner a certificate described in section 213(b)(1) of the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/390mm">43 U.S.C. 390mm(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3C252BD2C12C49BBBFCEF089725C8AD2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> <paragraph id="H5DEA4DE45CBC4DB3BB92485B820C17DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies any contractual rights under, or amends or reopens, the reclamation contract between the District and the United States; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04FF2777133D421C99DBBE209630D121"><enum>(2)</enum><text>modifies any rights, obligations, or relationships between the District and landowners in the District under Nebraska State law.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


