<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD825CE4B3F5840F7BF43B976F0F94A47" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1921 IH: GRAD Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1921</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150421">April 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer of Minnesota</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To facilitate the expedited review of applications of aliens applying for admission to the United
			 States under section 101(a)(15)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act
			 who are coming to the United States to participate in a program under
			 which they will receive graduate medical education or training, require
			 the Secretary of State to provide relevant Foreign Service officers with
			 training regarding such aliens, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0E198935F37F40E9BD508692EF72020A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8C64C74664934E57A370F09B804A88B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grant Residency for Additional Doctors Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>GRAD Act of 2015</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7B25C0CBB8224B64A5553E105300B8AE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited review of certain J–1 visas and training for Foreign Service officers</header> <subsection id="HBEBD44506BEE47BEB9B5A64737EF2A86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expedited review</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall designate an officer or employee of the Department of State whose sole responsibility during the months of March, April, May, June, and any other period of time as determined appropriate by the Secretary, shall be to facilitate the expedited review of applications of aliens applying for admission to the United States under section 101(a)(15)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(J)</external-xref>) who are coming to the United States to participate in a program under which such aliens will receive graduate medical education or training.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBBE28CDB2C5F4C9DAE5C6D536BD18B41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall provide to relevant Foreign Service officers training related to medical graduates and medical graduate programs in the countries in which such officers are serving. Such training shall be part of the training provided to such officers under section 701 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4021">22 U.S.C. 4021</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


