<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3FD4399610F345E69138C69262125D8E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1131 IH: Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1131</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for the refinancing of certain Federal student
			 loans, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6032E4F1615B4DFBAF2DDFFD1A1C9A93" style="OLC">
 <section id="H350663B683C24C87B15E3567DDBFED64" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5C7B3BEA89E14F44AD86565CDFBCC438"><enum>2.</enum><header>Refinancing programs</header> <subsection id="H1919E9EE8BF6484283ABBC21C8FA5187"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authority</header><text>Section 451(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H66C70BF1E5804FA89DE00B27BA043B98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>(2)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H215BC5AD1C0B4627BBB1142D2899657B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>; and (3) to make loans under section 460A and section 460B</quote> after <quote>section 459A</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C5FC9CBFDBF4C9D90852DE0F91316D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Refinancing Program</header><text>Part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73021884738F4F11A9325093C2F040EE" style="OLC">
					<section id="H56EF0826868D4B198D522B12D9D9579C"><enum>460A.</enum><header>Refinancing FFEL and Federal Direct Loans</header>
 <subsection id="H6E5DC51F61BD4BA0A4DD990EFA9BB837"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary, upon the receipt of an application from a qualified borrower, reissues the borrower's original loan under this part or part B as a loan under this part, in accordance with the provisions of this section, in order to permit the borrower to obtain the interest rate provided under subsection (c)).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H08286A0E60CF45C5B0A3F2536B7AC5A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reissuing Loans</header>
 <paragraph id="H288096FA3F39414193727C70F0D85A43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal Direct Loans</header><text>Upon application of a qualified borrower, the Secretary shall reissue a Federal Direct Stafford Loan, a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, a Federal Direct PLUS Loan, or a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan of the qualified borrower, for which the first disbursement was made, or the application for the reissuance of a loan under this section was received before July 1, 2015, in an amount equal to the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5E115FC9C9C14FD99D389301C7616151"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the unpaid principal, accrued unpaid interest, and late charges of the original loan; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1415976F00D481C8C9DD68C452BD95C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the administrative fee under subsection (d)(3).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H305F810449AB4E7BACD272E96A2CF58D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discharging and reissuing FFEL Program loans as refinanced Federal Direct Loans</header><text>Upon application of a qualified borrower for any loan that was made, insured, or guaranteed under part B and for which the first disbursement was made before July 1, 2010, the Secretary shall reissue such loan as a loan under this part, in an amount equal to the sum of the unpaid principal, accrued unpaid interest, and late charges of the original loan and the administrative fee under subsection (d)(3), to the borrower in accordance with the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0066803FE3504D39BF72F10248DC0962"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary shall pay the proceeds of such reissued loan to the eligible lender of the loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, in order to discharge the borrower from any remaining obligation to the lender with respect to the original loan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H578D46928A1C4041A8498FF1EE80DC47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall reissue—</text> <clause id="HC3218C7594344E61A41FE6CCB3D4C355"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a loan originally made, insured, or guaranteed under section 428 as a Federal Direct Stafford Loan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB1612714ADDE4133863486D908899DCE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a loan originally made, insured, or guaranteed under section 428B as a Federal Direct PLUS Loan;</text> </clause><clause id="HC509C9797DC54825AAED50667F7293C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a loan originally made, insured, or guaranteed under section 428H as a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF60695ADABE4D6593841110DCC5BEDB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a loan originally made, insured, or guaranteed under section 428C as a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB6A7E4487B4384BE636B40FE18B835"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The interest rate for each loan reissued under this paragraph shall be the rate provided under subsection (c)).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5751A5E9EF8E4FF384DD93E402257BD4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interest rate</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4283A8E8E6564ADF859E8398A4158781"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interest rate for the reissued Federal Direct Stafford Loans, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans, Federal Direct PLUS Loans, and Federal Direct Consolidation Loans, shall be a rate equal to the high yield of the 10-year Treasury note auctioned at the final auction held prior to the first day of the month in which the application for reissuance under this section is received, plus 1.0 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D7778FE0BCE483D9ACF178CB749A494"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fixed Rate</header><text>The applicable rate of interest determined under paragraph (1) for a reissued loan under this section shall be fixed for the period of the loan.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA066D30FEDFD463FA8D88CCB3986148A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms and conditions of loans</header>
 <paragraph id="H78748B98AB9B49E98774A7F6A140F575"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A loan that is reissued under this section shall have the same terms and conditions as the original loan, except as otherwise provided in this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64B1B5606766478086A91E861B34A581"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No automatic extension of repayment period</header><text>Reissuing a loan under this section shall not result in the extension of the duration of the repayment period of the loan, and the borrower shall retain the same repayment term that was in effect on the original loan. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prevent a borrower from electing a different repayment plan at any time in accordance with section 455(d)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5398CE070FF0499E9A7445CF61E360C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative fee</header><text>The Secretary shall charge the borrower of a loan reissued under this section an administrative fee of not more than 0.5 percent of the sum of the unpaid principal, accrued unpaid interest, and late charges, of the original loan.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1245A911FC5E4610882BA167E5FF33DD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition of qualified borrower</header>
 <paragraph id="H5C4C94353EFC4EC5BDB6268BC5C2D440"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified borrower</term> means a borrower—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B97A5A3281E45109D17C4D941FC32DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of a loan under this part or part B for which the first disbursement was made, or the application for reissuance under this section was received, before July 1, 2015; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD0A236800ED47E6ACAFF017373D8071"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who meets the eligibility requirements based on income or debt-to-income ratio established by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3968B5C9F3914238BD76C4493F63A3BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Income requirements</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish eligibility requirements based on income or debt-to-income ratio that take into consideration providing access to refinancing under this section for borrowers with the greatest financial need.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7A6CA3FFF27F4A32A3CDE21CA1B8CFEE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expiration of authority</header><text>The Secretary's authority to reissue loans under this section shall expire on the date that is determined in accordance with section 4 of the <short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title>.</text>
						</subsection></section><section id="H3C68FA85FC92489BB40C4AAB3DAA7DC9"><enum>460B.</enum><header>Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan program</header>
 <subsection id="H6FF76B86FFA04F0D86EA4EA2E35330C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H21DAF847EFE74CC79702FE4E9351D6BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible private education loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible private education loan</term> means a private education loan, as defined in section 140 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1650">15 U.S.C. 1650</external-xref>), that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA9E73E5B3AC345F3970E71EFF55FC583"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was disbursed to the borrower before July 1, 2015; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D27D4DF60F24B8E86B2FC25F2D1530E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was for the borrower’s own postsecondary educational expenses for an eligible program at an institution of higher education participating in the loan program under this part or part B, as of the date that the loan was disbursed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63659752FAAA4983A7FCB2971D48452A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan</header><text>The term <term>Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan</term> means a loan issued under subsection (b)(1).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BEABC2FA32F4C129A2D5E2F47095F34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Private educational lender</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>private educational lender</term> has the meaning given the term in section 140 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1650">15 U.S.C. 1650</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82C6A59882F3493A8D952EAF76801150"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified borrower</header><text>The term <term>qualified borrower</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="HA8249BA3046A46518EFAAAD64327BAEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has an eligible private education loan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD47544DF90F5402D9F5BA857FB033425"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been current on payments on the eligible private education loan for the 6 months prior to the date of the qualified borrower's application for refinancing under this section, and is in good standing on the loan at the time of such application;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA454A9F75314FD897418A6A9A6DDF74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not in default on the eligible private education loan or on any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part or part B or E; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6192A2AEF10B44CEACC223B54D75CB89"><enum>(D)</enum><text>meets the eligibility requirements based on income or debt-to-income ratio established by the Secretary under subsection (b)(2).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E8F5F47CD66441284E08A7FB3F3A211"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H3539E799FB9145C284BFA596820E4E31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall carry out a program under which the Secretary, upon application by a qualified borrower, shall issue such borrower a loan under this part in accordance with the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFF045BA54F6445FCBFDEC9267A833B23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The loan issued under this program shall be in an amount equal to the sum of the unpaid principal, accrued unpaid interest, and late charges of the private education loan and the origination fee under subsection (f).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F95C819D177400F88D29D727BDCA2CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall pay the proceeds of the loan issued under this program to the private educational lender of the private education loan, in order to discharge the qualified borrower from any remaining obligation to the lender with respect to the original loan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H274A3D2C386543BEB5C75F9285820514"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary shall require that the qualified borrower undergo loan counseling that provides all of the information and counseling required under clauses (i) through (viii) of section 485(b)(1)(A) before the loan is reissued in accordance with this section, and before the proceeds of such loan are paid to the private educational lender.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H532EE031B112408A916ED984B0011A01"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary shall issue the loan as a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan, which shall have the same terms, conditions, and benefits as a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, except as otherwise provided in this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H001406CD601843238EA1C0B04F637125"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Income requirements</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish eligibility requirements based on income or debt-to-income ratio that take into consideration providing access to refinancing under this section for borrowers with the greatest financial need.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAD99055C760423E897C29282AC63A0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interest rate</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H790878D952DC4ECB9254AB760FCABF12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The interest rate for a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan shall be a rate equal to the high yield of the 10-year Treasury note auctioned at the final auction held prior to the first day of the month in which the application for reissuance under this section is received, plus 1.0 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF028B57541A04A97A31A0909F22118E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fixed Rate</header><text>The applicable rate of interest determined under this subsection for a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan shall be fixed for the period of the loan.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20058DD2C4814BDAABC1A1096794129A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No inclusion in aggregate limits</header><text>The amount of a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan, or a Federal Direct Consolidated Loan to the extent such loan was used to repay a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan, shall not be included in calculating a borrower's annual or aggregate loan limits under section 428 or 428H.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDEC172C16A644F3EBCF2E2959C864AE1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No eligibility for service-Related repayment</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 428K(a)(2)(A), 428L(b)(2), 455(m)(3)(A), and 460(b), a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan, or any Federal Direct Consolidation Loan to the extent such loan was used to repay a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan, shall not be eligible for any loan repayment or loan forgiveness program under section 428K, 428L, or 460 or for the repayment plan for public service employees under section 455(m).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA1E046EBCC2C4AE4B3F7513FBA6D3886"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Origination fee</header><text>The Secretary shall charge the borrower of a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan an origination fee that equals the origination fee charged for Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans disbursed on the date upon which the Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan is issued.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF9887C16B7E425E8821766C40804AF4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expiration of Authority</header><text>The Secretary's authority to reissue loans under this section shall expire on the date that is determined in accordance with section 4 of the <short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41909D256DD34EF196BCD59693CEA1C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendments to public service repayment plan provisions</header><text>Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE14D03E0ABA4D198455A26A53747E6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AC890129D4846889A53E9F6CD1AF81E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A40BD89D60B4DA89CD07B2A815E9EAF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB410B1D2E1554783A9E234A94A22651A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules for section 460A loans</header> <subparagraph id="H67E9E401F1FE4C6BADFE263B36C4E680"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Refinanced Federal Direct loans</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), in determining the number of monthly payments that meet the requirements of such paragraph for an eligible Federal Direct Loan reissued under section 460A that was originally a loan under this part, the Secretary shall include all monthly payments made on the original loan that meet the requirements of such paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B6D2F87C1D645C39C5F036139EAF2EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Refinanced FFEL loans</header><text>In the case of an eligible Federal Direct Loan reissued under section 460A that was originally a loan under part B, only monthly payments made after the date on which the loan was reissued may be included for purposes of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4B851059E6D43A692CD4480A337DD37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A) (as redesignated by paragraph (1) of this subsection), by inserting <quote>(including any Federal Direct Stafford Loan, Federal Direct PLUS Loan, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, or Federal Direct Consolidation Loan reissued under section 460A)</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H764C269836B34B0B95E754EAA903B422"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Income-Based repayment</header><text>Section 493C of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098e">20 U.S.C. 1098e</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AA49B4F99394A85A782E73E807433F4" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HB8F158F3756145C38C34F667EC21B711"><enum>(f)</enum><header> Special rule for refinanced loans</header>
 <paragraph id="H562D73172FC34F19802AF04A66978881"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Refinanced Federal Direct and FFEL loans</header><text>In calculating the period of time during which a borrower of a loan that is reissued under section 460A has made monthly payments for purposes of subsection (b)(7), the Secretary shall deem the period to include all monthly payments made for the original loan, and all monthly payments made for the reissued loan, that otherwise meet the requirements of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29948D4FB9C84C858903845449B83420"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loans</header><text>In calculating the period of time during which a borrower of a Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan under section 460B has made monthly payments for purposes of subsection (b)(7), the Secretary shall include only payments—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H05BA274F260C406AA1D95B81A391B2B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that are made after the date of the issuance of the Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H549C3688FF43495FB1D9B2653813BDE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that otherwise meet the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB26BDC26A39346F9AB28FA884DC3D74E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Fair share tax on high-income taxpayers</header>
 <subsection id="HCADCFF57EA264BBA8CAF05B73457CF23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA879673B03D0454DA24E103FF25C3B73" style="OLC">
					<part id="HFD533E36684643169DDDB491739DEBD9"><enum>VII</enum><header>Fair share tax on high-income taxpayers</header>
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="HA05236875C464243990E1111966AB256" level="section">Sec. 59A. Fair share tax.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="HA05236875C464243990E1111966AB256"><enum>59A.</enum><header>Fair share tax</header>
							<subsection id="H37EAEDBE5388464F988E0700C2A3F5A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header>
 <paragraph id="H085E64E58A7648218516AB729BD83B6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Phase-in of tax</header><text>In the case of any high-income taxpayer, there is hereby imposed for a taxable year (in addition to any other tax imposed by this subtitle) a tax equal to the product of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H16B1DD594F734BB38D1DC735C429AE99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount determined under paragraph (2), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED7E8373FF2944BEBC141E6DE16A07D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a fraction (not to exceed 1)—</text>
 <clause id="HA46A763DB72A464CB4691D88080ECBD1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the numerator of which is the excess of—</text> <subclause id="H7659B2F0303642A09167CE585C97BCF6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the taxpayer's adjusted gross income, over</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9138590517FC4F09AC1BAF6E269762B9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the dollar amount in effect under subsection (c)(1), and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HC9C3541A3C1041CE86E0A864B908FF2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the denominator of which is the dollar amount in effect under subsection (c)(1).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB38BF74FAEEC4BE8A017BFE915939B25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of tax</header><text>The amount of tax determined under this paragraph is an amount equal to the excess (if any) of—</text> <subparagraph id="HA444F71F3DBD4150A1ADF8CD254F4EC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the tentative fair share tax for the taxable year, over</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0725B52724E845C19A317D098048DD75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the excess of—</text> <clause id="HA5A666E35C8D4114B84D6EFDD0A97E5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sum of—</text>
 <subclause id="HF49C41719E9B48D1B6C23AD94D11AACE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the regular tax liability (as defined in section 26(b)) for the taxable year,</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8636594B450B4048B419BCE257CA3134"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the tax imposed by section 55 for the taxable year, plus</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9D0B19DF228843DF91D6424974061A82"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the payroll tax for the taxable year, over</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HDBA006AE436142539E0B74E25D8A0F99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the credits allowable under part IV of subchapter A (other than sections 27(a), 31, and 34).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EE86D98B6D64966B2572D93B9EFE3BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tentative fair share tax</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H12063EBCCF174280B406063AD3CFB2C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The tentative fair share tax for the taxable year is 30 percent of the excess of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H46CB58B37F1948CA9B79D0E36210F1C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer, over</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EABBE44960449B99D5891EF8CE8030A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the modified charitable contribution deduction for the taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D089ECD59DD47A7BE106732D6CB88E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modified charitable contribution deduction</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2132BBE39ED4632B5623F163C43CA5E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The modified charitable contribution deduction for any taxable year is an amount equal to the amount which bears the same ratio to the deduction allowable under section 170 (section 642(c) in the case of a trust or estate) for such taxable year as—</text>
 <clause id="H29E60CE24FCA46DABDA18020F1ECE0DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of itemized deductions allowable under the regular tax (as defined in section 55) for such taxable year, determined after the application of section 68, bears to</text>
 </clause><clause id="H06ABAD3538F1430B8CF7D31C721E47BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such amount, determined before the application of section 68.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE46B9DC7B88B46148D23106E824D10A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Taxpayer must itemize</header><text>In the case of any individual who does not elect to itemize deductions for the taxable year, the modified charitable contribution deduction shall be zero.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65FA47FBA89146B2A754D0EF6042E4A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>High-Income taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H6A3E638416FE4291BA2367C1F8D7E1AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>high-income taxpayer</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, any taxpayer (other than a corporation) with an adjusted gross income for such taxable year in excess of $1,000,000 (50 percent of such amount in the case of a married individual who files a separate return).</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H744EF5F4B5634D03A73B1EDCDBDED1CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF37FDCB09791442CA6A222598BB43886"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a taxable year beginning after 2016, the $1,000,000 amount under paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <clause id="H7BA374C32DCB4BDA89AE71E0BF4D73E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </clause><clause id="H844E365E843D492D840A142AF7DAB270"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2015</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C56CAC358F14523A30D2F370AED5D84"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any amount as adjusted under subparagraph (A) is not a multiple of $10,000, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $10,000.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H425113BA7E504E75BF6E43EE05A584F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payroll tax</header><text>For purposes of this section, the payroll tax for any taxable year is an amount equal to the excess of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9F16A8FD4502441EADED7352247D1226"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the taxes imposed on the taxpayer under sections 1401, 1411, 3101, 3201, and 3211(a) (to the extent such taxes are attributable to the rate of tax in effect under section 3101) with respect to such taxable year or wages or compensation received during the taxable year, over</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE0336318FD54D628DD7F25607C3052E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the deduction allowable under section 164(f) for such taxable year.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC54FDA66CEEA4B63B62F0215E10C57D0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rule for estates and trusts</header><text>For purposes of this section, in the case of an estate or trust, adjusted gross income shall be computed in the manner described in section 67(e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9B07AF06291D48DE9728602BF9BA905B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Not treated as tax imposed by this chapter for certain purposes</header><text>The tax imposed under this section shall not be treated as tax imposed by this chapter for purposes of determining the amount of any credit under this chapter (other than the credit allowed under section 27(a)) or for purposes of section 55.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H14D8BF0BA81E46B0AD1E2560A35871B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/26">Section 26(b)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03F1A164716945199CB7185E7A7802AE" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H2E0C0C62985F4A6DBB338826AA3BEBC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 59A (relating to fair share tax),</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H57281A98C10A454CB7FF8EBA0B349154"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of parts for subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H627C254A91BF44DBB1DE588227142745" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="HFD533E36684643169DDDB491739DEBD9" level="part">Part VII—Fair share tax on high-Income taxpayers</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D9C6C24A5C44FFC940DB78CE2C55B99"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HCCD003ACF27A487A8A441DE3D97116F2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Deficit Neutral Implementation of Student Loan Refinancing Programs</header> <subsection id="HDA2CE69F57464AD09E75F824EB79A9A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amount of revenue</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title>, the Secretary of Education shall estimate the amount that is equal to the amount of the net increase in revenue received in the Treasury during the 10-year period beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title> attributable to the amendments made by section 3 of the <short-title>Fairness in Student Loan Lending Act</short-title>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59445262F66441EC8A876AA54B7F6693"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deficit-Neutral Termination of the Refinancing Program</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall terminate the refinancing programs carried out under sections 460A and 460B of the Higher Education Act of 1965 on the date that the net cost of carrying out such refinancing programs is equal to the amount of additional revenue estimated under <internal-xref idref="HDA2CE69F57464AD09E75F824EB79A9A0" legis-path="4.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4D5478B076ED444B9093C7454DB15E91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text>When estimating cost and revenue under this section, the Secretary shall utilize the accounting methods and assumptions that are used by the Congressional Budget Office, as of the date of enactment of this Act, to make such estimations.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2F187964B17542FAA0C87E5B70BD8827"><enum>5.</enum><header>Undue hardship exceptions to discharge</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 523(a)(8) of title 11, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>dependents, for</quote> and all that follows through the end of subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>dependents, for an educational benefit overpayment or loan made, insured, or guaranteed by a governmental unit or made under any program funded in whole or in part by a governmental unit or an obligation to repay funds received from a governmental unit as an educational benefit, scholarship, or stipend;</quote>.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


