<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H144D327FC1EA40929F1BB6E02FB0F8A8" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3932 IH: Ensuring Continued Operations and No Other Major Incidents, Closures, or Slowdowns Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3932</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947, to provide for the mandatory appointment of a
			 board of inquiry into slow-downs, strikes, or lock-outs when certain
			 specified events occur, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF35EFDCE6B0C4C9E8D34920865E12217" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA12C5E91350147E5BC8649F1961F9CC8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Continued Operations and No Other Major Incidents, Closures, or Slowdowns Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ECONOMICS Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD5E1CD3D18EA46BCBF83CF11AB92081D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conditions requiring appointment of board of inquiry</header> <subsection id="H018EF1149D7D44DB9E24AD1F97FB341F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 206 of the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/176">29 U.S.C. 176</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB6A5B93323FB49328E04609D171FA331"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Whenever in the opinion</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) Whenever in the opinion</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5C88C7CB2B54D9E9D2BB404F429E576"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a threatened or actual strike</quote> and inserting <quote>a slow-down, or a threatened or actual strike or lock-out</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E0C0FA2857C4298946FBBA2D4D9F446"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AEB194AB46842A1BFD367D6588F3EFD" style="traditional"> <subsection id="HD6C6C57FE2C340B39C1DBFD6184AA4D5"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The President shall appoint a board of inquiry described in subsection (a) not later than 10 days after any of the following events occur:</text>
 <paragraph id="HAD6143258FEB488E81D92875358CE155"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The U.S. Census Bureau reports that the monthly Import or Export Vessel Value decreased by 20 percent or more in any one month from the previous month in any one of the four metric identification regions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE78700534C4E3EA7504DDC3BE20314"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A slow-down, or a threatened or an actual strike or lock-out takes place at four or more port facilities in any one of the four metric identification regions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D418496A8AA4C59BDB20BB0B5AEB267"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A slow-down, or a threatened or an actual strike or lock-out occurs in which the total number of employees actively striking, locked-out, or slowing down at the affected port facilities in any one of the four metric identification regions, is 6,000 or greater.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9BF4FA175DE46BCA0C47A54A5D25834"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever a board of inquiry is appointed as required by the occurrence of any of the events described in subsection (b), such board shall submit a written report to the President not later than 10 days after its appointment. If a board of inquiry is appointed as required due to the occurrence of the event described in paragraph (1) of such subsection, such board shall include in its report an assessment as to whether a slow-down, or a threatened or an actual strike or lock-out contributed to the occurrence of such an event resulting in the board’s appointment. If the board determines that a slow-down, or a threatened or an actual strike or lock-out did contribute to the occurrence of such an event, the board shall also include in its report the additional criteria established in subsection (a). The President shall file a copy of such report with the Service and shall make its contents available to the public.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83B6B498E7C6468A9B1B35538CB93A63"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>metric identification region</quote> means one of the four regions into which each of the Nation’s maritime ports is classified by the Secretary of Transportation in accordance with section 4 of the <short-title>Ensuring Continued Operations and No Other Major Incidents, Closures, or Slowdowns Act</short-title>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8219D9147CBB4A03B72B281C845E2BCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 208(a) of the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/178">29 U.S.C. 178(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC665CDC86D0F4413AA87F1CE77A5A072"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such strike or lock-out</quote> and inserting <quote>such slow-down, strike, or lock-out</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD1BD844C190F4FA391CA86A9598B3EE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such threatened or actual strike</quote> and inserting <quote>such slow-down, or threatened or actual strike or lock-out</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAB2DB21DB5D84DE081633FA261595A37"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study and recommendations for additional conditions requiring appointment of board of inquiry</header> <subsection id="H342C800A546E4FF28AF0EDA2A56CB2E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Transportation Statistics shall collect the following data relating to activity at port facilities in the United States:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H9839B3598175485996636EDB9C7AE7A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The average number of lifts per hour of containers by crane.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5E6E4834E1184FE69D5948D93A5AFD73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The average cargo container dwell time.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H35BAB47CA712490587B51AEFFA853DE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The average truck times at ports.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HADF77F468CD0411981F95DE608C1AE9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The average rail time at ports.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8C358D24E6743909A6D98FC9C31940A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall transmit a report to Congress containing recommendations for determining whether conditions exist requiring the appointment of a board of inquiry pursuant to section 206(b) of the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947, using the data required to be collected in accordance with subsection (a), or any other metric recommended by the Director.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H93A3BA2A7B214A8A94DB7CAF4839EEE7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Classification of ports into regions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall classify the Nation’s maritime ports as belonging to one of the following four metric identification regions:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5B1EF79A54FD4963B5F7D606691C0D09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>West Coast.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H535DB31C77F54D6E8AAE3926EB230F89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>East Coast.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BE73374F534411B85359582BD75A001"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Gulf Coast.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD9D554F7584E8EA9764E47AE67F9BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Great Lakes.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


