<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F880D9D7DE0441989F4F8788613A155" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 965 IH: Facilitating Participation in Clinical Data Registries Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 965</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150213">February 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the issuance of guidance on the application of the Federal policy for the protection of human subjects with respect to clinical data registries.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H499A3A64673543CCAD91519D5152E05E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6EF47C16F109473288897E201ACECFEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Facilitating Participation in Clinical Data Registries Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3B9FF9AB1E604DF6A2C23A89C099C158"><enum>2.</enum><header>Guidance on application of Common Rule to clinical data registries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, through the Office for Human Research Protections of the Department of Health and Human Services, shall issue guidance on the application with respect to clinical data registries of the provisions of subpart A of part 46 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, or equivalent Federal regulations for the protection of human subjects in research.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


