<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7133434ED57D482FA31B354B4077D9DB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2256 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit an annual report on the Veterans Health Administration and the furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2256</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit an annual report on the Veterans Health Administration and the furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE9286DB92BCB427A8684A224066CAEC0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC9EFE3243B894CF1B5BDC79E14AB29DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited a the <quote>Veterans Information Modernization Act</quote>. </text></section> <section id="HE7BAD7AAE74A4DC0868B2A7101F49AE6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on Veterans Health Administration and furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care</header> <subsection id="H1D79A6970B38484299FACC1D67DB7AC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HBF53FC423D13428DBC85FCC5A2A749AD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H0F91BE4B9E644E0F82D10C104D453CD5"><enum>7330B.</enum><header>Annual report on Veterans Health Administration and furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care</header> 
<subsection id="HF8B89A129805476695A8B18F7834E34F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care under the laws administered by the Secretary and on the administration of the provision of such care and services by the Veterans Health Administration during the calendar year preceding the calendar year during which the report is submitted.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H36D465070EE145A78D31A072C09E3904"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text>Each report required by subsection (a) shall include each of the following for the year covered by the report:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD9B9E1D3CB2149FABE1B4FDEF3E288C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of the effectiveness of the Veterans Health Administration program in increasing the access of veterans eligible for hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care furnished by the Secretary to such care.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8228824994C4E159E640C403EF7F455"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An evaluation of the effectiveness of the Veterans Health Administration in improving the quality of health care provided to such veterans, without increasing the costs incurred by the Government or such veterans, which includes the relevant information for each medical center and Veterans Integrated Service Network of the Department set forth separately.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30FAA1CD9BF7405F8349DE293DC10321"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D9A5FE1930047228743A0A6A3DA1286"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the workload of physicians and other employees of the Veterans Health Administration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H461F50FC31F54D0BB007500866C6E287"><enum>(B)</enum><text>patient demographics and utilization rates;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0154FD273DBE4603886B6A5C8CDA218D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>physician compensation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5470CD94611545A196447B26207D2A9B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the productivity of physicians and other employees of the Veterans Health Administration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EABB064B23640E0BB01CF2874B7960A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the percentage of hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care provided to such veterans in Department facilities and in non-Department facilities and any changes in such percentages compared to the year preceding the year covered by the report; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD056B5B6812496BA901149CD3E25ADA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>pharmaceutical prices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD3B404A79C81497699A02E2E79664E81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <quote>hospital care</quote>, <quote>medical services</quote>, <quote>nursing home care</quote>, and <quote>non-Department facilities</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 1701 of this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDA59C221E6154431AEB8A1A699792249"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7330A the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H7401B9350C754A07A26B73541150F3F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">7330B. Annual report on Veterans Health Administration and furnishing of hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

