<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H61419460F8E14FB496DD21C1DE5B2B7F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 336 IH: To direct the Administrator of General Services, on behalf of the Archivist of the United States, to convey certain Federal property located in the State of Alaska to the Municipality of Anchorage, Alaska.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 336</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Administrator of General Services, on behalf of the Archivist of the United States,
			 to convey certain Federal property located in the State of Alaska to the
			 Municipality of Anchorage, Alaska.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8C6682FCD89D4354A7CBA4541ECA3D5A" style="OLC">
		<section id="H6465D2110EEF497AA0877C8E67A41E23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Real property conveyance</header>
 <subsection id="H9F6069B3ECE34FA89D84325F70283F34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act and after completion of the survey and appraisal described in this section, the Administrator of General Services, on behalf of the Archivist of the United States, shall convey to the City by quitclaim deed for the consideration described in subsection (c), all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to a parcel of real property described in subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H872F09E08F1D4EA3B798DFB6356E0BFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal description of property</header>
 <paragraph id="H87FFE97D95004501BACC2D1B7FFFCEFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The parcel to be conveyed under subsection (a) consists of approximately 9 acres and improvements located at 400 East Fortieth Avenue in the City that is administered by the National Archives and Records Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2ABF4B6AAD674A2789273A32B38D275B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Survey required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the exact acreage and legal description of the real property to be conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined by a survey, paid for by the City, that is satisfactory to the Archivist.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD93AC00FDB4640DA8BCF2299BE72C5F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
				<paragraph id="H49E27E91BDA64EE3A7843E471EC6F4E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consideration</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1FDB2C413BD846B4AD08C25E0DF61A4D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As consideration for the conveyance of the property under subsection (a), the City shall pay to the Archivist an amount not less than the fair market value of the conveyed property, to be determined as provided in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5795C5C6EA6F4789B88765079D406B18"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appraisal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fair market value of the property to be conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined based on an appraisal that—</text>
 <clause id="HA2C5A4E6EA8A43D98649E3B6DBD8B889"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is conducted by a licensed, independent appraiser that is approved by the Archivist and the City;</text> </clause><clause id="HB77C8072A24E4AF38AC1651B1DA1EFF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is based on the highest and best use of the property;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4F9BF8605E3A4C23BCBF9178051C390D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is approved by the Archivist; and</text> </clause><clause id="HC8E99B5D68B24B388DCE85CCAECC47D1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is paid for by the City.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59158DD133034845BFA8C973C99208CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preconveyance entry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Archivist, on terms and conditions the Archivist determines to be appropriate, may authorize the City to enter the property at no charge for preconstruction and construction activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7507E694E18472FBC55B3D1231E18C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Archivist may require additional terms and conditions in connection with the conveyance under subsection (a) as the Archivist considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCCB3508BEFB144A192053D33B678A3AD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>City defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>City</term> means the Municipality of Anchorage, Alaska.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

