<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB3BC421E28FD41688AC557B13D653656" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2472 IH: Everson Walls and Ron Springs Gift for Life Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2472</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a National Organ and Tissue Donor Registry Resource Center, to authorize grants for State organ and tissue donor registries, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE360FB345E924C8E92196FB70865166F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2C9819A8E8334EF18A73F416C782CC78" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Everson Walls and Ron Springs Gift for Life Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF244A28C2D5B49F7A6360E2370233798"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Organ and Tissue Donor Registry Resource Center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part H of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/273">42 U.S.C. 273 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 371A the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D62CF454B8A4350B8E90F491270C7DD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H892351696CD547959173939DDCAB45F4"><enum>371B.</enum><header>National Organ and Tissue Donor Registry Resource Center</header> 
<subsection id="HCDB17CF19DD24475B570E2F92DFF65BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall establish a National Organ and Tissue Donor Registry Resource Center (referred to in this section as the <quote>Center</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA184026DB08444FA8BFC7C5878063A97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Center shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H34C7A4FAC9604007BE6A0309F3066AE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advance the development, expansion, and evaluation of State organ and tissue donor registries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC6149A4C2444C4793BF41CE0514C9D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate timely access to and exchange of accurate donor information between State registries 7 days each week on a 24-hour basis;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3981BF10C5CE404B941B7DC35489428A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that State organ and tissue donor registries funded through section 371C are in compliance with the requirements described in such section, including the operating standards described in section 371C(d);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58D4D8D49EFB47E4A7BA8E17F423F55D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to States for the establishment and operation of State organ and tissue registries; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE8FCCD9FFD4402B91067AD4C98ABA49"><enum>(5)</enum><text>maintain a registry information clearinghouse, including by maintaining a Web site, to collect, synthesize, and disseminate best practices information about organ and tissue donor registries.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9BDE2AA85D3D47559A0B1C7BFE2CF770"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this section. This section shall be carried out, for fiscal years 2016 through 2020, using amounts otherwise available for such purpose.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H820463FD5368439684B73091C3725F2B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for State organ and tissue donor registries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part H of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/273">42 U.S.C. 273 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 371B, as inserted by section 2, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B2FE32D22B04A4B91F8CCCEFA484A59" style="OLC"> <section id="H308CCAA32BE44C698B1BD040E4CC3B01"><enum>371C.</enum><header>Grants for State organ and tissue donor registries</header> <subsection id="HCC6F744E256043F0BF4D079502002BC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to support the development, enhancement, expansion, and evaluation of State organ and tissue donor registries.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H11663F4EB90F49E0BBD6A4B4876480E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State agency or a State contracted entity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8658947C808F4BD0B6995DFC4065C906"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>As a condition on the receipt of a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to use the grant or cooperative agreement—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2D3C9DCE4D384C8999AF7CE3891B817B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop, expand, or maintain a State organ and tissue donor registry; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H977CB7C0C35F4405AF4BB1454281D544"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to establish benchmarks for improvement in organ and tissue donation in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7979EEE3035C40C788DF1C8E7F011D61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Operating standards</header><text>As a condition on the receipt of a grant or cooperative agreement under this section for a State organ and tissue donor registry, an eligible entity shall agree to maintain the registry in accordance with the following:</text> <paragraph id="H25BF27427B354FBEA9DF7FC8B39E98EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The registry must allow a donor or any other person authorized by the donor to include in the registry a statement or symbol that the donor has made, amended, or revoked an anatomical gift.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFECB6FA436D24D778ACB7347E33D3AD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The registry must be accessible to any qualified organ procurement organization described in section 371(b) to allow the organization to obtain relevant information on the registry to determine, at or near the death of the donor or a prospective donor, whether the donor or prospective donor has made, amended, or revoked an anatomical gift.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1F81FCC75784F69BF3C36A735A3CFFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The registry must be accessible as described in paragraphs (1) and (2) 7 days each week on a 24-hour basis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D66220075234874A5445481BBFF27F1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The registry must ensure that personally identifiable information on the registry about a donor or prospective donor may not be used or disclosed without the express consent of the donor or prospective donor for any purpose other than to determine, at or near the death of the donor or prospective donor, whether the donor or prospective donor has made, amended, or revoked an anatomical gift.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7AE39BBC781741ACAE33191EEE6C568E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB3EDDC7600A4FCFBBC108F653C1816F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>As a condition on the receipt of a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, not later than 180 days after receipt of the grant or cooperative agreement, and every 180 days thereafter (through the date of completion of the activities funded through the grant or cooperative agreement), an eligible entity shall prepare and submit a report to the Secretary that—</text> <paragraph id="HA9835319BF9F4EBB8D9CE9E1D60F78A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the manner in which such entity has used amounts received through the grant or cooperative agreement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5200BD88C814011903F0325D141A203"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses initiatives that may be replicated in other States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB61B37592A5442A38A53CF5EB02D7ECE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this section. This section shall be carried out, for fiscal years 2016 through 2020, using amounts otherwise available for such purpose.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HE25C3BFB331948978D8D169F505C1376"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part H of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/273">42 U.S.C. 273 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 371C, as inserted by section 3, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEA377C12DCA42BAA15E489EFBDFE00D" style="OLC"> <section id="H065DCC5368B54714B83BA8B41CEC2BCE"><enum>371D.</enum><header>Limitation on liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No person may be held civilly liable by reason of having harvested or taken an individual’s organs or tissues without having obtained valid consent for the harvesting or taking, if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H97F13EFBFAAC4D91B7C750EA0A5B1A84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such person has verified that, at the time of the harvesting or taking, the individual is registered as a donor with a State organ and tissue donor registry; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB063DC342C684F38AD99CD04BD9B392A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the harvesting or taking is within the scope of the consent given by such individual for purposes of such registration.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H93EB2C1C61314143890BF4BAE0E0B835"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study on feasibility of establishing a living donor database</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 371A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/273a">42 U.S.C. 273a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4876928B810C4DB0A5BEB5E8AB237BDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary may establish</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general.—</header-in-text>The Secretary may establish</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC98666A491BB41ED9EF202102E26EF29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92760FFF200445D9B2CCD6253284E006" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H0BB2926B7D914283A704C057EBD6FE09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Everson Walls and Ron Springs Gift for Life Act of 2015</short-title>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0521FBF59A8B4C64998FB7212DEDBA47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complete a study to determine the feasibility of establishing a living donor database for the purpose of tracking the short- and long-term health effects for such donors associated with living organ donation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C1D58321A6B479E82F9B4BAA3A9FD56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report to the Congress on the results of such study.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

