<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB97621AF15184E90A8E3A8226281F84B" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1267 IH: To exempt certain class A CDL drivers from the requirement to obtain a hazardous material endorsement while operating a service vehicle with a fuel tank containing 3,785 liters (1,000 gallons) or less of diesel fuel.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1267</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000182">Mr. Neugebauer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To exempt certain class A CDL drivers from the requirement to obtain a hazardous material endorsement while operating a service vehicle with a fuel tank containing 3,785 liters (1,000 gallons) or less of diesel fuel.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H1A187298FB0742488E7A21077B37CB36" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7495657709E049EE9F70ABD8F8A5339E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Hazardous material endorsement exemption</header> 
<subsection id="HA8979BEB201C4BDFA2C64D485058B669"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5117(d)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8FEE717108E745F08C085B310CEBE240"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F148217377749CBBCCF4E537C0833C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC88692B261374A5CA373E7551CDFC73C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H160E86C729F7495CBEF08E03F9D7565A" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HB3AA3661397343688DB1D5A757DACA17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a service vehicle carrying diesel fuel in quantities of 3,785 liters (1,000 gallons) or less that is—</text> <clause id="HE185BE45DB3C49B0A9E4A55E6C82FE72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>driven by a class A commercial driver's license holder who is a custom harvester, an agricultural retailer, an agricultural business employee, an agricultural cooperative employee, or an agricultural producer; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF7FE335BEACF46EBAAD002F99132A6DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>clearly marked with a placard reading <term>Diesel Fuel</term>.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4B6CE605F6044957929051EA2A153951"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 31315(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAD74721F3244DA49A504F7EB9796016" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H554778572B784B8EA686D80E5F94338C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Hazardous materials endorsement exemption</header><text>The Secretary shall exempt all class A commercial driver's license holders who are custom harvesters, agricultural retailers, agricultural business employees, agricultural cooperative employees, or agricultural producers from the requirement to obtain a hazardous material endorsement under part 383 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, while operating a service vehicle carrying diesel fuel in quantities of 3,785 liters (1,000 gallons) or less if the tank containing such fuel is clearly marked with a placard reading <term>Diesel Fuel</term>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

