<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H15F6310411EC46F4A9247CB0BC196B38" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3830 IH: Reducing Gun Violence in our Neighborhoods Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3830</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151026">October 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reduce gun violence, increase mental health counseling, and enhance the tracking of lost and
			 stolen firearms.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H01BFB6834BC24C02B3B5BE2F3310B6C4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H31FD2974C712448CAD95B0D5E8B84491" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reducing Gun Violence in our Neighborhoods Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF80064C545F64E2E9167D707DFF79C92"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tax on firearms</header> <subsection id="H1A9B4BB30C48402E9364CF1010BB5647"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4181">Section 4181</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H853A0D81F7644DFD91052AE964322681"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>There is hereby</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF37F341E9F8A4BF39796FA79E8E3336E" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H9616D3496F4C44F7A4C62A9B40DA3FDF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1067FD9DD9274F47AF2552C8138E64C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H810367A52B6A4E7091233F327F45E830" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H509D85C42216486BB96124D8A80060C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional tax on firearms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the tax imposed by subsection (a), there is hereby imposed upon the sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any firearm a tax in the amount of $100.</text>
						</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53F09269BAFD4480960BDB43433F1F52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption for firearms acquired for law enforcement</header><text>Section 4182 of such Code is amended by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e) and by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF87E80A8C8984187962FF9B0A4CD1937" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H8E5BBE3F423B42AAB1CE3BAF93DA78F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption from additional tax for firearms acquired for law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tax imposed by section 4181(b) shall not apply to any firearm which is purchased by the United States or by a State or local government for police or other law enforcement purposes.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6BC7433B19F543C686ACF4C8EA2974E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to sales in calendar months beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HDAF6E39834C44B3CAD1930BFF0E78802"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Gun Violence Reduction and Mental Health Counseling Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="HF424E7A5EF6E49B690F79D6887FAE2FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HB14FC3B923524E6CA80C29320AB0BF69">
					<section id="HB1F974EA68324313AAE1ACE043D4C692"><enum>9512.</enum><header>Gun Violence Reduction and Mental Health Counseling Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="HDFD9B7C53851452E9B0264DB555F5E0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of trust fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Gun Violence Reduction and Mental Health Counseling Trust Fund</quote>, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to such fund as provided in this section or section 9602(b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4D90A39DF0A241D4B28DF38317D29B47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to trust fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the Gun Violence Reduction and Mental Health Counseling Trust Fund amounts equivalent to taxes received in the Treasury under section 4181(b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC7F986E9BA994DD7B571E598AE887C83"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Gun Violence Reduction and Mental Health Counseling Trust Fund shall be available, without need of further appropriation and without regard to any fiscal year limitation, as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H81E213DAEE544E06B3D618194EC6ADDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of such amounts for making expenditures to carry out, with respect to block grants for community mental health services, subparts I and III of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x">42 U.S.C. 300x et seq.</external-xref>), and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F917544E11C45BD8102AC3EC2A326AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of such amounts for making expenditures to carry out subpart 1 of part E of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3750">42 U.S.C. 3750 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
							</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Amounts made available under this subsection shall supplement and not supplant amounts otherwise
			 made available to carry out the provisions referred to this subsection.</continuation-text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFFEE57DA3DEA4A16BB2C2A152901C73A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter A of chapter 98 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E3C844184554E1685AD18FF1ABE9B55" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HB14FC3B923524E6CA80C29320AB0BF69" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="HB1F974EA68324313AAE1ACE043D4C692" level="section">Sec. 9512. Gun Violence Reduction and Mental Health Counseling Trust Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H478876478B4B408EAB92A0BE6B359816"><enum>4.</enum><header>Passive capability to identify lost and stolen firearms</header>
			<subsection id="H854F9F0B49D64D1686D06DCF7C582085"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of national standard</header>
 <paragraph id="HFBEEB5EA70FB4D258FAE7C8E34B5B571"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall, in consultation with the National Institute for Standards and Technology, establish in regulations a national standard for the incorporation of a passive identification capability into all firearms sold in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H923C278D44594C14B548972A601F7579"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Passive identification capability defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>passive identification capability</quote> means a technology that—</text> <subparagraph id="H257E524377EA48B4984CD7309651E43C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enables a firearm to be identified by a mobile or fixed reading device; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4958C14FF974B34930D7DB34C10BEB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not emit or broadcast an electronic signal or other information that would enable the firearm or its owner to be monitored or tracked.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47A14D50A1694D00850F15397E816575"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing the standard, the Attorney General shall give equal priority to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HDDE34AEDCE4D407ABC03065F100B0AFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The right of firearm owners to maintain their full right to privacy under the 4th Amendment and their right to legally own firearms under the 2nd Amendment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0158A5D682FD41639AFD9580A99E6379"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The ability of law enforcement authorities to use the capability to track lost and stolen guns.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA71553EE85F4FC69EF30A4D3F4772AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The ability of manufacturers to incorporate the capability using existing firearm manufacturing processes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50D2D82CFF75451499885B0B8CE538C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The resistance to tampering and destruction of the technology used to incorporate the capability.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H422477950EA94F6198196CD5A70E3A62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition; penalty</header> <paragraph id="H77F6C6F62E4E4229B93F8DBD57E2C4C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, to manufacture a firearm that does not have a passive identification capability that meets the national standard established under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAF2D182973347B490894E9774EA8D89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>After notice and opportunity for hearing, the Attorney General shall impose on a person who violates paragraph (1) a civil money penalty in such amount, not exceeding $1,000 per firearm, as the Attorney General shall prescribe in regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H643D8DE3DB414B28B0929053C2DA3479"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall take effect on such date as the Attorney General shall prescribe in regulations that is not later than 3 years after the establishment of the national standard under subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H158F236A40384E3296DC3F5BD9BBCD9F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting of lost and stolen firearms</header>
 <subsection id="H0683D00393A940E7AE10A030CF500B44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives shall establish a database of firearms reported to be lost or stolen in the United States, which shall be known as the <quote>National Database of Lost and Stolen Firearms</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0ABA4E370A9A40FC8D2B6C6CACC28C5D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The database shall include the following information with respect to each firearm reported to the database:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB4C2867DE9134EA2BFE719D05BBD303B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the firearm, including the type of the firearm.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H237CC68BC233402395CE4939B5405C48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether the firearm is reported lost or stolen.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DA51BDA53E24FB9B2FFE0974E975E98"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The date of the report.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC507E2C1C7B243228F47D0AED40738C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The name of the owner of the firearm, if known.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61D4FCA9E9FA4245B815055D5D26F493"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The name and location of the person from whom the firearm was obtained, if known.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H70EA8717367E492A9C120449E514895F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The location where the firearm is reported to have been lost or stolen.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FDAB418ECB74EC8BE900906574076EC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Whether the firearm has been reported to the database as having been recovered, since being reported to the database as lost or stolen.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B1A0D4D7B5441938AE29396DDD74917"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of database</header><text>The information in the database shall be made available to all Federal, State, and local law enforcement authorities.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H274A36C10074491AA66B017053752767"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting of lost or stolen firearms to local law enforcement authorities</header>
 <paragraph id="H900A48B1568A459FBDC2B116B410276F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91879D56750946E7B89BD7BE56347D5F" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7A12BD41E4424F35B14927920B11B124"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 48 hours after a person who owns a firearm that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce discovers the theft or loss of the firearm, the person shall report the theft or loss to local law enforcement authorities.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6F143CCF0244A4EB639823C37F5A26A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Section 924 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C9B7D7A8EDE4C04B805142A6C79734B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HDA0C8A7C353C42F8814D5549B4EA246D"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Penalty for failure To report loss or theft of firearm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever violates section 922(aa) shall be fined $10,000 with respect to each firearm involved in the violation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EA28F5847F84B99BFC7D50FBCE44E95"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirement that local law enforcement authorities report lost or stolen firearms to the national
 registry</header><text>Within 7 days after a local law enforcement authority receives a report that a firearm is lost or stolen, the authority shall transmit the report to the National Database of Lost and Stolen Firearms.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


