<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2997E0A1FBEF48C38796CB012E4EE1EB" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1925 IH: To award a Congressional Gold Medal to Dr. Balazs “Ernie” Bodai in recognition of his many outstanding contributions to the Nation, including a tireless commitment to breast cancer research.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1925</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150421">April 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B000213">Mr. Barton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000613">Mr. Dold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000063">Mr. Yoder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To award a Congressional Gold Medal to Dr. Balazs <quote>Ernie</quote> Bodai in recognition of his many outstanding contributions to the Nation, including a tireless
			 commitment to breast cancer research.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE84B2C0FD89F46349103C4533F66DC8B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H25D35B47CA0344F6A18B473C4B8AB5E6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H8E777A4F0BC34D1FAC3532C5F71CC8E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dr. Balazs <quote>Ernie</quote> Bodai was born in Budapest, Hungary, in 1951.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76713FC55D6D4510AEBAE92E5C05364C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As a child, Dr. Bodai and his family lived in a bomb shelter for over a year during the Hungarian Revolution of 1956 before managing to escape and immigrate to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H503B99FA0D7146F7B7ADC9CB13A220F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Dr. Bodai received his B.A. and M.S. degrees from the University of California, Los Angeles, and subsequently received his M.D. degree from the University of California, Davis, at the young age of 26.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91697D95F9D2402BA086652B235A36FA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Dr. Bodai has authored over 250 medical articles and published 5 books, 4 of which focus on cancer.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H63FFCF29F2D5442EB1DABAF858CD94C7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>After working as a breast cancer surgeon for over 30 years and treating more than 15,000 patients, Dr. Bodai remains frustrated with the pace of breast cancer research funding.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02925FB9F55A47399A6E5C7AEC7385BF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 1996, Dr. Bodai launched a campaign to create a postal stamp to benefit breast cancer research.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H087949AA132547DC82F40DA5FC14E9CB"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After several trips to Washington, DC, and countless visits with United States Senators and Members of Congress, the Stamp Out Breast Cancer Act, which allowed a breast cancer stamp to be sold at up to 8 cents above the normal first-class rate, was passed and signed into law in August 1997.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6596DA682D740E38D9A802F8FE1F5E5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As a direct result of Dr. Bodai’s tireless commitment to breast cancer research, as of February 2015, more than 985,000,000 breast cancer stamps have been sold in the United States—providing over $80,000,000 for crucial, life-saving research.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CA59D242F384ABD8AC6D988F975B8B9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Breast Cancer Research Stamp recently surpassed the Elvis Presley Stamp to become the all-time best seller for the United States Postal Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1674484CEADC45968D09E41170ED8E64"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In an effort to expand breast cancer research internationally, in 2005, Dr. Bodai introduced the first ever <quote>global stamp</quote> to raise awareness and funding to conquer the disease worldwide.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10A9D57E2E9044C88CE135B85E8FC26B"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of 2014, as a direct result of Dr. Bodai’s tireless commitment, over 70 countries have either created their own stamp or are in the process of doing so—making breast cancer research, early detection, and eradication a global health priority.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5EEB513925A4A58B42FF8B66EED28B8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header>
 <subsection id="HFAD0AD96F73841ED9E2298FE4713CEA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of the Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design, to Dr. Balazs <quote>Ernie</quote> Bodai in recognition of his many outstanding contributions to the Nation, including a tireless commitment to breast cancer research.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1347DE64307E44FA84C6D7355CE90A96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions to be determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2C2C41CF183A4D49875204020CCB6796"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 2 under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses, and the cost of the gold medal.</text>
		</section><section id="H87B63B0D62CC4E018B406A0F5F827FC5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Status of medals</header>
 <subsection id="HF7C20E55289D4456BD3EE3A79D21B57F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H32168CDCEEC546F297A880641AAC9619"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


