<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0D1E5AF62AC3478BB2BB56CCAD3968D0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 594 IH: Waters of the United States Regulatory Overreach Protection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 594</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150128">January 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000373">Mr. Ashford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000456">Mr. Fleming</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001057">Mr. Huelskamp</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001060">Mr. Hurt of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000182">Mr. Neugebauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000602">Mr. Pompeo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000570">Mr. Ryan of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001179">Mr. Schock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000364">Mr. Shimkus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000238">Mr. Thornberry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001070">Mr. Hardy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000413">Mr. Whitfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000796">Mr. Westmoreland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001045">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000445">Mr. Forbes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000367">Mr. Amash</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To preserve existing rights and responsibilities with respect to waters of the United States, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H46FBC31D70914D809E71F648FBE1209C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H05C28D8EE7E64AFAB5C58870CD8717BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Waters of the United States Regulatory Overreach Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H12C198BAFB4F414B9CB9C25416B39FD9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rules and guidance</header> <subsection id="H1EB8D25021E444FFB9C05C0FF3992429"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of waters protected by the Clean Water Act</header> <paragraph id="HB5EAB1CE213B44B3AF7BE749EDC2C9B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator are prohibited from—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD2F54A6DBA224ADF864E085DA40A0C62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing, finalizing, adopting, implementing, applying, administering, or enforcing—</text> <clause id="H86EED6D066CC43DDB329A1D46023102A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proposed rule described in the notice of proposed rule published in the Federal Register entitled <quote>Definition of <quote>Waters of the United States</quote> Under the Clean Water Act</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 22188 (April 21, 2014)); or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD4C0797D54864D03B4A89AC456181B3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proposed guidance submitted to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget for regulatory review under Executive Order 12866, entitled <quote>Guidance on Identifying Waters Protected By the Clean Water Act</quote> and dated February 17, 2012 (referred to as <quote>Clean Water Protection Guidance</quote>, Regulatory Identifier Number (RIN) 2040–ZA11, received February 21, 2012); or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7663A43525544066A8EAC7C3788C982C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>using the proposed rule or proposed guidance described in subparagraph (A), any successor document, or any substantially similar proposed rule or guidance, as the basis for any rulemaking or decision regarding the scope or enforcement of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35414C0991344961A5E20E0C8C1CDBFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of rules and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of the proposed rule or proposed guidance described in paragraph (1)(A), any successor document, or any substantially similar proposed rule or guidance, as the basis for any rulemaking or decision regarding the scope or enforcement of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act shall be grounds for vacating the final rule, decision, or enforcement action.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC0282B9254B14B7A83C95EC30B69BEDE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption for certain agricultural conservation practices</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H7061186661824B71A3DAB5859483B396"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Administrator are prohibited from developing, finalizing, adopting, implementing, applying, administering, or enforcing the interpretive rule described in the notice of availability published in the Federal Register entitled <quote>Notice of Availability Regarding the Exemption from Permitting Under Section 404(f)(1)(A) of the Clean Water Act to Certain Agricultural Conservation Practices</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 22276 (April 21, 2014)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA5A832AD14F04ACDB1CC790A4CD698BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Administrator shall withdraw the interpretive rule described in paragraph (1), and such interpretive rule shall have no force or effect.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC00637E6A05342A6B48C960EE6F01FF8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 404(f)(1)(A) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(f)(1)(A)</external-xref>) shall be applied without regard to the interpretive rule described in paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA4C6C35A2EC94F03B8F0508DE896F19E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federalism consultation</header>
 <subsection id="H6D4D535425CF4064963AC4330A67E12C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall jointly consult with relevant State and local officials to develop recommendations for a regulatory proposal that would, consistent with applicable rulings of the United States Supreme Court, identify—</text>
 <paragraph id="H257D06D04F994CF9847CB4779FFEF565"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the scope of waters covered under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF401C20FAE07409FBD90F0CBDADB9308"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the scope of waters not covered under such Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA2F0A6AC92544BDAAA87DDF05D67C15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation requirements</header><text>In developing the recommendations under subsection (a), the Secretary and the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3FB79EA0CDC944EC8D3B312CB0D5758F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide relevant State and local officials with notice and an opportunity to participate in the consultation process under subsection (a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFD0E9D561B74D4E9003066B363F5B7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to consult State and local officials that represent a broad cross-section of regional, economic, and geographic perspectives in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE8D0075B33F4BF3BA66F651BD0A8885"><enum>(3)</enum><text>emphasize the importance of collaboration with and among the relevant State and local officials;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BE6316D4E78487ABE3191E3F8FEBDE8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>allow for meaningful and timely input by State and local officials;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD866390B2BEF446FBA3C39D13BEF60EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>be respectful of maintaining the Federal-State partnership in implementing the Federal Water Pollution Control Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF28401923434B13AB1092090D7F6013"><enum>(6)</enum><text>take into consideration the input of State and local officials regarding matters involving differences in State and local geography, hydrology, climate, legal frameworks, economies, priorities, and needs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03CF4F54BD3844B49C6706D3DCB4CAB3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>promote transparency in the consultation process under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5CF7086AE054184AD3A4B1CC5D509E9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>explore with State and local officials whether Federal objectives under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act can be attained by means other than through a new regulatory proposal.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55B548E1F47544A1BC25C7F62A56AA57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="HBC174CDCAEC447FEB357ADF06AF64E72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register a draft report describing the recommendations developed under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB7279EF82637430E9AD9A02023E8CD79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consensus requirement</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator may include a recommendation in the draft report only if consensus has been reached with regard to the recommendation among the Secretary, the Administrator, and the State and local officials consulted under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2444FD6EE284FF0BB1251435CF3CFF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Failure to reach consensus</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary, the Administrator, and the State and local officials consulted under subsection (a) fail to reach consensus on a regulatory proposal, the draft report shall identify that consensus was not reached and describe—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3A36290B260845EAB4B93E8A1B44D686"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the areas and issues where consensus was reached;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB45916BCC7642C18E85A57A0ABDE31B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the areas and issues of continuing disagreement that resulted in the failure to reach consensus; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEFC6613FD244FB99145CFC94BFFE0CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the reasons for the continuing disagreements.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EC902BB04D248F68E190CBDF8F63424"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duration of review</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall provide not fewer than 180 days for the public review and comment of the draft report.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DB92557F0E94679B948660170870595"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall, in consultation with the relevant State and local officials, address any comments received under paragraph (4) and prepare a final report describing the final results of the consultation process under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6927D1C408EA4403879DE6FFED382205"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission of report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Administrator shall jointly submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and make publicly available the final report prepared under subsection (c)(5).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H61321E9D3FD34F65A21040D241325E1C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H2AC1FAC4E19840A79A50CD99F9047CA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C7564A55B0446FE84D520FC9CB2CAEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H787D937ACFFC455A9517F850A07B3DAA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State and local officials</header><text>The term <term>State and local officials</term> means elected or professional State and local government officials or their representative regional or national organizations.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


