<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H06B7AA17681449FF8DC52E3C7E2603C2" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2062 IH: Protecting Student Athletes From Concussions Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2062</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To promote State requirements for local educational agencies and public elementary and secondary
			 schools relating to the prevention and treatment of concussions suffered
			 by students.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8B2D6AF1BEAA4C889768B8D3BD71E1BD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7B9DBFAFC0AA4C2B967BA97BC9EB8963" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Student Athletes From Concussions Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFFD3D21FF5514597908403E22D0AFE26"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minimum State requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part E of title IX of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7901">20 U.S.C. 7901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H16DE2D551358450C81C04406727D667F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the heading relating to subpart 2 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H318DA2CE8A0A4599AA98801746465A05" style="OLC"> <subpart id="HC2B52638F93745C58367C660E47FE0DB"><enum>3</enum><header>Other provisions</header></subpart><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD4890545FC64ADF8CAF28B5F6195DDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subpart 1, the following new subpart:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3612774208C4E1C84C9EA6DD06467BF" style="OLC">
					<subpart id="HB8AB290891CA4D9FB4C6816A532F45AF"><enum>2</enum><header>State requirements for the prevention and treatment of concussions</header>
						<section id="H45F8CAD9799C4E44A481F160C9FB6D29"><enum>9511.</enum><header>Minimum State requirements</header>
 <subsection id="H01EFC46263194BF784C712931465E7AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning fiscal year 2017, as a condition of receiving funds under this Act for a fiscal year, a State shall, not later than July 1 of the preceding fiscal year, certify to the Secretary in accordance with subsection (b) that the State has in effect and is enforcing a law or regulation that, at a minimum, establishes the following requirements:</text>
 <paragraph id="H18C6B6227AF54607B203CC7AF1088448"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agency concussion safety and management plan</header><text>Each local educational agency in the State (including each charter school that is considered a local educational agency under State law), in consultation with members of the community in which the local educational agency is located, shall develop and implement a standard plan for concussion safety and management for public schools served by the local educational agency that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H16E6A792FB13422E9A629FBDCE341F5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the education of students, parents, and school personnel about concussions, including—</text> <clause id="HA9637C257C2F4E208F369F2B2D5657AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the training of school personnel on evidence-based concussion safety and management, including on prevention, recognition, risk, academic consequences, and response for both initial and any subsequent concussions; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HACC4C0DA1E6140D2917B810A59575DFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>using, maintaining, and disseminating to students and parents release forms, treatment plans, observation, monitoring, and reporting forms, recordkeeping forms, and post-injury and prevention fact sheets about concussions;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACC8A32A50D7488D826DDC709F7CD34D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supports for each student recovering from a concussion, including—</text> <clause id="H83E375D90BA14C3AB4A175DC6120E6C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>guiding the student in resuming participation in school-sponsored athletic activities and academic activities with the help of a multidisciplinary concussion management team, which shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="HB89192331AF6472D817BF1AFBC9C2F65"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a health care professional, the parents of such student, and other relevant school personnel; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H177626A226354494A96DD41EDDA41849"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an individual who is assigned by the public school in which the student is enrolled to oversee and manage the recovery of the student;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H941A05552ADC40F581190B735CB5914B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing appropriate academic accommodations aimed at progressively reintroducing cognitive demands on such a student; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1252A512061A454C95150AC3D2B8250A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the student’s symptoms of concussion persist for a substantial period of time—</text> <subclause id="H3DE4A72118304547AF4DB04CE58FC39C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>evaluating the student in accordance with section 614 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1414">20 U.S.C. 1414</external-xref>) to determine whether the student is eligible for services under part B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1411">20 U.S.C. 1411 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H49983F4502EF409C8D1568055D99B09A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>evaluating whether the student is eligible for services under section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CC51D7262124943BB2216652997D77B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>best practices designed to ensure, with respect to concussions, the uniformity of safety standards, treatment, and management, including—</text>
 <clause id="H6BDA5D7B493B4A68AC52231AD2A5942C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disseminating information on concussion safety and management to the public; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCFE6376E8E0A45948AEAB917555D2E77"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applying best practice and uniform standards for concussion safety and management to all students enrolled in the public schools served by the local educational agency.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6423C368DA5446C391120BB1D1034DAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Posting of information on concussions</header><text>Each public school in the State shall post on school grounds, in a manner that is visible to students and school personnel, and make publicly available on the school website, information on concussions that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H04A2A14C98B1458C9C1F1874758E9AAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is based on peer-reviewed scientific evidence or consensus (such as information made available by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE35BE4B1161C460ABA12E320E088DE38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include—</text> <clause id="H8393C7CCEFEF4EA98B5A4C9F4B77C543"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the risks posed by sustaining a concussion or multiple concussions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H90D879736704420CACF5C13C129C381D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the actions a student should take in response to sustaining a concussion, including the notification of school personnel; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B741F8C58A941ABB4516FF77F4C81AC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the signs and symptoms of a concussion; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BCEF2F092354AA39C454D10724C3F02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may include—</text>
 <clause id="HC1A9FFDAF02243E3AC0BC2D291738E1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the definition of a concussion under section 9512(1);</text> </clause><clause id="HE1422C511E5745CDA30A7551108BFAD9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the means available to the student to reduce the incidence or recurrence of a concussion; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC315D032EEE84720928BF024340C10DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effects of a concussion on academic learning and performance.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2DF80D939604CC8AA8C3005D2364612"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Response to a concussion</header><text>If any school personnel of a public school in the State suspect that a student has sustained a concussion during a school-sponsored athletic activity or other school-sponsored activity—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7B83ADD798D142D48173850B9BD9AB5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the student shall be—</text> <clause id="H7DD21626292046CC996616C8311EFDB4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>immediately removed from participation in such activity; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA897C9B8EF3445ECA8478CE5B658AFD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prohibited from resuming participation in school-sponsored athletic activities—</text> <subclause id="H6CC481EFBC624634975D6310E62947E0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on the day the student sustained the concussion; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7E6BD90A0C5A49CE9DC4614414292BA1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">until the day the student is capable of resuming such participation, according to the student’s written release, as described in paragraph (4);</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF2CDB4AE89841E6B83D2E1AD8F0932F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the school personnel shall report to the concussion management team—</text> <clause id="H939F1478186B45F49F43681C880AAC54"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the student may have sustained a concussion; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6978FF87246A43E4ABF5B11265C697AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all available information with respect to the student’s injury; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H328D01637B2344E48A4CBCFE2928FD9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the concussion management team shall confirm and report to the parents of the student—</text>
 <clause id="HEC3A0A5D36BA427C87C8040CC692469C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the type of injury, and the date and time of the injury, suffered by the student; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8CAC8A7D1CB04E6799CFCFC1C7A942CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any actions that have been taken to treat the student.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DECB0548523472D89B62B819F3B714C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Return to athletics</header><text>If a student enrolled in a public school in the State sustains a concussion, before the student resumes participation in school-sponsored athletic activities, the relevant school personnel shall receive a written release from a health care professional, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9EE90D83EE7F42B5B2842C3C295AEC77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may require the student to follow a plan designed to aid the student in recovering and resuming participation in such activities in a manner that—</text>
 <clause id="H52CB325DDAA74DDA8C76B6A1A7D27661"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is coordinated, as appropriate, with periods of cognitive and physical rest while symptoms of a concussion persist; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3EC3DCEF36543E595929DD3608B79F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reintroduces cognitive and physical demands on the student on a progressive basis so long as such increases in exertion do not cause the reemergence or worsening of symptoms of a concussion; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06CEEEFE43CE45DC924C782FC497B87C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">states that the student is capable of resuming participation in such activities once the student is asymptomatic.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B08A30EF93344BC8521106238CC3A70"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Return to academics</header><text>If a student enrolled in a public school in the State has sustained a concussion, the concussion management team (as described under paragraph (1)(B)(i)) of the school shall consult with and make recommendations to relevant school personnel and the student to ensure that the student is receiving the appropriate academic supports, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H64B245F86B8248AAB74BF336C4AA74AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing for periods of cognitive rest over the course of the school day;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FA722BB117D4D8BBFF5788A927D7447"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing modified academic assignments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0004E020BF2444EB560D2FBE5BE3B06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allowing for gradual reintroduction to cognitive demands; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B423048F4E84DBA86297ED2EB922202"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other appropriate academic accommodations or adjustments.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37F008DB658B494B8747D7F6FC6357C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification requirement</header><text>The certification required under subsection (a) shall be in writing and include a description of the law or regulation that meets the requirements of subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD9C605C689FD43D08BC480EE3E2AF17C"><enum>9512.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text> <paragraph id="H52E0310772B14726A2BD45B5F55CCC10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Concussion</header><text>The term <term>concussion</term> means a type of mild traumatic brain injury that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5A8E4EC5D70641EC89A8B7F23B7709DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is caused by a blow, jolt, or motion to the head or body that causes the brain to move rapidly in the skull;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2887CD89884641A6BCFF1B4C968B49D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disrupts normal brain functioning and alters the physiological state of the individual, causing the individual to experience—</text>
 <clause id="H1F77159D7B49400ABE4A9E1E94D6D306"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any period of observed or self-reported—</text> <subclause id="H52CEAEF65BBF41DE937195559CCB2081"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transient confusion, disorientation, or altered consciousness;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7F41A94B807B43249A0F8DE22C171D7D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>dysfunction of memory around the time of injury; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5DFDABA5C0AF4551A42974A076F732D9"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disruptions in gait or balance; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCC3D6B41A9AF49EC977D134C9AF2F703"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>symptoms that may include—</text> <subclause id="HA8FF23B930E74F1A80AA47F9B8BF041C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>physical symptoms, such as headache, fatigue, or dizziness;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBF190428212F4917B9FE78D1771C3C2B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cognitive symptoms, such as memory disturbance or slowed thinking;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4548870E60694271AFFE9B03C433328D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>emotional symptoms, such as irritability or sadness; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6B7F7A58F1384500A6608FF5B0621C7C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>difficulty sleeping; and</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H699E68A43E9D478E80454F2598FD0AAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>occurs—</text>
 <clause id="H12D86D5887474CDE8328C2020BE420A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with or without the loss of consciousness; and</text> </clause><clause id="H895AB71093CD433E8F5B821D550490B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during participation—</text>
 <subclause id="H280AC5C73D064B8ABE6C24B00DF550D2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in a school-sponsored athletic activity; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFA964DDD067945738D94201640761716"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in any other activity without regard to whether the activity takes place on school property or during the school day.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AC02F6C20D74A46980FA016F278BCFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care professional</header><text>The term <term>health care professional</term> means a physician (including a medical doctor or doctor of osteopathic medicine), nurse, athletic trainer, physical therapist, neuropsychologist, or other qualified individual—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA83D470CCD2D4FA98191FE306B9B99A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is registered, licensed, certified, or otherwise statutorily recognized by the State to provide medical treatment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73870601705B44BB9F0DB0E2C224D5F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose scope of practice and experience includes the diagnosis and management of traumatic brain injury among a pediatric population.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A91ACCA52CB4CBDB328CC24393A9F1F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public school</header><text>The term <term>public school</term> means a public elementary school or public secondary school.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3747BC9B57094140AD639F4F8559733F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School personnel</header><text>The term <term>school personnel</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4151, except that such term includes coaches and athletic trainers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2E17FB9AC5F46EC85F931DB0C1A1005"><enum>(5)</enum><header>School-sponsored athletic activity</header><text>The term <term>school-sponsored athletic activity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB47B682E8FA44D9EA9BFC0F84E0EC5B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any physical education class or program of a public school;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25A88147FDD74A3FBB8B2C721C96F409"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any athletic activity authorized by a public school that takes place during the school day on the school’s property;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF217552353FD47C8A2C9DFF21411FBF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any activity of an extra-curricular sports team, club, or league organized by a public school; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7389DAC3E38642CB93A226A2314691D6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any recess activity of a public school.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H9494E780445544C8A63DA61C9CB987E3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB509284A23494FA2BD29E45779A5CD1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to the heading of subpart 2 of part E of title IX and inserting the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6F8846AE108443A97D8288142D04E80" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="subpart">Subpart 3. General Provisions</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD007B7EBD4344A11B2CFA6BA63AC63AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 9506, the following new items:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAE6F9F5425A4230B67AEE5FA4351B82" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subpart">Subpart 2. State Requirements for the Prevention and Treatment of Concussions</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9511. Minimum State requirements.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9512. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

