<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" bill-type="appropriations" dms-id="A1" public-print="no" public-private="public" stage-count="1" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2250 RS: Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 116</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2250</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 114–64]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSAP00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20150611">June 11, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type display="yes">AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H7BB60E2EA0CC4906B45F0612E66F6222" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="appropriations">
		<section changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="undesignated-section"><pagebreak></pagebreak>
			<continuation-text changed="deleted" continuation-text-level="section" reported-display-style="strikethrough">That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise
			 appropriated, for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending
			 September 30, 2016, and for other purposes, namely:</continuation-text></section><title changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="idF00F8D03F21445D995B5F75F33D4F0D6" level-type="subsequent" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-style="traditional-section-style" style="traditional-inline"><enum>I</enum><header>LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</header>
			<appropriations-major id="HA5C83A447CA0475E91CDADBCA477531B"><header>House of Representatives</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H5EF0C0ADD2584FB8A8104945859E226F"><header>Payment to Widows and Heirs of Deceased Members of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payment to Tori B. Nunnelee, widow of Alan Nunnelee, late a Representative from the State of Mississippi, $174,000.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H364E618555EB43B5AE11EB340A1FCFCF"><header>Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the House of Representatives, $1,180,736,000, as follows:</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H495926B28038454DA085DDB16E33D45A"><header>House Leadership Offices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses, as authorized by law, $22,278,891, including: Office of the Speaker, $6,645,417, including $25,000 for official expenses of the Speaker; Office of the Majority Floor Leader, $2,180,048, including $10,000 for official expenses of the Majority Leader; Office of the Minority Floor Leader, $7,114,471, including $10,000 for official expenses of the Minority Leader; Office of the Majority Whip, including the Chief Deputy Majority Whip, $1,886,632, including $5,000 for official expenses of the Majority Whip; Office of the Minority Whip, including the Chief Deputy Minority Whip, $1,459,639, including $5,000 for official expenses of the Minority Whip; Republican Conference, $1,505,426; Democratic Caucus, $1,487,258: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That such amount for salaries and expenses shall remain available from January 3, 2016 until January 2, 2017.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HA4AC4C285A424747AB1FDDB7AA57DE4E"><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Members’ Representational Allowances</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H421D4DD069034AA495DCD4E01AFEC453"><header>Including Members’ Clerk Hire, Official Expenses of Members, and Official Mail</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Members' representational allowances, including Members' clerk hire, official expenses, and official mail, $554,317,732.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H958DAC0A09554CAABF9A9901752FCC6A"><header>Committee Employees</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HE1021232F2D14FDD8137E243F762BCAA"><header>Standing Committees, Special and Select</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of standing committees, special and select, authorized by House resolutions, $123,903,173: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That such amount shall remain available for such salaries and expenses until December 31, 2016.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H42D27462AEBE464DABC8A684D6839D8D"><header>Committee on Appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Committee on Appropriations, $23,271,004, including studies and examinations of executive agencies and temporary personal services for such committee, to be expended in accordance with section 202(b) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 and to be available for reimbursement to agencies for services performed: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That such amount shall remain available for such salaries and expenses until December 31, 2016.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HA666082EEDD64BFF85F56C49CCDDBD0C"><header>Salaries, Officers and Employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For compensation and expenses of officers and employees, as authorized by law, $175,713,679, including: for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Clerk, including the positions of the Chaplain and the Historian, and including not more than $25,000, of which not more than $20,000 is for the Family Room and not more than $2,000 is for the Office of the Chaplain, for official representation and reception expenses, $24,980,898; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms, including the position of Superintendent of Garages and the Office of Emergency Management, and including not more than $3,000 for official representation and reception expenses, $14,827,120 of which $4,784,229 shall remain available until expended; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer including not more than $3,000 for official representation and reception expenses, $115,010,000, of which $1,350,000 shall remain available until expended; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Inspector General, $4,741,809; for salaries and expenses of the Office of General Counsel, $1,413,450; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Parliamentarian, including the Parliamentarian, $2,000 for preparing the Digest of Rules, and not more than $1,000 for official representation and reception expenses, $1,974,606; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Law Revision Counsel of the House, $3,119,766; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the House, $8,352,975; for salaries and expenses of the Office of Interparliamentary Affairs, $814,069; for other authorized employees, $478,986.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H21D89133987D402AA506E8C92288AD47"><header>Allowances and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For allowances and expenses as authorized by House resolution or law, $281,251,521, including: supplies, materials, administrative costs and Federal tort claims, $3,625,236; official mail for committees, leadership offices, and administrative offices of the House, $190,486; Government contributions for health, retirement, Social Security, and other applicable employee benefits, $254,447,514, to remain available until March 31, 2017; Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery, $16,217,008 of which $5,000,000 shall remain available until expended; transition activities for new members and staff, $2,084,000, to remain available until expended; Wounded Warrior Program $2,500,000, to remain available until expended; Office of Congressional Ethics, $1,467,030; and miscellaneous items including purchase, exchange, maintenance, repair and operation of House motor vehicles, interparliamentary receptions, and gratuities to heirs of deceased employees of the House, $720,247.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H4893F450CA6649038DD252D907DB8551"><header>Administrative Provisions</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><section id="HD6182433D9A44A049721EC2C5F98FADC"><enum>101.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H508C652D6CCB4A058A59E4C4A97D4324"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring Amounts Remaining in Members' Representational Allowances To Be Used for Deficit
 Reduction or To Reduce the Federal Debt</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any amounts appropriated under this Act for <quote><header-in-text level="subsection">HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES—Salaries and Expenses—Members’ Representational Allowances</header-in-text></quote> shall be available only for fiscal year 2016. Any amount remaining after all payments are made under such allowances for fiscal year 2016 shall be deposited in the Treasury and used for deficit reduction (or, if there is no Federal budget deficit after all such payments have been made, for reducing the Federal debt, in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury considers appropriate).</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H7BC2BAD551214504A1D506BCC2086580" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives shall have authority to prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="HF997ADB1A6434D1EB31069275CBEF444" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>As used in this section, the term <quote>Member of the House of Representatives</quote> means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text> </subsection></section><appropriations-small id="HD095955A1757448FBD294F11FC692368"><header>delivery of bills and resolutions</header> </appropriations-small><section id="HA180C5D04A194201830E4050E623DD00"><enum>102.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to deliver a printed copy of a bill, joint resolution, or resolution to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) unless the Member requests a copy.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="HB91F5ACBB4604F65B625768E36D5F37C"><header>delivery of congressional record</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="H12FA890A6AD24966960E83DF3E237F1E"><enum>103.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to deliver a printed copy of any version of the Congressional Record to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress).</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H804B90981B074762AB77C784E24211C6"><header>limitation on amount available to lease vehicles</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="HB0031F0ED01F4A49BF5AD88C5E77F9A0"><enum>104.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives to make any payments from any Members' Representational Allowance for the leasing of a vehicle, excluding mobile district offices, in an aggregate amount that exceeds $1,000 for the vehicle in any month.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H7018A66647C44B57B79D01695DC038F5"><header>limitation on printed copies of u.s. code to house</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="H443F28D6B3AD4958A47DE692DDF44116"><enum>105.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to provide an aggregate number of more than 50 printed copies of any edition of the United States Code to all offices of the House of Representatives.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H5E3396CFB8B64B7BA931C1EA76213088"><header>delivery of reports of disbursements</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="HE2BAD5FB67074AFAA18AF8CAA463EDD5"><enum>106.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to deliver a printed copy of the report of disbursements for the operations of the House of Representatives under section 106 of the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/5535">2 U.S.C. 5535</external-xref>) to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress).</text>
				<appropriations-small id="HDA42180C1D874BB9839631E2AE2489EE"><header>delivery of daily calendar</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="H310B131DF9CE4F9FBE5F50E3B3FEB908"><enum>107.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to deliver to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) a printed copy of the Daily Calendar of the House of Representatives which is prepared by the Clerk of the House of Representatives.</text>
 <appropriations-major commented="no" id="idAE9D1164537341EDB5F28AD056E2B9DE"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">JOINT ITEMS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Joint Committees, as follows:</text> </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id78B5AA15AFEE404CAE6E556A52A650A7"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Joint Economic Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Joint Economic Committee, $4,203,000, to be disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id1A0D2EB26E15451BA398B9C90D3F32AE"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Joint Committee on Taxation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Joint Committee on Taxation, $10,095,000, to be disbursed by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For other joint items, as follows:</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id55266F720E404F19BC6453644DE56255"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the Attending Physician</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For medical supplies, equipment, and contingent expenses of the emergency rooms, and for the Attending Physician and his assistants, including:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7861E88F983949DCABBEDADE3D38CBF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an allowance of $2,175 per month to the Attending Physician;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H42C5B1A11BCC4410AA7B5BCCFCF1725D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an allowance of $1,300 per month to the Senior Medical Officer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75995AF5FE334884AB4975859FFB5C07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an allowance of $725 per month each to three medical officers while on duty in the Office of the Attending Physician;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D25C4A6D72B497CB02248EC23160A90"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an allowance of $725 per month to 2 assistants and $580 per month each not to exceed 11 assistants on the basis heretofore provided for such assistants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H218261CDB89F4D459F1BB0D44103BC4C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$2,692,000 for reimbursement to the Department of the Navy for expenses incurred for staff and equipment assigned to the Office of the Attending Physician, which shall be advanced and credited to the applicable appropriation or appropriations from which such salaries, allowances, and other expenses are payable and shall be available for all the purposes thereof, $3,784,000, to be disbursed by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</text>
					</paragraph></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id09C123F847F245C3949579829A416F80"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of Congressional Accessibility Services</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H8678B88814B44CFF858267687C8F6B83"><header>Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services, $1,387,000, to be disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate.</text>
				</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major commented="no" id="idB64ECC11C20842F6A2E106EC98D439E4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">CAPITOL POLICE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HF3A56FDDCE2D4EC4B6CDAE98EDD3AA50"><header>Salaries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries of employees of the Capitol Police, including overtime, hazardous duty pay, and Government contributions for health, retirement, social security, professional liability insurance, and other applicable employee benefits, $300,000,000 of which overtime shall not exceed $30,928,000 unless the Committee on Appropriations of the House and Senate are notified, to be disbursed by the Chief of the Capitol Police or his designee.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H18B562B73E504C75B7E18D5F8CD07FB3"><header>General Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Capitol Police, including motor vehicles, communications and other equipment, security equipment and installation, uniforms, weapons, supplies, materials, training, medical services, forensic services, stenographic services, personal and professional services, the employee assistance program, the awards program, postage, communication services, travel advances, relocation of instructor and liaison personnel for the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, and not more than $5,000 to be expended on the certification of the Chief of the Capitol Police in connection with official representation and reception expenses, $69,000,000, to be disbursed by the Chief of the Capitol Police or his designee: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the cost of basic training for the Capitol Police at the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center for fiscal year 2016 shall be paid by the Secretary of Homeland Security from funds available to the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
				</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H3C0E4A3171404BB9A62685D8C9F3DC6F"><header>Administrative Provision</header>
				</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idB9650E905158439D9C86D533111BD3DA"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">deposit of reimbursements for law enforcement assistance</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="H3A8A0EE514B94754BA47D00C1C8A8564" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1001.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBA32732EF26B44B997C95D13F109DF56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Section 2802(a)(1) of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1905">2 U.S.C. 1905(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>District of Columbia)</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>District of Columbia), and from any other source in the case of assistance provided in connection with an activity that was not sponsored by Congress</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H693648CCFC834865B8B379B8FD906818" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming Amendment</header><text>Section 2802(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1905">2 U.S.C. 1905(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>law enforcement assistance to any Federal, State, or local government agency (including any agency of the District of Columbia)</quote> and inserting <quote>any law enforcement assistance for which reimbursement described in paragraph (1) is made</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H556EC1B0491943D38C0AABB732DA6653" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to any reimbursement received before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id44CE1BEAEAEA4CE7801227FA77AD5A8B"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">OFFICE OF COMPLIANCE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id9E630D6A69E84180A96D383C97394762"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Office of Compliance, as authorized by section 305 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1385">2 U.S.C. 1385</external-xref>), $3,959,000, of which $450,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2017: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not more than $500 may be expended on the certification of the Executive Director of the Office of Compliance in connection with official representation and reception expenses.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id8CA31C591EB24B20AB5C84005DA1835F"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id62FCAA9C724649A28E70F3C0FE8DD579"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses necessary for operation of the Congressional Budget Office, including not more than $6,000 to be expended on the certification of the Director of the Congressional Budget Office in connection with official representation and reception expenses, $47,270,000.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id4921C792FFE34BE89F6FB154F6C1A60A"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idB6CBD297232149B2B30ACDC8FEBB9537"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Capitol Construction and Operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries for the Architect of the Capitol, and other personal services, at rates of pay provided by law; for all necessary expenses for surveys and studies, construction, operation, and general and administrative support in connection with facilities and activities under the care of the Architect of the Capitol including the Botanic Garden; electrical substations of the Capitol, Senate and House office buildings, and other facilities under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol; including furnishings and office equipment; including not more than $5,000 for official reception and representation expenses, to be expended as the Architect of the Capitol may approve; for purchase or exchange, maintenance, and operation of a passenger motor vehicle, $90,946,000.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id521364690A734CD7B96A689CC9D85CE1"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Building</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of the Capitol, $46,737,000, of which $22,737,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id99EA504893344C669BD9FAB52FA58CD4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Grounds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for care and improvement of grounds surrounding the Capitol, the Senate and House office buildings, and the Capitol Power Plant, $11,880,000, of which $2,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HB4D6DF7E5F474D3FBA0A34C06DF2A532"><header>House Office Buildings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of the House office buildings, $149,962,000, of which $23,886,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020, and of which $62,000,000 shall remain available until expended for the restoration and renovation of the Cannon House Office Building.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, for a payment to the House Historic Buildings Revitalization Trust Fund, $10,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idA050C40952274133A450B4327700B1B1"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Power Plant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of the Capitol Power Plant; lighting, heating, power (including the purchase of electrical energy) and water and sewer services for the Capitol, Senate and House office buildings, Library of Congress buildings, and the grounds about the same, Botanic Garden, Senate garage, and air conditioning refrigeration not supplied from plants in any of such buildings; heating the Government Printing Office and Washington City Post Office, and heating and chilled water for air conditioning for the Supreme Court Building, the Union Station complex, the Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building and the Folger Shakespeare Library, expenses for which shall be advanced or reimbursed upon request of the Architect of the Capitol and amounts so received shall be deposited into the Treasury to the credit of this appropriation, $91,549,898, of which $14,408,898 shall remain available until September 30, 2020: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not more than $9,000,000 of the funds credited or to be reimbursed to this appropriation as herein provided shall be available for obligation during fiscal year 2016.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idE792AAE399E444138077A5333951FEF4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Library Buildings and Grounds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the mechanical and structural maintenance, care and operation of the Library buildings and grounds, $36,589,000, of which $11,646,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id5DCDFDFA9E1942E58515DA698FF76EB8"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Police Buildings, Grounds and Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of buildings, grounds and security enhancements of the United States Capitol Police, wherever located, the Alternate Computer Facility, and AOC security operations, $22,058,000, of which $4,525,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idD5AD163CF0514FB195E00CC93F44CEA2"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Botanic Garden</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of the Botanic Garden and the nurseries, buildings, grounds, and collections; and purchase and exchange, maintenance, repair, and operation of a passenger motor vehicle; all under the direction of the Joint Committee on the Library, $11,892,000; of which $2,100,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That of the amount made available under this heading, the Architect of the Capitol may obligate and expend such sums as may be necessary for the maintenance, care and operation of the National Garden established under section 307E of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2146">2 U.S.C. 2146</external-xref>), upon vouchers approved by the Architect of the Capitol or a duly authorized designee.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HF9C90D993D1340BEAAB9C93768E55D7C"><header> Capitol Visitor Center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the operation of the Capitol Visitor Center, $20,557,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H26FE510415AD4DD2985D1C8BDAC404CD"><header>Administrative Provisions</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H2B2C50A833E74EABA712DEE6A2E3130C"><header>no bonuses for contractors behind schedule or over budget</header> </appropriations-small><section id="H9E5B0497C895401684D566D57786F09E"><enum>1101.</enum><text>None of the funds made available in this Act for the Architect of the Capitol may be used to make incentive or award payments to contractors for work on contracts or programs for which the contractor is behind schedule or over budget, unless the Architect of the Capitol, or agency-employed designee, determines that any such deviations are due to unforeseeable events, government-driven scope changes, or are not significant within the overall scope of the project and/or program.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="HAC5C215390F4491E9FBE2DD37B59386D"><header>scrims</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="H5508F5EDBDDB4DB9AE10ADA42B21E3A8"><enum>1102.</enum><text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used for scrims containing photographs of building facades during restoration or construction projects performed by the Architect of the Capitol.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H8AF5D09C1E68488883B38C218B107564"><header>acquisition of parcel at fort meade</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="HB45BD7CDD54C497DA3AFF7B783C3A09F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1103.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4D6F3530CB9745998B542CA631FE3495"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acquisition</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol is authorized to acquire from the Maryland State Highway Administration, at no cost to the United States, a parcel of real property (including improvements thereon) consisting of approximately 7.34 acres located within the portion of Fort George G. Meade in Anne Arundel County, Maryland, that was transferred to the Architect of the Capitol by the Secretary of the Army pursuant to section 122 of the Military Construction Appropriations Act, 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/141">2 U.S.C. 141</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H665E1124104745D686782D834041608A" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms and conditions applicable under subsections (b) and (d) of section 122 of the Military Construction Appropriations Act, 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/141">2 U.S.C. 141</external-xref> note) to the property acquired by the Architect of the Capitol pursuant to such section shall apply to the real property acquired by the Architect pursuant to the authority of this section.</text>
				</subsection></section><appropriations-small id="H7B1D877357C147359F0C7C6551157A6E"><header>oversight plan for funds provided for large scale projects</header>
 </appropriations-small><section id="H77AD21B7E95844FA967D08E6F98017EC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1104.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H61EB70D75A2443658AF2BE6CE728C04F"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Architect of the Capitol may not obligate more than 25 percent of the amount made available to the Architect under this Act for any project for which $5,000,000 or more is appropriated under this Act until—</text>
 <paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="HFC47593F69AC4EA4ABE2923658A20AC8" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Architect submits to the Comptroller General and the Committee on Appropriations of House of Representatives a plan for the use of the funds provided for the project which includes a description of any changes to the project’s schedule (including benchmarks for the timing of the completion of various stages of the project) or the project’s costs (including estimates of the total costs of the project or the total life cycle costs of the project), as well as a description of the accounting and other safeguards the Architect will implement to ensure that the project will be carried out in a timely and cost-effective manner; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H2620CCC799294FD7BBF19A02876EB4B4" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Comptroller General and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives approves such plan.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id24EEAF90578646BB8A406F97869B9D66"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">LIBRARY OF CONGRESS</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idF3448F0CDCCE4A7D98133A0C3A45A6EC"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Library of Congress not otherwise provided for, including development and maintenance of the Library's catalogs; custody and custodial care of the Library buildings; special clothing; cleaning, laundering and repair of uniforms; preservation of motion pictures in the custody of the Library; operation and maintenance of the American Folklife Center in the Library; preparation and distribution of catalog records and other publications of the Library; hire or purchase of one passenger motor vehicle; and expenses of the Library of Congress Trust Fund Board not properly chargeable to the income of any trust fund held by the Board, $419,357,000, of which not more than $6,000,000 shall be derived from collections credited to this appropriation during fiscal year 2016, and shall remain available until expended, under the Act of June 28, 1902 (chapter 1301; 32 Stat. 480; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/150">2 U.S.C. 150</external-xref>) and not more than $350,000 shall be derived from collections during fiscal year 2016 and shall remain available until expended for the development and maintenance of an international legal information database and activities related thereto: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Library of Congress may not obligate or expend any funds derived from collections under the Act of June 28, 1902, in excess of the amount authorized for obligation or expenditure in appropriations Acts: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the total amount available for obligation shall be reduced by the amount by which collections are less than $6,350,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the total amount appropriated, not more than $12,000 may be expended, on the certification of the Librarian of Congress, in connection with official representation and reception expenses for the Overseas Field Offices: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the total amount appropriated, $8,231,000 shall remain available until expended for the digital collections and educational curricula program.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id6652CEF441514028ADE0498C8D1CC3B0"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Copyright Office</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id2669AA65FBB84F00AB860D8C98DFCCD4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses of the Copyright Office, $57,008,000, of which not more than $30,000,000, to remain available until expended, shall be derived from collections credited to this appropriation during fiscal year 2016 under section 708(d) of title 17, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Copyright Office may not obligate or expend any funds derived from collections under such section, in excess of the amount authorized for obligation or expenditure in appropriations Acts: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not more than $5,777,000 shall be derived from collections during fiscal year 2016 under sections 111(d)(2), 119(b)(3), 803(e), 1005, and 1316 of such title: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the total amount available for obligation shall be reduced by the amount by which collections are less than $35,777,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not more than $100,000 of the amount appropriated is available for the maintenance of an <quote>International Copyright Institute</quote> in the Copyright Office of the Library of Congress for the purpose of training nationals of developing countries in intellectual property laws and policies: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not more than $6,500 may be expended, on the certification of the Librarian of Congress, in connection with official representation and reception expenses for activities of the International Copyright Institute and for copyright delegations, visitors, and seminars: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That notwithstanding any provision of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/17/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 17, United States Code, any amounts made available under this heading which are attributable to royalty fees and payments received by the Copyright Office pursuant to sections 111, 119, and chapter 10 of such title may be used for the costs incurred in the administration of the Copyright Royalty Judges program, with the exception of the costs of salaries and benefits for the Copyright Royalty Judges and staff under section 802(e).</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id9778A37A04F34999B4C8ED5244FB37FF"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congressional Research Service</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id6C3BB74128B44B7891FB9181D15C2742"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out the provisions of section 203 of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/166">2 U.S.C. 166</external-xref>) and to revise and extend the Annotated Constitution of the United States of America, $106,945,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That no part of such amount may be used to pay any salary or expense in connection with any publication, or preparation of material therefor (except the Digest of Public General Bills), to be issued by the Library of Congress unless such publication has obtained prior approval of either the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id88F603EF900447ED876DCCC09D1CD392"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Books for the Blind and Physically Handicapped</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id5A31D1A70BB44A78BD80D2EACAB90896"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses to carry out the Act of March 3, 1931 (chapter 400; 46 Stat. 1487; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/135a">2 U.S.C. 135a</external-xref>), $50,248,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That of the total amount appropriated, not more than $650,000 shall be available to contract to provide newspapers to blind and physically handicapped residents at no cost to the individual.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id28EFF1608357467BA4F1ADFDAB7B37A8"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrative Provision</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H18405820E3134AAAA7F0B7F3441D6061"><header>reimbursable and revolving fund activities</header>
 </appropriations-small><section id="HAAC02CDC2D2F43A0B2B9EAFE9C703C0D"><enum>1201.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF8F23BBA750B442AA8A3D313FEF29538"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2016, the obligational authority of the Library of Congress for the activities described in subsection (b) may not exceed $186,015,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H08F7DC9919894AF48C6859675E21887B" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The activities referred to in subsection (a) are reimbursable and revolving fund activities that are funded from sources other than appropriations to the Library in appropriations Acts for the legislative branch.</text>
				</subsection></section><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id4D6F15C66EFF4C26A5B12921B4A6DCFD"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">GOVERNMENT PUBLISHING OFFICE</header>
			</appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id54CC056D3B324DEBA04E5CE655536394"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congressional Publishing</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id68383670931B459AA84B3183728EFF75"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For authorized publishing of congressional information and the distribution of congressional information in any format; expenses necessary for preparing the semimonthly and session index to the Congressional Record, as authorized by law (section 902 of title 44, United States Code); publishing of Government publications authorized by law to be distributed to Members of Congress; and publishing, and distribution of Government publications authorized by law to be distributed without charge to the recipient, $79,736,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That this appropriation shall not be available for paper copies of the permanent edition of the Congressional Record for individual Representatives, Resident Commissioners or Delegates authorized under section 906 of title 44, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That this appropriation shall be available for the payment of obligations incurred under the appropriations for similar purposes for preceding fiscal years: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That notwithstanding the 2-year limitation under section 718 of title 44, United States Code, none of the funds appropriated or made available under this Act or any other Act for printing and binding and related services provided to Congress under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, may be expended to print a document, report, or publication after the 27-month period beginning on the date that such document, report, or publication is authorized by Congress to be printed, unless Congress reauthorizes such printing in accordance with section 718 of title 44, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any unobligated or unexpended balances in this account or accounts for similar purposes for preceding fiscal years may be transferred to the Government Publishing Office business operations revolving fund for carrying out the purposes of this heading, subject to the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That notwithstanding sections 901, 902, and 906 of title 44, United States Code, this appropriation may be used to prepare indexes to the Congressional Record on only a monthly and session basis.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idDAD1CB3E4E69419CBD8B51DB823702D2"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public Information Programs of the Superintendent of Documents</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id0848AD2A9C444D648D9EAB7883915718"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">salaries and expenses</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id12A02FB70EF14F0990598ACA8AE14BF7"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses of the public information programs of the Office of Superintendent of Documents necessary to provide for the cataloging and indexing of Government publications and their distribution to the public, Members of Congress, other Government agencies, and designated depository and international exchange libraries as authorized by law, $30,500,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That amounts of not more than $2,000,000 from current year appropriations are authorized for producing and disseminating Congressional serial sets and other related publications for fiscal years 2014 and 2015 to depository and other designated libraries: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any unobligated or unexpended balances in this account or accounts for similar purposes for preceding fiscal years may be transferred to the Government Publishing Office business operations revolving fund for carrying out the purposes of this heading, subject to the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idBB347A8A339F4476BC08484A74F2DF0B"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Government Publishing Office Business Operations Revolving Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Government Publishing Office is hereby authorized to make such expenditures, within the limits of funds available and in accordance with law, and to make such contracts and commitments without regard to fiscal year limitations as provided by section 9104 of title 31, United States Code, as may be necessary in carrying out the programs and purposes set forth in the budget for the current fiscal year for the Government Publishing Office business operations revolving fund: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not more than $7,500 may be expended on the certification of the Director of the Government Publishing Office in connection with official representation and reception expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the business operations revolving fund shall be available for the hire or purchase of not more than 12 passenger motor vehicles: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That expenditures in connection with travel expenses of the advisory councils to the Director of the Government Publishing Office shall be deemed necessary to carry out the provisions of title 44, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the business operations revolving fund shall be available for temporary or intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, but at rates for individuals not more than the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That activities financed through the business operations revolving fund may provide information in any format: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the business operations revolving fund and the funds provided under the heading <quote>Public Information Programs of the Superintendent of Documents</quote> may not be used for contracted security services at GPO's passport facility in the District of Columbia.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id027826AF9B2E41C1AE464F09A7BABA99"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">GOVERNMENT ACCOUNTABILITY OFFICE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id7B0BAF923F8040E9B74E8B4E9B06E1D6"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Government Accountability Office, including not more than $12,500 to be expended on the certification of the Comptroller General of the United States in connection with official representation and reception expenses; temporary or intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, but at rates for individuals not more than the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title; hire of one passenger motor vehicle; advance payments in foreign countries in accordance with section 3324 of title 31, United States Code; benefits comparable to those payable under sections 901(5), (6), and (8) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4081">22 U.S.C. 4081(5)</external-xref>, (6), and (8)); and under regulations prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States, rental of living quarters in foreign countries, $522,000,000: <proviso><italic> Provided</italic></proviso>, That, in addition, $25,450,000 of payments received under sections 782, 791, 3521, and 9105 of title 31, United States Code, shall be available without fiscal year limitation: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That this appropriation and appropriations for administrative expenses of any other department or agency which is a member of the National Intergovernmental Audit Forum or a Regional Intergovernmental Audit Forum shall be available to finance an appropriate share of either Forum's costs as determined by the respective Forum, including necessary travel expenses of non-Federal participants: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That payments hereunder to the Forum may be credited as reimbursements to any appropriation from which costs involved are initially financed.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H1DADCEFA9DA3425B84E4AB9690128425"><header>Administrative Provision</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H57296BA5BE6745F0B8E7E55E063F03EF"><header>Federal Government Details</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><section id="HB672561763334B918898D5854E373B04" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1301.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8CA81D6E453543C681A82AF6F21969EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permitting Details From Other Federal Offices</header><text>Section 731 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6695B70EEBD94BDD97E4E60AEB56D681" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H8D6ED96E96D1481C92B1C32D5970D5C6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Federal Government Details</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The activities of the Government Accountability Office may, in the reasonable discretion of the Comptroller General, be carried out by receiving details of personnel from other offices of the Federal Government on a reimbursable, partially-reimbursable, or nonreimbursable basis.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="HB9BD394919F747C0B7641EE7F752B5D0" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2016 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection></section><appropriations-major id="H14037CC68171483C8CC5BCFB54EACF72"><header>OPEN WORLD LEADERSHIP CENTER TRUST FUND</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For a payment to the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund for financing activities of the Open World Leadership Center under section 313 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1151">2 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>), $5,700,000 (reduced by $5,700,000), except that any funds made available under this heading to support Russian participants shall only be used for those engaging in free market development, humanitarian activities, and civic engagement, and shall not be used for officials of the central government of Russia.</text>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H71C5598CDD8E45F587F9521707391D5F"><header>John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payment to the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Development Trust Fund established under section 116 of the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1105">2 U.S.C. 1105</external-xref>), $430,000.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate></title><title changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="ID866DEFC8DB6D4ABAA25614A28610D962" level-type="subsequent" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>II</enum><header>GENERAL PROVISIONS</header>
			<appropriations-small id="H8EFDDCE9C67846CBAE8E4C8ADC6A3E29"><header>MAINTENANCE AND CARE OF PRIVATE VEHICLES</header>
 </appropriations-small><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDA52A6101B8014C88B88816915B1F3C3E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><text>No part of the funds appropriated in this Act shall be used for the maintenance or care of private vehicles, except for emergency assistance and cleaning as may be provided under regulations relating to parking facilities for the House of Representatives issued by the Committee on House Administration and for the Senate issued by the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H6CF203A03A8D417BBC86BE45AE28C12E"><header>FISCAL YEAR LIMITATION</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDEDE926D05CE649D38D7EEFBC9CB62703" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><text>No part of the funds appropriated in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond fiscal year 2016 unless expressly so provided in this Act.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H0C937F9AFEBD462CA33E8216F8AF2926"><header>RATES OF COMPENSATION AND DESIGNATION</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID9428BE0E4F85430991E5062DF5673FAE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>203.</enum><text>Whenever in this Act any office or position not specifically established by the Legislative Pay Act of 1929 (46 Stat. 32 et seq.) is appropriated for or the rate of compensation or designation of any office or position appropriated for is different from that specifically established by such Act, the rate of compensation and the designation in this Act shall be the permanent law with respect thereto: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the provisions in this Act for the various items of official expenses of Members, officers, and committees of the Senate and House of Representatives, and clerk hire for Senators and Members of the House of Representatives shall be the permanent law with respect thereto.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H9A69FC921BDE4B519C6F11198DDA48F5"><header>CONSULTING SERVICES</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDCED47B021D3343D286123928DAD76007" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>204.</enum><text>The expenditure of any appropriation under this Act for any consulting service through procurement contract, under section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, shall be limited to those contracts where such expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, except where otherwise provided under existing law, or under existing Executive order issued under existing law.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="HC5AFF77B902549E48B49838D341FA137"><header>COSTS OF LBFMC</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID07EBF1A9C2BD4060AF0453F4D6E6A290" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>205.</enum><text>Amounts available for administrative expenses of any legislative branch entity which participates in the Legislative Branch Financial Managers Council (LBFMC) established by charter on March 26, 1996, shall be available to finance an appropriate share of LBFMC costs as determined by the LBFMC, except that the total LBFMC costs to be shared among all participating legislative branch entities (in such allocations among the entities as the entities may determine) may not exceed $2,000.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H963807BB4A4C4B559613B5D13548BADF"><header>LANDSCAPE MAINTENANCE</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="H211F348342B544A6A03E7A6ADC813E52"><enum>206.</enum><text>For fiscal year 2016 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Architect of the Capitol, in consultation with the District of Columbia, is authorized to maintain and improve the landscape features, excluding streets, in Square 580 up to the beginning of I–395.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H09E4B179E3ED43699CF04B29E25160FF"><header>LIMITATION ON TRANSFERS</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID56B9980596D54FC8A59BC95133011BD9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>207.</enum><text>None of the funds made available in this Act may be transferred to any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, except pursuant to a transfer made by, or transfer authority provided in, this Act or any other appropriation Act.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H32639F09D1034B9BB04A4F8C780A17A0"><header>GUIDED TOURS OF THE CAPITOL</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID5F500D1642994CA9A1AF6AD50F063A96" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>208.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idED52F4C476704A9C93C92BA3E6B44295"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), none of the funds made available to the Architect of the Capitol in this Act may be used to eliminate or restrict guided tours of the United States Capitol which are led by employees and interns of offices of Members of Congress and other offices of the House of Representatives and Senate</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDB1726772E5EB440DBB8FA548812A2539" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the direction of the Capitol Police Board, or at the direction of the Architect of the Capitol with the approval of the Capitol Police Board, guided tours of the United States Capitol which are led by employees and interns described in subsection (a) may be suspended temporarily or otherwise subject to restriction for security or related reasons to the same extent as guided tours of the United States Capitol which are led by the Architect of the Capitol.</text>
				</subsection></section><appropriations-small id="H000B701AFA164C70BE019694055F620C"><header>BATTERY RECHARGING STATIONS FOR PRIVATELY OWNED VEHICLES IN PARKING AREAS UNDER THE JURISDICTION OF
			 THE LIBRARIAN OF CONGRESS AT NO NET COST TO THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT</header>
 </appropriations-small><section id="H418078E591184A0DB714E4F6B13EE20B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>209.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8E82DF9BAFE34DBC9685662659B863D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered employee</term> means—</text> <paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="HF83BCCECF0AD45309E70DE93B3BDDEF7" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an employee of the Library of Congress; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H64E10F652675459B85620263EFA8F3C8" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other individual who is authorized to park in any parking area under the jurisdiction of the Library of Congress on the Library of Congress buildings and grounds.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H6B5314C105F04E7B87E03D8C9914706B" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header>
 <paragraph id="HE9F3A90017794226A86AB5092B6FDF0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), funds appropriated to the Architect of the Capitol under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="appropriations">Capitol Power Plant</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-major" style="appropriations">Architect of the Capitol</header-in-text></quote> in any fiscal year are available to construct, operate, and maintain on a reimbursable basis battery recharging stations in parking areas under the jurisdiction of the Library of Congress on Library of Congress buildings and grounds for use by privately owned vehicles used by covered employees.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3ECCE1108B412E823B190A06CD8FB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vendors authorized</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Architect of the Capitol may use one or more vendors on a commission basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC69A14ADC734633B24961C64859C206"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval of construction</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol may construct or direct the construction of battery recharging stations described under paragraph (1) after—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H946CBDEA7DA94AE0A331CBF67638321D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submission of written notice detailing the numbers and locations of the battery recharging stations to the Joint Committee on the Library; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FF1DB19C8174302BD3CE5A89A95DCBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approval by that Committee.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H791C69C208D54F268ECE9E0707DA5149" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fees and charges</header> <paragraph id="H9A16808178714ACEA0C0641D00AA3439"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Architect of the Capitol shall charge fees or charges for electricity provided to covered employees sufficient to cover the costs to the Architect of the Capitol to carry out this section, including costs to any vendors or other costs associated with maintaining the battery recharging stations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H415D0842ADDA43989FF917F4405465EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval of fees or charges</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol may establish and adjust fees or charges under paragraph (1) after—</text> <subparagraph id="H001997CD65634538858E94AF664B83AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submission of written notice detailing the amount of the fee or charge to be established or adjusted to the Joint Committee on the Library; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA0670797D4D4D618B6DBBCCEFA028CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approval by that Committee.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H740BDF96C3104D60B0A07F5D643EDE75" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deposit and availability of fees, charges, and commissions</header><text>Any fees, charges, or commissions collected by the Architect of the Capitol under this section shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBABBE38B90634108B4981CB58F3CE078"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the appropriations account described under subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7517AE616560461DAE68335833ECCA26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>available for obligation without further appropriation during the fiscal year collected.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="H8BDDF34A9D6A4B9DB8FB4C5D741B83F0" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H27593BB8FD374ACDAB8B5064E9861BAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Architect of the Capitol shall submit a report on the financial administration and cost recovery of activities under this section with respect to that fiscal year to the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HE409393877C2463EA617ED19C6CFBD5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Avoiding subsidy</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0AB479A2FE2C4D0BA65AD8532EDD0CF1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act and every 3 years thereafter, the Architect of the Capitol shall submit a report to the Joint Committee on the Library determining whether covered employees using battery charging stations as authorized by this section are receiving a subsidy from the taxpayers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H059087B49ADE41AC87F559BDCBD4FBC9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modification of rates and fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a determination is made under subparagraph (A) that a subsidy is being received, the Architect of the Capitol shall submit a plan to the Joint Committee on the Library on how to update the program to ensure no subsidy is being received. If the Joint Committee does not act on the plan within 60 days, the Architect of the Capitol shall take appropriate steps to increase rates or fees to ensure reimbursement for the cost of the program consistent with an appropriate schedule for amortization, to be charged to those using the charging stations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="deleted" committee-id="SSAP00" id="HD41B5717356543F49AC7574B2B16E488" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2016 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text> </subsection></section><appropriations-small id="H5AC99BD969024E769C2E6780A27D08A4"><header>COST OF LIVING ADJUSTMENT</header> </appropriations-small><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E90BFA27F4B45BDAA74AD3E7501CC43" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>210.</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no adjustment shall be made under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) (relating to cost of living adjustments for Members of Congress) during fiscal year 2016.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H3FADCFC161694EA3AA3C7932DC8482E3"><header>SPENDING REDUCTION ACCOUNT</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22B1E7E03FA5405FAE401119F030B8AE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>211.</enum><text>The amount by which the applicable allocation of new budget authority made by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives under section 302(b) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, excluding Senate items, exceeds the amount of proposed new budget authority is $0 (increased by $5,700,000).</text>
 </section><section id="H737A4DD32B50454A8EBC01E231AB0C42"><enum>212.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to deliver a printed copy of the Congressional Pictorial Directory to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress).</text>
 <appropriations-small id="H13B3CD00B3FF4208B5738D69BD9FE9B1"><pagebreak></pagebreak><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016</short-title></quote>.</text></appropriations-small></section></title></legis-body> <legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause" style="appropriations"> <section changed="added" committee-id="SSAP00" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idfb0ea27a-260a-4880-a54b-be896d0f9a12" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for other purposes, namely:</text>
		</section><title changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id5B92196242354956BF21374AFF314016" level-type="subsequent" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>I</enum>
			<appropriations-major commented="no" id="idA690F3D6437A41C5803401501CFA1C3C"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH </header>
			</appropriations-major><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id809B4458FED64624A9E0E87D3B745687"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">SENATE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idC2981409BCF6409DA3CE37611437F8D5"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expense allowances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expense allowances of the Vice President, $18,760; the President Pro Tempore of the Senate, $37,520; Majority Leader of the Senate, $39,920; Minority Leader of the Senate, $39,920; Majority Whip of the Senate, $9,980; Minority Whip of the Senate, $9,980; Chairmen of the Majority and Minority Conference Committees, $4,690 for each Chairman; and Chairmen of the Majority and Minority Policy Committees, $4,690 for each Chairman; in all, $174,840.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idADCD72DFE0A24C229D207476048B1B04"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representation Allowances for the Majority and Minority Leaders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For representation allowances of the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate, $14,070 for each such Leader; in all, $28,140<italic>.</italic></text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id31EC6B3371164F5A8C3F886075A8EB4C"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries, officers and employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For compensation of officers, employees, and others as authorized by law, including agency contributions, $179,185,311<italic>,</italic> which shall be paid from this appropriation without regard to the following limitations:</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idA13A6009D40441289531911207A1ED2B"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the Vice President</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the Office of the Vice President, $2,417,248<italic>.</italic></text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id045EA688B84743E88D37FF2E3C7A579B"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the President Pro Tempore</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the Office of the President Pro Tempore, $723,466<italic>.</italic></text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id7532DDEC66EC461284FAA084B67179FA"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Offices of the Majority and Minority Leaders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Offices of the Majority and Minority Leaders, $5,255,576<italic>.</italic></text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id16E061D2D49845B19327C02D5192E5B5"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Offices of the Majority and Minority Whips</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Offices of the Majority and Minority Whips, $3,359,424<italic>.</italic></text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id0CB857B27FAD45BC887DF9BB430EA932"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries of the Committee on Appropriations, $15,142,000<italic>.</italic></text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id53583BDD75664627AE52521DE2BFF7C1"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conference Committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the Conference of the Majority and the Conference of the Minority, at rates of compensation to be fixed by the Chairman of each such committee, $1,658,000 for each such committee; in all, $3,316,000<italic>.</italic></text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idF067C76E1C18476D92EDC83D58BCA74B"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Offices of the Secretaries of the Conference of the Majority and the Conference of the Minority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Offices of the Secretaries of the Conference of the Majority and the Conference of the Minority, $817,402<italic>.</italic></text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id58829B325B874E95977253FAB18B33CA"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Policy Committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries of the Majority Policy Committee and the Minority Policy Committee, $1,692,905 for each such committee; in all, $3,385,810<italic>.</italic></text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idA9BCC60A2F49469786A3E05897F0FAEE"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the Chaplain</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Office of the Chaplain, $436,886<italic>.</italic></text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id0948B3D5A8D847AF92A986FB336F1F9E"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Office of the Secretary, $24,772,000<italic>.</italic></text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id8B52917787FC44C18A553D856F0E20D8"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper, $69,000,000<italic>.</italic></text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idB538A7CEE3664B3E9A7A4E67EF4DD751"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Offices of the Secretaries for the Majority and Minority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Offices of the Secretary for the Majority and the Secretary for the Minority, $1,762,000<italic>.</italic></text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idFFD9F509ECB14B459E4CDE34B796629A"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency Contributions and Related Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For agency contributions for employee benefits, as authorized by law, and related expenses, $48,797,499.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idB9A5124A56F44900A8F65C320052AD60"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the Legislative Counsel of the Senate</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id896B27DE3161439685856FA9C56105D6"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the Senate, $5,408,500<italic>.</italic></text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idBECF974FCBA84FA8AFDE22C195ADADCC"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of Senate Legal Counsel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Office of Senate Legal Counsel, $1,120,000.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idD490C6DE93914B7688CE2D538E60FDEC"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expense Allowances of the Secretary of the Senate, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate,
 and Secretaries for the Majority and Minority of the Senate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expense allowances of the Secretary of the Senate, $7,110; Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, $7,110; Secretary for the Majority of the Senate, $7,110; Secretary for the Minority of the Senate, $7,110<italic></italic>; in all, $28,440.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id95EBAD3D7B8641B5BB6BC517FA028981"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contingent Expenses of the Senate </header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idFDA395502BA545FF8609B89EC0075E12"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inquiries and Investigations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses of inquiries and investigations ordered by the Senate, or conducted under paragraph 1 of rule XXVI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, section 112 of the Supplemental Appropriations and Rescission Act, 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/304">Public Law 96–304</external-xref>), and Senate Resolution 281, 96th Congress, agreed to March 11, 1980, $133,265,000, of which $26,650,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2018.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id5FFE1EA5E72D4E788CD76A9852D8B1D4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expenses of the United States Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses of the United States Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control, $508,000.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id43D9E9F5AEFA4ACAB9AD12D47E6FC976"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary of the Senate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate, $8,750,000 of which $4,350,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020 and of which $2,500,000 shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idDB2497B26451496B902110B2041A9515"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, $130,000,000<italic>,</italic> which shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id9F717B9A8D104C07A292D5C4F9867C5E"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Miscellaneous Items</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For miscellaneous items, $21,390,270 which shall remain available until September 30, 2018.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id19A75993533642C18AC1E207608100E4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account, $390,000,000<italic></italic> of which $19,121,212 shall remain available until September 30, 2018.<italic></italic></text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id8A0144D738BE4C1A9F6F48671B2E7EE3"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Official Mail Costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for official mail costs of the Senate, $300,000.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="id729F1879A5034429B90B52CD2940C23E"><header>Administrative Provisions</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="id6EEC8419198F4752948328024DFA306C"><header>Requiring Amounts Remaining in Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account to Be Used
			 for Deficit Reduction or to Reduce the Federal Debt</header>
 </appropriations-small><section commented="no" id="id29573A66B7E647CF9A09E64490A2E80B"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any amounts appropriated under this Act under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-major" style="appropriations">Senate</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="appropriations">Contingent Expenses of the Senate</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-small" style="appropriations">Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account</header-in-text></quote> shall be available for obligation only during the fiscal year or fiscal years for which such amounts are made available. Any unexpended balances under such allowances remaining after the end of the period of availability shall be returned to the Treasury in accordance with the undesignated paragraph under the center heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-major" style="appropriations">General Provision</header-in-text></quote> under chapter XI of the Third Supplemental Appropriation Act, 1957 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4107">2 U.S.C. 4107</external-xref>) and used for deficit reduction (or, if there is no Federal budget deficit after all such payments have been made, for reducing the Federal debt, in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury considers appropriate).</text>
				<appropriations-small id="idB7E77A1F277D41FBB1463F1710C835B6"><header>Authority for transfer of funds</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="idcecf952395ea4d7a895e88dfc1c6587f"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/6153">2 U.S.C. 6153</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idE4685EA4D624443FB4DFA41EA75BA1D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id12A26BAAA7FF4535A17ADFBB516869E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSAP00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id111c1f9ba0654131ad48217d3b19eb02" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idcc23be45631b4249a33192432a734e50"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id0A1D04D96DAA4183969FA0C32FB724D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Chaplain of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at the election of the Chaplain of the Senate, transfer funds from the appropriation account for salaries for the Office of the Chaplain of the Senate to the account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, from which expenses are payable for the Office of the Chaplain.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id755b4894a7724cff818dd38c4b261bc5" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Chaplain of the Senate may, during any fiscal year, at the election of the Chaplain of the Senate, transfer funds from the appropriation account for expenses, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for the Office of the Chaplain to the account from which salaries are payable for the Office of the Chaplain of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;  </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id18ADB5099D7345D9BE6D2255F8393AB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="id0BE4CFACF0404C48A78C8AF7FE833E67"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or the Office of the Chaplain of the Senate, as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>such committee</quote> each place it appears; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE7EFB5438C3A47E28A7C2D81BD78FD97"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or the Chaplain of the Senate, as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>the Chairman</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA7CEEB97DECE410F8CCDBD04A04AAC12"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote>or the Chaplain of the Senate, as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>The Chairman of a committee</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></section><appropriations-major id="idF6FB1E750D444643AC26F370CBADD12F"><header>House of Representatives</header>
			</appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="idE3502E128F8D4EBD853BC1286E055C65"><header>Salaries and Expenses</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id2EF59959089F4070A0783F4E6CEB7A82"><header>Payment to widows and heirs of deceased members of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payment to Tori B. Nunnelee, widow of Alan Nunnelee, late a Representative from the State of Mississippi, $174,000.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the House of Representatives, $1,180,736,000, as follows:</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id5bf2600e-03e2-4c9c-87dd-9fe05039a38f"><header>House Leadership Offices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses, as authorized by law, $22,278,891, including: Office of the Speaker, $6,645,417, including $25,000 for official expenses of the Speaker; Office of the Majority Floor Leader, $2,180,048, including $10,000 for official expenses of the Majority Leader; Office of the Minority Floor Leader, $7,114,471, including $10,000 for official expenses of the Minority Leader; Office of the Majority Whip, including the Chief Deputy Majority Whip, $1,886,632, including $5,000 for official expenses of the Majority Whip; Office of the Minority Whip, including the Chief Deputy Minority Whip, $1,459,639, including $5,000 for official expenses of the Minority Whip; Republican Conference, $1,505,426; Democratic Caucus, $1,487,258: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That such amount for salaries and expenses shall remain available from January 3, 2016 until January 2, 2017.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id393DB3E365074FACAF7179F94BC07993"><header>Members’ Representational Allowances</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id0b119119-8727-471e-bd5c-3e563a093bb5"><header>Including Members’ Clerk Hire, Official Expenses of Members, and Official Mail</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Members' representational allowances, including Members' clerk hire, official expenses, and official mail, $554,317,732.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id03d3372c-e353-4e22-b5ea-bc93c09b3b7d"><header>Committee Employees</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id4768c00b-4601-468c-ae17-d3305719a2af"><header>Standing Committees, Special and Select</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of standing committees, special and select, authorized by House resolutions, $123,903,173: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That such amount shall remain available for such salaries and expenses until December 31, 2016.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id0fbe6087-04c5-4f09-91c3-b92620c00413"><header>Committee on Appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Committee on Appropriations, $23,271,004, including studies and examinations of executive agencies and temporary personal services for such committee, to be expended in accordance with section 202(b) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 and to be available for reimbursement to agencies for services performed: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That such amount shall remain available for such salaries and expenses until December 31, 2016.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="idb6decd56-e7f4-467f-92e9-20eec60e8efa"><header>Salaries, Officers and Employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For compensation and expenses of officers and employees, as authorized by law, $175,713,679, including: for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Clerk, including the positions of the Chaplain and the Historian, and including not more than $25,000, of which not more than $20,000 is for the Family Room and not more than $2,000 is for the Office of the Chaplain, for official representation and reception expenses, $24,980,898; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms, including the position of Superintendent of Garages and the Office of Emergency Management, and including not more than $3,000 for official representation and reception expenses, $14,827,120 of which $4,784,229 shall remain available until expended; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer including not more than $3,000 for official representation and reception expenses, $115,010,000, of which $1,350,000 shall remain available until expended; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Inspector General, $4,741,809; for salaries and expenses of the Office of General Counsel, $1,413,450; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Parliamentarian, including the Parliamentarian, $2,000 for preparing the Digest of Rules, and not more than $1,000 for official representation and reception expenses, $1,974,606; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Law Revision Counsel of the House, $3,119,766; for salaries and expenses of the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the House, $8,352,975; for salaries and expenses of the Office of Interparliamentary Affairs, $814,069; for other authorized employees, $478,986.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id7189cb54-cbec-4d2c-8052-2584e7d01162"><header>Allowances and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For allowances and expenses as authorized by House resolution or law, $281,251,521, including: supplies, materials, administrative costs and Federal tort claims, $3,625,236; official mail for committees, leadership offices, and administrative offices of the House, $190,486; Government contributions for health, retirement, Social Security, and other applicable employee benefits, $254,447,514, to remain available until March 31, 2017; Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery, $16,217,008 of which $5,000,000 shall remain available until expended; transition activities for new members and staff, $2,084,000, to remain available until expended; Wounded Warrior Program $2,500,000, to remain available until expended; Office of Congressional Ethics, $1,467,030; and miscellaneous items including purchase, exchange, maintenance, repair and operation of House motor vehicles, interparliamentary receptions, and gratuities to heirs of deceased employees of the House, $720,247.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id0a786283-ca68-4b2e-a85b-8bb039ba5197"><header>Administrative Provisions</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><section id="id7b8f2bbe-bf97-4ad8-b0b4-7a420c016f6f"><enum>101.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5a66804f-b049-4294-ad0a-946bd9c9f636"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring Amounts Remaining in Members' Representational Allowances To Be Used for Deficit
 Reduction or To Reduce the Federal Debt</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any amounts appropriated under this Act for <quote><header-in-text level="subsection">HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES—Salaries and Expenses—Members’ Representational Allowances</header-in-text></quote> shall be available only for fiscal year 2016. Any amount remaining after all payments are made under such allowances for fiscal year 2016 shall be deposited in the Treasury and used for deficit reduction (or, if there is no Federal budget deficit after all such payments have been made, for reducing the Federal debt, in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury considers appropriate).</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="added" committee-id="SSAP00" id="idb9a005f3-0771-4497-a915-efdbf0bc580e" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives shall have authority to prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f691525-efb5-4e91-8159-7a909b673328" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>As used in this section, the term <quote>Member of the House of Representatives</quote> means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text> </subsection></section><appropriations-small id="H842A2E28AAB6458FBC58FB870E0B527D"><header>delivery of bills and resolutions</header> </appropriations-small><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46E8E37F9A1B43BABCF75C1D58C99905" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to deliver a printed copy of a bill, joint resolution, or resolution to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) unless the Member requests a copy.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H63F007202E484BA5928DBE82234BC1A9"><header>delivery of congressional record</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA999844DB4EA4A99865B95CCF129414A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>103.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to deliver a printed copy of any version of the Congressional Record to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress).</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H55DFBEEB10274264A4B26BFE00F0831E"><header>limitation on amount available to lease vehicles</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F501B81CD4043F391BD1C1AEA982CE8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>104.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives to make any payments from any Members' Representational Allowance for the leasing of a vehicle, excluding mobile district offices, in an aggregate amount that exceeds $1,000 for the vehicle in any month.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="HDE5E933843F549419337E274876A9A00"><header>limitation on printed copies of u.s. code to house</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB030B6D34EE43D5A0A53859EDF6D5FB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>105.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to provide an aggregate number of more than 50 printed copies of any edition of the United States Code to all offices of the House of Representatives.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="idDAA19BB234184035B7F5CC8689CA2DB1"><header>delivery of reports of disbursements</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="H89168C0EB5B2469D9057FDCF8F1801DB"><enum>106.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to deliver a printed copy of the report of disbursements for the operations of the House of Representatives under section 106 of the House of Representatives Administrative Reform Technical Corrections Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/5535">2 U.S.C. 5535</external-xref>) to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress).</text>
				<appropriations-small id="id1FA52CD0BAED4C5383DF15AB93EEC971"><header>delivery of daily calendar</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6417704B345F4FC794DC8EEC88740310" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>107.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to deliver to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) a printed copy of the Daily Calendar of the House of Representatives which is prepared by the Clerk of the House of Representatives.</text>
 <appropriations-major commented="no" id="id997E06BEC75B42D782F5D1C49EA9F9EC"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">JOINT ITEMS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Joint Committees, as follows:</text> </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id04f3aaa5-b032-425c-b386-e5b348a987c1"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Joint Economic Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Joint Economic Committee, $4,203,000, to be disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="idCF6DFC45174D4959A2F7F96FE7D6B782"><header>Joint congressional committee on inaugural ceremonies of 2017</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses associated with conducting the inaugural ceremonies of the President and Vice President of the United States, January 20, 2017, in accordance with such program as may be adopted by the joint congressional committee authorized to conduct the inaugural ceremonies of 2017, $1,250,000 to be disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate and to remain available until September 30, 2017: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That funds made available under this heading shall be available for payment, on a direct or reimbursable basis, whether incurred on, before, or after, October 1, 2016: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the compensation of any employee of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate who has been designated to perform service with respect to the inaugural ceremonies of 2017 shall continue to be paid by the Committee on Rules and Administration, but the account from which such staff member is paid may be reimbursed for the services of the staff member out of funds made available under this heading: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That there are authorized to be paid from the appropriations account for <quote>Expenses of Inquiries and Investigations</quote> of the Senate such sums as may be necessary, without fiscal year limitation, for agency contributions related to the compensation of employees of the joint congressional committee.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id8edbd237-1d6d-4986-b5a0-82120767e4f1"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Joint Committee on Taxation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Joint Committee on Taxation, $10,095,000, to be disbursed by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For other joint items, as follows:</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id383f72ba-321e-4b7a-8e3b-1041acea6fdf"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the Attending Physician</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For medical supplies, equipment, and contingent expenses of the emergency rooms, and for the Attending Physician and his assistants, including:</text>
 <paragraph id="HECF85676F5A9440B8EF3B956ACFCB2A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an allowance of $2,175 per month to the Attending Physician;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF5D883A28994054948DABEB28BB39A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an allowance of $1,300 per month to the Senior Medical Officer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB526EAD999694C36831BF060E3291B9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an allowance of $725 per month each to three medical officers while on duty in the Office of the Attending Physician;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7368B276675F414FADD90948BB4850FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an allowance of $725 per month to 2 assistants and $580 per month each not to exceed 11 assistants on the basis heretofore provided for such assistants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75440CFAA50A4980B02FF8F89854134D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$2,486,000 for reimbursement to the Department of the Navy for expenses incurred for staff and equipment assigned to the Office of the Attending Physician, which shall be advanced and credited to the applicable appropriation or appropriations from which such salaries, allowances, and other expenses are payable and shall be available for all the purposes thereof, $3,371,000, to be disbursed by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.</text>
					</paragraph></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id1de7cc7d-d56a-49ee-b9ae-a41606bffa6b"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of Congressional Accessibility Services</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id92699a18-6cd7-4f2f-ad9a-2f70904a4bd4"><header>Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services, $1,387,000, to be disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate.</text>
				</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id34994e67-5156-4a1f-acff-1e62d88cf8ef"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">CAPITOL POLICE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-small id="HCC942FDBA0B94F85B31BBB3A65FC6049"><header>salaries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries of employees of the Capitol Police, including overtime, hazardous duty pay, and Government contributions for health, retirement, social security, professional liability insurance, and other applicable employee benefits, $300,000,000 of which overtime shall not exceed $30,928,000 unless the Committee on Appropriations of the House and Senate are notified, to be disbursed by the Chief of the Capitol Police or his designee.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H05CC316253BF4035A2C363595254D9DB"><header>general expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Capitol Police, including motor vehicles, communications and other equipment, security equipment and installation, uniforms, weapons, supplies, materials, training, medical services, forensic services, stenographic services, personal and professional services, the employee assistance program, the awards program, postage, communication services, travel advances, relocation of instructor and liaison personnel for the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, and not more than $5,000 to be expended on the certification of the Chief of the Capitol Police in connection with official representation and reception expenses, $66,465,499, to be disbursed by the Chief of the Capitol Police or his designee: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the cost of basic training for the Capitol Police at the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center for fiscal year 2016 shall be paid by the Secretary of Homeland Security from funds available to the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
				</appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="idCAEB7161F97B44D98639681217007813"><header>ADMINISTRATIVE PROVISION</header>
				</appropriations-major><appropriations-small id="idDD26B3C2120145A5854CF28F7D9B4A2E"><header>DEPOSIT OF REIMBURSEMENTS FOR LAW ENFORCEMENT ASSISTANCE</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="id2de5169b7d0049e6a217c846fd2f087d"><enum>1001.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ide3a1c40d8eef497a80b6041d9b6a8a3f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2802(a)(1) of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1905">2 U.S.C. 1905(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>District of Columbia)</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>District of Columbia), and from any other source in the case of assistance provided in connection with an activity that was not sponsored by Congress</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="added" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id361726ec5e374b448bc4093fb53fb08e" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 2802(a)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1905">2 U.S.C. 1905(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>law enforcement assistance to any Federal, State, or local government agency (including any agency of the District of Columbia)</quote> and inserting <quote>any law enforcement assistance for which reimbursement described in paragraph (1) is made</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="added" committee-id="SSAP00" id="idc8c496b1352b4585b0c9e19ae2a607b6" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall only apply with respect to any reimbursement received before, on, or after the date of the enactment of the Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id620C9A1D539445889B1055CE26D736F1"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">OFFICE OF COMPLIANCE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idA9447D41FD2D4F16BDA9AF0D5E7535C9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Office of Compliance, as authorized by section 305 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1385">2 U.S.C. 1385</external-xref>), $3,959,000, of which $450,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2017: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not more than $500 may be expended on the certification of the Executive Director of the Office of Compliance in connection with official representation and reception expenses.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major commented="no" id="idfb4ecaf1-4bfe-4301-9e40-37494cef0d38"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id7e850f7f-a716-416a-a3ce-649c98981085"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses necessary for operation of the Congressional Budget Office, including not more than $6,000 to be expended on the certification of the Director of the Congressional Budget Office in connection with official representation and reception expenses, $45,700,000.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id7610b8dc-48e2-4881-82ab-90a92dc98d92"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL</header>
			</appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="id723F547528A64A148C2F3606B373B693"><header>Capitol Construction and Operations</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idf58aadee-0333-4519-b987-a1323917bd27"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries for the Architect of the Capitol, and other personal services, at rates of pay provided by law; for all necessary expenses for surveys and studies, construction, operation, and general and administrative support in connection with facilities and activities under the care of the Architect of the Capitol including the Botanic Garden; electrical substations of the Capitol, Senate and House office buildings, and other facilities under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol; including furnishings and office equipment; including not more than $5,000 for official reception and representation expenses, to be expended as the Architect of the Capitol may approve; for purchase or exchange, maintenance, and operation of a passenger motor vehicle, $91,589,000.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idD25BE4D7B6A74F08BFF4D5BF114E83B7"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Building</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of the Capitol, $45,546,000, of which $21,237,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idC08AAC518B8343A8BC01E9A3256143E4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Grounds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for care and improvement of grounds surrounding the Capitol, the Senate and House office buildings, and the Capitol Power Plant, $11,973,000, of which $2,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idE111650C5994448FBAE8C6687433A8AC"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Senate Office Buildings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of Senate office buildings; and furniture and furnishings to be expended under the control and supervision of the Architect of the Capitol, $84,221,000, of which $26,283,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idCAD5EA7E3F0C48A2B4C9E04BD6CCAEC3"><header>House Office Buildings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of the House office buildings, $149,962,000, of which $23,886,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020, and of which $62,000,000 shall remain available until expended for the restoration and renovation of the Cannon House Office Building.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idE724FC8AF443461DB1D719D9E0951631"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, for a payment to the House Historic Buildings Revitalization Trust Fund, $10,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id821462b7-ba7e-463c-8697-08c87eecff0c"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Power Plant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of the Capitol Power Plant; lighting, heating, power (including the purchase of electrical energy) and water and sewer services for the Capitol, Senate and House office buildings, Library of Congress buildings, and the grounds about the same, Botanic Garden, Senate garage, and air conditioning refrigeration not supplied from plants in any of such buildings; heating the Government Printing Office and Washington City Post Office, and heating and chilled water for air conditioning for the Supreme Court Building, the Union Station complex, the Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building and the Folger Shakespeare Library, expenses for which shall be advanced or reimbursed upon request of the Architect of the Capitol and amounts so received shall be deposited into the Treasury to the credit of this appropriation, $101,601,000, of which $19,635,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not more than $9,000,000 of the funds credited or to be reimbursed to this appropriation as herein provided shall be available for obligation during fiscal year 2016.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id3DCD5468434B4D37AB3E35B67CDEFE1E"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Library Buildings and Grounds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the mechanical and structural maintenance, care and operation of the Library buildings and grounds, $29,132,000, of which $3,994,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id98c6e28f-3501-439c-8a6b-277c7dabe9fa"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Police Buildings, Grounds, and Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of buildings, grounds and security enhancements of the United States Capitol Police, wherever located, the Alternate Computer Facility, and AOC security operations, $22,535,000, of which $4,376,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idC09C30B675774994804F624DBC13E3DD"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Botanic Garden</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the maintenance, care and operation of the Botanic Garden and the nurseries, buildings, grounds, and collections; and purchase and exchange, maintenance, repair, and operation of a passenger motor vehicle; all under the direction of the Joint Committee on the Library, $11,980,000, of which $2,100,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, of the amount made available under this heading, the Architect of the Capitol may obligate and expend such sums as may be necessary for the maintenance, care and operation of the National Garden established under section 307E of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2146">2 U.S.C. 2146</external-xref>), upon vouchers approved by the Architect of the Capitol or a duly authorized designee.</text>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id8462C6D01F30468687C057BEE7AA5EBC"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Capitol Visitor Center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses for the operation of the Capitol Visitor Center, $20,844,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id852C4B9FB2E2419580E531BF9696BB1E"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrative Provisions</header></appropriations-intermediate><section id="idBADB7EEF3CC54A529EFB8A8D422FFEED"><enum>1101.</enum><header>No bonuses for contractors behind schedule or over budget </header><text>None of the funds made available in this Act for the Architect of the Capitol may be used to make incentive or award payments to contractors for work on contracts or programs for which the contractor is behind schedule or over budget, unless the Architect of the Capitol, or agency-employed designee, determines that any such deviations are due to unforeseeable events, government-driven scope changes, or are not significant within the overall scope of the project and/or program.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H8AF60847A2E4489196364518473F6F36"><header>scrims</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC543340E7C664376ADC1A7B7E1454C23" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1102.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used for scrims containing photographs of building facades during restoration or construction projects performed by the Architect of the Capitol.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="idBF5B4368E0754B62B741AA95B20C819D"><header>ACQUISITION OF PARCEL AT FORT MEADE</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="idc5a9de28d67c4552a4668006daa7cdb9"><enum>1103.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id04c571e966e84b2582f07d676a30f001"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acquisition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Architect of the Capitol is authorized to acquire from the Maryland State Highway Administration, at no cost to the United States, a parcel of real property (including improvements thereon) consisting of approximately 7.34 acres located within the portion of Fort George G. Meade in Anne Arundel County, Maryland, that was transferred to the Architect of the Capitol by the Secretary of the Army pursuant to section 122 of the Military Construction Appropriations Act, 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/141">2 U.S.C. 141</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="added" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id2b1cf3f9a92d45019e57d138f4723a5c" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>The terms and conditions applicable under subsections (b) and (d) of section 122 of the Military Construction Appropriations Act, 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/141">2 U.S.C. 141</external-xref> note) to the property acquired by the Architect of the Capitol pursuant to such section shall apply to the real property acquired by the Architect pursuant to the authority of this section.</text>
				</subsection></section><appropriations-major commented="no" id="id30fe4d95-0a75-4cad-9c86-93eba4243a8b"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">LIBRARY OF CONGRESS</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id6dfd5cd3-d945-4f64-b355-370c8e812997"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Library of Congress not otherwise provided for, including development and maintenance of the Library's catalogs; custody and custodial care of the Library buildings; special clothing; cleaning, laundering and repair of uniforms; preservation of motion pictures in the custody of the Library; operation and maintenance of the American Folklife Center in the Library; preparation and distribution of catalog records and other publications of the Library; hire or purchase of one passenger motor vehicle; and expenses of the Library of Congress Trust Fund Board not properly chargeable to the income of any trust fund held by the Board, $421,607,000, of which not more than $6,000,000 shall be derived from collections credited to this appropriation during fiscal year 2016, and shall remain available until expended, under the Act of June 28, 1902 (chapter 1301; 32 Stat. 480; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/150">2 U.S.C. 150</external-xref>) and not more than $350,000 shall be derived from collections during fiscal year 2016 and shall remain available until expended for the development and maintenance of an international legal information database and activities related thereto: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Library of Congress may not obligate or expend any funds derived from collections under the Act of June 28, 1902, in excess of the amount authorized for obligation or expenditure in appropriations Acts: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the total amount available for obligation shall be reduced by the amount by which collections are less than $6,350,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, of the total amount appropriated, not more than $12,000 may be expended, on the certification of the Librarian of Congress, in connection with official representation and reception expenses for the Overseas Field Offices: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the total amount appropriated, $8,231,000 shall remain available until expended for the digital collections and educational curricula program: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, of the total amount appropriated, $750,000 shall remain available until expended for upgrade of the Legislative Branch Financial Management System.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="ide2cdf99d-1f65-4d4a-8cb3-05f67c65fb6a"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Copyright Office</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idc8be4bb9-a0e9-4406-aa03-79a1a9c41ce9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For all necessary expenses of the Copyright Office, $56,490,000, of which not more than $30,000,000, to remain available until expended, shall be derived from collections credited to this appropriation during fiscal year 2016 under section 708(d) of title 17, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Copyright Office may not obligate or expend any funds derived from collections under such section, in excess of the amount authorized for obligation or expenditure in appropriations Acts: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not more than $5,777,000 shall be derived from collections during fiscal year 2016 under sections 111(d)(2), 119(b)(2), 803(e), 1005, and 1316 of such title: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the total amount available for obligation shall be reduced by the amount by which collections are less than $35,777,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not more than $100,000 of the amount appropriated is available for the maintenance of an <quote>International Copyright Institute</quote> in the Copyright Office of the Library of Congress for the purpose of training nationals of developing countries in intellectual property laws and policies: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not more than $6,500 may be expended, on the certification of the Librarian of Congress, in connection with official representation and reception expenses for activities of the International Copyright Institute and for copyright delegations, visitors, and seminars: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding any provision of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/17/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 17, United States Code, any amounts made available under this heading which are attributable to royalty fees and payments received by the Copyright Office pursuant to sections 111, 119, and chapter 10 of such title may be used for the costs incurred in the administration of the Copyright Royalty Judges program, with the exception of the costs of salaries and benefits for the Copyright Royalty Judges and staff under section 802(e).</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id15E9FEC1894041A0B4DE4B71C35060BB"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congressional Research Service</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idF0233C0BB77D41E7B0C48F7D5F191DC4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out the provisions of section 203 of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/166">2 U.S.C. 166</external-xref>) and to revise and extend the Annotated Constitution of the United States of America, $106,945,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That no part of such amount may be used to pay any salary or expense in connection with any publication, or preparation of material therefor (except the Digest of Public General Bills), to be issued by the Library of Congress unless such publication has obtained prior approval of either the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idE22F1A678FAB4EC8BD1FDCCBC3017266"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Books for the Blind and Physically Handicapped</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id7EC1D948E4654329B33CEA40A23A0FD2"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses to carry out the Act of March 3, 1931 (chapter 400; 46 Stat. 1487; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/135a">2 U.S.C. 135a</external-xref>), $50,248,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, of the total amount appropriated, $650,000 shall be available to contract to provide newspapers to blind and physically handicapped residents at no cost to the individual.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idfe766a12-e646-480f-bc6d-128c38f7f657"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrative Provision</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="id97c2b608-1040-4b25-948c-3e3f32633722"><header>reimbursable and revolving fund activities</header>
 </appropriations-small><section id="id5a7cd22e-25eb-48df-99ee-f84beecd0c37"><enum>1201.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id55480841-f7da-49a3-9538-c21a69d7d7ac"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2016, the obligational authority of the Library of Congress for the activities described in subsection (b) may not exceed $186,015,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb32accc4-af0f-4a56-94b5-1d39b29ceee4" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The activities referred to in subsection (a) are reimbursable and revolving fund activities that are funded from sources other than appropriations to the Library in appropriations Acts for the legislative branch.</text>
				</subsection></section><appropriations-major commented="no" id="idFD459C59BEB64D07B0B76CF1181AD7DE"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">GOVERNMENT PUBLISHING OFFICE</header>
			</appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idAF5C66016DA9447A84A2ADC562E69030"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congressional Publishing</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id48EFA0EDF6F14AEFB356DF5E6355EC25"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(INCLUDING TRANSFER OF FUNDS)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For authorized publishing of congressional information and the distribution of congressional information in any format; expenses necessary for preparing the semimonthly and session index to the Congressional Record, as authorized by law (section 902 of title 44, United States Code); publishing of Government publications authorized by law to be distributed to Members of Congress; and publishing and distribution of Government publications authorized by law to be distributed without charge to the recipient, $79,736,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That this appropriation shall not be available for paper copies of the permanent edition of the Congressional Record for individual Representatives, Resident Commissioners or Delegates authorized under section 906 of title 44, United States Code:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That this appropriation shall be available for the payment of obligations incurred under the appropriations for similar purposes for preceding fiscal years:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That, notwithstanding the 2-year limitation under section 718 of title 44, United States Code, none of the funds appropriated or made available under this Act or any other Act for printing and binding and related services provided to Congress under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, may be expended to print a document, report, or publication after the 27-month period beginning on the date that such document, report, or publication is authorized by Congress to be printed, unless Congress reauthorizes such printing in accordance with section 718 of title 44, United States Code:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That any unobligated or unexpended balances in this account or accounts for similar purposes for preceding fiscal years may be transferred to the Government Publishing Office business operations revolving fund for carrying out the purposes of this heading, subject to the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding sections 901, 902, and 906 of title 44, United States Code, this appropriation may be used to prepare indexes to the Congressional Record on only a monthly and session basis.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="idFEBF3A7E779E49C9999B66A431F0AE85"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public Information Programs of the Superintendent of Documents</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idEA9B16DEC03D47949A4D07BC0F5A3FDB"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idC206141A67CC4F468974A812F4E06651"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(INCLUDING TRANSFER OF FUNDS)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses of the public information programs of the Office of Superintendent of Documents necessary to provide for the cataloging and indexing of Government publications and their distribution to the public, Members of Congress, other Government agencies, and designated depository and international exchange libraries as authorized by law, $30,500,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That amounts of not more than $2,000,000 from current year appropriations are authorized for producing and disseminating Congressional serial sets and other related publications for fiscal years 2014 and 2015 to depository and other designated libraries:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That any unobligated or unexpended balances in this account or accounts for similar purposes for preceding fiscal years may be transferred to the Government Publishing Office business operations revolving fund for carrying out the purposes of this heading, subject to the approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id4C3B1FC46BB54C7DBE1158AA186B82F9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Government Publishing Office Business Operations Revolving Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payment to the Government Publishing Office Business Operations Revolving Fund, $8,764,000, to remain available until expended, for information technology development and facilities repair: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Government Publishing Office is hereby authorized to make such expenditures, within the limits of funds available and in accordance with law, and to make such contracts and commitments without regard to fiscal year limitations as provided by section 9104 of title 31, United States Code, as may be necessary in carrying out the programs and purposes set forth in the budget for the current fiscal year for the Government Publishing Office business operations revolving fund:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That not more than $7,500 may be expended on the certification of the Director of the Government Publishing Office in connection with official representation and reception expenses:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the business operations revolving fund shall be available for the hire or purchase of not more than 12 passenger motor vehicles:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That expenditures in connection with travel expenses of the advisory councils to the Director of the Government Publishing Office shall be deemed necessary to carry out the provisions of title 44, United States Code:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the business operations revolving fund shall be available for temporary or intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, but at rates for individuals not more than the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That activities financed through the business operations revolving fund may provide information in any format:<proviso><italic> Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the business operations revolving fund and the funds provided under the heading <quote>Public Information Programs of the Superintendent of Documents</quote> may not be used for contracted security services at GPO's passport facility in the District of Columbia.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major commented="no" id="ida284a46d-b03c-47df-9356-2b3f2834ccef"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">GOVERNMENT ACCOUNTABILITY OFFICE</header>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id358cdb48-6599-47dd-8311-39c30b04ff50"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Government Accountability Office, including not more than $12,500 to be expended on the certification of the Comptroller General of the United States in connection with official representation and reception expenses; temporary or intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, but at rates for individuals not more than the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title; hire of one passenger motor vehicle; advance payments in foreign countries in accordance with section 3324 of title 31, United States Code; benefits comparable to those payable under sections 901(5), (6), and (8) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4081">22 U.S.C. 4081(5)</external-xref>, (6), and (8)); and under regulations prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States, rental of living quarters in foreign countries, $525,000,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, in addition, $25,450,000 of payments received under sections 782, 3521, and 9105 of title 31, United States Code, shall be available without fiscal year limitation: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That this appropriation and appropriations for administrative expenses of any other department or agency which is a member of the National Intergovernmental Audit Forum or a Regional Intergovernmental Audit Forum shall be available to finance an appropriate share of either Forum's costs as determined by the respective Forum, including necessary travel expenses of non-Federal participants: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That payments hereunder to the Forum may be credited as reimbursements to any appropriation from which costs involved are initially financed.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id3DDB5BA89C7242AA9D2E03753409BCF9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrative Provision</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="id4A7083BCDC7E4AF884CD5732E0042763"><header>Federal Government Details</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><section id="idAA174C1473794E0DBBBEB9E1E6A96B54"><enum>1301.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 731 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8610A0066A9C4ECA8758BAE81CF58E83" style="appropriations">
 <subsection id="id7F1FEA0D0A434335A5C23DE6D89D6585"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Federal Government Details</header><text>The activities of the Government Accountability Office may, in the reasonable discretion of the Comptroller General, be carried out by sending or receiving details of personnel to other branches or agencies of the Federal Government, on a reimbursable, partially-reimbursable, or nonreimbursable basis.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 <appropriations-major commented="no" id="idC9B02987FEA641A19A2D35BD35D1F995"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For a payment to the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund for financing activities of the Open World Leadership Center under section 313 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1151">2 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>), $5,700,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That funds made available to support Russian participants shall only be used for those engaging in free market development, humanitarian activities, and civic engagement, and shall not be used for officials of the central government of Russia.</text>
 </appropriations-major><appropriations-major commented="no" id="idE9138269691A4943885CF9E0BAB9A698"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payment to the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Development Trust Fund established under section 116 of the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1105">2 U.S.C. 1105</external-xref>), $430,000.</text>
				</appropriations-major></section></title><title changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id968DEBD47A584C74BA342E122E978705" level-type="subsequent" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>II</enum>
			<appropriations-major commented="no" id="idB5CE6D72C05840ABA472A9DA430D9F6C"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">GENERAL PROVISIONS</header>
			</appropriations-major><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id901061EB1C5B493098F4146F47FC57E5"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">MAINTENANCE AND CARE OF PRIVATE VEHICLES</header>
 </appropriations-small><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDF074A895DDE4C5F8267BB1B1F422DF9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of the funds appropriated in this Act shall be used for the maintenance or care of private vehicles, except for emergency assistance and cleaning as may be provided under regulations relating to parking facilities for the House of Representatives issued by the Committee on House Administration and for the Senate issued by the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
				<appropriations-small commented="no" id="idA6E1F0EA120E493B8B73BE5C022DD570"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">FISCAL YEAR LIMITATION</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id089cb7d7-8d12-4f8d-bf4f-a2796daf3917" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of the funds appropriated in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond fiscal year 2016 unless expressly so provided in this Act.</text>
				<appropriations-small commented="no" id="id2FC8C1DF9F2F4DADBF971DE6FA59BC1D"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">RATES OF COMPENSATION AND DESIGNATION</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7B6DA63939AB45349DAA2EA641466E4A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>203.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever in this Act any office or position not specifically established by the Legislative Pay Act of 1929 (46 Stat. 32 et seq.) is appropriated for or the rate of compensation or designation of any office or position appropriated for is different from that specifically established by such Act, the rate of compensation and the designation in this Act shall be the permanent law with respect thereto: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the provisions in this Act for the various items of official expenses of Members, officers, and committees of the Senate and House of Representatives, and clerk hire for Senators and Members of the House of Representatives shall be the permanent law with respect thereto.</text>
				<appropriations-small commented="no" id="idCB5D8896949D418B8AC055E1B0284373"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">CONSULTING SERVICES</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD782E87923F047D5B7BE5675FEF8E120" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>204.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expenditure of any appropriation under this Act for any consulting service through procurement contract, under section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, shall be limited to those contracts where such expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, except where otherwise provided under existing law, or under existing Executive order issued under existing law.</text>
				<appropriations-small commented="no" id="id7820D92225A84017AC3340BD5DF30E70"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline"> COSTS OF LBFMC</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCD3DDA6B05E44337888CDFDFFC6CB502" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>205.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts available for administrative expenses of any legislative branch entity which participates in the Legislative Branch Financial Managers Council (LBFMC) established by charter on March 26, 1996, shall be available to finance an appropriate share of LBFMC costs as determined by the LBFMC, except that the total LBFMC costs to be shared among all participating legislative branch entities (in such allocations among the entities as the entities may determine) may not exceed $2,000.</text>
				<appropriations-small commented="no" id="id98501E0DB7B9403297B2D88DB63B801F"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">LANDSCAPE MAINTENANCE</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD2891EA5FFCF4589AD97B2A306918890" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>206.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2016 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Architect of the Capitol, in consultation with the District of Columbia, is authorized to maintain and improve the landscape features, excluding streets, in Square 580 up to the beginning of I–395.</text>
				<appropriations-small commented="no" id="id8068A54BA51648DBBAB73105025B8B4A"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">LIMITATION ON TRANSFERS</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id886618CD6FBA45D492DECED5F6A578BF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>207.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be transferred to any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, except pursuant to a transfer made by, or transfer authority provided in, this Act or any other appropriation Act.</text>
				<appropriations-small commented="no" id="id6399DCA52B5E4202A2685BE6F3823DB7"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">GUIDED TOURS OF THE CAPITOL</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id422AAA47CDB6453BB484896CAD970644" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>208.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idE8B68134593F4A7095671B23152B3D2F"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), none of the funds made available to the Architect of the Capitol in this Act may be used to eliminate or restrict guided tours of the United States Capitol which are led by employees and interns of offices of Members of Congress and other offices of the House of Representatives and Senate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04A10D4851834099ADADE6EF68B167B2" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the direction of the Capitol Police Board, or at the direction of the Architect of the Capitol with the approval of the Capitol Police Board, guided tours of the United States Capitol which are led by employees and interns described in subsection (a) may be suspended temporarily or otherwise subject to restriction for security or related reasons to the same extent as guided tours of the United States Capitol which are led by the Architect of the Capitol.</text>
				</subsection></section><appropriations-small commented="no" id="id15827DB8101C463893F2202DFE2EFE5E"><header>BATTERY RECHARGING STATIONS FOR PRIVATELY OWNED VEHICLES IN PARKING AREAS UNDER THE JURISDICTION OF
			 THE LIBRARIAN OF CONGRESS AT NO NET COST TO THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT</header>
 </appropriations-small><section commented="no" id="idaea17068a7244b3f9cd015eb1ea906f1"><enum>209.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idac3fe1fc9a414b83afc9ae430bff5c67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered employee</quote> means—</text> <paragraph changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id35ce9cd572cb4f2399bcfcc06b333b35" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an employee of the Library of Congress; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="idc465de985179448b91b2007867a591cd" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other individual who is authorized to park in any parking area under the jurisdiction of the Library of Congress on the Library of Congress buildings and grounds.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id815bccf936f74c56ad8918f300e4bc14" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id492a16d243404037a88aec3faf7dd422"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), funds appropriated to the Architect of the Capitol under the heading <quote>Capitol Power Plant</quote> under the heading <quote>ARCHITECT OF THE CAPITOL</quote> in any fiscal year are available to construct, operate, and maintain on a reimbursable basis battery recharging stations in parking areas under the jurisdiction of the Library of Congress on Library of Congress buildings and grounds for use by privately owned vehicles used by covered employees.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9536a091148b42b8acc9370e3524f286"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vendors authorized</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Architect of the Capitol may use one or more vendors on a commission basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idde307071133e4c168430f14cdc957e4c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval of construction</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol may construct or direct the construction of battery recharging stations described under paragraph (1) after—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id0a7d4ead16624082aef991ee9ec34982"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submission of written notice detailing the numbers and locations of the battery recharging stations to the Joint Committee on the Library; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id162a93a3943e45818db3e36ac5ed866b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approval by that Committee.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id2df93fe9d1f24ef496f62cabd3ada308" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fees and charges</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="idf537b3b8a67f4573a8cd1ad2c9a4d6bc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Architect of the Capitol shall charge fees or charges for electricity provided to covered employees sufficient to cover the costs to the Architect of the Capitol to carry out this section, including costs to any vendors or other costs associated with maintaining the battery charging stations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id0c286cddce174a93a9313d524189ccb7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval of fees or charges</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol may establish and adjust fees or charges under paragraph (1) after—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="ide186a2350cef49cd9532528fd1095b55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submission of written notice detailing the amount of the fee or charge to be established or adjusted to the Joint Committee on the Library; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id6bd67c09ed184f9fb1c54b22ab0ccaa3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approval by that Committee.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id37552964762f4d52b8c1e2052dab803e" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deposit and availability of fees, charges, and commissions</header><text>Any fees, charges, or commissions collected by the Architect of the Capitol under this section shall be—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id7e0e8ccb3168412aa7d104d052e26afb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the appropriations account described under subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idea75321dd0a44038b84e461bc34f917d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>available for obligation without further appropriation during the fiscal year collected.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id6e61f18d7a1b407bba72c79ef86fe1fd" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="id61d9356c25af4855878999005de1107e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Architect of the Capitol shall submit a report on the financial administration and cost recovery of activities under this section with respect to that fiscal year to the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idc47e1cb6666f449dab443795d278c267"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Avoiding subsidy</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="ida1f18d42cb4c4a2e856a2f7c4134c42a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act and every 3 years thereafter, the Architect of the Capitol shall submit a report to the Joint Committee on the Library determining whether covered employees using battery charging stations as authorized by this section are receiving a subsidy from the taxpayers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id016b46bb15184a309eaaa563cc4e2bf4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modification of rates and fees</header><text>If a determination is made under subparagraph (A) that a subsidy is being received, the Architect of the Capitol shall submit a plan to the Joint Committee on the Library on how to update the program to ensure no subsidy is being received. If the Joint Committee does not act on the plan within 60 days, the Architect of the Capitol shall take appropriate steps to increase rates or fees to ensure reimbursement for the cost of the program consistent with an appropriate schedule for amortization, to be charged to those using the charging stations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSAP00" id="id642e848e2d8d4184be8949ca1e3a5736" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2016 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text> </subsection></section><appropriations-small commented="no" id="idDB2DA9FF2DB44886BAD50D467544B7C9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">COST OF LIVING ADJUSTMENT</header> </appropriations-small><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id902EFFFD3B534037AB62CFDE303567F2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>210.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no adjustment shall be made under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) (relating to cost of living adjustments for Members of Congress) during fiscal year 2016.</text>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCE475DB776D24ED9B1C7B61DD57A29C7"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>May 20, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations</action-desc><action-date>June 11, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

