<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCC24E166B8AD4A4E96803C55B5225647" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2237 IH: Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2237</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150505">May 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans to establish within the Department of Veterans Affairs a center
			 of excellence in the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and
			 rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0D52FA2500F241E590B886641531B301" style="OLC">
 <section id="H552EE6E3AB734939A883BDD5FD4BAA29" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H93353BED8905444585891D72133CE5A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Center of excellence in prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures</header> <subsection id="HD3AC3317D0B7472AB0BCB6D3D0B7C769"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish within the Department of Veterans Affairs a center of excellence in the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures to carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (d). Such center shall be established using—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFCB6E04F34D14F29991CE44C1139129C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the directives, policies, and Comptroller General and Inspector General recommendations in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE92AE10097BD49A294E9EBC751B3AADE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>guidance issued pursuant to section 313 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 1692; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1074">10 U.S.C. 1074</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56B5429CC1734007BF467346028B06CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting the site for the center of excellence established under subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall consider entities that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H91FBC94A3CE943E4BD9DE6580AB70A9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are equipped with the specialized equipment needed to study, diagnose, and treat health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD934E8FD88D4CC48297174220DFF915"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a publication track record of post-deployment health exposures among veterans who served in the Armed Forces in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CC76379F1D8415B9161833654BC1586"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have collaborated with a geosciences department that has a medical geology division;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H843267D9E5414010B1DC491AA64940D1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have developed animal models and in vitro models of dust immunology and lung injury consistent with the injuries of members of the Armed Forces who served in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40B4391C9D6C45D686B4DF506B9F63A8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>have expertise in allergy and immunology, pulmonary diseases, and industrial and management engineering.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2EE11516A1E499E937600E0D9FD021C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the center of excellence collaborates, to the maximum extent practicable, with the Secretary of Defense, institutions of higher education, and other appropriate public and private entities (including international entities) to carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H43090D1A3EB34EBA8D1C6E832B85CD44"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The center of excellence shall have the following responsibilities:</text> <paragraph id="H664A64BADE224AC59F6D0992D0342376"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide for the development, testing, and dissemination within the Department of Veterans Affairs of best practices for the treatment of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C764A6893E9480C94756A3417305EBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide guidance for the health system of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense in determining the personnel required to provide quality health care for members of the Armed Forces and veterans with health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E9343427DDF47E4872C66E1377A9B94"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To establish, implement, and oversee a comprehensive program to train health professionals of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense in the treatment of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EA8B592EF634FD1BBC4E11B7AC38246"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To facilitate advancements in the study of the short-term and long-term effects of exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4C5D6EFA5BD499ABC9FA05FBCCAE60E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To disseminate within the military medical treatment facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs best practices for training health professionals with respect to health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECD8A34B080F4CB6B774B4EFE8DF9394"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To conduct basic science and translational research on health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures for the purposes of understanding the etiology of such conditions and developing preventive interventions and new treatments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F808540D8CC47E1BB8843E664FC5A1F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide medical treatment to all veterans identified as part of the burn pits registry established under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/527">38 U.S.C. 527</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14F9F2E48C4C4AB9A572FC5B9D932CAB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of burn pits registry data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out its responsibilities under subsection (d), the center shall have access to and make use of the data accumulated by the burn pits registry established under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/527">38 U.S.C. 527</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H58CE1B8F779E4282BC357D2C14B1306E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD9552A9C2D9A41FEB00762CD599B7CCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>burn pit</quote> means an area of land located in Afghanistan or Iraq that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H60F26F7E55CE4BB78A92AFEECAEBC281"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designated by the Secretary of Defense to be used for disposing solid waste by burning in the outdoor air; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6D21859C2F247AC8AA57FCEF7BDD9E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not contain a commercially manufactured incinerator or other equipment specifically designed and manufactured for the burning of solid waste.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49053D1121624CF0BB0A4F7661F11C18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>other environmental exposures</quote> means exposure to environmental hazards, including burn pits, dust or sand, hazardous materials, and waste at any site in Afghanistan or Iraq that emits smoke containing pollutants present in the environment or smoke from fires or explosions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB84375A74A114F80BBBBC32DEA9ECA0C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


