<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A86A3FAE423420D90766CCBE428092E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1423 IH: Self-Insurance Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1423</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from the definition of health insurance coverage certain medical stop-loss insurance obtained by certain plan sponsors of group health plans.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H09BDCA4F241241C29EB0E15F956E3DB1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H79487346CF4944C98BDF3D1438DA2DDF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Self-Insurance Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H623BD97899F44A33A1DFC52FBFAC7EB3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certain medical stop loss insurance obtained by certain plan sponsors of group health plans not included under the definition of health insurance coverage</header> <subsection id="H33C33BD37FB24A61B7AC380FC29C3D22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>PHSA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2791(b)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such term shall not include a stop loss policy obtained by a self-insured health plan or a plan sponsor of a group health plan that self-insures the health risks of its plan participants to reimburse the plan or sponsor for losses that the plan or sponsor incurs in providing health or medical benefits to such plan participants in excess of a predetermined level set forth in the stop loss policy obtained by such plan or sponsor.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H32E6A0A4F2A8442F860241194890D42B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>ERISA</header><text>Section 733(b)(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1191b">29 U.S.C. 1191b(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such term shall not include a stop loss policy obtained by a self-insured health plan or a plan sponsor of a group health plan that self-insures the health risks of its plan participants to reimburse the plan or sponsor for losses that the plan or sponsor incurs in providing health or medical benefits to such plan participants in excess of a predetermined level set forth in the stop loss policy obtained by such plan or sponsor.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBCA3076647934F23BEED7506DF493BC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>IRC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9832">Section 9832(b)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such term shall not include a stop loss policy obtained by a self-insured health plan or a plan sponsor of a group health plan that self-insures the health risks of its plan participants to reimburse the plan or sponsor for losses that the plan or sponsor incurs in providing health or medical benefits to such plan participants in excess of a predetermined level set forth in the stop loss policy obtained by such plan or sponsor.</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


