<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE52AC57DA74E4C219AD5E529A5F39501" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1093 IH: Clean Water Compliance and Ratepayer Affordability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1093</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out a pilot program to
			 work with municipalities that are seeking to develop and implement
			 integrated plans to meet their wastewater and stormwater obligations under
			 the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3F62C00987E54BCB97609F7157EED0A5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE3473B2428A646C9A1155A6EB652D92C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Water Compliance and Ratepayer Affordability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA55AE9083092477FB0B4A3B07A80808C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Integrated municipal stormwater and wastewater approach framework</header> <subsection id="H3440A82F6DCE470CBF0D7BB007C61DA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the first 5 fiscal years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in coordination with appropriate State, local, and regional authorities, shall carry out a pilot program under which the Administrator shall work cooperatively with and facilitate the efforts of municipalities to develop and implement integrated plans to meet their wastewater and stormwater obligations under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) in a more cost-effective and flexible manner.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB368F9069708416680461D493022D6D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Framework</header><text>The Administrator shall carry out the pilot program in a manner that is consistent with the Integrated Municipal Stormwater and Wastewater Approach Framework issued by the Environmental Protection Agency, dated May 2012.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4C87C04F61744B1D89D007D2C78AD5C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of municipalities</header>
 <paragraph id="H2544C567F13B4A2E8D0FF304C3EAD155"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with States that have approved National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System programs, shall select not fewer than 15 municipalities to participate in the pilot program each fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EE016653DE74E7D8C7BCC2D7158D20E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility of municipalities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A municipality shall be eligible to participate in the pilot program if the municipality—</text> <subparagraph id="H8E41A744518F4DEDB30329FD3B83B6A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System permit holder or designee; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H686585F473FB49599E3FD972D42FD9CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is operating under an administrative order, administrative consent agreement, or judicial consent decree to comply with the requirements of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E936A68C3614D518FFA4E40858F4206"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In selecting municipalities under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF10C3AB243F64BACA721C40FD5ECF628"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifically focus on—</text>
 <clause id="H0702BDEB19D9474FB73EBE5A450F1791"><enum>(i)</enum><text>municipalities that are operating under an administrative order, administrative consent agreement, or judicial consent decree to comply with the requirements of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2F0E0C8207A44A6EABDC098CA6B64F85"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>municipalities facing compliance issues under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, in addition to the municipalities described in clause (i); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3AD002E520364C2BB8D764BC6A039CC5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>municipalities that are affected by affordability constraints in planning and implementing control measures to address wet weather discharges from their wastewater and stormwater facilities; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B28E04320BA42799E1C05E9D40CF95B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>give priority to eligible municipalities with a history of knowledgeable, detailed, and comprehensive efforts to develop integrated and adaptive clean water management practices, without regard to the status of the municipality in the process of planning or implementing such practices.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB91CF1ABA8C34EC98FB1D05F5912F00A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval of integrated plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H6DD1238B9EC74B9C8C633CB3538A5E7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In approving the integrated plan of a municipality under the pilot program, the Administrator shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDD083ECBD529460AB361B623EDAFA43C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>account for the financial capability of the municipality to adequately address the requirements of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act that apply to the municipality;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E6715075C84422BBC73420ABE7D50E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prioritize the obligations of the municipality under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act according to the most cost-effective and environmentally beneficial outcomes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B97E1D357904224A0558FA52F4FA79B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>account for the maintenance, operational, and regulatory obligations of the municipality; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA80ECF0B3C5348FC950E171F03979C8F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enable the municipality to implement innovative and flexible approaches to meet the obligations of the municipality under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A3CE50182AD4B268293DA247081DB4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of adaptive management approaches</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF4EB36EE8DDB42DFAF329D8A855E9E2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting municipalities to participate in the program, the Administrator may give priority to a municipality that is seeking to develop and implement an integrated plan that includes adaptive approaches to account for changed or future uncertain circumstances.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39B176DB9B45434DB4A7B3CBF311F55C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Types of adaptive approaches</header><text>Adaptive approaches referred to in subparagraph (A) include, at a minimum—</text> <clause id="HC989CCB7350D4FB09910CFB0D0DF0215"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of new innovative technical or institutional approaches; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H509274E213CF4708B6BCDD8835C50356"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ability to adapt the integrated plan in response to new regulatory requirements and reductions in financial capability.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9017E954F075406AA943B6F92F03F109"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional authorities</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Administrator may, in full coordination and mutual agreement with a municipality selected to participate in the pilot program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC7173544349E468194781EE2171E5F28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>extend the allowable national pollutant discharge elimination system permit term under section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>) to a maximum of 25 years, and make corresponding changes to any associated implementation schedule;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACA60194535242B69F976DADC5C5D747"><enum>(B)</enum><text>modify the implementation terms of a consent decree entered into by the municipality with the Administrator pursuant to that Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C8D5D56292D4669A5F64493245567D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide additional regulatory flexibility under that Act in approving and implementing an integrated plan that includes adaptive approaches in order to encourage the innovation integral to such approaches.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95AA7B71792043169DD3FF7C4ECC3B45"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Municipality defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>municipality</quote> means a county, city, town, township, or subdivision of a State or local government.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H9E17BCC4C69B4F5CB9BE4E9F5F2DE3A1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter for 5 years, the Administrator shall transmit to Congress a report on the results of the pilot program, including a description of the specific outcomes expected to be achieved that will reduce the costs of complying with the requirements of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act for municipalities participating in the program and similarly situated municipalities.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


