<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4BA57033792F401388E81226B406EC4E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1971 IH: Climate Solutions Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1971</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reduce greenhouse gas emissions and protect the climate.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H614F9CCE28E94124AF74AE681D1C71B8" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCB7741BCFE25443A989F4FB87FCD0E49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Solutions Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC5C34B4226BB497E812A4BCEC742E007"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H9DA1AC80D5504E82ADC28D2AD948E538"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD0125663220F4CC38C911FD8A1315B10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has the objective of stabilizing greenhouse gas concentrations in the atmosphere at a level that would prevent <quote>dangerous anthropogenic interference</quote> with the climate system by becoming a party to the 1992 United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, pledging to China to reduce greenhouse gas emissions to 28 percent of their 2005 levels by 2025, and regulating greenhouse gas emissions from stationary sources, mobile sources, and electrical power suppliers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF00032113B614CC380CA13A88B0477C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To achieve this objective, the increase in global mean surface temperature should not exceed 2°C (3.6°F) above preindustrial temperature, much of which is already projected to occur by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2A3C71E4845473B877B3FDE329A8BDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The risks associated with a temperature increase above 2°C (3.6°F) are grave, including the disintegration of the Greenland ice sheet, which, if it were to melt completely, would raise global average sea level by approximately 23 feet, devastating many of the world’s coastal areas and population centers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14627184760648C18ECBF8F835D0AB8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change projects that temperatures will rise between 1.8°C to 4.0°C (3.2°F to 7.2°F) by the end of the century, under a range of expected emissions trends, but if there are common goals to limit greenhouse gas emissions, the temperature increase can be limited to 2°C (3.6°F) or less.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0297CD02B8F4E3BB34905571E3CCC1D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Serious global warming impacts have already been observed in the United States and worldwide, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5EDAC03DDD344A0C9B8DED99FF2CB95C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increases in heat waves and other extreme weather events;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD7A659AC58C4D2F92895CE4166573F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rise in sea level, retreat of glaciers and polar ice;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0922C656CB7C4189BBB0AF30296A15C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>decline in mountain snowpack, increased drought (including droughts in the West and South United States) resulting in damage to our economy and property;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5DDD9AF778E40C3AE9A507C6FAC5A68"><enum>(D)</enum><text>extreme weather conditions resulting in wildfires, stronger hurricanes and polar vortex occurrences resulting in further damage to property and our economy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C6A667CC62F45678860CF71F82FC1BB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>damage to our environment such as ocean acidification, extensive coral bleaching, migrations, and shifts in the yearly cycles of plants and animals; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFC1B4D5A26B4332B4F874A803579C40"><enum>(F)</enum><text>effects on human population including population displacement and adverse health effects such as the spread of infectious diseases and climate-related conditions such as asthma.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02A84B9B80514C1083A16A1D2FA11E8B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Scientists project that under a midrange estimate of global warming, by 2050, roughly 25 percent of animal and plant species will be committed to extinction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFCEABC87ECA4714B8F205DD6D4A4FA4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Decisive action is needed to minimize the many dangers posed by global warming.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H119FE90E69204828AB2837B41D24B7E6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The timing of such action is critical, given that greenhouse gases can persist in the atmosphere for more than a century.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9074FA2E06D746CBAA91443A999EBFA0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The International Energy Agency has warned in its most recent World Energy Outlook report that, unless there is a serious commitment to investing in zero carbon renewable energy resources, much of the amount of projected limits necessary to avoid greenhouse-gas-emission-caused dangerous anthropogenic interference with the climate system will be locked in and exceeded.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA76A3E06686440218F69D00AF60CBE19"><enum>(10)</enum><text>PricewaterhouseCoopers Low Carbon Economy Index Report estimates that carbon-based fuel use needs to be reduced 6.5 percent per year through the year 2100, nearly six times the current rate, to avoid dangerous anthropogenic interference with the climate system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CFF08A0834241879861578CE45623F9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>With only 5 percent of the world population, the United States emits approximately 20 percent of the world’s total greenhouse gas emissions and must be a leader in addressing global warming.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59EE56BED5404DC98F62A5C1AF043F56"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The State of California, the 8th largest economy in the world, has shown that renewable energy standards and greenhouse gas emissions regulation can reduce greenhouse gas emissions while fostering significant economic growth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7755C5B28F164D89A627982B6ED39A68"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Existing energy efficiency and clean, renewable energy technologies can reduce global warming pollution, while saving consumers money, reducing our dependence on oil, enhancing national security, cleaning the air, and protecting pristine places from drilling and mining.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21B245B35ECF49798CBEF38368DF9C78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of the Congress that the United States should participate in negotiations under the 1992 United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change and honor its commitments therefrom with the objective of securing United States participation in agreements that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4A4EDE10C3E8438D88E7DAE866103F7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish mitigation commitments by all countries that are major emitters of greenhouse gases, consistent with the principle of common but differentiated responsibilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A88BA6772FF4899BACB51EF0894A555"><enum>(2)</enum><text>achieve reductions in global greenhouse gas emissions at a pace and level sufficient to avoid dangerous interference with the Earth’s climate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7FFE812B32841189AE958C514339E31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advance and protect the economic and national security interests of the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><title id="H05AAA25544DB4735B567580B07D92721"><enum>I</enum><header>RENEWABLE ENERGY</header> <section id="HC6A5E6A53B594D73A9C94496EFAAF489"><enum>101.</enum><header>National renewable energy standard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824a-4">16 U.S.C. 824a–4 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H4DC576DBD089448AAF0AE92F3E1E9DE5" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD256992096B74AB38E544330EF2A3C96"><enum>610.</enum><header>National renewable energy standard</header>
 <subsection id="H8D8FB4ECD28E4C9384191D7686213401"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations requiring that—</text> <paragraph id="HE13308758FA74534B505DA53B54DA8AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>beginning in calendar year 2020, the percentage of electric energy generated from renewable sources that is sold at the retail level in the United States shall increase each year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7183E1FB41024B3D93C2B5092BB6783E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in calendar year 2030 and each subsequent calendar year, such percentage shall be not less than 40 percent of the total electric energy sold at the retail level in the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8EF37AE6E5BB4FEE9A0EB0D3CFA1CC61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in calendar year 2050 and each subsequent calendar year, such percentage shall not be less than 80 percent of the total electric energy sold at the retail level in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8E235EA68004E928899514F284DD489"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H90B22A2D150A49B988810D36AB9FA447"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subsequent increases</header><text>Upon petition or upon the Secretary’s own initiative, the Secretary may increase the percentage required by subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1888E08E72224684828DC0B99E093FA1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt or limit State actions to enhance renewable energy generation or energy efficiency.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H1F09C028C80E442E8F25A6423BF9C78B"><enum>II</enum><header>ENERGY EFFICIENCY</header>
 <section id="HB180C37C5DA144419D488AE71A5F9C2B"><enum>201.</enum><header>National energy efficiency standard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824a-4">16 U.S.C. 824a–4 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 101 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H72AA29FEAF0C44EA916D8B141493BBAE" style="OLC">
					<section id="HC65C239005C54CF1BCE617E71EDC20D6"><enum>611.</enum><header>National energy efficiency standard</header>
 <subsection id="H1FE6AA59631E49B99FDCCAB9062AE89E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations in accordance with this section setting end-user savings targets for retail electric energy and natural gas suppliers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD3C81AB9EE534770878DF8E0F5AAC9A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB28CEF1CF29B4042A320BFEF322C639E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>With respect to targets under subsection (a):</text> <paragraph id="H1C733F99AC234766BC63860CD22F3266"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The targets shall require each supplier to secure annual savings of a set percentage of the supplier’s most recent year’s sales to retail customers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89783B003E2246928F271915F40E3C08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The savings shall be achieved through end-use efficiency improvements at customer facilities.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD15AE47D5B1148E5AB522DFB743C596C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The targets—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCDAFADBCC01849278018139E8C40D604"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for retail electric energy suppliers shall increase gradually from 0.25 percent of sales in 2018 to 1.5 percent of sales in 2023 and each year thereafter through 2028; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE51F070D9D054A54829EF7DF951CECFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for retail natural gas suppliers shall increase gradually from 0.25 percent of sales in 2018 to 0.5 percent of sales in 2023 and each year thereafter through 2028.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA42C59D799A429F8712D76440776850"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The targets are cumulative. Each year’s savings shall be achieved in addition to the previous years’ savings.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4D1171CBE9B404C8152FA0B5AF45362"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Required percentages after 2028</header><text>The Secretary may, upon petition or upon the Secretary’s own initiative, increase the required percentage of end-user savings for years after 2028.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H923C4F7225D84DE3879C994319EAB22F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Market-Based Trading System</header><text>The Secretary shall allow suppliers to achieve the targets under subsection (a) through a market-based trading system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HABAD47AD89274BFCB2E1E295826759E6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt or limit State actions to enhance renewable energy generation or energy efficiency.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H7FEA831A6B5145558C2EECB6D27B175E"><enum>III</enum><header>Science-Based Reductions</header>
 <section id="HA8E4F16AE5974C40A5967BD522831CD5"><enum>301.</enum><header>Emission reduction targets</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (in this title referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall promulgate annual emission reduction targets for each of calendar years 2030 through 2050, so as to ensure that the quantity of United States greenhouse gas emissions—</text>
 <paragraph id="H52CBFC3C336A4206B556FADBD8788FDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in 2035, is at least 40 percent below the quantity of such emissions in 1990; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE62DA7C653947FDB27B2A20F49ABA5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in 2050, is at least 80 percent below the quantity of such emissions in 1990.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HAC34D0368E454565AFFF14D4F5DCD117"><enum>302.</enum><header>National academies review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Administrator shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academies (or, if the National Academies decline to enter into such arrangement, another appropriate entity) under which the National Academies, acting through the National Academy of Sciences and the National Research Council, will submit a report to the Administrator and the Congress on the prospects for avoiding dangerous anthropogenic interference with the climate system and the progress made to date. Each such report shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD5A8B5E61FA84E0EA3DC5E635BC471AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate whether the emission reduction targets promulgated pursuant to section 301 and the policies to reduce United States greenhouse gas emissions under this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and other provisions of law, including the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>), are likely to be sufficient to avoid dangerous climate change, taking into account the actions of other nations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF68E7F6DBA974FFAA2BC6B54419D9F42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the National Academies concludes that such targets and policies are not likely to be sufficient to avoid dangerous climate change—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1E92C955209C41C7909BD189D8F6CB02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify the needed amount of further reductions in atmospheric greenhouse gas concentrations; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF24A4F1C89EB457C81847D47463572B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommend additional United States and international actions to further reduce atmospheric greenhouse gas concentrations.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HA8F668833743424C809AA02B29BCD119"><enum>303.</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <subsection id="HD735A1DF579644399A9357C95C7DB0AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEC2EC5A651E54EB4AF9046C178B52E67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act, promulgate final regulations to implement the emission reduction targets under section 301; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3E09BFEC736462E83B29FE8D972D27E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less than every 5 years thereafter—</text> <subparagraph id="H25534F5E044743F0A11CA256D050CF28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review such regulations, taking into account the reports under section 302; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9962CC2FF2804E45B9A5C05C837ACF42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>revise such regulation as necessary to implement such emission reduction targets.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BE27A4C3A2543F79A84E281B3984F3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking on recommendations of national academies</header><text>If any report under section 302 includes a recommendation under section 302(2)(B) for regulatory action by a Federal department or agency, and such regulatory action is within the authority of such department or agency (under law other than this subsection), the head of such department or agency shall, not later than 2 years after the submission of such report, finalize a rulemaking—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD2A9D12F151C4AB7B4680AF85CD1D363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to carry out such regulatory action; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC3DE538FB649C9A5DE45AA4518F81A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to explain the reasons for declining to act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H170769231A5E4876B0F0D6791EEEA6A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional regulations</header><text>The regulations promulgated under subsection (a) may include additional regulations to reduce emissions of United States greenhouse gases from any source or sector. Any such regulations that address sources whose greenhouse gas emissions are regulated pursuant to section 111(d) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(d)</external-xref>) shall account for the compliance schedule promulgated pursuant to such section 111(d). Regulations under this section may include market-based measures, emissions performance standards, efficiency performance standards, best management practices, technology-based requirements, and other forms of requirements.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H381E042FD5BC48C3A5B5611D4B4E89F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relation to other authority</header><text>The authority vested by this title is in addition to the authority to regulate greenhouse gas emissions pursuant to other provisions of law.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC391DF4D5F4A4589AF870DAB7CE659E2"><enum>304.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall be interpreted to preempt or limit State actions to address climate change.</text>
 </section><section id="H985D4F4DB6024E4BBA49017A70A74FD2"><enum>305.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HE1CD26E2B8854CF89B885BFCC83186FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas</header><text>The term <term>greenhouse gas</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD4E3955FF96B4533B1D646681EF28325"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carbon dioxide;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB77DA18123841E987762D7B7FACFBD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>methane;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H417EF28A243244D38D9B101471BB044C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nitrous oxide;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F2FCE45D5404718B6B6FE5322BF3FC1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>hydrofluorocarbons;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA72C37CAC1F9417895F4BA10B5E3C026"><enum>(E)</enum><text>perfluorocarbons;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06BC2B52BE494278819ED89280ADA489"><enum>(F)</enum><text>sulfur hexafluoride; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7492FC5EEBD94E118ABEC1E4D7A4F828"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other anthropogenically emitted gas that is determined by the Administrator, after notice and comment, to contribute to global warming to a non-negligible degree.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD03487FE4B64EEAAD3C7373D66899FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States greenhouse gas emissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States greenhouse gas emissions</term> means the total quantity of greenhouse gas emissions calculated by the Administrator on an annual basis and reported to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change Secretariat.</text>
				</paragraph></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


