<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H63864ABF40CF4565A82860C440CE7863" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1197 IH: Accelerating the End of Breast Cancer Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1197</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150302">March 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for the establishment of a Commission to Accelerate the End of Breast Cancer.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HF731739001814469A9B60A2A7525CCA8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H826EFEA70BBB495EB7D63A938530EAB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerating the End of Breast Cancer Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0BBB01EAD51E4805BDC6E7C4F38FE267"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="H826EFEA70BBB495EB7D63A938530EAB1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0BBB01EAD51E4805BDC6E7C4F38FE267" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4F55D752CBFF4DD7A562E1A778616F80" level="section">Sec. 3. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H124287CCDA1140B3970AA5372AEAFA32" level="section">Sec. 4. Establishment.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE71AC1EB0116468A8D832A363C52E1F1" level="section">Sec. 5. Mission; duties.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H052ACDC83CFC411FA0C3ED3655A4B9CA" level="section">Sec. 6. Membership.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDA42582ECC1540D38B33253F1DA60BBD" level="section">Sec. 7. Chairperson and commissioners.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5705DD911CC34C9894AA848C33E1D193" level="section">Sec. 8. Coordination and nonduplication.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2B6190223FA640F2ACF81138ABBE6788" level="section">Sec. 9. Evaluation of the commission.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H6AA47211CD6A4F53B0DAFBB3EF1E5FD4" level="section">Sec. 10. Termination.</toc-entry></toc></section> 
<section id="H4F55D752CBFF4DD7A562E1A778616F80" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFF78BEEC6CC34BC0A4184F7A73B3C2BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the United States, the chance of a woman developing breast cancer during her lifetime has increased from 1 in 11 in 1975 to 1 in 8 today.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF0C1CB0A94A34A9A93008DD2BA8B4A3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Worldwide, breast cancer is the most frequently diagnosed cancer in women with 1.7 million new cancer cases diagnosed in 2012. Breast cancer is also one of the leading causes of cancer death in women, with 522,000 women dying from the disease worldwide in 2012, a 14 percent increase since 2008.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA5AA4B8136F4ACA92F841FEC3A85884"><enum>(3)</enum><text>More than 90 percent of deaths from breast cancer are caused by metastasis, when breast cancer has spread to other organs or bone.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1F5C8297A9524AC38251484C7F95F41D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2010, the National Cancer Institute estimated that breast cancer care in the United States cost $16.5 billion and cost the Nation $12.1 billion in lost productivity. It is projected that, with no changes, the cost of breast cancer care will rise to at least $20.9 million in 2020. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H266AF7FEF59E498F823EC9157899DD65"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Very little has improved in terms of breast cancer incidence, morbidity, and mortality rates over the past 40 years.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H124287CCDA1140B3970AA5372AEAFA32"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall establish a commission to be known as the Commission to Accelerate the End of Breast Cancer (in this Act referred to as the <quote>the Commission</quote>).</text></section> <section id="HE71AC1EB0116468A8D832A363C52E1F1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Mission; duties</header> <subsection id="H383E2CAA94404DAF9D1EDBD096FBA258"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mission of the Commission shall be to help end breast cancer by January 1, 2020.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2CE90B3B3BDC4D79ADB2D00DBCA4AC44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="H53BB4BA485F644498DAFB8282CC59388"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify opportunities and ideas within government and the private sector that are key components in achieving the end of breast cancer and which have been overlooked, yet are ripe for collaboration and investment, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79F4C98579694E58A741FDCD302CD355"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommend projects to leverage such opportunities and ideas in the areas of—</text> <subparagraph id="H22D057B923F14314AFBBA3B23101CA97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the primary prevention of breast cancer; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D1846E323FC4DA1BEFA4248D784D0E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the causes and prevention of breast cancer metastasis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9581584301474E1F85991F9887BBAC4A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Means</header><text>In carrying out the duties described in subsection (b), the Commission shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H021640A2363A482C8DC9850508E5104F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify revolutionary opportunities and ideas in fundamental and applied sciences and epidemiology with a focus on ending breast cancer;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D0383ABF49F4113AD5919F2FEF4289B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify timely opportunities and scientific discoveries which can be turned into real world strategies to prevent breast cancer and prevent breast cancer metastasis and deaths;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA403B3B19E6F436F93B93A3EDADB2CEC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote ideas that are intellectually compelling, innovative, and imaginative;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA23004F06EF4D51B21283F96099E26A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>accelerate potential transformational scientific advances—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2A0AD074BD2340FD9C4518D3B7F6AD0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not being prioritized within the Federal Government, but which can help to achieve the mission described in subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1816917453BD473FB1138A905326E549"><enum>(B)</enum><text>unlikely to be achieved by the private sector due to technical and financial uncertainty;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CC66A81C9554C658BE483F971898B4D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify promising, underdeveloped areas of research that would benefit from a cluster of government, industry, and academia forming innovation communities to rapidly advance knowledge into practice, while creating new opportunities for job creation and advancement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12D10020404D4F7F99A694FD698827F4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identify opportunities for transdisciplinary cross-cutting collaborations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF2C15B652DF406E913D1BE3BA55C8EA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify opportunities for seed grants to leverage identified opportunities and ideas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFFC5D45D11CA47B791D1F877C9FB1372"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Strategic vision</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the appointment of the initial members of the Commission, the Commission shall submit to the President and the relevant authorizing and appropriations committees of the Congress a description of the Commission’s strategic vision for making progress in achieving the mission described in subsection (a) by January 1, 2020.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1AD7CC41604846D489001F9262DA3C51"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall submit an annual report to the President, the Congress, and the public describing the Commission’s activities under this section, including its progress in achieving the mission described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H052ACDC83CFC411FA0C3ED3655A4B9CA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Membership</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HE2F3B6E7B0E849D686FB85517807F549"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number; appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of not more than 10 members, of which—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8C6C3FFFAA864F40927843391B112D95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 8 shall be appointed by the President;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D9DDA13BA5E40BCA39EB12E90C52906"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H785E1D7B324F41A1B518E6A72F737A84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H440F73F39DEA488F8AC453A9CC449F87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header> <paragraph id="H8446286455804FB59D5094E28571A034"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall be appointed to represent one of the following 3 categories:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3372ECC31516476582092BA27CADA450"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Representatives of varied disciplines within the biomedical research field.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C02519D98084A01A02A23ED1167C0D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Representatives of varied disciplines outside of the biomedical research field.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0AC7A857B3AD41DEA3F5C6E777E814F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Educated patient advocates, meaning individuals who—</text> <clause id="HA869634EBE1646CAAB72F36CFDD7F715"><enum>(i)</enum><text>represent a patient-led, patient-centered organization with a patient constituency;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H35F9919DEC4B4267ABB399AD14DB5000"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have been personally affected by breast cancer; and</text></clause> <clause id="H644F580FCA074CDB8D68D22282E26B94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are trained, knowledgeable, and prepared to participate in the decisionmaking process of science and medicine.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA4B253ECC6E4F489DC1C729C23D9D96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Representation of membership categories</header><text>Of the members of the Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="H0591E6F7721A44DCA7D8A32C9EA8D236"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least 1 but not more than 3 shall be appointed to represent the category described in paragraph (1)(A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9112211730A84740B9EDFDD7668A38D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least 1 but not more than 3 shall be appointed to represent the category described in paragraph (1)(B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB0C7AE830A14FF4AEDD7966460AD84C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at least 2 but not more than 4 shall be appointed to represent the category described in paragraph (1)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDDAFC61B433E474395B76B28211542C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial members</header><text>The initial members of the Commission shall be appointed not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H997C9848A5F8480DA5B96264386160F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms</header> <paragraph id="HF152D98156444120B027A2EFFBA46176"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall be appointed for a term of 3 years and may be reappointed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5F00C687CB546D792287EC6C2C239FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any member of the Commission appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term. A member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office. A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H36F363317DC04DABA5E36CD3D29AD67B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDA42582ECC1540D38B33253F1DA60BBD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Chairperson and commissioners</header> 
<subsection id="H5C2C0BF88B014039BC3594338F000325"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Chairperson</header> 
<paragraph id="H4A58862AA7984FFB991AC0B32C171E6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Of the members of the Commission appointed under section 6(a), the President shall at the time of appointment, designate one to serve as Chairperson of the Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H103D345055824A2AAAD080916D5F08D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The Chairperson shall be an individual who, by reason of professional background and experience, is especially qualified to manage areas of study pertaining to ending breast cancer by January 1, 2020.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64566433008C49C88E0F59FB23E72EB8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities of the Chairperson shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D25D0EAFDA642FE9851DD0424567612"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approving all new study projects and areas of study of the Commission based on innovation, impact, and scientific and technical merit;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E974FD7AA8142588324DE393A013076"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing criteria (including milestones) for assessing, and overseeing assessment of, the success of the study projects and areas of study of the Commission;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H772B453725564DE7AD0C0B0116873C45"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying opportunities for seed grants and other funding through awards, prizes, grants, and contracts to achieve the mission described in section 5(a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46548B7E6A4748A6AD58287A411DA2CF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>terminating study projects and areas of study of the Commission that are not achieving the mission described in section 5(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD89EB87C2F4949119D1DB457C0439FF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commissioners</header> <paragraph id="H25C4E9B855774BFB9F5E7660AF796431"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may appoint members of the Commission to oversee one or more areas of study of the Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39E8D3423A8C44B6A5BBD0CC56229778"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>A member appointed under paragraph (1) shall, with respect to one or more areas of study, be responsible for—</text> <subparagraph id="HE5024BE3E68445DA87C6B6BD881CEDFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommending novel proposals, projects, and collaborations based on scientific and technical merit to achieve the mission described in section 5(a) with a focus on strategies for the primary prevention of breast cancer, and methods to prevent breast cancer metastasis;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8DA51F867604915A39DAF3DC3CD0CF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying ideas and opportunities to achieve the mission described in section 5(a) that are intellectually compelling, innovative, and imaginative, including such ideas and opportunities not being prioritized for breast cancer relevance within Federal agencies or programs or the private sector;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD04B9C02C2B24B518BFB28B3F805E6F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>working with other relevant Federal agencies to identify areas of concurrent interests in order to maximize Federal investment and stimulate collaborative projects;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEAF49EDECB141ABBA8D38E766C89C89"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifying opportunities for transdisciplinary, cross-cutting collaborations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72F6C5AF0669435F97E5843F2FABB54D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>monitoring the progress of study projects and areas of study and recommending restructure or termination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5705DD911CC34C9894AA848C33E1D193"><enum>8.</enum><header>Coordination and nonduplication</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, the Commission shall ensure that the activities of the Commission are coordinated with, and do not duplicate the efforts of, programs and laboratories of other government agencies.</text></section> <section id="H2B6190223FA640F2ACF81138ABBE6788"><enum>9.</enum><header>Evaluation of the commission</header> <subsection id="HD3346A245CFD4748A8F01F75EFA5C641"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall seek to enter into an agreement with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences under which the Institute, after the Commission has been in operation for 3 years, completes an evaluation of how well the Commission is making progress towards achieving the mission described in section 5(a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H670AA4D349634D65996096A6E1D91D8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The evaluation under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HEC1E8995CC7F4ABAA7D91B041C95EF88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a recommendation on whether the Commission should be continued or terminated; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H061DB31C32F947028CCD61279DDA64D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of lessons learned from operation of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8CED44339AD946B69C00D533D775CDD4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>On completion of the evaluation under subsection (a), the Commission shall make the evaluation available to the Congress and the public.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6AA47211CD6A4F53B0DAFBB3EF1E5FD4"><enum>10.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate on June 1, 2020.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

