<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE4C6145A507E426EA5F6535D130C10FC" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1330 IH: American-Made Energy and Infrastructure Jobs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1330</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct offshore oil and gas leasing, to use revenues from such leasing to capitalize bonds that provide a dedicated source of revenue to fund highway, other transportation, and water infrastructure projects, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H39CDDDB3B5D7464F8CDDE6FAAAD97D28" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0885670789B04473A36AD4CE2CA690D1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American-Made Energy and Infrastructure Jobs Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HE15E30E449E743A8A1990BEBCD3F44EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="H0885670789B04473A36AD4CE2CA690D1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE15E30E449E743A8A1990BEBCD3F44EB" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H84499921F97E4BA59055769935894494" level="title">Title I—Outer Continental Shelf Leasing Program Reforms</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0FBF3766493B4D2094D581CFC1BC602F" level="section">Sec. 101. Outer Continental Shelf leasing program reforms.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H499A365A28984A7CAD140F52D0D22717" level="section">Sec. 102. Domestic oil and natural gas production goal.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H74FBBCE153AE499D95AFC4A9913A9203" level="section">Sec. 103. Development and submittal of new 5-year oil and gas leasing program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0A925C6D33A3460A8A249B2ADBB90C90" level="title">Title II—Enhancing the 2012–2017 Five-Year Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC1D04CA0E1114D5A81D873E3C35A91FC" level="section">Sec. 201. Requirement to conduct proposed oil and gas Lease Sale 220 on the Outer Continental Shelf offshore Virginia.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5D41886FCA6D4FE79F4F3A4E8C1FCDB3" level="section">Sec. 202. South Carolina lease sale.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H94417A6277C1417288834248E0921B66" level="section">Sec. 203. Southern California existing infrastructure lease sale.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB191A45D1DF64C6EAEDF189730D6A5F1" level="section">Sec. 204. Environmental impact statement requirement.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H586D3098A7E544FD8BC2E8ED0E604F32" level="section">Sec. 205. National defense.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF5F3144D911C43CF87795F921C5B12C1" level="title">Title III—Equitable Sharing of Outer Continental Shelf Revenues</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H304C008469604294B3D6AC0DF4A40321" level="section">Sec. 301. Disposition of Outer Continental Shelf revenues to coastal States.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE8DDFB7B6BAC4AAFBC8698A7E13DC138" level="section">Sec. 302. Acceleration of Phase II GOMESA revenue sharing.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2F7CF29D20F84F87A9257FD87E76A12A" level="title">Title IV—Reorganization of Minerals Management Agencies of the Department of the Interior</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE0ED9B46678640579C1267B95193ED56" level="section">Sec. 401. Establishment of Under Secretary for Energy, Lands, and Minerals and Assistant Secretary of Ocean Energy and Safety.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H70B2E7FFE1004E0C8698972B9FAC064F" level="section">Sec. 402. Bureau of Ocean Energy.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H209081E2F6B846D5B6801B40552FFD3D" level="section">Sec. 403. Ocean Energy Safety Service.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H86775E28187340578D9933A220D8F831" level="section">Sec. 404. Office of Natural Resources revenue.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H17CECFE0091848029C14ADD3B39C23DC" level="section">Sec. 405. Ethics and drug testing.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H824677FE38F24212AB97D9453BBA0481" level="section">Sec. 406. Abolishment of Minerals Management Service.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H952B1676378E40F0A065BD2DD997E18B" level="section">Sec. 407. Conforming amendments to Executive Schedule pay rates.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H650EAF4A250D49F6B97CCDAC61BE2DFC" level="section">Sec. 408. Outer Continental Shelf Energy Safety Advisory Board.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC87D225D657A44379C27E13459B4F8A2" level="section">Sec. 409. Outer Continental Shelf inspection fees.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8108AE8A4CC2499CB907D5A7DA61A7FF" level="title">Title V—United States Territories</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7298C041A01749D4BECE0927D05763E7" level="section">Sec. 501. Application of Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act with respect to territories of the United States.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCFEAA7FD224F4FD0A5408B942B765D6E" level="title">Title VI—Infrastructure Revenue Bonds</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD69CCC474DAA4AF39D2EAB27802BEC64" level="section">Sec. 601. Leveraging Infrastructure Trust Account with infrastructure revenue bonds.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE3FDDC4FA4354803A9A1ACD0B1AA1956" level="section">Sec. 602. Ninety-five percent of bond proceeds for Highway Trust Fund.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H849FD538826A4096AD9E79ECA67E8AF8" level="section">Sec. 603. Five percent of bond proceeds for State revolving loan funds for wastewater treatment facilities and drinking water facilities.</toc-entry></toc> </section>
<title id="H84499921F97E4BA59055769935894494"><enum>I</enum><header>Outer Continental Shelf Leasing Program Reforms</header> 
<section id="H0FBF3766493B4D2094D581CFC1BC602F"><enum>101.</enum><header>Outer Continental Shelf leasing program reforms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 18(a) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HC80A539BA93D4D8A8391E0911B3D468E" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H8B95E39462E743B9BC22B27819FF61CB"><enum>(5)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1E514B1B87FE4D59B9578250CF895330"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In each oil and gas leasing program under this section, the Secretary shall make available for leasing and conduct lease sales including at least 50 percent of the available unleased acreage within each outer Continental Shelf planning area considered to have the largest undiscovered, technically recoverable oil and gas resources (on a total btu basis) based upon the most recent national geologic assessment of the outer Continental Shelf, with an emphasis on offering the most geologically prospective parts of the planning area.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA3B3063131EB42E2BA81D3C6A6BF24DA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall include in each proposed oil and gas leasing program under this section any State subdivision of an outer Continental Shelf planning area that the Governor of the State that represents that subdivision requests be made available for leasing. The Secretary may not remove such a subdivision from the program until publication of the final program.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF40AF7FCAFA47918B78F467817E24B4" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph the term <quote>available unleased acreage</quote> means that portion of the outer Continental Shelf that is not under lease at the time of a proposed lease sale, and that has not otherwise been made unavailable for leasing by law.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61F648B37BBD4411B30A839F8373E1FF"><enum>(6)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE4C98AEFCA5545FD8F46B518245E2786"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the 5-year oil and gas leasing program, the Secretary shall make available for leasing any outer Continental Shelf planning areas that—</text> <clause id="HB384D4E6E8DD47E0B265EC63158DCE84" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are estimated to contain more than 2,500,000,000 barrels of oil; or</text> </clause>
<clause id="HC626B55733B94CA6B1CE7EB0B00D73F2" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are estimated to contain more than 7,500,000,000,000 cubic feet of natural gas.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H383CD8C4A3A14F5C8869F02AD2183793" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To determine the planning areas described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall use the document entitled <quote>Minerals Management Service Assessment of Undiscovered Technically Recoverable Oil and Gas Resources of the Nation’s Outer Continental Shelf, 2006</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section>
<section id="H499A365A28984A7CAD140F52D0D22717"><enum>102.</enum><header>Domestic oil and natural gas production goal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 18(b) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H105AB7DF247743C787024A5B07F6B524" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H35377E6B77CB4E13A067AAA68463049F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Domestic oil and natural gas production goal</header><text>–</text> 
<paragraph id="HDE25B475E3074F4F9D16C5BCD9C677A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In developing a 5-year oil and gas leasing program, and subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall determine a domestic strategic production goal for the development of oil and natural gas as a result of that program. Such goal shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HAEFA38D5508F4A6BBD54944CB7AB0CB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the best estimate of the possible increase in domestic production of oil and natural gas from the outer Continental Shelf;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1AA08F2CCAD3493F8A8790E63CAC88D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>focused on meeting domestic demand for oil and natural gas and reducing the dependence of the United States on foreign energy; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC78267F676254F4EBEA1C13EDB1DDC29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>focused on the production increases achieved by the leasing program at the end of the 15-year period beginning on the effective date of the program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H99CD742A810242E292B44AAC5EAF2E70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program goal</header><text>For purposes of the 5-year oil and gas leasing program, the production goal referred to in paragraph (1) shall be an increase by 2033 of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB917D4E7E60844B4A60E75375B331BB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no less than 3,000,000 barrels in the amount of oil produced per day; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H10020AA5B15A417D86FD31F080FA4556"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no less than 10,000,000,000 cubic feet in the amount of natural gas produced per day.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B3383E0C4F84263B66BA0837C3C3EAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Secretary shall report annually, beginning at the end of the 5-year period for which the program applies, to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate on the progress of the program in meeting the production goal. The Secretary shall identify in the report projections for production and any problems with leasing, permitting, or production that will prevent meeting the goal.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section>
<section id="H74FBBCE153AE499D95AFC4A9913A9203"><enum>103.</enum><header>Development and submittal of new 5-year oil and gas leasing program</header> 
<subsection id="H8D765B5E72F34B9E93DCEAA62D9C10DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall—</text> <paragraph id="H206564F8C1B64F3A91733B5661065BAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by not later than July 15, 2015, publish and submit to Congress a new proposed oil and gas leasing program under section 18 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) for the 5-year period beginning on such date and ending July 15, 2021; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F0FEA6EFA6A4676ABB84339A6D5DF12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by not later than July 15, 2016, approve a final oil and gas leasing program under such section for such period.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8B44105009BD4A3495D303E2FE4E2F2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration of all areas</header><text>In preparing such program the Secretary shall include consideration of areas of the Continental Shelf off the coasts of all States (as such term is defined in section 2 of that Act, as amended by this Act), that are subject to leasing under this Act.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HEFC757C1BDB24E618BD4682A431393A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical correction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 18(d)(3) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344(d)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or after eighteen months following the date of enactment of this section, whichever first occurs,</quote>.</text> </subsection></section></title> <title id="H0A925C6D33A3460A8A249B2ADBB90C90"><enum>II</enum><header>Enhancing the 2012–2017 Five-Year Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program</header> <section id="HC1D04CA0E1114D5A81D873E3C35A91FC"><enum>201.</enum><header>Requirement to conduct proposed oil and gas Lease Sale 220 on the Outer Continental Shelf offshore Virginia</header> <subsection id="H1C587B7826AB418DBDE41FD6CD55BB29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the inclusion of Lease Sale 220 in the Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil &amp; Gas Leasing Program 2012–2017, the Secretary of the Interior shall conduct offshore oil and gas Lease Sale 220 under section 8 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>) as soon as practicable, but not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H410F011DCA8344619B73C9EDDC7EC6E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To make replacement lease blocks available</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each lease block in a proposed lease sale under this section for which the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, under the Memorandum of Agreement referred to in section 205(b), issues a statement proposing deferral from a lease offering due to defense-related activities that are irreconcilable with mineral exploration and development, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall make available in the same lease sale one other lease block in the Virginia lease sale planning area that is acceptable for oil and gas exploration and production in order to mitigate conflict.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H58A8B65C00BF407CAAABEF292EEB4EC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Balancing military and energy production goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recognition that the Outer Continental Shelf oil and gas leasing program and the domestic energy resources produced therefrom are integral to national security, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Defense shall work jointly in implementing this section in order to ensure achievement of the following common goals:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8014C2FFDB8F46D9B945291095D68A7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Preserving the ability of the Armed Forces of the United States to maintain an optimum state of readiness through their continued use of the Outer Continental Shelf.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DE79195FB024F168DF3B41C415D8C6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Allowing effective exploration, development, and production of our Nation’s oil, gas, and renewable energy resources.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB0BDE31916294079BB1466560944F6AB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF764827F23B04649A9B753918179CCC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lease sale 220</header><text>The term <quote>Lease Sale 220</quote> means such lease sale referred to in the Request for Comments on the Draft Proposed 5-Year Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) Oil and Gas Leasing Program for 2010–2015 and Notice of Intent To Prepare an Environmental Impact Statement (EIS) for the Proposed 5-Year Program published January 21, 2009 (74 Fed. Reg. 3631).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2E048003631C437D879BEA4D2F498B4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Virginia lease sale planning area</header><text>The term <quote>Virginia lease sale planning area</quote> means the area of the outer Continental Shelf (as that term is defined in the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1331">33 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>)) that is bounded by—</text> <subparagraph id="HED01BE23FC744B6A97333ED9EC66FA04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a northern boundary consisting of a straight line extending from the northernmost point of Virginia’s seaward boundary to the point on the seaward boundary of the United States exclusive economic zone located at 37 degrees 17 minutes 1 second North latitude, 71 degrees 5 minutes 16 seconds West longitude; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA56021CBD98546AF8135EAF4CA8A7842"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a southern boundary consisting of a straight line extending from the southernmost point of Virginia’s seaward boundary to the point on the seaward boundary of the United States exclusive economic zone located at 36 degrees 31 minutes 58 seconds North latitude, 71 degrees 30 minutes 1 second West longitude.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5D41886FCA6D4FE79F4F3A4E8C1FCDB3"><enum>202.</enum><header>South Carolina lease sale</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding inclusion of the South Atlantic Outer Continental Shelf Planning Area in the Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil &amp; Gas Leasing Program 2012–2017, the Secretary of the Interior shall conduct a lease sale not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act for areas off the coast of South Carolina determined by the Secretary to have the most geologically promising hydrocarbon resources and constituting not less than 25 percent of the leasable area within the South Carolina offshore administrative boundaries depicted in the notice entitled <quote>Federal Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) Administrative Boundaries Extending from the Submerged Lands Act Boundary seaward to the Limit of the United States Outer Continental Shelf</quote>, published January 3, 2006 (71 Fed. Reg. 127).</text> </section>
<section id="H94417A6277C1417288834248E0921B66"><enum>203.</enum><header>Southern California existing infrastructure lease sale</header> 
<subsection id="HCDD1C32F7D424C3FAAFDD29AB185E142"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall offer for sale leases of tracts in the Santa Maria and Santa Barbara/Ventura Basins of the Southern California OCS Planning Area as soon as practicable, but not later than December 31, 2015.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HDE79DAACD20D45F88EE4922580DCDF0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of Existing Structures or Onshore-Based Drilling</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall include in leases offered for sale under this lease sale such terms and conditions as are necessary to require that development and production may occur only from offshore infrastructure in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act or from onshore-based, extended-reach drilling.</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="HB191A45D1DF64C6EAEDF189730D6A5F1"><enum>204.</enum><header>Environmental impact statement requirement</header> 
<subsection id="HA68AE44308FB4A22BF91773678683498"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>For the purposes of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall prepare a multisale environmental impact statement under section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>) for all lease sales required under this title.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HAD832F05EF0C424D8C1AEEB424ED5420"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions To be considered</header><text>Notwithstanding section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>), in such statement—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF2C06F5EB1DA4E1C84170A4674E1898B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary is not required to identify nonleasing alternative courses of action or to analyze the environmental effects of such alternative courses of action; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF882D33805442BA8CCD661FEF3CA75A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary shall only—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H84B7085D84C5448796E59020B6D2B6B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify a preferred action for leasing and not more than one alternative leasing proposal; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE839EE2A53404DCCB52569EAFDC0B80F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>analyze the environmental effects and potential mitigation measures for such preferred action and such alternative leasing proposal.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H586D3098A7E544FD8BC2E8ED0E604F32"><enum>205.</enum><header>National defense</header> 
<subsection id="H3D8F888D74104D9BAA5209E80F4440FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Defense Areas</header><text>This Act does not affect the existing authority of the Secretary of Defense, with the approval of the President, to designate national defense areas on the Outer Continental Shelf pursuant to section 12(d) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1341">43 U.S.C. 1341(d)</external-xref>).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H464DF55CAEC44779BF3A6470F19FD160"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on Conflicts With Military Operations</header><text>No person may engage in any exploration, development, or production of oil or natural gas on the Outer Continental Shelf under a lease issued under this Act that would conflict with any military operation, as determined in accordance with the Memorandum of Agreement between the Department of Defense and the Department of the Interior on Mutual Concerns on the Outer Continental Shelf signed July 20, 1983, and any revision or replacement for that agreement that is agreed to by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Interior after that date but before the date of issuance of the lease under which such exploration, development, or production is conducted.</text> </subsection></section></title>
<title id="HF5F3144D911C43CF87795F921C5B12C1"><enum>III</enum><header>Equitable Sharing of Outer Continental Shelf Revenues</header> 
<section id="H304C008469604294B3D6AC0DF4A40321"><enum>301.</enum><header>Disposition of Outer Continental Shelf revenues to coastal States</header> 
<subsection id="H6B4C8D5566BF47A9BABDE46FFE6F4876"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1338">43 U.S.C. 1338</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB6C0615989BB4D7FAA0C2E960B9C40C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the existing text—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5D12F3A0E11449EAA3B1F0B248C1F53A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first sentence, by striking <quote>All rentals,</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8CE69B1A581435FBFAA86746F16CCF2" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H1DDFE1DFB1F443A089DEFEE5BD884EFB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposition of revenue under old leases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All rentals,</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8E46BBC43EE04380AA989BB408798C64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c) (as designated by the amendment made by subparagraph (A) of this paragraph), by striking <quote>for the period from June 5, 1950, to date, and thereafter</quote> and inserting <quote>in the period beginning June 5, 1950, and ending on the date of enactment of the <short-title>American-Made Energy and Infrastructure Jobs Act</short-title></quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09008C6128A84A62AE011073F4242E73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after subsection (c) (as so designated) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0DAB5EBC45D47F8BB5C6B777B72576A" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H71AD45F672354312AA5EFE12516EE517"><enum>(d)</enum><header> Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3F2764C7C27E46B3A9BD722481F4303F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coastal State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>coastal State</quote> includes a territory of the United States.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0DDB691B996747C7BBF47ED08A5DF4C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New leasing revenues</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>new leasing revenues</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H31FE345DC2C34BC39B26B4083CB4B3FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means amounts received by the United States as bonuses, rents, and royalties under leases for oil and gas, wind, tidal, or other energy exploration, development, and production on areas of the outer Continental Shelf that are authorized to be made available for leasing as a result of enactment of the <short-title>American-Made Energy and Infrastructure Jobs Act</short-title> and leasing under that Act; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD9DD579E712C441AA914C8D387C850D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include amounts received by the United States under any lease of an area located in the boundaries of the Central Gulf of Mexico and Western Gulf of Mexico Outer Continental Shelf Planning Areas on the date of enactment of the <short-title>American-Made Energy and Infrastructure Jobs Act</short-title>, including a lease issued before, on, or after such date of enactment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H19F8498D18984A53AC1C117418DFF166"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting before subsection (c) (as so designated) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12621556D8E84DE59540D5EDCE971322" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HA192AE1BBD7D494EB9A7AA9F2982992D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payment of new leasing revenues to coastal States</header> 
<paragraph id="H6B199797FC4B4270BC274911DB90411E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), of the amount of new leasing revenues received by the United States each fiscal year, 37.5 percent shall be allocated and paid in accordance with subsection (b) to coastal States that are affected States with respect to the leases under which those revenues are received by the United States.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H11212702845C4740888B08D5E4288C5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Phase-in</header> <subparagraph id="H13E83D6807164384A65ABC91256F2C61"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), paragraph (1) shall be applied—</text> 
<clause id="HC18D10B16D7644EF9067BE239CDB5950"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to new leasing revenues under leases awarded under the first leasing program under section 18(a) that takes effect after the date of enactment of the <short-title>American-Made Energy and Infrastructure Jobs Act</short-title>, by substituting <quote>12.5 percent</quote> for <quote>37.5 percent</quote>; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HC33C246199084B2DB69AE78F48849CFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to new leasing revenues under leases awarded under the second leasing program under section 18(a) that takes effect after the date of enactment of the <short-title>American-Made Energy and Infrastructure Jobs Act</short-title>, by substituting <quote>25 percent</quote> for <quote>37.5 percent</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBD87AF1C98274FAE9F88AEB8B31A5038"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exempted lease sales</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply with respect to any lease issued under title II of the <short-title>American-Made Energy and Infrastructure Jobs Act</short-title>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5914E7AB4B774CF5A5F9DDEB3F09809F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation of payments</header> <paragraph id="H6D98CA9F3CB94711A05EFE9586FA5940"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of new leasing revenues received by the United States with respect to a leased tract that are required to be paid to coastal States in accordance with this subsection each fiscal year shall be allocated among and paid to coastal States that are within 200 miles of the leased tract, in amounts that are inversely proportional to the respective distances between the point on the coastline of each such State that is closest to the geographic center of the lease tract, as determined by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC85C0301E8E34357AE2150B8D1FD89D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum and maximum allocation</header><text>The amount allocated to a coastal State under paragraph (1) each fiscal year with respect to a leased tract shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H9AD4959D75AF4B228AAA287B2AE90FBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a coastal State that is the nearest State to the geographic center of the leased tract, not less than 25 percent of the total amounts allocated with respect to the leased tract;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1BED67F4160C48C79A6C01547CC735C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of any other coastal State, not less than 10 percent, and not more than 15 percent, of the total amounts allocated with respect to the leased tract; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C5034DA3A4B4F7C970B18CE42BE4E8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a coastal State that is the only coastal State within 200 miles of a least tract, 100 percent of the total amounts allocated with respect to the leased tract.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H966EE75312D94249965F306E447FB984"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Amounts allocated to a coastal State under this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H2A6A3C77B2D14B909342B14C98D0FC31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be available to the coastal State without further appropriation;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3A36E14F8A314EC39C14F5BEC8C3A12F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall remain available until expended; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H83115D18F6C5442784FDA5B483303279"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall be in addition to any other amounts available to the coastal State under this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H327BC9ADAC544636A7C7CD4FF8F9FED4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDC63477390D5443C816D61A60479BFD9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a coastal State may use funds allocated and paid to it under this subsection for any purpose as determined by the laws of that State.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H112CBFBD48604C80983B8BC2A2616C7D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction on use for matching</header><text>Funds allocated and paid to a coastal State under this subsection may not be used as matching funds for any other Federal program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB2D25A31C69B48A2B94763787532D9F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendment made by this section shall not affect the application of section 105 of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 (title I of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/432">Public Law 109–432</external-xref>; (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref> note)), as in effect before the enactment of this Act, with respect to revenues received by the United States under oil and gas leases issued for tracts located in the Western and Central Gulf of Mexico Outer Continental Shelf Planning Areas, including such leases issued on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HE8DDFB7B6BAC4AAFBC8698A7E13DC138"><enum>302.</enum><header>Acceleration of Phase II GOMESA revenue sharing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 105 of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAF3B33BE333D4CAC807D2154A23292E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4AB6823767C7453AB2F4D41151E32A05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading for paragraph (1), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">2016</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">2015</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6728CB73D4504D38A33D1B6EA54AF405"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph">2016</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph">2015</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DD038A4967D4E9B989280C8E9D06307"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H48FC6F25D285430397BCFFD3309FC293"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading for paragraph (1), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">2017</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">2016</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF9DD9299DE9D40488D8792323A7B1AEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph">2017</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph">2016</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H133754D279784933B070328F88C0B9DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1), by inserting before the period <quote>, except that such amount shall increase by $250,000,000 upon the issuance of each 5-year oil and gas leasing program under section 18 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></title> <title id="H2F7CF29D20F84F87A9257FD87E76A12A"><enum>IV</enum><header>Reorganization of Minerals Management Agencies of the Department of the Interior</header> <section id="HE0ED9B46678640579C1267B95193ED56" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>401.</enum><header>Establishment of Under Secretary for Energy, Lands, and Minerals and Assistant Secretary of Ocean Energy and Safety</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There shall be in the Department of the Interior—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3056C94ACA0B4E719B83DF35333CA2D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an Under Secretary for Energy, Lands, and Minerals, who shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEBAC6DACB5164BF59C7DADB9B4A0866B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be appointed by the President, by and with the advise and consent of the Senate;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC0B80FE0CEE14EF183377ED2E9D93F76"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report to the Secretary of the Interior or, if directed by the Secretary, to the Deputy Secretary of the Interior;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H203AD20C0B74415D96783C99CE419A36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be paid at the rate payable for level III of the Executive Schedule; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H33A916E62F6B469CBB63FD0B0C1E79D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be responsible for—</text> <clause id="H1C114FB7BDC04BC780EABB46EBC65B45"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the safe and responsible development of our energy and mineral resources on Federal lands in appropriate accordance with United States energy demands; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H008E54695CCA441EA70F3F233AC82B14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring multiple-use missions of the Department of the Interior that promote the safe and sustained development of energy and minerals resources on public lands (as that term is defined in the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>));</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7955605402FC44EFBB3FEE03E1F638E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an Assistant Secretary of Ocean Energy and Safety, who shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H22CD58F5E83A42E281DAFE73F9AB2297"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be appointed by the President, by and with the advise and consent of the Senate;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEEE20C11059D45D0B8CB08B48F60CCCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report to the Under Secretary for Energy, Lands, and Minerals;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H12A41000FF954C6BACEFEEFA8379B41C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be paid at the rate payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB40A56DBDA644D87ABC6D3B6DF4EA21B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be responsible for ensuring safe and efficient development of energy and minerals on the Outer Continental Shelf of the United States; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H3B8F9E54C8014F71BFDD7EAF797C07AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an Assistant Secretary of Land and Minerals Management, who shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4C144326D3F14CDF94C6CFE8DF08D602"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be appointed by the President, by and with the advise and consent of the Senate;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC2327EFD296E493D8601DC02DD53EEF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report to the Under Secretary for Energy, Lands, and Minerals;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H09CAB427B8E940CAB6D7B7BD23A4A4EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be paid at the rate payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1481673E54014614B7423BC7B27FB98B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be responsible for ensuring safe and efficient development of energy and minerals on public lands and other Federal onshore lands under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior, including implementation of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1201">30 U.S.C. 1201 et seq.</external-xref>) and administration of the Office of Surface Mining.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H70B2E7FFE1004E0C8698972B9FAC064F"><enum>402.</enum><header>Bureau of Ocean Energy</header> <subsection id="H29ACDFD8F8E14F92AC8EBA3C7665E944"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of the Interior a Bureau of Ocean Energy (referred to in this section as the <quote>Bureau</quote>), which shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAB4F3C8DA8DC402AAD72509B891C1799"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be headed by a Director of Ocean Energy (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H455EB17F52474451AE184CD75A4B282B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be administered under the direction of the Assistant Secretary of Ocean Energy and Safety.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3F8850AA69164801B367CEFA0664F48E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header> 
<paragraph id="HC65B41739A4641D597BD0CCFCEF99852"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Director shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HED7A8BD77D8D46029B0533DB257550E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Director shall be compensated at the rate provided for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBF428CCF296E41E79579127DECDDF816"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header> 
<paragraph id="HF7813F9FDBB64C17BFF6C328ACBCAD1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall carry out through the Bureau all functions, powers, and duties vested in the Secretary relating to the administration of a comprehensive program of offshore mineral and renewable energy resources management.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6E2D03EBA3044A2981FC4E7639C2377"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific authorities</header><text>The Director shall promulgate and implement regulations—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4C2D4D422F1C44559507BFC99761FFEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the proper issuance of leases for the exploration, development, and production of nonrenewable and renewable energy and mineral resources on the Outer Continental Shelf;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F190A1C9601424E9E11C60C6DC761DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relating to resource identification, access, evaluation, and utilization;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9DDA5B1FCF1844BA85D443B89DB3268E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for development of leasing plans, lease sales, and issuance of leases for such resources; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51313C7959E84BB4A21BD40F26E579AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regarding issuance of environmental impact statements related to leasing and post leasing activities including exploration, development, and production, and the use of third party contracting for necessary environmental analysis for the development of such resources.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF532BA8533BA47999127918E14A56A97"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall not carry out through the Bureau any function, power, or duty that is—</text> <subparagraph id="H600DC0425D2C46A8A62154780DAC5C8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>required by section 403 to be carried out through the Ocean Energy Safety Service; or</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE749F383ADF4FA7B59B06D29FFA2C45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>required by section 404 to be carried out through the Office of Natural Resources Revenue.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H025EA97D20D64D448430B1D06475F2AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Responsibilities of land management agencies</header><text>Nothing in this section shall affect the authorities of the Bureau of Land Management under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) or of the Forest Service under the National Forest Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/588">Public Law 94–588</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="H209081E2F6B846D5B6801B40552FFD3D"><enum>403.</enum><header>Ocean Energy Safety Service</header> 
<subsection id="H2A546299D4A4487B862AEB867C097274"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of the Interior an Ocean Energy Safety Service (referred to in this section as the <quote>Service</quote>), which shall—</text> <paragraph id="H7FD2AAF813F14FB9BED374C095D86FD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be headed by a Director of Energy Safety (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>); and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H293264998D8148B38D8FA16C174ED431"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be administered under the direction of the Assistant Secretary of Ocean Energy and Safety.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAAB3974FE723423E90E14F7CBAC3346F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header> <paragraph id="HC39884675B004AB5B16A83454A9F9D51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Director shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBDB17D2D39E04178A5726614B2376AC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Director shall be compensated at the rate provided for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H429FE21801B14FCCA4EF72A8F7D6B309"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header> <paragraph id="H31571D1F6BE54F81A0579007BF030C59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall carry out through the Service all functions, powers, and duties vested in the Secretary relating to the administration of safety and environmental enforcement activities related to offshore mineral and renewable energy resources on the Outer Continental Shelf pursuant to the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>) including the authority to develop, promulgate, and enforce regulations to ensure the safe and sound exploration, development, and production of mineral and renewable energy resources on the Outer Continental Shelf in a timely fashion.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC1C5BE4468B04093B063C6E6E545DB82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific authorities</header><text>The Director shall be responsible for all safety activities related to exploration and development of renewable and mineral resources on the Outer Continental Shelf, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H3058D2105F0A4DC18E34BE50F5A897B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exploration, development, production, and ongoing inspections of infrastructure;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAEE21239BA494A2F8EB07B1C54BC19AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the suspending or prohibiting, on a temporary basis, any operation or activity, including production under leases held on the Outer Continental Shelf, in accordance with section 5(a)(1) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1334">43 U.S.C. 1334(a)(1)</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1BBF73F2DBC74AC5A95D870AB03D00B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cancelling any lease, permit, or right-of-way on the Outer Continental Shelf, in accordance with section 5(a)(2) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1334">43 U.S.C. 1334(a)(2)</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9648172877B1403F9C6661EFA2788350"><enum>(D)</enum><text>compelling compliance with applicable Federal laws and regulations relating to worker safety and other matters;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2377507A76640F49E8E925EBE79C0F1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>requiring comprehensive safety and environmental management programs for persons engaged in activities connected with the exploration, development, and production of mineral or renewable energy resources;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H54656FED84404100A0B2A1429F79116B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>developing and implementing regulations for Federal employees to carry out any inspection or investigation to ascertain compliance with applicable regulations, including health, safety, or environmental regulations;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E91D12B2C7B44068060D890145BDB54"><enum>(G)</enum><text>implementing the Offshore Technology Research and Risk Assessment Program under section 21 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1347">43 U.S.C. 1347</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H922103218B64497290E5110A5B4A02EF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>summoning witnesses and directing the production of evidence;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB990A52C48E54A5A82D6B666CC174CAF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>levying fines and penalties and disqualifying operators;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H271328524C0140FDAE4394DFCD6518A9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>carrying out any safety, response, and removal preparedness functions; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C6C66CFCFDE4EA4BCC9CF6E8945B8EE"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the processing of permits, exploration plans, development plans.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H557B18B314B84CE0AEA5A3AB83EB56AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employees</header> 
<paragraph id="H1E2047EED6B44ED59AC04207A9B67766"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the inspection force of the Bureau consists of qualified, trained employees who meet qualification requirements and adhere to the highest professional and ethical standards.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H745B1098814F4C07B02029DF52F71F49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The qualification requirements referred to in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H839766BB2B9E4B6E8316E6DA745ABE88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be determined by the Secretary, subject to subparagraph (B); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9626B43AE1441B897315F30DEE9052D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H64B76BDAD22B42E8918BB78C1146211E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>three years of practical experience in oil and gas exploration, development, or production; or</text> </clause> <clause id="HD9F425CDA4B4492B92C93EE5F51A1056"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a degree in an appropriate field of engineering from an accredited institution of higher learning.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9606D651A22A4D16BDAA15F5F5B1BCDB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assignment</header><text>In assigning oil and gas inspectors to the inspection and investigation of individual operations, the Secretary shall give due consideration to the extent possible to their previous experience in the particular type of oil and gas operation in which such inspections are to be made.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C02A2D20D334F93A16D81FE6AB51D1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Background checks</header><text>The Director shall require that an individual to be hired as an inspection officer undergo an employment investigation (including a criminal history record check).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD62ACDE3BCC84F6792E21E3F60E27DD1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Language requirements</header><text>Individuals hired as inspectors must be able to read, speak, and write English well enough to—</text> <subparagraph id="HCB7B44AF941D4F52812B9F7031F2ACF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out written and oral instructions regarding the proper performance of inspection duties; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6F853F88CAF0499A971F688B4250D42C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>write inspection reports and statements and log entries in the English language.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H505688B239E2403F848EB42552AAEA3D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Veterans preference</header><text>The Director shall provide a preference for the hiring of an individual as a inspection officer if the individual is a member or former member of the Armed Forces and is entitled, under statute, to retired, retirement, or retainer pay on account of service as a member of the Armed Forces.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F06F84C382940D3BC353EC44480D454"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Annual proficiency review</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2FE013595C2145459D32A000D5FD52E8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual proficiency review</header><text>The Director shall provide that an annual evaluation of each individual assigned inspection duties is conducted and documented.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45F1022E2BB844EC8C18973970EA8BAD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Continuation of employment</header><text>An individual employed as an inspector may not continue to be employed in that capacity unless the evaluation demonstrates that the individual—</text> 
<clause id="HE77DCAD9E3A34E52A8713EEBFFF3BC24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>continues to meet all qualifications and standards;</text> </clause> <clause id="HC8789AD5C7DB415183B34EA7EFB6C0F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a satisfactory record of performance and attention to duty based on the standards and requirements in the inspection program; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="HB07792E8D3F64A7FB760599138C988B6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>demonstrates the current knowledge and skills necessary to courteously, vigilantly, and effectively perform inspection functions.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC18F61077DD440F984D85D0CECFCA87B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Limitation on right to strike</header><text>Any individual that conducts permitting or inspections under this section may not participate in a strike, or assert the right to strike.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB6D95FF3F994400CB64597B8D48EFA95"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Personnel authority</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director may employ, appoint, discipline and terminate for cause, and fix the compensation, terms, and conditions of employment of Federal service for individuals as the employees of the Service in order to restore and maintain the trust of the people of the United States in the accountability of the management of our Nation’s energy safety program.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3353CCB6504C45CD9A44B31FB9E67D0D"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Training Academy</header> <subparagraph id="H6993C14C0D874CD9A9866E72364C1B96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and maintain a National Offshore Energy Safety Academy (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>Academy</quote>) as an agency of the Ocean Energy Safety Service.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6E4AE5D4FF2C480E8ED87A8A2F29826B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Functions of Academy</header><text>The Secretary, through the Academy, shall be responsible for—</text> <clause id="H22FEEA06F6414191A7E1F553B39FA8B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the initial and continued training of both newly hired and experienced offshore oil and gas inspectors in all aspects of health, safety, environmental, and operational inspections;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H06DF43C4E22940548503060F45993DFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the training of technical support personnel of the Bureau;</text> </clause> <clause id="HBEC5B5A161994E8F89D483662CA54E10"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other training programs for offshore oil and gas inspectors, Bureau personnel, Department personnel, or other persons as the Secretary shall designate; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H6115EB7E735D4B50A0684A4D30B15BE7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>certification of the successful completion of training programs for newly hired and experienced offshore oil and gas inspectors.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F329E3D31444875B790886FCF449301"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header> <clause id="H4A8042EEC23442FF909AB2E41F46540A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In performing functions under this paragraph, and subject to clause (ii), the Secretary may enter into cooperative educational and training agreements with educational institutions, related Federal academies, other Federal agencies, State governments, safety training firms, and oil and gas operators and related industries.</text> </clause>
<clause id="H341DD9E2C7664D779022454BE83CA5C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Training requirement</header><text>Such training shall be conducted by the Academy in accordance with curriculum needs and assignment of instructional personnel established by the Secretary.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE49DFE7B2B62448B9B09DB0B785E966A"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Use of Department personnel</header><text>In performing functions under this subsection, the Secretary shall use, to the extent practicable, the facilities and personnel of the Department of the Interior. The Secretary may appoint or assign to the Academy such officers and employees as the Secretary considers necessary for the performance of the duties and functions of the Academy.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H86A3617B0B944D9FACBFD66B177EC88B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Additional training programs</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4BF039BB188543F499EB9F7395BD8A63"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall work with appropriate educational institutions, operators, and representatives of oil and gas workers to develop and maintain adequate programs with educational institutions and oil and gas operators that are designed—</text> <clause id="H8A6D8AB3ABAC4E969A821BA2F3C9DE44"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to enable persons to qualify for positions in the administration of this Act; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H6504A7A37BFE472BB891D3CC73DB9C72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to provide for the continuing education of inspectors or other appropriate Department of the Interior personnel.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H027DBA37DF754FE29623F9730E6729A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Financial and technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may provide financial and technical assistance to educational institutions in carrying out this paragraph.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H363085F0B1384B88BD4FEC0B76235A44"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall not carry out through the Service any function, power, or duty that is—</text> <paragraph id="H99C41006D1C641EDA55CF626916630CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>required by section 402 to be carried out through Bureau of Ocean Energy; or</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0048F4BB68AA4907B1261440EEEC509F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>required by section 404 to be carried out through the Office of Natural Resources Revenue.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H86775E28187340578D9933A220D8F831"><enum>404.</enum><header>Office of Natural Resources revenue</header> <subsection id="HE092100A3E3345F2B041C1944FCDDDFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of the Interior an Office of Natural Resources Revenue (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>) to be headed by a Director of Natural Resources Revenue (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HB39D9930FBD04B6BA5B3F33C897C2060"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment and compensation</header> 
<paragraph id="HAF3C895010BE43E098E26C9FCD9D89CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF3CDCE05DA1453C819613296545CBE1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Director shall be compensated at the rate provided for Level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9DAD4B042BA14717A31D7FD1E219C61D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header> 
<paragraph id="HB5B586C9F56E4EB3B1E1DD97D084777C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall carry out, through the Office, all functions, powers, and duties vested in the Secretary and relating to the administration of offshore royalty and revenue management functions.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8636483A6D3141E99F36928112C703DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific authorities</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out, through the Office, all functions, powers, and duties previously assigned to the Minerals Management Service (including the authority to develop, promulgate, and enforce regulations) regarding offshore royalty and revenue collection; royalty and revenue distribution; auditing and compliance; investigation and enforcement of royalty and revenue regulations; and asset management for onshore and offshore activities.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE89AFFB45BEE498AB142D556C46E5E71"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall not carry out through the Office any function, power, or duty that is—</text> <paragraph id="H33022CBBAAB34027A0A47E51AE9EFCF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>required by section 402 to be carried out through Bureau of Ocean Energy; or</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDC6B9AA2018740DAA4DA489CF3E85245"><enum>(2)</enum><text>required by section 403 to be carried out through the Ocean Energy Safety Service.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H17CECFE0091848029C14ADD3B39C23DC"><enum>405.</enum><header>Ethics and drug testing</header> <subsection id="HAC86AC4164234D71966D8A85D41029DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall certify annually that all Department of the Interior officers and employees having regular, direct contact with lessees, contractors, concessionaires, and other businesses interested before the Government as a function of their official duties, or conducting investigations, issuing permits, or responsible for oversight of energy programs, are in full compliance with all Federal employee ethics laws and regulations under the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) and part 2635 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, and all guidance issued under subsection (c).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H676C29670F1D429383E739612912A150"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Drug Testing</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a random drug testing program of all Department of the Interior personnel referred to in subsection (a).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HD28FD8D705BB426A825F7EC69C0BA982"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue supplementary ethics and drug testing guidance for the employees for which certification is required under subsection (a). The Secretary shall update the supplementary ethics guidance not less than once every 3 years thereafter.</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="H824677FE38F24212AB97D9453BBA0481"><enum>406.</enum><header>Abolishment of Minerals Management Service</header> 
<subsection id="HA736D6AC67D54F1989E8ABB1917D9EA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Abolishment</header><text>The Minerals Management Service is abolished.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H3C3A2CB2EF574F959C6C6C7830168107"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Completed administrative actions</header> <paragraph id="H674AC3B970734409A00CCA8EF6AC724F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Completed administrative actions of the Minerals Management Service shall not be affected by the enactment of this Act, but shall continue in effect according to their terms until amended, modified, superseded, terminated, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by an officer of the United States or a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCFD02AC358D144F8BCEA7E5C1A68C32B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Completed administrative action defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>completed administrative action</quote> includes orders, determinations, memoranda of understanding, memoranda of agreements, rules, regulations, personnel actions, permits, agreements, grants, contracts, certificates, licenses, registrations, and privileges.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC58CE00E059E4BC78900C495B53A0CE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pending Proceedings</header><text>Subject to the authority of the Secretary of the Interior and the officers of the Department of the Interior under this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HADCAC3335EAE440D874FF5B867003D7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pending proceedings in the Minerals Management Service, including notices of proposed rulemaking, and applications for licenses, permits, certificates, grants, and financial assistance, shall continue, notwithstanding the enactment of this Act or the vesting of functions of the Service in another agency, unless discontinued or modified under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such discontinuance or modification could have occurred if this Act had not been enacted; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9FB96A46DE141D2B51F70DD622D5F76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>orders issued in such proceedings, and appeals therefrom, and payments made pursuant to such orders, shall issue in the same manner and on the same terms as if this Act had not been enacted, and any such orders shall continue in effect until amended, modified, superseded, terminated, set aside, or revoked by an officer of the United States or a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9222328F9CA643759C20AA57B184C7DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pending Civil Actions</header><text>Subject to the authority of the Secretary of the Interior or any officer of the Department of the Interior under this Act, pending civil actions shall continue notwithstanding the enactment of this Act, and in such civil actions, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered and enforced in the same manner and with the same effect as if such enactment had not occurred.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H459ECB3D4F33418D966F53BEE49DDE54"><enum>(e)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">References relating to the Minerals Management Service in statutes, Executive orders, rules, regulations, directives, or delegations of authority that precede the effective date of this Act are deemed to refer, as appropriate, to the Department, to its officers, employees, or agents, or to its corresponding organizational units or functions. Statutory reporting requirements that applied in relation to the Minerals Management Service immediately before the effective date of this Act shall continue to apply.</text> </subsection></section>
<section commented="no" id="H952B1676378E40F0A065BD2DD997E18B"><enum>407.</enum><header>Conforming amendments to Executive Schedule pay rates</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H76EA0EAEB0A745BE9303EDE4B214B17F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Under Secretary for Energy, Lands, and Minerals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5314 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <quote>Under Secretaries of the Treasury (3)</quote> the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD50AFFE64D88402CB479DC88243B7537" style="OLC"><list level="paragraph"><list-item>Under Secretary for Energy, Lands, and Minerals, Department of the Interior.</list-item></list><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H9E691AFD65214BB8985228167F3993D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistant Secretaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Assistant Secretaries, Department of the Interior (6)</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H935CECE92092431A9114052489601D9F" style="OLC"><list level="paragraph"><list-item>Assistant Secretaries, Department of the Interior (7).</list-item></list><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection>
<subsection id="H0AB489C2FBD94C7B9A0F97682F54E6D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Directors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5316 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Director, Bureau of Mines, Department of the Interior.</quote> and inserting the following new items:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACA008B3467B43C4A421BB079F173CFC" style="OLC"><list level="paragraph"><list-item>Director, Bureau of Ocean Energy, Department of the Interior.</list-item><list-item>Director, Ocean Energy Safety Service, Department of the Interior.</list-item><list-item>Director, Office of Natural Resources Revenue, Department of the Interior.</list-item></list><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> <section id="H650EAF4A250D49F6B97CCDAC61BE2DFC"><enum>408.</enum><header>Outer Continental Shelf Energy Safety Advisory Board</header> <subsection id="H48E033F0A806466D8EF3BC33F9118FC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall establish, under the Federal Advisory Committee Act, an Outer Continental Shelf Energy Safety Advisory Board (referred to in this section as the <quote>Board</quote>)—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC7E16F09A122474E85E078415A9E7042"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide the Secretary and the Directors established by this Act with independent scientific and technical advice on safe, responsible, and timely mineral and renewable energy exploration, development, and production activities; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA86D6392E72418DBA36C14C2561DCD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to review operations of the National Offshore Energy Health and Safety Academy established under section 403(d), including submitting to the Secretary recommendations of curriculum to ensure training scientific and technical advancements.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BBE0F26B8B54AB2889F8DE911C9BDEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="H0F9607E227514ADDA8417D7EED8C7321"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Size</header><text>The Board shall consist of not more than 11 members, who—</text> <subparagraph id="H9CC64B6BBA1E4B4BB664146B5F8F846E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be appointed by the Secretary based on their expertise in oil and gas drilling, well design, operations, well containment and oil spill response; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9591BFECAC6E437F8BEEE7A185383B86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>must have significant scientific, engineering, management, and other credentials and a history of working in the field related to safe energy exploration, development, and production activities.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BD636AE6CE2472893A459DF59631171"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation and nominations</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with the National Academy of Sciences and the National Academy of Engineering to identify potential candidates for the Board and shall take nominations from the public.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF050DBB68AC647869D451E21B019837A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint Board members to staggered terms of not more than 4 years, and shall not appoint a member for more than 2 consecutive terms.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H6820246083954085B2AB1503A781F3C3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Balance</header><text>In appointing members to the Board, the Secretary shall ensure a balanced representation of industry and research interests.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAB08F8470A1E4C319320A41A8EF3540F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint the Chair for the Board from among its members.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HC1F640C4CA8841FAB128E6B057907E11"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Board shall meet not less than 3 times per year and shall host, at least once per year, a public forum to review and assess the overall energy safety performance of Outer Continental Shelf mineral and renewable energy resource activities.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H5C651EB199D84748880770AA200C2749"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Offshore drilling safety assessments and recommendations</header><text>As part of its duties under this section, the Board shall, by not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section and every 5 years thereafter, submit to the Secretary a report that—</text> <paragraph id="H6AD6D917CA2E4AEEBDAFDE15FA67646C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses offshore oil and gas well control technologies, practices, voluntary standards, and regulations in the United States and elsewhere; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFCDCCB17D5B34A65A87EE7DC88F9692F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as appropriate, recommends modifications to the regulations issued under this Act to ensure adequate protection of safety and the environment, including recommendations on how to reduce regulations and administrative actions that are duplicative or unnecessary.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2D5B228659604288AF968AFFCCACA59D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Reports of the Board shall be submitted by the Board to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House or Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and made available to the public in electronically accessible form.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HE900CBF5AB1D418CA59586D9B5A50A52"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Members of the Board, other than full-time employees of the Federal Government, while attending meeting of the Board or while otherwise serving at the request of the Secretary or the Director while serving away from their homes or regular places of business, may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by section 5703 of title 5, United States Code, for individuals in the Government serving without pay.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HC87D225D657A44379C27E13459B4F8A2"><enum>409.</enum><header>Outer Continental Shelf inspection fees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 22 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1348">43 U.S.C. 1348</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of the section the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H898722DE16EC4534BC299C739A74CD19" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H209B143F0B834362B6D9988B112FC687"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Inspection fees</header> 
<paragraph id="H8BF0CE7407BD4C4F9E8243F8CE64EB72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall collect from the operators of facilities subject to inspection under subsection (c) non-refundable fees for such inspections—</text> <subparagraph id="HD68E603734D84FF5BDAD850814E3D18A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at an aggregate level equal to the amount necessary to offset the annual expenses of inspections of outer Continental Shelf facilities (including mobile offshore drilling units) by the Department of the Interior; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBBAABC840F144ADFBE4750F666622B5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>using a schedule that reflects the differences in complexity among the classes of facilities to be inspected.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA66F11E045241C3B3764111FE3FAF39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ocean energy safety fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury a fund, to be known as the <quote>Ocean Energy Enforcement Fund</quote> (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Fund</quote>), into which shall be deposited all amounts collected as fees under paragraph (1) and which shall be available as provided under paragraph (3).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBCD606A07B0B4B1A9DC5B7CF4EF44C2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of fees</header> 
<subparagraph id="H673065B71F6744BF993B1C9EF45BA588"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, United States Code, all amounts deposited in the Fund—</text> <clause id="H6C705D9EF8DB4E76A430F432D6120826"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be credited as offsetting collections;</text> </clause>
<clause id="HD89E205C875C42478EE2E3159DC7150F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be available for expenditure for purposes of carrying out inspections of outer Continental Shelf facilities (including mobile offshore drilling units) and the administration of the inspection program under this section;</text> </clause> <clause id="H87029EBAAF4F4449A013F7FC3FE3BA12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall be available only to the extent provided for in advance in an appropriations Act; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H80EC7ADF07284326B04FEC5974317556"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>shall remain available until expended.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H114F5B52278E4513B0A8AC565BF6DCA5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use for field offices</header><text>Not less than 75 percent of amounts in the Fund may be appropriated for use only for the respective Department of the Interior field offices where the amounts were originally assessed as fees.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F7824BA8C884D81AF525BC16966DDEF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fees shall be established under this subsection for the fiscal year in which this subsection takes effect and the subsequent 10 years, and shall not be raised without advise and consent of the Congress, except as determined by the Secretary to be appropriate as an adjustment equal to the percentage by which the Consumer Price Index for the month of June of the calendar year preceding the adjustment exceeds the Consumer Price Index for the month of June of the calendar year in which the claim was determined or last adjusted.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H34FB5414AA8C4CF2B4BEF9AA1D144E4B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual fees</header><text>Annual fees shall be collected under this subsection for facilities that are above the waterline, excluding drilling rigs, and are in place at the start of the fiscal year. Fees for each fiscal year in the period of fiscal years 2015 through 2024 shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H186EB2C1A490414DB7E33E7FBD655776"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,500 for facilities with no wells, but with processing equipment or gathering lines;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC38A32F276794A368DD863FAC498130A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$17,000 for facilities with 1 to 10 wells, with any combination of active or inactive wells; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBF75FB281A8E42C2BD95A341A3C0FF7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$31,500 for facilities with more than 10 wells, with any combination of active or inactive wells.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51390B8EC91348F1B4AF0DE805F93474"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fees for drilling rigs</header><text>Fees for drilling rigs shall be assessed under this subsection for all inspections completed in fiscal years 2015 through 2024. Fees for fiscal year 2015 shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFA75ED8C89CC4B28B225258B54704F67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$30,500 per inspection for rigs operating in water depths of 1,000 feet or more; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19222AF05B324ABBBA908B85F6C7E608"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$16,700 per inspection for rigs operating in water depths of less than 1,000 feet.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H41D31033E39344BEAA8F758C430D3B1E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Billing</header><text>The Secretary shall bill designated operators under paragraph (5) within 60 days after the date of the inspection, with payment required within 30 days of billing. The Secretary shall bill designated operators under paragraph (6) within 30 days of the end of the month in which the inspection occurred, with payment required within 30 days after billing.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4EF8D7CC2D74186819EC5637A7992DF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>No fee may be collected under this subsection for any fiscal year after fiscal year 2024.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF482B177FA5C4A41ABEA55B250AECB5E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Annual reports</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB6CACECB0C1A43AC8845A996878F0A47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the end of each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2015, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on the operation of the Fund during the fiscal year.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DA693EFCBFA4294B26204B0C1FEDDA5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report shall include, for the fiscal year covered by the report, the following:</text> 
<clause id="HCF2352851B664637A9F6F317216863B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A statement of the amounts deposited into the Fund.</text> </clause> <clause id="H0190BBD8CC824B0DA5EC39CCE486CF43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of the expenditures made from the Fund for the fiscal year, including the purpose of the expenditures and the additional hiring of personnel.</text> </clause>
<clause id="H2DDA6096FF804067AD17351DC3198B22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A statement of the balance remaining in the Fund at the end of the fiscal year.</text> </clause> <clause id="H066B68632F794EEDA863F394FD0C3A92"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An accounting of pace of permit approvals.</text> </clause>
<clause id="HF1405125A4F342E889AED7F8490E8E54"><enum>(v)</enum><text>If fee increases are proposed after the initial 10-year period referred to in paragraph (5), a proper accounting of the potential adverse economic impacts such fee increases will have on offshore economic activity and overall production, conducted by the Secretary.</text> </clause> <clause id="H5E35CA4FE04F4F5BAD4CAE5F9363316A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Recommendations to increase the efficacy and efficiency of offshore inspections.</text> </clause>
<clause id="H6E59A432533148089130995AE13931D4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Any corrective actions levied upon offshore inspectors as a result of any form of misconduct.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></title> <title id="H8108AE8A4CC2499CB907D5A7DA61A7FF"><enum>V</enum><header>United States Territories</header> <section id="H7298C041A01749D4BECE0927D05763E7"><enum>501.</enum><header>Application of Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act with respect to territories of the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB8B774EC1ACD4674990D9F666CE2E544"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (a), by inserting after <quote>control</quote> the following: <quote>or lying within the United States exclusive economic zone and the Continental Shelf adjacent to any territory of the United States</quote>;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8035726BFF2E4192B680BF3771CDE28E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (p), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58BBA45C072E445F94F626FC03DEB94D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (q), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF30C5E99A14A418CA2166D3111B92882"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H57625D4A4AFD46828CBD5BFE4F9B98D2" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H971BB33FAE984B64B2E84FBB3CD33791"><enum>(r)</enum><text>The term <quote>State</quote> includes each territory of the United States.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section></title> <title id="HCFEAA7FD224F4FD0A5408B942B765D6E"><enum>VI</enum><header>Infrastructure Revenue Bonds</header> <section id="HD69CCC474DAA4AF39D2EAB27802BEC64"><enum>601.</enum><header>Leveraging Infrastructure Trust Account with infrastructure revenue bonds</header> <subsection id="H0E55EC45FAEE43A1BEA24D36721229F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of chapter 31 of subtitle III of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after section 3102 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE87B2EFDB0346BDA8620EFC9DFC395D" style="USC"> 
<section id="H5E17FD2D3A5A4B0EB2D7913C2FF20D1D"><enum>3102A.</enum><header>Infrastructure revenue bonds</header> 
<subsection id="HB7740DF3377243BFB94508F947D9D671"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With the approval of the President, the Secretary of the Treasury may borrow for highway and transportation project expenditures, and water infrastructure expenditures, authorized by law after the date of the enactment of this section and may issue interest-bearing bonds for the amounts borrowed and may buy, redeem, and make refunds under section 3111 of this title. The Secretary may prescribe conditions under section 3121 of this title, except that such bonds shall mature 20 years from the date of issue.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H0F4AD47417A04D02A3A3F804ED634A5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Financed with Infrastructure Trust Account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such obligations, and the interest thereon, are not guaranteed by the United States and shall be paid solely from amounts deposited in the Infrastructure Trust Account established by paragraph (6)(A)(ii) of section 8(g) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(g)</external-xref>).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H3CD77460B26B46078D4BFC6A158E23F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The aggregate face amount of obligations issued during a calendar year under subsection (a) shall not exceed—</text> <paragraph id="HAE7D03577A444A2CA3BB4669B5590D68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$25,000,000,000 for each of calendar years 2015 through 2020; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC42A36C1AA5449118B9A5E27F29B8D16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$0 for each calendar year thereafter.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCB79C0336FA24433AC94CB816DF48DD5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Redemption</header><text>The Government may redeem any part of a series of bonds before maturity by giving at least 4 months’ notice.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection>
<subsection id="H29C808E70D63474E81AEA34AEACC1D82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections subchapter I of chapter 31 of subtitle III of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3102 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C39491368FF4F19BB8762120295482A" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">3102A. Infrastructure revenue bonds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> <section id="HE3FDDC4FA4354803A9A1ACD0B1AA1956"><enum>602.</enum><header>Ninety-five percent of bond proceeds for Highway Trust Fund</header> <subsection id="H4CC2789DF28C48B0997AE16EC49EFC86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95681346E81F4B599F96FC68E827BAC5" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HB2429C9FF0494EEE86EB9DEC28EA2671"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Infrastructure revenue bond proceeds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the Highway Trust Fund amounts equivalent to 95 percent of any proceeds from the issuance of infrastructure revenue bonds under section 3102A of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="HF7F1ED0CB2D74E67B06BA00505A04838"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The heading for subsection (b) of section 9503 of such Code is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">taxes and penalties</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">taxes, penalties, and bond proceeds</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="H849FD538826A4096AD9E79ECA67E8AF8"><enum>603.</enum><header>Five percent of bond proceeds for State revolving loan funds for wastewater treatment facilities and drinking water facilities</header> 
<subsection id="H37DA631ECACD494089146B999596FBEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Wastewater treatment facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts equivalent to 2.5 percent of any proceeds from the issuance of infrastructure revenue bonds under section 3102A of title 31, United States Code, shall be made available to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for making capitalization grants to eligible States under title VI of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1381">33 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HD6C0295A1119480BB77411F91D5243C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Drinking water facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts equivalent to 2.5 percent of any proceeds from the issuance of infrastructure revenue bonds under section 3102A of title 31, United States Code, shall be made available to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for making capitalization grants to eligible States under section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-12">42 U.S.C. 300j–12</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section></title>
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


