<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H08C026423C834373BA23CD49C6282EFE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4253 IH: Avonte’s Law Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4253</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151215">December 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a grant program to help State and local law enforcement agencies reduce the risk of
			 injury and death relating to the wandering characteristics of some
			 children with autism and other disabilities.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6BF9639140E54E0692071EFBEE893F58" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAD185C9B4D3C4982B968E1525355387C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Avonte’s Law Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA8175B42083946B4A3DD823C5EB44CF2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program to reduce injury and death relating to the wandering and safety of individuals with disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3711">42 U.S.C. 3711 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9D022C17784470FA9B10D300388323D" style="OLC">
				<part id="H2E256F6E2EDF45058320BA48278B164F"><enum>LL</enum><header>Grant program to reduce injury and death relating to the wandering and safety of individuals with
			 disabilities</header>
					<section id="HB5458CB7659A4117B5AA385E37BB7053"><enum>3021.</enum><header>Program authorized</header>
 <subsection id="H87ABA553F712418B9649401148122995"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may make grants to law enforcement agencies to—</text> <paragraph id="H5B624990C7D44A0A875D86BABF84D5BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduce the risk of injury and death relating to the wandering characteristics of some individuals with autism and other disabilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90F7E8C2E45447BD8A1D106C94A2BF48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>safeguard the well-being of individuals with disabilities during interactions with law enforcement.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABFB2FAD67904E4DB0564AAF286B4D91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0FB9FBA482E34BF0946E4B018EA908C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>distributed directly to a law enforcement agency; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3F4FF3DD089402BB6992F43924E5CD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>used to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC2358BB17A24A58A27D0D0A67D3CE31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide education and resources to law enforcement agencies, first responders, schools, clinicians, and the public in order to—</text>
 <clause id="HC88226CB9C4B4C58A172D6C8673E292A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduce the risk of wandering by individuals with autism or other disabilities;</text> </clause><clause id="H6A0BB9E6C6F744578EAA84E41722E755"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>help to identify signs of abuse in individuals with autism or other disabilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8C1EF6E5CB5F4C9D9DB8296B8B30370D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increase personal safety and survival skills for individuals with autism or other disabilities; and</text> </clause><clause id="H862B06CA2C024CD5BF288728968F763A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>facilitate effective communication with individuals who have communication-related disabilities, including the use of assistive communication techniques and technology;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8F827FCC03E4151A52BAF26E76BA9A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide training and emergency protocols for school administrators, staff, and families;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81BCA51B0E294FC2B56EF46A674545CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide response tools and training for law enforcement and search-and-rescue agencies, including—</text>
 <clause id="H8A64542F58C347FAAC873508AB7EE372"><enum>(i)</enum><text>tracking technology;</text> </clause><clause id="HCE26C42D17E240AF89337D6D30F37164"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reverse 911 technology;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H19D3D5032194482C86B0B25541A94906"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assistive communication technology;</text> </clause><clause id="H4B26CEB0D40E48E8975659CAE07AB06B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Endangered Missing Advisories; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFB0571C7525F4AA39E3C6D41373A54B9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Federal search-and-rescue guidelines for special needs children; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A51EE478F2B4CB78C785BD04AA68C74"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide response tools and training to law enforcement agencies in order to recognize and respond to individuals with intellectual and developmental disabilities.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C997D0E1F6E46659A7317455192A71A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standards and best practices for use of tracking devices</header>
							<paragraph id="H2275443A091E449EB69DD0AA86E4D207"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAAC49B63F4C5453F9C2C38CC72AAAC3E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this part, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and leading research, advocacy, self-advocacy, and service organizations, shall establish standards and best practices relating to the use of tracking technology to monitor children with autism and other disabilities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6186C187CD0F400B91BAD9E3DFA77FB3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In establishing the standards and best practices required under subparagraph (A), the Attorney General—</text>
 <clause id="HC3CEF01CCE664A449B774B562F6AA734"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall determine—</text> <subclause id="HF35426D330CE48178C6A6984DA9378AB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the criteria used to determine which individuals would benefit from the use of a tracking device; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5732055A7C76481BA411EBC58ADE4253"><enum>(II)</enum><text>who should have direct access to the tracking system; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HEA9945692E2A4E04B158F7EEE287011D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may establish standards and best practices the Attorney General determines are necessary to the administration of a tracking system, including procedures in order to—</text>
 <subclause id="H4D28E209B96342929C9759568452C72D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>safeguard the privacy of the data used by the tracking device such that—</text> <item id="H8C7385915F07495FB640A5F71D7B7119"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>access to the data is restricted to agencies determined necessary by the Attorney General; and</text>
 </item><item id="H0DAC4A6760754A86954C788FC44D8FB1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>use of the data is solely for the purpose of preventing injury or death;</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HDE67689CD170468AA2C552EFB1235C56"><enum>(II)</enum><text>develop criteria to determine whether use of the tracking device is the least restrictive alternative in order to prevent risk of injury or death prior to issuing the tracking device, including the previous consideration of less restrictive alternatives;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8E82E1CEDA834CABBC3805C7E23B3EA1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide training for law enforcement agencies to recognize signs of abuse in their interactions with applicants;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H483E2FE3E5FF40D39E506D197316C945"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>protect the civil rights and liberties of children with disabilities who use tracking devices, including their rights under the Fourth Amendment of the Constitution of the United States;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD7D2BFB0F53E4D40BC9C35AC1FFC0D7E"><enum>(V)</enum><text>establish a complaint and investigation process to address—</text> <item id="H02D6304A03304BB393129719E4C176D5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>incidents of noncompliance by grant recipients with the best practices established by the Attorney General or other applicable law; and</text>
 </item><item id="H7E7550D8CF7A44929722B9BE36459940"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>use of a tracking device over the objection of a child with a disability; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H065A9747502343A9921905ECDD490578"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the role which State agencies responsible for providing services to children with developmental disabilities and State agencies responsible for child protective services should have in the administration of a tracking system.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H461A23603DCB4656AE52DE405C4569ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required compliance</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6CDB340D34CD4F039ADB9F134A3F6D54"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each law enforcement agency that receives a grant under this section shall comply with any standards and best practices relating to the use of tracking devices as established by the Attorney General under paragraph (1), in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and leading research, advocacy, self-advocacy, and service organizations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9127768B29954F329951365F7A266935"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination of compliance</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall determine whether a law enforcement agency that receives a grant under this section acts in compliance with the requirement described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF9277917ACD4BA68FEC2CE67ED267CB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability of standards and best practices</header><text>The standards and best practices established by the Attorney General under paragraph (1) shall apply only to the grant program authorized under this part.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H71ECE48A01DA40D4BA5C75D13B4DE1FD"><enum>3022.</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To request a grant under section 3021, the head of a law enforcement agency shall submit an application to the Attorney General in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text>
 </section><section id="H7CB0FA4FFED8479B90085A2BB5F88DD3"><enum>3023.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part—</text> <paragraph id="HAFA81ED183FE4851A549167E7A0FD834"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>child</term> means an individual who is less than 18 years of age;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D68AA2AE64B46B2B6BB65CB63BC63FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the same meaning as in section 4(e) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b(e)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3FF03E1F3DE41479674705385D82E4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>law enforcement agency</term> means an agency of a State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe that is authorized by law or by a government agency to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of any violation of criminal law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H402CF713023A44FEA9FA7F7167DC8194"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E39EC8EE3574CCCBBC3F41183A1A98B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>unit of local government</term> means a county, municipality, town, township, village, parish, borough, or other unit of general government below the State level.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H21027EE63B1B46F3BA8BA8074CFED6B1"><enum>3024.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


