<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H22A9DCD6E994428296BBCC36668BC679" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 710 EH: Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 710</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to prepare a comprehensive security assessment of the transportation security card program, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB3D4EFC0362B442B99E6243E78AF9E14" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA1B0EAEC74F047C8922B767BDD1210E7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1AF58B92D8D04EF5B4CA20EA49024AF4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Comprehensive security assessment of the transportation security card program</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A2578079358467D99C0E5516DCA7B94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Comptroller General of the United States a comprehensive assessment of the effectiveness of the transportation security card program under section 70105 of title 46, United States Code, at enhancing security and reducing security risks for facilities and vessels regulated pursuant to section 102 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/295">Public Law 107–295</external-xref>. Such assessment shall be conducted by a national laboratory that, to the extent practicable, is within the Department of Homeland Security laboratory network with expertise in maritime security or by a maritime security university-based center within the Department of Homeland Security centers of excellence network.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7D8E075C94104202897F390B1F6DED7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The comprehensive assessment shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H8BF9B2D786B2404685A68E1CA05980F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation of the extent to which the program, as implemented, addresses known or likely security risks in the maritime environment;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6AED46C160234CA2940D998860C6B178"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the extent to which deficiencies identified by the Comptroller General have been addressed; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B49526BA8764C8C9F8EC7DF4DEA1211"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a cost-benefit analysis of the program, as implemented.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDAAC5819211641CA99C6D7A032D59F19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Corrective action plan; program reforms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the Secretary submits the assessment under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit a corrective action plan to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate that responds to the assessment under subsection (b). The corrective action plan shall include an implementation plan with benchmarks, may include programmatic reforms, revisions to regulations, or proposals for legislation, and shall be considered in any rule making by the Department relating to the transportation security card program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3AB72D44FEDE4D2A8B2BFA5297306D5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Comptroller General review</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the Secretary issues the corrective action plan under subsection (c), the Comptroller General shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H75CBDD2FB01F482BAC8B907CEFCEB62C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the extent to which such plan implements—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB22AF2D7E654868B23910EF8473F07A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations issued by the national laboratory or maritime security university-based center, as applicable, in the assessment submitted under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H052431C758E241CAA8DCB39E404A9D30"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations issued by the Comptroller General before the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H940D5740A68243DA899DC5D41509771F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate as to the responsiveness of such plan to such recommendations.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H12376BEAA9F94E47A76B7E02A4F3FC5A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transportation security card reader rule</header>
<paragraph id="H1D8BEFBDE37049D69F4E35A803FCB572"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not issue a final rule requiring the use of transportation security card readers until—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9889BBA7CC140AAAE5FE33AFDCE1287"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Comptroller General informs the Committees on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and Commerce, Science and Transportation of the Senate that the submission under subsection (a) is responsive to the recommendations of the Comptroller General; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5B3E9CD3C4634B2F9A3AFFCD37722F0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary issues an updated list of transportation security card readers that are compatible with active transportation security cards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31FB8863763047C1A3BD1ACCE7481FC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any final rule issued pursuant to the notice of proposed rulemaking on Transportation Worker Identification Credential (TWIC)-Reader Requirements published by the Coast Guard on March 22, 2013 (78 Fed. Reg. 17781)</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6A62961F95C84FB48DD11B4F6B3A2586"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Comptroller General oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than 18 months after the date of the issuance of the corrective action plan under subsection (c), and every 6 months thereafter during the 3-year period following the date of the issuance of the first report under this subsection, the Comptroller General shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate regarding implementation of the corrective action plan.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H00677A3E5ADC40BAACCF258362641D2F"><enum>3.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and this Act and such amendments shall be carried out using amounts otherwise available for such purpose.</text></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20150210" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives February 10, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


