<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0B090D315D9F405A92C5D14A8E12F4FD" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3413 IH: Efficient Space Exploration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3413</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require a report on requirements and risks in connection with the use of radioisotopic power
			 systems for space exploration beyond low-Earth orbit.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H25DE331E492E40988FB8B067F2205828" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAB361084700D40DC8B4B736E7C34D803" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Efficient Space Exploration Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD64E89B68A2B4D289E4BDCE577396430"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on requirements and risks in use of radioisotopic power systems for space exploration beyond low-Earth orbit</header> <subsection id="H7D39CB66729C46CD8C569FAD67FEC221"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF58EBDA3DE5840F89D6BA0A2BDC2175D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conducting deep space exploration requires radioisotope power systems, such as thermoelectric and Stirling generators and converters;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H196BF2C851E8423DA2A817016AD45C9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing continuity in the production of the material needed to power such radioisotope power systems is paramount to the success of future deep space missions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H143F727F508648C2BB5A58381A1DB56E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Federal agencies supporting the National Aeronautics and Space Administration through the production of the material described in paragraph (2) should do so in a cost effective manner so as not to impose excessive reimbursement requirements on the Administration.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB632CFA934394216BEBD028E8D1A044F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Analysis of requirements and risks</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies, conduct an analysis of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBBC6A08FB991418AA358149D9E6B7D24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the requirements of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for radioisotope power system material that is needed to carry out planned, high priority robotic missions in the solar system and other surface exploration activities beyond low-Earth orbit; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD1ABC2A36B945E68577B3AA65AA9D44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the risks to missions of the Administration in meeting those requirements, or any additional requirements, due to a lack of adequate radioisotope power system material.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7AFA4BD9ED7843F793B6496E8F28B290"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents of analysis</header><text>The analysis conducted under subsection (b) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HECF95A3B5E3F4C1EB3DB013CF2BA3F98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>detail the current projected mission requirements and associated timeframes for radioisotope power systems and radioisotope power system material;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B744D5B63A54399B4BDCB96DD702CC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>explain the assumptions used to determine the requirements of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for the material, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H86E592FE413848F480E15160C6F48E90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the planned use of advanced thermal conversion technology, such as advanced thermocouples and Stirling generators and converters; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B1DBCFF8B574265AE2B9DC665C3C041"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the risks and implications of, and contingencies for, any delays or unanticipated technical challenges affecting or related to the mission plans of the Administration for the anticipated use of advanced thermal conversion technology;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73F51119E7A343B38A82A785DE0AA942"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess the risk to the programs of the Administration of any potential delays in achieving the schedule and milestones for planned domestic production of radioisotope power system material;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F89C68B8C4F4CFF845D1A685BD72790"><enum>(4)</enum><text>outline a process for meeting any additional Administration requirements for the material;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF37332800EC34EF481C4E27DA77A7749"><enum>(5)</enum><text>estimate the incremental costs required to increase the amount of material produced each year, if such an increase is needed to support additional Administration requirements for the material;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD13A903A17B0417AAD124F79C3AD9EE6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>detail how the Administration and other Federal agencies will manage, operate, and fund production facilities and the design and development of all radioisotope power systems used by the Administration and other Federal agencies as necessary;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF508DBCC25084E239A6C3C7DD1F0ADC6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>specify the steps the Administrator will take, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, to preserve the infrastructure and workforce necessary for production of radioisotope power systems and ensure that Administration reimbursements to the Department of Energy associated with such preservation are equitable and justified;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2670D4D4FD904533949FD6D0EEA7B78A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>identify the steps the Administrator will take to preserve taxpayer investment to date in Advanced Stirling Convertor technology; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27543DF3A3854B268582E93061799B1D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>detail how the Administrator has implemented or rejected the recommendations of the National Research Council in the 2009 report titled <quote>Radioisotope Power Systems: An Imperative for Maintaining U.S. Leadership in Space Exploration</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H181BAA061AA249CCB513F55444BE1127"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transmittal</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall transmit the results of the analysis conducted under subsection (b) to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


