<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7C654FD008D54124BE56917D4E093E7E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3983 IH: Building Opportunity for Student Startups Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3983</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for a report on the role of incubators and accelerators in the commercialization of
			 federally funded research and regional economic development.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD75D1FDA70AA4820AADB49F9545302B0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3C1758C8910D41289E8DF8C31671464F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Opportunity for Student Startups Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BOSS Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2D58C2185AD941CE9AE6DBE88298A1F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Academies report on incubators and accelerators</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study on the role of incubators and accelerators, including university-based incubators and accelerators, in the commercialization of federally funded research and regional economic development. The study shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3882AEECF54640DA9E94624E0E26336C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include an examination of metrics for comparing startups that have and have not completed incubator or accelerator programs, and include the role of incubators and accelerators in developing regional innovation clusters; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31B5599E8FCE4DDCB9F92FD26E4D2569"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify best practices in the structure, goals, operation, management, and funding mechanisms of leading incubators and accelerators.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


