<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB8246DA8966947DDA1F993C476ABDE41" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 885 IH: Voting Rights Amendment Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 885</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150211">February 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000596">Mr. Pierluisi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Voting Rights Act of 1965 to revise the criteria for determining which States and
			 political subdivisions are subject to section 4 of the Act, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9254A418A24F483683627749DA866ABB" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAD582E66DA70493CA1793860B3F49A48" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voting Rights Amendment Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H834889AC9D624C039AA399B99B97EDF6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Violations triggering authority of court to retain jurisdiction</header> <subsection id="HA4FE96A766F24073865D0D25CEAC4F52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Types of Violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(c) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10302">52 U.S.C. 10302(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>violations of the fourteenth or fifteenth amendment</quote> and inserting <quote>violations of the 14th or 15th Amendment; violations of this Act (other than a violation of section 2(a) which is based on the imposition of a requirement that an individual provide a photo identification as a condition of receiving a ballot for voting in an election for Federal, State, or local office); or violations of any Federal voting rights law that prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, color, or membership in a language minority group,</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF09051DD7D9A4F908992ABEC2C0D5058"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10302">52 U.S.C. 10302(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>violations of the fourteenth or fifteenth amendment</quote> and inserting <quote>violations of the 14th or 15th Amendment, violations of this Act, or violations of any Federal voting rights law that prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, color, or membership in a language minority group,</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9A4D3D1DC24C4D69AAE5829A47D7B9EE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Criteria for coverage of States and political subdivisions</header>
			<subsection id="HA3ED61FE2CBF4BA8B187EB7DF156E2E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination of States and Political Subdivisions Subject to Section 4(<enum-in-header>a</enum-in-header>)</header>
 <paragraph id="HC0A9C7BB980247328FA0C13350456720"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4(b) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10303">52 U.S.C. 10303(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD0A8349D30D4DD0A73BBD4F330BF196" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HC2F24DB17470441D8814F232CE866263"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of States and Political Subdivisions Subject to Requirements</header> <paragraph id="HD9DA37E0FD5C43258430A929381908A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existence of voting rights violations during previous 15 years</header> <subparagraph id="H7EF9404C23074290A6CAFABCA5A361DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Statewide application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) applies with respect to a State and all political subdivisions within the State during a calendar year if 5 or more voting rights violations occurred in the State during the previous 15 calendar years, at least one of which was committed by the State itself (as opposed to a political subdivision within the State).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7834CA92BFB84D7581C70F7C310F4201"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application to specific political subdivisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) applies with respect to a political subdivision during a calendar year if—</text> <clause id="H7E5C023E53CE4EAEAC5C52EE11B50A8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>3 or more voting rights violations occurred in the subdivision during the previous 15 calendar years; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8DB16DF5AB62477AA5B6B4AA5B600550"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 or more voting rights violations occurred in the subdivision during the previous 15 calendar years and the subdivision had persistent, extremely low minority turnout during the previous 15 calendar years.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46944EB852F044E2BEBBA8E612F8E05D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of application</header>
 <subparagraph id="H73F4C10AF3824622B092E1C6E142D0C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), if, pursuant to paragraph (1), subsection (a) applies with respect to a State or political subdivision during a calendar year, subsection (a) shall apply with respect to such State or political subdivision for the period—</text>
 <clause id="HFD051021718F4A8CB7D58B69FCF88F5F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that begins on January 1 of the year in which subsection (a) applies pursuant to the applicable provisions of paragraph (1); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H33F72313FF3F4ABFB5AC82DEB8B644EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that ends on the date which is 10 years after January 1 of the year in which the most recent voting rights violation occurred in the State or political subdivision.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAACDA58CC624CF6B591FA2B7919A8C4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No further application after declaratory judgment</header>
 <clause id="HDA55B1F371B94A36B2F62CB005745665"><enum>(i)</enum><header>States</header><text>If a State obtains a declaratory judgment under subsection (a), and the judgment remains in effect, subsection (a) shall no longer apply to such State pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) unless, after the issuance of the declaratory judgment, paragraph (1)(A) applies to the State solely on the basis of voting rights violations occurring after the issuance of the declaratory judgment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H65E39C8CCADD4535A1CC19B63A3AC203"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Political subdivisions</header><text>If a political subdivision obtains a declaratory judgment under subsection (a), and the judgment remains in effect, subsection (a) shall no longer apply to such political subdivision pursuant to paragraph (1), including pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) (relating to the statewide application of subsection (a)), unless, after the issuance of the declaratory judgment, paragraph (1)(B) applies to the political subdivision solely on the basis of voting rights violations (and, in the case of paragraph (1)(B)(ii), extremely low minority turnout) occurring after the issuance of the declaratory judgment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H15266E36DD15493D863389D024C475B5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of voting rights violation</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), a voting rights violation occurred in a State or political subdivision if any of the following applies:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7E33FC74AC824CAFA08D827B16EBF184"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a final judgment (which has not been reversed on appeal), any court of the United States has determined that a denial or abridgement of the right of any citizen of the United States to vote on account of race, color, or membership in a language minority group, in violation of the 14th or 15th Amendment, occurred anywhere within the State or subdivision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F84D8DF40014C4E9B52DB930614A109"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a final judgment (which has not been reversed on appeal), any court of the United States has determined that a voting qualification or prerequisite to voting or standard, practice, or procedure with respect to voting was imposed or applied or would have been imposed or applied anywhere within the State or subdivision in a manner that resulted or would have resulted in a denial or abridgement of the right of any citizen of the United States to vote on account of race or color, or in contravention of the guarantees set forth in subsection (f)(2), in violation of section 2.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66F4BFFADA574468AE522A21C9B169DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a final judgment (which has not been reversed on appeal), any court of the United States has denied the request of the State or subdivision for a declaratory judgment under section 3(c) or section 5, and thereby prevented a voting qualification or prerequisite to voting or standard, practice, or procedure with respect to voting from being enforced anywhere within the State or subdivision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H082FBC1D22F4408B86BC149F7C61EEC9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General has interposed an objection under section 3(c) or section 5 (and the objection has not been overturned by a final judgment of a court or withdrawn by the Attorney General), and thereby prevented a voting qualification or prerequisite to voting or standard, practice, or procedure with respect to voting from being enforced anywhere within the State or subdivision, other than an objection which is based on a voting qualification or procedure which consists of the imposition of a requirement that an individual provide a photo identification as a condition of receiving a ballot for voting in an election for Federal, State, or local office.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC1BC84E34E84AA491201C438F394BDF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Determination of persistent, extremely low minority turnout</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B)(ii), a political subdivision has persistent, extremely low minority turnout with respect to a calendar year if any of the following applies:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE9472FC68E184F9C8A668C3C1891822B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the general elections for the office of President which were held in the political subdivision during the previous 15 calendar years—</text>
 <clause id="H1DEFAA8B171241858DF974F12B8538BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the majority of such elections, the minority turnout rate in the political subdivision was below—</text>
 <subclause id="HEABF1DB531714ADBAEB7190D13A731A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the minority turnout rate for the entire Nation,</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5607EE1C1D444F34BEBDD57C7955F148"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the nonminority turnout rate for the entire Nation,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6671FFBDA1434CF5855D9A958389110D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the minority turnout rate for the State in which the political subdivision is located,</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF718B1C7B4094BCD88DF48006AB82A5C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the nonminority turnout rate for the State in which the political subdivision is located, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3353D3A009464A55B22AA6ACF31B63FC"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the nonminority turnout rate for the political subdivision; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HEA4F199E8BB04B17A7D9D16836947248"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average minority turnout rate across all such elections in the political subdivision was more than 10 percentage points below the average nonminority turnout rate for the entire Nation.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4C9017C58E44494B5E956317A2BAD7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the general elections for Federal office which were held in the political subdivision during the previous 15 calendar years—</text>
 <clause id="H27CFFBBA67A744DD99D43DDA482BA2AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the majority of such elections, the minority turnout rate in the political subdivision was below—</text>
 <subclause id="H143602649AC441209241308AC28A0F74"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the minority turnout rate for the State in which the political subdivision is located,</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7F40696010274B4CA1BCBF2527D3EDF7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the nonminority turnout rate for the State in which the political subdivision is located, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCD7D36BC236C4ECC9044F0CB81FB16C2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the nonminority turnout rate for the political subdivision; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HA6D4276A8A6949708A47F9D2A47D3689"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average minority turnout rate across all such elections in the political subdivision was more than 10 percentage points below the average nonminority turnout rate for the State in which the political subdivision is located.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD8975EB053943E296B6EAA1A141AA50"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Timing of determinations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5594761315D34AC8AC1B60AB4187DBDF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determinations of voting rights violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As early as practicable during each calendar year, the Attorney General shall make the determinations required by this subsection (other than the determinations described in subparagraph (B)), including updating the list of voting rights violations attributable to each State and political subdivision for the previous calendar year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2BE4C9256CB4426BA78D18157B53624"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determinations of turnout rates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As early as practicable during each odd-numbered calendar year, the Attorney General, in consultation with the heads of the relevant offices of the government, shall make the determinations of turnout rates required by this subsection, including the minority and nonminority turnout rates for the general elections for Federal office held in the previous year in each State and political subdivision (expressed as percentages of the citizen voting-age population of the State and subdivision and determined using scientifically accepted statistical methodologies).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00CE6652DCD446E78C5D1CA0A1A2FF41"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effective upon publication in Federal Register</header><text>A determination or certification of the Attorney General under this section or under section 8 or 13 shall be effective upon publication in the Federal Register.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H931C077692974FF094B1BE4AA1A2A6A1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H6E5B43DEB44A42CA83E54C1B9F7C1218"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>general election for Federal office</term> means a general election held solely or in part for the purpose of electing any candidate for the office of President, Vice President, Presidential elector, Senator, Member of the House of Representatives, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H161265812CB54E59B2BD2D9BE014F081"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minority</term> means persons who identify themselves as being—</text> <clause id="H7668F6F1866B404FACEEBF7266411DCC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of Hispanic or Latino origin;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC008184FAE20414E915E6DF004A796E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of a race other than White; or</text> </clause><clause id="H56AFA8AD006345629031B83712C47875"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>of 2 or more races.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E9A4A28DD42426EB2B09A5EC74E9BDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term “nonminority” means persons who identify themselves as being—</text> <clause id="H7F0ED67E82E24A79AF6D766B91D2C7C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not of Hispanic or Latino origin;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9018952E0E51432B9EA1C3DBAF0DBB0F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>White; and</text> </clause><clause id="H7A75C35B6C7447A1B910E38E6471E48F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not of any other race.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD9C406F1C9044B698647600631CC14B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>turnout rate</term> means, with respect to a demographic group and an election, the amount (expressed as a percentage) equal to the quotient of—</text>
 <clause id="HF9AAA50B7A3C4DEF8D414D7B536149A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of individuals in that group who are citizens of the United States, who are 18 years of age or older on the date of the election, and who cast ballots in the election; divided by</text>
 </clause><clause id="H249179267BB14283AAAC16C9F6AFE2F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total number of individuals in that group who are citizens of the United States and who are 18 years of age or older on the date of the election.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B3D7A21AEEB41D3946E3BAB5633F8B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 4(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10303">52 U.S.C. 10303(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H325E96B2C1B94974BF4BF1389CD1D9DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) in the first sentence of the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>any State with respect to which</quote> and all that follows through <quote>unless</quote> and inserting <quote>any State to which this subsection applies during a calendar year pursuant to determinations made under subsection (b), or in any political subdivision of such State (as such subdivision existed on the date such determinations were made with respect to such State), though such determinations were not made with respect to such subdivision as a separate unit, or in any political subdivision with respect to which this subsection applies during a calendar year pursuant to determinations made with respect to such subdivision as a separate unit under subsection (b), unless</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5994824ABC3C4DF689F68AE728FA8917"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking the second sentence;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H071D0CCE2CE94EBB9F47C490F807496D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>(in the case of a State or subdivision seeking a declaratory judgment under the second sentence of this subsection)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H230175DBEC134AC499D2E7393ECF1FF4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>(in the case of a State or subdivision seeking a declaratory judgment under the second sentence of this subsection)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96345FAA71F14170AC8E9CE97B1EF774"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>(in the case of a State or subdivision seeking a declaratory judgment under the second sentence of this subsection)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41A6030499BA428FA271D8E1FC89962B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>(in the case of a State or subdivision which sought a declaratory judgment under the second sentence of this subsection)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BFBEE7BEEFD4FAD8C4CFF42885DA8F7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (7) and (8).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FF82B9DC8C5481F9AEDA43AFF7A6E24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of Treatment of Members of Language Minority Groups</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10303">52 U.S.C. 10303(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>race or color,</quote> and inserting <quote>race or color or in contravention of the guarantees of subsection (f)(2),</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9F8820B598BA4CF3B47B865B0C3A62FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeal of Retention of Jurisdiction of 3-Judge Court</header><text>Section 4(a)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10303">52 U.S.C. 10303(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the second and third sentences.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB1E08FA0D4ED4AE38D3F1310803FEEAD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Promoting transparency to enforce the Voting Rights Act</header>
			<subsection id="HDF7E6018D62C428A96B9D02F0C8C1FBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transparency</header>
 <paragraph id="HD5003AA9D47549C9910F59443EFD4CF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 5 the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E0C92B6170A46DD8DD3FECCFF355FBF" style="traditional">
						<section id="H77E77847DB704321BD1746EA09891433"><enum>6.</enum><header>transparency regarding changes to protect voting rights</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA380F90BE0734D4FBEDB9BF4151F9521"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice of Enacted Changes</header>
 <paragraph id="HB6D5600A67484445A730BF19B3F8415E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of Changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State or political subdivision makes any change in any prerequisite to voting or standard, practice, or procedure affecting voting in any election for Federal office that will result in the prerequisite, standard, practice, or procedure being different from that which was in effect as of 180 days before the date of the election, the State or political subdivision shall provide reasonable public notice in such State or political subdivision and on the Internet, in a reasonably convenient and accessible format, of a concise description of the change, including the difference between the changed prerequisite, standard, practice, or procedure and the prerequisite, standard, practice, or procedure which was previously in effect.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA85D914F413C4E84A4FAB51FEE98210A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or political subdivision shall provide the public notice required under paragraph (1) not later than 48 hours after making the change involved.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CAF18EFCC3A44A8A41C602C5EC7C03F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transparency Regarding Polling Place Resources</header>
 <paragraph id="H562EC809BCB1435AAEF86986A851B7EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to identify any changes that may impact the right to vote of any person, prior to the 30th day before the date of an election for Federal office, each State or political subdivision with responsibility for allocating registered voters, voting machines, and official poll workers to particular precincts and polling places shall provide reasonable public notice in such State or political subdivision and on the Internet, in a reasonably convenient and accessible format, of the information described in paragraph (2) for precincts and polling places within such State or political subdivision.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAAE0E868914425280B8042DBA1A714E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information described</header><text>The information described in this paragraph with respect to a precinct or polling place is as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC14786C6BB3845F6B3931FDFBF12DC2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The name or number.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89EBDE3C8F6B4CA38B7B207AC60D6796"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a polling place, the location, including the street address.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA7C35D994F04ADA92427FB3562C624D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The voting-age population of the area served by the precinct or polling place, broken down by demographic group if such breakdown is reasonably available to such State or political subdivision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12EF0A40EA4445569F41496120CD50DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of registered voters assigned to the precinct or polling place, broken down by demographic group if such breakdown is reasonably available to such State or political subdivision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7C13660CE1F44D487551A8D9CD1D7CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The number of voting machines assigned.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D900E41F36C4750A0FB0D99CF8283BD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The number of official paid poll workers assigned.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB0E6C0D218D4EACA2D94B05AF030A2C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The number of official volunteer poll workers assigned.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE460E1975D34F7BB8CA1C7CE5F7CBCD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>In the case of a polling place, the dates and hours of operation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAAFFF842419402E9D2114AFF319C431"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates in information reported</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State or political subdivision makes any change in any of the information described in paragraph (2), the State or political subdivision shall provide reasonable public notice in such State or political subdivision and on the Internet, in a reasonably convenient and accessible format, of the change in the information not later than 48 hours after the change occurs or, if the change occurs fewer than 48 hours before the date of the election, as soon as practicable after the change occurs.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E60F95F367D4881B6C507BCADAB8E04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transparency of Changes Relating to Demographics and Electoral Districts</header>
 <paragraph id="HE8AD5C3F9A7C4B75ABA8498AA503B0DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring public notice of changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after making any change in the constituency that will participate in an election for Federal, State, or local office or the boundaries of a voting unit or electoral district in an election for Federal, State, or local office (including through redistricting, reapportionment, changing from at-large elections to district-based elections, or changing from district-based elections to at-large elections), a State or political subdivision shall provide reasonable public notice in such State or political subdivision and on the Internet, in a reasonably convenient and accessible format, of the demographic and electoral data described in paragraph (3) for each of the geographic areas described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88E3B30A87BD4401AFF0A7646E8F9EEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geographic areas described</header><text>The geographic areas described in this paragraph are as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="HEC4B5B4FAACC4C75B5E2AFD9F5B80C0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State as a whole, if the change applies statewide, or the political subdivision as a whole, if the change applies across the entire political subdivision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACE82002D0F049548308A4BDE7D4B0EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the change includes a plan to replace or eliminate voting units or electoral districts, each voting unit or electoral district that will be replaced or eliminated.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAEDC65567754A7E983C43416F836619"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the change includes a plan to establish new voting units or electoral districts, each such new voting unit or electoral district.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEA45DEAC729421D94042F6D47736A7C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Demographic and electoral data</header><text>The demographic and electoral data described in this paragraph with respect to a geographic area described in paragraph (2) are as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB9D47FCE402144BE840A29564BF5A287"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The voting age population, broken down by demographic group.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1497B9152788404494C8209EF7C049C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If it is reasonably available to the State or political subdivision involved, an estimate of the population of the area which consists of citizens of the United States who are 18 years of age or older, broken down by demographic group.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFE477C5E4244F648021A37F8076F3B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of registered voters, broken down by demographic group if such breakdown is reasonably available to the State or political subdivision involved.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE7165B0B8444F14AF01DBFE71440EE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The actual number of votes, or (if it is not reasonably practicable for the State or political subdivision to ascertain the actual number of votes) the estimated number of votes received by each candidate in each statewide election and (if the change applies to only one political subdivision) in each subdivision-wide election held during the 5-year period which ends on the date the change involved is made.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2549F9898F14EB7846869F5F0A27CD5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Voluntary Compliance by Smaller Jurisdictions</header><text>Compliance with this subsection shall be voluntary for a political subdivision of a State unless the subdivision is one of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3FE288AB523D424EA102281A2C148E36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A county or parish.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0195C6A5E52949DB844338CB509FC36C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A municipality with a population greater than 10,000, as determined under the most recent decennial census.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C70847CBF344FF38FCE0FEA52BE977E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A school district with a population greater than 10,000, as determined under the most recent decennial census. For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>school district</term> means the geographic area under the jurisdiction of a local educational agency (as defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5D2C47EC4FD4776A925980F686F17F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules Regarding Format of Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may issue rules specifying a reasonably convenient and accessible format that States and political subdivisions shall use to provide public notice of information under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H68A4B1CD811749768A07FD8450632CDE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No denial of right To vote</header><text>The right to vote of any person shall not be denied or abridged because the person failed to comply with any change made by a State or political subdivision if the State or political subdivision involved did not meet the applicable requirements of this section with respect to the change.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB188D929CE0F453FAB13CC71C24275E8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H02E055D5CD184923ADCF501715D92CC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>demographic group</term> means each group which section 2 protects from the denial or abridgement of the right to vote on account of race or color, or in contravention of the guarantees set forth in section 4(f)(2); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H517DE821F1E44A778F33363A0CABFF9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>election</term> means, with respect to Federal office, any general, special, primary, or runoff election held solely or in part for the purpose of electing any candidate for the office of President, Vice President, Presidential elector, Senator, Member of the House of Representatives, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB95651FD591541C58DA092EB42C72F9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 3(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10302">52 U.S.C. 10302(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>in accordance with section 6</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF7B8AA9951A481EA103EEE79B279532"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a)(1) shall apply with respect to changes which are made on or after the expiration of the 60-day period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H7DFEB360CF2146359EE9B90903226ED4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to assign observers</header>
 <subsection id="HB1D733204EF34C73AC91D1BE76E58A5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of Authority in Political Subdivisions Subject to Preclearance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(a)(2)(B) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10305">52 U.S.C. 10305(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H157D902D0B764C8192CF96E0534E6E1B" style="traditional">
 <subparagraph id="HAAD80D6B6CEA4A81993B6761D5CC2927"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the Attorney General's judgment, the assignment of observers is otherwise necessary to enforce the guarantees of the 14th or 15th Amendment or any provision of this Act or any other law of the United States protecting the right of citizens of the United States to vote;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0053B6B1E5104E80B622958545DB9C5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assignment of Observers To Enforce Bilingual Election Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10305">52 U.S.C. 10305(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H911B170098D0455D804B318728CE51F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA398B7B87A3B45F296914C262ED1AA0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (2); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H10B6A9D7FC9A4D8E87A801C343C82B0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CD1C96D8FF548F9BD75A85DF54B8E20" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HBA0C8BB8F8FF4B8BB2F773B9231D27D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Attorney General certifies with respect to a political subdivision that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2631697A541479E9F5AF9F83E663C1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Attorney General has received written meritorious complaints from residents, elected officials, or civic participation organizations that efforts to violate section 203 are likely to occur, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64F4305B0E61450BBA766DB401BF7E20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the Attorney General’s judgment, the assignment of observers is necessary to enforce the guarantees of section 203;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0712B19AB3B14F1C899E8C35188B8531" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Injunctive relief</header>
 <subsection id="HC3FFA3773DD5495F9053FF4EF5DDF424"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of Scope and Persons Authorized To Seek Relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12(d) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10308">52 U.S.C. 10308(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H06E322081FEA4BBF9234AE03B8CD8721"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 2, 3, 4, 5, 7, 10, 11, or subsection (b) of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>the 14th or 15th Amendment, this Act, or any Federal voting rights law that prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, color, or membership in a language minority group</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6295B7CFA67C43DDA3CC88AC468CF9B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Attorney General may institute for the United States, or in the name of the United States,</quote> and inserting <quote>the aggrieved person or (in the name of the United States) the Attorney General may institute</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A3C26ACD5FA41D883E3FA09F2DCCA77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grounds for Granting Relief</header><text>Section 12(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10308">52 U.S.C. 10308(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCEEEEB45C5FF4D7C8FBAF55BB2485916"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(d) Whenever any person</quote> and inserting <quote>(d)(1) Whenever any person</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDB8F481F0374FDC9B5ABEBDABDEE3FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1) to permit</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) to permit</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86B9E7BC9BD8416F97768705794DC1D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(2) to count</quote> and inserting <quote>(B) to count</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D016F603BB64B478584606C20732EDB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82356CB100BD43A9ADED3AB58C153DE2" style="traditional">
						<paragraph id="HCA17B17E434F4E689FB93E0FFDA965DA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H19B0204B00E244BA88EB5DEDE96274CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action for relief described in this subsection, the court shall grant the relief if the court determines that, on balance, the hardship imposed upon the defendant by the issuance of the relief will be less than the hardship which would be imposed upon the plaintiff if the relief were not granted.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF60384BC161D423A88F5F32A798EC024" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making its determination under this paragraph with respect to a change in any voting qualification, prerequisite to voting, or standard, practice, or procedure affecting voting, the court shall consider the following factors (to the extent applicable to the action):</text>
 <clause id="HAF022AE4CB5C46C5A90CFF8E011DE10A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the qualification, prerequisite, standard, practice, or procedure in effect prior to the change was adopted as a remedy for a Federal court judgment, consent decree, or admission regarding—</text>
 <subclause id="H4E160565BFDF44FEA98D02536620BB39"><enum>(I)</enum><text>discrimination on the basis of race or color in violation of the 14th or 15th Amendment;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H439FF3F720324C139E5E748FC602014F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a violation of this Act; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC59ECB641CB54D129AA907B3F8E66CDC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>voting discrimination on the basis of race, color, or membership in a language minority group in violation of any other Federal or State law.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HB39560B7D11D4435A43BF1EC138A53C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the qualification, prerequisite, standard, practice, or procedure in effect prior to the change served as a ground for the dismissal or settlement of a claim alleging—</text>
 <subclause id="H43E833D4BCEF45D787C0DB0F3F6CA5D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>discrimination on the basis of race or color in violation of the 14th or 15th Amendment;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4ECFCF2349A74C30B2D299AED1B70789"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a violation of this Act; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H62180BEBC1F8406EA82DBC830F6774FD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>voting discrimination on the basis of race, color, or membership in a language minority group in violation of any other Federal or State law.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H89C999840E2C40FD9F75CE95BFA26B03"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Whether the change was adopted fewer than 180 days before the date of the election with respect to which it is to take effect.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9AB6396056894D3DA9C0F9594728FEE6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Whether the defendant has failed to provide timely or complete notice of the adoption of the change as required by applicable Federal or State law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H99A95D9F03994A89AD7DF9AC41086020"><enum>7.</enum><header>Other technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7315578E4D27462BB65D49BBFDAF5A8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Actions Covered Under Section 3</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(c) of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10302">52 U.S.C. 10302(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBCD3D922D93944EFBB133E3A10FAFC6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>any proceeding instituted by the Attorney General or an aggrieved person under any statute to enforce</quote> and inserting <quote>any action under any statute in which a party (including the Attorney General) seeks to enforce</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DDD199E8CD46D3A53DDA6A49E8A1E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>at the time the proceeding was commenced</quote> and inserting <quote>at the time the action was commenced</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5736634BDBFE4CD096576EA504EBC84D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of Treatment of Members of Language Minority Groups</header><text>Section 4(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10303">52 U.S.C. 10303(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC1DAF88866384EEFBE162DB32B61D737"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking the second sentence; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HACEE6D2A958B4309840986E77AC4C049"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (3) and (4).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7656E0B04E7045E59523D3754E6F09BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period During Which Changes in Voting Practices are Subject to Preclearance Under Section 5</header><text>Section 5 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10304">52 U.S.C. 10304</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7DD2415B78C245A3887FDBE17166C4F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>based upon determinations made under the first sentence of section 4(b) are in effect</quote> and inserting <quote>are in effect during a calendar year</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2069B16652DF4DD39B812FF0A9BF8483"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>November 1, 1964</quote> and all that follows through <quote>November 1, 1972</quote> and inserting <quote>the applicable date of coverage</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H78F9E4600559482DBA8265EA3C1A8DA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H138E89A9B2474D3B9D48EA982E38430E" style="traditional">
 <subsection id="HA56B0CF245394F1B89EF7FD6364AEAD1"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable date of coverage</term> means, with respect to a State or political subdivision—</text> <paragraph id="H70DB906C145144988B51B42AA7502870"><enum>(1)</enum><text>June 25, 2013, if the most recent determination for such State or subdivision under section 4(b) was made on or before December 31, 2015; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H147163094A974C6BACB827E2103FC057"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the most recent determination for such State or subdivision under section 4(b) was made, if such determination was made after December 31, 2015.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


