<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB5A3B74E8457478BBDB732F9CCB6D41C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 313 IH: Wounded Warriors Federal Leave Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 313</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide leave to any new Federal employee who is a veteran
			 with a service-connected disability rated at 30 percent or more for
			 purposes of undergoing medical treatment for such disability, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HDAD1794D1699403591678F576251C8C5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H70592361FD934167A758A7FBC90E5E6E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wounded Warriors Federal Leave Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE2D797B077134AC88DEC645DA9CCEEF1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional leave for Federal employees who are disabled veterans</header> <subsection id="HD7D2E6ECC0124318A3EA8798089E75D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4AE35BA685D64179B9DA0CBE1867A944" style="USC">
					<section id="H013B8A9C512C4632904A1AB31C267B01"><enum>6329.</enum><header>Disabled veteran leave</header>
 <subsection id="H845ABC77A1D44C518EBBBB5B9204F4FC"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 12-month period beginning on the first day of employment, any employee who is a veteran with a service-connected disability rated at 30 percent or more is entitled to leave, without loss or reduction in pay, for purposes of undergoing medical treatment for such disability for which sick leave could regularly be used.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H619C8E2A5FC641F2B26E51761722E66E"><enum>(b)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H171E1237A5D34D4B8CE8289D17420955"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The leave credited to an employee under subsection (a) may not exceed 104 hours.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H209062EFFEB34E948926BEBA426F76BE" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any leave credited to an employee pursuant to subsection (a) that is not used during the 12-month period described in such subsection may not be carried over and shall be forfeited.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0F5BC3405A14ACB8BA520868CC785C6"><enum>(c)</enum><text>In order to verify that leave credited to an employee pursuant to subsection (a) is used for treating a service-connected disability, such employee shall submit to the head of the employing agency certification, in such form and manner as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe, that such employee used such leave for purposes of being furnished treatment for such disability by a health care provider.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H575C1D22455444F799C5FB7321C36302"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE7F02A26E76E4716B4CB40DC7A314FC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2105, and includes an officer or employee of the United States Postal Service or of the Postal Regulatory Commission;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C12BFBDA15E4B53BB5DA11AAA7DF7EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>service-connected</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(16) of title 38; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H11E4809291DB4650868AD1FFA103CC37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>veteran</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(2) of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF7AB95FC5468415BB08EA612E62FEEF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 6328 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CB1449B99454798A8517AB50B7F26E9" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">6329. Disabled veteran leave.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7B33DAB619674FDD8AA0C494745D82A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any employee (as that term is defined in section 6329(d)(1) of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)) hired on or after the date that is one year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5EF8B2C7CCB841228461310789B650F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HECE4B33B7E6E4AB1AB234C696B92C556"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations with respect to the leave provided by the amendment in subsection (a) for employees, but not including employees of the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DA2E9DCE39544B18BF93ACC420DEDFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Postmaster General shall prescribe regulations for such leave with respect to officers and employees of the United States Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


