<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD26E0894A8B04B9981DFC290B02B27DD" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 635 IH: Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 635</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150202">February 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To facilitate the export of United States agricultural products to Cuba as authorized by the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000, to remove impediments to the export to Cuba of medical devices and medicines, to allow travel to Cuba by United States legal residents, to establish an agricultural export promotion program with respect to Cuba, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H76A6959DE52E48C3B01C29DD0CDDD51B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H710DC5606F8B4FCAA384A09CDC7757C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H277298C78C9E4CA583488DF0CAA9201B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification of payment terms under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 908(b)(4) of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7207">22 U.S.C. 7207(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56E22157396D46418A838A0C412B0E02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF581E8052C0F490C939FACD748BC6505"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEB05920CCE14C53A51F58406EF681A5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H99C46280F688436DACC94AFA23491878" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H2948DD4CE6B64C91863CCFD14D05B971"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>payment of cash in advance</term> means, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the payment by the purchaser of an agricultural commodity or product and the receipt of such payment by the seller prior to—</text> 
<clause id="HD355E9C51349461DACF2C8BC11239906"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the transfer of title of such commodity or product to the purchaser; and</text></clause> <clause id="H46A9B5CDF6C140CBA37B60D27A6E9E16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the release of control of such commodity or product to the purchaser.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HACF865310BD34EF08331F1743E03B32C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of direct transfers between Cuban and United States financial institutions under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000</header> 
<subsection id="HF96255049C414D708C513F40CB4FEA47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may not restrict direct transfers from a Cuban depository institution to a United States depository institution executed in payment for a product authorized for sale under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7201">22 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H47AF6068623A4D18AD4F8B9AC141EFAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Depository institution defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>depository institution</term> means any entity that is engaged primarily in the business of banking (including a bank, savings bank, savings association, credit union, trust company, or bank holding company).</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H102AF058A4664C889993674171D61EB6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of agricultural export promotion program with respect to Cuba</header> 
<subsection id="H2A247CD781F5451C880D8051B5E3BD14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a program to provide information and technical assistance to United States agricultural producers, cooperative organizations, or State agencies that promote the sale of agricultural commodities, in order to promote and facilitate United States exports of agricultural products to Cuba as authorized by the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7201">22 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H7E11A79E9467428B883FFD25D18406BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance To facilitate exports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall maintain on the Web site of the Department of Agriculture information to assist exporters and potential exporters of United States agricultural commodities with respect to Cuba.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H31F64694BBEB4D2BB05C22495A013D21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to expend such sums as may be available in the Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9512">section 9512</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by section 9(b) of this Act).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H84FA475F89A34F13AC4334FF6C335E02"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of visas to conduct activities in accordance with the trade sanctions reform and export enhancement act of 2000</header> <subsection id="HF538E5D6D86A40189F46D49E0C3B6780"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance of visas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of a Cuban national whose itinerary documents an intent to conduct activities, including phytosanitary inspections, related to purchasing United States agricultural goods under the provisions of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7201">22 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.</external-xref>), a consular officer (as defined in section 101(a)(9) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(9)</external-xref>)) may issue a nonimmigrant visa under section 101(a)(15)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(B)</external-xref>) to the national, if the national is not inadmissible to the United States under section 212 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C3EAC5A1935432682CD07BC3E6C0C95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H7AAA763444E34E68BC50B9E8C611E64C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 3 months thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the issuance of visas described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1914BBF9C4341F993C3FFC7708C3389"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report shall contain a full description of each application received from a Cuban national to travel to the United States to engage in purchasing activities pursuant to the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7201">22 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.</external-xref>) and shall describe the disposition of each such application.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5FF2C6F562A44A5AA53704AC95F312C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H8F0B45BFC5AB43F8A4C6EFFD5C9D72EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H395CF13254284042987D28AAE5DBE214"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC7DA0CFC07B4454CA39B096ED3516E02"><enum>6.</enum><header>Adherence to international agreements for the mutual protection of intellectual property</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6384D67FEB414071987204D1AF539667"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of Prohibition on Transactions or Payments With Respect to Certain United States Intellectual Property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 211 of the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (section 101(b) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/277">Public Law 105–277</external-xref>; 112 Stat. 2681–88), is repealed.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD344FC7D85194DC7A00E362DB901E51C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out the repeal made by subsection (a), including removing any prohibition on transactions or payments to which subsection (a)(1) of section 211 of the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (as such section was in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act), applied.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H09D7F16BDB654620954CA3279707EAD4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Further regulations</header> <paragraph id="HA359D99E9C56447C93D2342073B43791"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall amend part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (the Cuban assets control regulations), to authorize under general license the transfer or receipt of any trademark or trade name subject to United States law in which a designated national has an interest.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H977A4AF6FC6641CB964B172C80B6152A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designated national defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>designated national</term> has the meaning given the term in subsection (d)(1) of section 211 of the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (as such section was in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5B53E26DFD04183A3773A3B8565D58E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Travel to Cuba</header> <subsection id="HAC106DF7304E4ED89F4804264EE3F5B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Freedom of travel for United States citizens and legal residents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (c), travel to and from Cuba by individuals who are citizens or residents of the United States, and any transactions incident to such travel as specified in subsection (b), may not be regulated or prohibited if such travel would be lawful in the United States. The President shall rescind all regulations in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act that so regulate or prohibit such travel or transactions.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD890D9D7F7DE4508B9886347BD2AC485"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transactions incident to travel</header><text>The transactions referred to in subsection (a) include, but are not limited to—</text> <paragraph id="H107132984BAD497D8157BC6BC803622C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any transactions ordinarily incident to travel to or from Cuba, including the importation into Cuba or the United States of accompanied baggage for personal use only;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5F2344DFEC9F4330A988F2B36D0E809D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any transactions ordinarily incident to travel or maintenance within Cuba, including the payment of living expenses and the acquisition of goods or services for personal use;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78073B29400649D0B42FE6FFD1FBE782"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any transactions ordinarily incident to the arrangement, promotion, or facilitation of travel to, from, or within Cuba;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3EC8292F08D499E981D3DD200735D5D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any transactions incident to nonscheduled air, sea, or land voyages, except that this paragraph does not authorize the carriage of articles into Cuba or the United States except accompanied baggage; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F0E6A6564DC4981B832371769AFDE08"><enum>(5)</enum><text>normal banking transactions incident to the activities described in the preceding provisions of this subsection, including the issuance, clearing, processing, or payment of checks, drafts, travelers checks, credit or debit card instruments, or similar instruments.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCFBEE375C8B948AC84EDE3DC75E5C191"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The restrictions on authority contained in subsection (a) do not apply in a case in which the United States is at war with Cuba, armed hostilities between the two countries are in progress, or there is imminent danger to the public health or the physical safety of United States citizens or legal residents.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2E3498CF604F48AEB3D39BB6186308D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section applies to actions taken by the President before the date of the enactment of this Act which are in effect on such date of enactment, and to actions taken on or after such date of enactment.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H349D3DBE4AF74C729593D4055B5DE03F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inapplicability of other provisions</header><text>This section applies notwithstanding section 102(h) of the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6032">22 U.S.C. 6032(h)</external-xref>) and section 910(b) of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7209">22 U.S.C. 7209(b)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="H9944974BB0584219A01ACA69932E1122"><enum>8.</enum><header>Export of medicines and medical devices to Cuba</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HC3FC4E0F6D1449B6A461DD0936092DD2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of requirement for onsite verifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1705 of the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6004">22 U.S.C. 6004</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (d).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4071195DDF1B4EE787B338656C9B0E3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in the amendment made by subsection (a) shall be construed to restrict the authority of the President to—</text> <paragraph id="H348CD88E0C614BA990BFDD82E3F32189"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impose export controls with respect to the export of medicines or medical devices under sections 5 or 6 of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA252D1FEDF65484B84D73BC12D3365B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>exercise the authorities the President has under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act with respect to Cuba pursuant to a declaration of national emergency required by that Act that is made on account of an unusual and extraordinary threat, that did not exist before the date of the enactment of this Act, to the national security, foreign policy, or economy of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HDA950F2469754B4A8CB08247034C0161"><enum>9.</enum><header>Increase in airport ticket tax for transportation between United States and Cuba; establishment of agricultural export promotion trust fund</header> <subsection id="HE8890B787315465FAF99189F8E8B6548"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase in ticket tax</header><text>Subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4261">section 4261</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to use of international travel facilities) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56A6337B1C414FC38FA25BECFA9F517B" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HC77CFCE9FDF3413C96CEDAE1AF4E3090"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rule for cuba</header><text>In any case in which the tax imposed by paragraph (1) applies to transportation beginning or ending in Cuba before January 1, 2017, such tax shall be increased by $1.00.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H53BD8FC668894697AB8B0DE70583D5BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agricultural export promotion trust fund</header> <paragraph id="H3A55DD8925404CB08BED311D7EB657BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to establishment of trust funds) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEDE59674C6C46E3A4B7A91282F8A211" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7143D0848771431F8E72EBEBD9006ED8"><enum>9512.</enum><header>Agricultural export promotion trust fund</header> 
<subsection id="H4C600042933443A6B0442955B60FDE79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of trust fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <term>Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund</term>, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to such fund as provided in this section or section 9602(b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCFF26851A981437D965FFADB95982F76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to trust fund</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to the Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the taxes received in the Treasury by reason of section 4261(c)(4).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1345305D09284B9BA360C719B63E5D1D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund shall be available, as provided by appropriation Acts, for making expenditures to the Office of the Secretary of Agriculture for the purposes set out in section 4 of the Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2015.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59CFE1FA7CC5434F83463B0372C73965"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Subparagraph (c) of section 9502(b)(1) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(other than by reason of subsection (c)(4) thereof)</quote> after <quote>sections 4261</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D78A466D0CE4D81A4865B5AC4D8B8E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter A of chapter 98 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H019E3D8DF406484184FFA1AC98816E6C" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry idref="H7143D0848771431F8E72EBEBD9006ED8" level="section">Sec. 9512. Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H390DC71CE8EF4A0F957AE8902E4611D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to transportation beginning after the 90-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, except that such amendment shall not apply to amounts paid before the end of such period.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

