<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD9DC6B2922F34F31B684D336454C3996" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1490 IH: SOS Campus Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1490</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150319">March 19, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to have an independent advocate for campus sexual assault prevention and response.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H31F15F9772584FA6AD933D03B7C4CCED" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H281E42750C3040EB9410BB626DE2673A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Survivor Outreach and Support Campus Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SOS Campus Act</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H679820D8C5A640C8BF8C8152631652DA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Independent advocate for campus sexual assault prevention and response</header> <subsection id="HF17041BD1A554E538034EC806397C556"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part G of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 485E the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H011AA4FB1B37459C87C34680B178DD55" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD07988A1CF00499EBDEEC9DCB9AB48BF"><enum>485F.</enum><header>Independent advocate for campus sexual assault prevention and response</header> 
<subsection id="H481C69A4E4B74B05A1FC6C6FAB86B33B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible institution participating in any program under this title shall designate an independent advocate for campus sexual assault prevention and response (in this section referred to as the <quote>Advocate</quote>) who shall be appointed based on certifications, experience, and a demonstrated ability of the individual to effectively provide sexual assault victim services.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H60722DC2BE464C49BCD8E531B7134C2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification of existence of and information for the advocate</header><text>Each employee of an eligible institution who receives a report of sexual assault shall notify the victim of the existence of, contact information for, and services provided by the Advocate of the institution.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H19C2390F6DE841AB81B6995575F22A4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advocate oversight</header><text>Each Advocate shall—</text> <paragraph id="HDCC84BD70F2A4BBD9D403C5614186050"><enum>(1)</enum><text>report to an individual outside the body responsible for investigating and adjudicating sexual assault complaints at the institution;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8A6438E0C1A4A2797B7F0BD2591F7B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to such individual an annual report summarizing how the resources supplied to the Advocate were used, including the number of male and female sexual assault victims assisted; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5B132F7B43E416E897CC1B92AC55494"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be appointed in such manner as the Secretary determines is appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9067576286B94DDABE662AFB2911B1F8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Role</header> 
<paragraph id="H0F2878FE12154F5D8A279B0ECD4FEED4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the responsibilities described in this section, the Advocate shall represent the interests of the student victim without regard to whether such interests are in conflict with the interests of the institution designating such Advocate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDD741556C7F49138A54793330069156"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on retaliation</header><text>No institution of higher education designating an Advocate in accordance with this section may discipline, penalize, or otherwise retaliate against such Advocate for representing the interests of a student victim, without regard to whether such interests are in conflict with the interests of such institution.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H134BB1B340FD4F979B3C6914361B8733"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header> 
<paragraph id="H0FA14F720E9542ED8EA9BAC4AA5C8E28" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Services available at all times</header><text>Each Advocate shall ensure that victims of sexual assault at the institution are able to receive, at the election of the victim and at any time of day, each day of the week—</text> <subparagraph id="H83D08A52257E4AABBD887EBB9F9B555C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on how to report a campus sexual assault to law enforcement;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C4E0B2EB6894AE1A0DD500676489C31" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emergency medical care, including follow up medical care as requested; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H853D8BF8F9124440A78509FB06DC19CC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>medical forensic or evidentiary examinations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38D7E22331D94C68A5744916802E1571" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other services</header><text>Each Advocate shall ensure that victims of sexual assault at the institution are able to receive, at the election of the victim—</text> <subparagraph id="H42BDB3E45F38454F900123B20B42E813"><enum>(A)</enum><text>crisis intervention counseling and ongoing counseling;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D82B6D4EE2045D48F2ED27B64CA1E68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on the victim’s rights and referrals to additional support services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD65E8A5177B6445799164D7ED1349613"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on legal services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF0084CFB07D47568FF949083BC1FA77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Each Advocate shall guide victims of sexual assault who request assistance through the reporting, counseling, administrative, medical and health, academic accommodations, or legal processes of the institution designating such Advocate or local law enforcement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13050505D17B45D084A2D1AC72E75BC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attendance at adjudications</header><text>At the request of the victim of sexual assault, each Advocate shall attend any administrative or institution-based adjudication proceeding related to such assault as an advocate for the victim.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF493706570C2481390F8E343A716DFAF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Privacy and confidentiality</header><text>Each Advocate shall maintain the privacy and confidentiality of the victim of, and any witness to, such sexual assault and shall not notify the institution designating such Advocate or any other person of the identity of the victim or any such witness or the alleged circumstances surrounding the reported sexual assault except—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E388FF38444474C894AFA38868B1703"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as otherwise required by the applicable laws in the State where such institution is located;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3A7F5C4FE4AD4C8295C1B644C87FB90C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the identity of the victim, with the consent of the victim; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCC2A8F11C2249898E9047256DFBF1B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to the identity of such witness, with the consent of such witness.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAEA5969FB114E49B3A85E39B3AC3CBA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public information campaign</header><text>Each Advocate shall conduct a public information campaign to inform the students enrolled at the institution designating such Advocate of the existence of, contact information for, and services provided by the Advocate, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HD394AF317F0048E9B31CF0619A294284"><enum>(A)</enum><text>posting information—</text> 
<clause id="H55CA2F5CFFF6458D9D6AB7D340CD9592"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on the website of such institution;</text></clause> <clause id="H48F4219997C84BDAA5FBBE9DE2AC1632"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in student orientation materials; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCD408DE554B44B928E0B638543E7EE14"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on posters displayed in dormitories, cafeterias, sports arenas, locker rooms, entertainment facilities, and classrooms; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09A3E7A9206B471AA136467527B3E67D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training coaches, faculty, school administrators, resident advisors, and other staff to provide information on the existence of, contact information for, and services provided by the Advocate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C51EAE7297341BD9A6679EA284DAEE2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Availability of services</header><text>The services described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (e) shall be provided—</text> <paragraph id="H403634FED4FD4B42A8A0DEFD6EABB797"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pursuant to a memorandum of understanding (that includes transportation services), at a rape crisis center, legal organization, or other community-based organization located within a reasonable distance from an institution; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1878DCB1B041431CB387F7CD2FB8A9DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on the campus of an institution in consultation with a rape crisis center, legal organization, or other community-based organization.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H17179BE191D4468C9CD9786CCA2B9981" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibition on retaliation towards victims</header><text>A victim of sexual assault may not be disciplined, penalized, or otherwise retaliated against for reporting such assault to the Advocate.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H13F7CA6855854F228266F451A793276B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No effect on Clery Act and title IX</header><text>Nothing in this section shall alter or amend the rights, duties, and responsibilities under section 485(f) or title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) (also known as the Patsy Takemoto Mink Equal Opportunity in Education Act).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8221099F05DA4A1CAA0E3C47E0EFA651"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sexual assault defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>sexual assault</term> means penetration, no matter how slight, of the vagina or anus with any body part or object, or oral penetration by a sex organ of another person, without the consent of the victim, including when the victim is incapable of giving consent.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBBA17855C35F4E638605F696043ADA43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall issue regulations to carry out section 485F of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

