<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA17355A2A14040D6AD93AE5AE107E347" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4042 IH: Pre-K for USA Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4042</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151117">November 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide grants for high-quality prekindergarten programs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H10529C7E21F54FCBA81E4377A98E8B52" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5AFEAEC5A8E8471283ADCF2E6B10F2F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pre-K for USA Act.</short-title></quote></text> </section><section id="HCA9BBE6DA6124E2C9E1BD6C7B2936B4D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC7B74120BADE443BAAE4F39295FDD78C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States ranks 25th in early learning enrollment with fewer than 3 out of 10 four-year-olds enrolled in high-quality prekindergarten programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC536ECCCE78D463B9692B56AB2DBB0C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Studies show that children with access to high-quality prekindergarten programs are less likely to repeat a grade or drop out of high school, and more likely to succeed in their careers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE991C2DC376C44A19169EFDDDFAFF32A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Every public dollar spent on high-quality prekindergarten programs returns $7 through a reduced need for spending on other services such as remedial education, grade repetition, and special education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H715C430195544B4690BA7DE94119864E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Children who attended prekindergarten are less likely to develop drug problems, commit a felony, and go to prison, and are half as likely to be arrested.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H097A369C50BF41FEB9B8B14BFD26FADB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Children who attended prekindergarten usually have higher grade point averages and are more likely to attend a four-year college.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H879143957FE24ECB9CF9FE320FFB97D7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>About 40 percent of school districts do not offer prekindergarten programs.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HACE6E612B4904932A26EDEAF2C8F6D3F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Over half of school districts that have pre-kindergarten programs offer only part-day programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE36057335F145B1AE76A2B3941B05CF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Texas missed out on up to $118.48 million in Federal funding to expand prekindergarten programs.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7944ED4F3DFD4ED4BC93CF6F0E8BDABE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Reports showed that in 2011 the Texas legislature cut approximately $5.4 billion in education funding and eliminated the $200 million in grants it offered to schools to expand prekindergarten programs from half-day to full-day.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEE8A1467F65424C948B2C0F7B335F61"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In response to the State of Texas’ education funding cuts, certain local governments took it upon themselves to fund full-day prekindergarten programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED7552341A1E4C44A4CF9D3E91976C7D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>For these reasons, certain localities, including local governments and local educational agencies would benefit from direct application prekindergarten Federal program funding.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H112480D63075450796BC65BCD76FB582"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prekindergarten development grants</header>
 <subsection id="H08018F20AC06404B93E52B70CBCDA6E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall award competitive grants to States, local educational agencies, or other local government entities that wish to increase their capacity and build the infrastructure within the State to offer high-quality prekindergarten programs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC5FBFD92EAC948FC99387FA7D3D964B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant duration</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under this Act for a period of not more than 3 years. Such grants shall not be renewed.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H00C4AFB8087E489EB5033CBFB8975B29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="HB43B0F72F9B64772A0003FC874146604"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Governor, or chief executive officer of a State, a local educational agency, or another local government entity that desires to receive a grant under this Act shall submit an application to the Secretary of Education at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5685984B391418ABFDE9B2186D01FB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of state application</header><text>In developing an application for a grant under this Act, a State shall consult with the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care and incorporate their recommendations, where applicable.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE33B7182A05449682D0B2E6EC158F7F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header>
 <paragraph id="HD16F6B4DC0804692AA461249E0F32CFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this Act, a State, local educational agency, or other local government entity shall contribute for the activities for which the grant was awarded non-Federal matching funds in an amount equal to not less than 20 percent of the amount of the grant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2267A4CEE8E4456D92A5990A3E8C0F68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal funds</header><text>To satisfy the requirement of paragraph (1), a State, local educational agency, or other local government entity may use—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H003E9489C30D4844A51532902C1D9B85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>non-Federal resources in the form of State funding, local funding, or contributions from philanthropy or other private sources, or a combination of such resources; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65973047D4C74DC490B2EDCAD88F9E01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in-kind contributions.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B3254433AA74F69ABE5AC458FEE13F8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial hardship waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive paragraph (1) or reduce the amount of matching funds required under that paragraph for a State, local educational agency, or other local government entity that has submitted an application for a grant under this subsection if the State, local educational agency, or other local government entity demonstrates, in the application, a need for such a waiver or reduction due to extreme financial hardship, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE94E8CF4CCC49E1BE5DDAA354184695"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subgrants</header>
 <paragraph id="HC159C9165B844B7899ECC061F9E7B0D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State, local educational agency, or other local government entity awarded a grant under this subtitle may use the grant funds to award subgrants to eligible local entities, to carry out the activities under the grant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA30BEEBEDD3840C9A2B2BA8B5DC5A61B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subgrantees</header><text>An eligible local entity awarded a subgrant under paragraph (1) shall comply with the requirements of this Act relating to grantees, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70952D1BB3E54879B1CE4D18ABC68A09"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Double-Dipping prevention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not award a subgrant to a local educational agency or other local government entity under subsection (e) for a program in a fiscal year if the State, agency, or entity received funding for the program in such fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H825DDA845EE942DAB2C528754C645677"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text> <paragraph id="H8CA080D444494B21A4B80A436B94D902"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$750,000,000 for fiscal year 2016; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2E4109A68464B618F2F53CCA7A45413"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2025.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H31DEA32C6D1447E7A8BE95E28DDBF7CC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6BB6516411DC4993B7E7A4B5E5B6CF89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible local entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible local entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H317EB87A5A78456B82BE328CF82B38F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local educational agency, including a charter school or a charter management organization that acts as a local educational agency, or an educational service agency in partnership with a local educational agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49901B77EAEF4CB3803C705FD14E7FB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity (including a Head Start program or licensed child care setting) that carries out, administers, or supports an early childhood education program; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEB93F096A6C4F70AD549DEF3E4876EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described under subparagraph (A) or (B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA95D45E7D25844D0BEAEE8A36FF03514"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Full-day</header><text>The term <term>full-day</term> means a day that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDD6033C2FBF84772B4F685D1E9E3CFE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>equivalent to a full school day at the public elementary schools in the State; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3456D7FE33E4DAFBB18D5AFF900A4F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 5 hours.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EDD109B84754CE0A09CE0E42A0C8159"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High-quality prekindergarten program</header><text>The term <term>high-quality prekindergarten program</term> means a prekindergarten program supported by an eligible local entity that includes, at a minimum, the following elements based on nationally recognized standards:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7DC4004A9E0E4A14BF49683AE6C00A93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Serves children who—</text> <clause id="HB9BB70FD14174E0A8BF6176F9F17C36F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are age 4 or children who are age 3 or 4, by the eligibility determination date (including children who turn age 5 while attending the program); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3F6F856E0EEB4AE4824547072FBB9D7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have attained the legal age for State-funded prekindergarten.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8ACC5C332554278B1A62B1ABEF81C8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Requires high staff qualifications, including that teachers meet the requirements of 1 of the following clauses:</text>
 <clause id="HA0C350B12CBE4BC8A0C912B041282CE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The teacher has a bachelor’s degree in early childhood education or a related field with coursework that demonstrates competence in early childhood education;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5C8879B4C4594474A3761531F172E41C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The teacher—</text> <subclause id="H0C6AA8C454054A1295B8160E3AD03E8C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has a bachelor’s degree in any field;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC931B4641AA4454AAD5DEB4BAEF6C8A0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has demonstrated knowledge of early childhood education through passage of a State-approved assessment in early childhood education;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HABA1899D306F457C99F5068B55210E93"><enum>(III)</enum><text>engages in ongoing professional development in early childhood education for not less than 2 years; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H36FAC7EC7643439E8D3CF8CFC6B50645"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>is enrolled in a State-approved educator preparation program in which the teacher receives ongoing training and support in early childhood education and is making progress toward the completion of the program in not more than 3 years; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H8BDDEC571DCC41618529F3C9B04C7E5F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The teacher has a bachelor’s degree in any field with a credential, license, or endorsement that demonstrates competence in early childhood education.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7411D1B33064EB0B4071DAD7D53BF2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Maintains a maximum class size of 20 children.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB241563F3FD643B39A8B7AF12F71CCC4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Maintains a child to instructional staff ratio that does not exceed 10 to 1.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E22597AB78C4681A072A6330457B5C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Offers a full-day program.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5901A079A8E48078DD32D7CE13B5153"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Provides developmentally appropriate learning environments and evidence-based curricula that are aligned with the State’s early learning and development standards.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H189A93CAFF5243799893453B370B89E3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Offers instructional staff salaries comparable to kindergarten through grade 12 teaching staff.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BB0E56D8BB04D7AA2E63DC676D3C60E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Provides for ongoing monitoring and program evaluation to ensure continuous improvement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB1083CB62F24DAC8512CF2215228D99"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Offers accessible comprehensive services for children that—</text> <clause id="HC10796DBFE6E46F8AA9D20F462D1E0F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include, at a minimum—</text>
 <subclause id="H32D1C0219EB54C048978B25987817569"><enum>(I)</enum><text>screenings for vision, dental, health (including mental health), and development and referrals, and assistance obtaining services, when appropriate;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF272A63D19D1421F8055316A3653187E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>family engagement opportunities (taking into account home language), such as parent conferences (including parent input about their child’s development) and support services, such as parent education and family literacy services;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HADE2B813D477427D825DFC6A9B2FA1D5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>nutrition services, including nutritious meals and snack options aligned with requirements set by the most recent Child and Adult Care Food Program guidelines promulgated by the Department of Agriculture as well as regular, age-appropriate, nutrition education for children and their families;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H24D29992FCC44554A663A70868F3942B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>programs coordinated with local educational agencies and entities providing programs authorized under section 619 and part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (20 U.S.C. 1419 and 1431 et seq.);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H170653482BD24CFE8F75B15FFEF5D1D1"><enum>(V)</enum><text>physical activity programs aligned with evidence-based guidelines, such as those recommended by the Institute of Medicine, and that take into account and accommodate children with disabilities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H225641F7167649B9BD2FC8ADAE8C786D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>additional support services, as appropriate, based on the findings of a needs analysis; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H8A03DD21B0384F5B8ADB61F67FDC6621"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are provided on-site, to the maximum extent feasible.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA949DE1744FA4CC89FB4FAC43D952FBB"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Provides high-quality professional development for staff, including regular in-class observation for teachers and teacher assistants by individuals trained in observation and which may include evidence-based coaching.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA3737B06BD144FD8F0A529930ECDE79"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Meets the education performance standards in effect under section 641A(a)(1)(B) of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9836a">42 U.S.C. 9836a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42C84CAA8EAC4C0987CCCA7C5F61AF26"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Maintains evidence-based health and safety standards.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26E51071B9164FDCA5F6F4DBF522BA1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>State</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42C18ABE4B6D48B5BDCEBA0E35368E54"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

