<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H64EB81D4648645F0A33E4D2FB1C8FA7E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 908 IH: California Coastal National Monument Santa Cruz Redwoods Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 908</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To include the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands in the California Coastal National Monument as a part of the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCEDF60183BC345A3851A837D75CCC0F3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H242FA22DDB7E4021BC2C02AD0025215A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; definitions</header> 
<subsection id="H722921D8B02E414180026AF00D2ACA3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>California Coastal National Monument Santa Cruz Redwoods Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H45F734C88B4843B4AFC620B4F4FF3EFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0B51D333161F43DEBB51F3B89FEB8F6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>map</term> means the map created by the Bureau of Land Management, entitled <quote>Santa Cruz Redwoods California Coastal National Monument Addition</quote> and dated February 3, 2015.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DE5FC7607F24A538804C2B44F9250C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monument</header><text>The term <term>Monument</term> means the California Coastal National Monument established by Presidential Proclamation 7264.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86CC5DFCB90D49E1834FECCABF541467"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands</header><text>The term <term>Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands</term> means the Federal land comprising approximately 5,800 acres in Santa Cruz County, California, as generally depicted on the map.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE287A026F2634E5FBF12C9DD701B6BC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Presidential proclamation 7264</header><text>The term <term>Presidential Proclamation 7264</term> means Presidential Proclamation Number 7264, dated January 11, 2000 (65 Fed. Reg. 2821).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FD35AF256EB44849A90F0326A26B46C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HFE952798CACC41A3886B358F8116E5AD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection id="H25B02D5C93B947EBADBED5882EBBD3DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2DD8E931717B4270A34029B166A1D6B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands contain significant and diverse natural landscapes including six watersheds, redwood and riparian forests, freshwater wetlands, and rolling coastal terrace grasslands in the Santa Cruz Mountains that should be preserved for present and future generations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16E5E56FF46F44FF9FF735312ED3E9EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands are habitat for numerous wildlife populations including endangered and rare species such as the California red-legged frog, the American peregrine falcon, coho salmon, and steelhead trout;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6800B51814934A3088857128BF560649"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the ocean and coastal ecosystems adjacent to and visible from the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands are within the California Coastal Monument, and contain habitat for endangered and unique marine species including gray whales, sea otters, and harbor seals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34A8BD0C25664B1BA3A8838666C5A43A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands contain threatened vegetation communities such as purple needlegrass and riparian red alder forest;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEACA0DE0698A4DD2BFE60BB2691C5136"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands and surrounding coastal lands have been used by humans since prehistoric times and were historically inhabited by the native Ohlone people;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FA6DAF5515D40E0B1426974649BECA9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands are historically associated with adjacent lands managed for the enjoyment of current and future generations, including Coast Dairies State Park and Wilder Ranch State Park;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAB7C570B075468D92780229DEFBF0C9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands represent a model partnership where future management can be successfully accomplished among the Federal Government, State of California, Santa Cruz County, local communities, and private landowners;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97F9F8359D8F4B7186BE3861C48FF5B4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>permanent protection of the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands will provide important economic benefits to surrounding communities, and has broad public support in the community;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H181B9A3D04964E6EB023145D39EDB288"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands will make a significant addition to the California Coastal National Monument and National Landscape Conservation System administered by the Bureau of Land Management of the Department of the Interior; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B962B10482F47F4BC463A571B05908B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>statutory protection would ensure that the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands remain a part of the historical, cultural, and natural heritage of the United States and a source of inspiration for the people of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1692463E4BB44F25801253E5F04BADEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to protect, conserve, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the unique and nationally important historical, natural, cultural, scientific, educational, and scenic values of the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands, while allowing certain recreational and research activities to continue.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H02FDA97F722B4C89AA8EB18128EDFF8D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion of California coastal national monument</header> <subsection id="HB217500A9FBB4D5EA7D34AF724ADDC23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The boundary of the Monument established by Presidential Proclamation 7264 is expanded to include the Federal land shown on the map.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6206895BA5B45318AE315F14C0D7B22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header> 
<paragraph id="H10E9C0F333484A7B889133269343F29C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall create a map and boundary description of the land added to the Monument by this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B39C4D3C3314B54AF11E5DFA89AB59F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text>The map and boundary description described under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any minor errors in the map and boundary descriptions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC16D317AAE0B4DBE981E84C18F707B54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of map and boundary description</header><text>The map and boundary description described under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H36601DB3D4E543DD8AF266FA8FB32113"><enum>4.</enum><header>Administration</header> <subsection id="H68FB217BA97D4C8990F95803B2AB2D61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall manage the land added to the Monument by this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE96380DF897C40379741AF8F7C17EE0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as a part of the Monument;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD02E7CE75B44497EABDAEDEC6FDFA103"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by allowing only such uses of the Monument as will further the purposes for which the Monument is established; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BBBB05A199949BC9942146BB1AB3B6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in accordance with Presidential Proclamation 7264.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2E39E48EA4E54083BC30532035F9D85B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management plan</header> <paragraph id="HF65E6F643D6347BCBA75F7FDD3A028F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize an amendment to the Monument management plan for the long-term protection and management of the land added to the Monument by this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE73D7C7BD58B4BA0B4A2A9078DBD7ED0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The plan amendment shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4EF296A6D644E04B8C1226424156416"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be developed with an opportunity for full public participation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8599394D86C5462985B780CA10C69F62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the appropriate uses and management of the land consistent with this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9C2AB56D533B40E9BA6432C0E744C4CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Motorized and mechanized transport</header><text>Except as needed for emergency or authorized administrative purposes, the use of motorized and mechanized vehicles in the Monument shall be permitted only on roads and trails designated for their use.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0ADEC42157A5440AB76C045FD4810073"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Incorporation of land and interests</header> 
<paragraph id="H79CA8DF7FBDD4BA2BEE315A0BE472483"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary may acquire non-Federal land or interests in land within or adjacent to the land added to the Monument by this Act only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1CE22C33DBE4F0CB2DB8F1CB3EFEE35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Any land or interests in land within or adjacent to the land added to the Monument by this Act acquired by the United States after the date of enactment of this Act shall be added to and administered as part of the Monument.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H11712877ABFF4B4BBBC24C336EF47208"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Overflights</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H2D8AF56CE7894BF08412112E4116BEE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>restricts or precludes overflights, including low-level overflights or military, commercial, and general aviation overflights that can be seen or heard within the land added to the Monument by this Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53AEAE3ECA124E5DBA06C79AED6D0D4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>restricts or precludes the designation or creation of new units of special use airspace or the establishment of military flight training routes over the land added to the Monument by this Act; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9763D69495624EB482E3ED491430FCED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modifies regulations governing low-level overflights above the adjacent Monterey Bay National Marine Sanctuary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H736589DB4CA74D199C51A9BAC40133F9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act affects the ongoing restoration and reclamation being performed pursuant to the December 2, 1968 lease between the Coast Dairies and Land Company and the Lone Star Cement Corporation, or under a renegotiation or renewal of that lease, as long as such restoration and reclamation furthers the purpose of the Monument described in section 2(b) and is performed in accordance with—</text> <paragraph id="HD6D93A43CF3A4267B4B8D1EF94E1CC4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45F7BEC45C714557BE0FF68599A55BB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA7DC4A6A55594E9BA367CD3487FF7A18"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Native American uses</header><text>Nothing in this Act enlarges, diminishes, or modifies the rights of any Indian Tribe or Indian religious community.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB090485381FB4B09919C47152EBA193D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header> 
<paragraph id="H28C7A171B6C94D8AB53715B85A2F04CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The expansion of the Monument is not intended to lead to the establishment of protective perimeters or buffer zones around the land included in the Monument by this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B95346BDCCA47CE9BC7B6448D3B193A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities outside the monument</header><text>The fact that activities outside the Monument can be seen or heard within the land added to the Monument by this Act shall not, of itself, preclude those activities or uses up to the boundary of the Monument.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCCD6A273726A4EA69AFFBB470E5DD4C5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the grazing of livestock within the Santa Cruz Redwoods Public Lands.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9D46F53C6CF147D49C841A13FF4C8B4D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the Santa Cruz Redwoods expansion to the Monument is withdrawn from—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC915DA06ED954DE0839232089C3DFC33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDC12FF9FE3349A59F063616E68AA1CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44B4459EEEAE4C5897FC818E0CCE1E00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>leasing or disposition under all laws relating to—</text> <subparagraph id="HD075871D02F84D5E8155A7A86BA78C51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>minerals; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABD35ABDA379447E817F2E15AB74D542"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H260692D03637487FA2B53EBCC100F667"><enum>(k)</enum><header>National landscape conservation system</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Monument as part of the National Landscape Conservation System.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

