<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H48EB3AB47E0242DC9D3856AB319A1712" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 955 IH: To authorize assistance and sustainment to the military and national security forces of Ukraine.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 955</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000238">Mr. Thornberry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000363">Mr. Kline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize assistance and sustainment to the military and national security forces of Ukraine.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H46B95DE4DC524605B496E598C84E0A5A" style="OLC">
		<section id="H949EA5D9BDDD47A581CDA50179D58947" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Assistance and sustainment to the military and national security forces of Ukraine</header>
 <subsection id="H50F46FA9309A4C98AE1255E7F69E7424"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense is authorized, in coordination with the Secretary of State, to provide assistance, including training, equipment, lethal weapons of a defensive nature, logistics support, supplies and services, and sustainment to the military and national security forces of Ukraine, through September 30, 2017, to assist the government of Ukraine for the following purposes:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6396A9240217485D8F91E0F18D96F215"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Securing its sovereign territory against foreign aggressors.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H091BFC7E7D26482F8DAAC5B30B29AC5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Protecting and defending the Ukrainian people from attacks posed by Russian-backed separatists.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20A95EB6E38A4EAEB15F49C80D32C826"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Promoting the conditions for a negotiated settlement to end the conflict.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H117D4BB0722B489EB1EDEC3538728857"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice before provision of assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated under this Act, not more than 10 percent of such funds may be obligated or expended until not later than 15 days after the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report in unclassified form with a classified annex as appropriate that contains a description of the plan for providing such assistance, including a description of the types of training and equipment to be provided, the estimated number and role of United States Armed Forces personnel involved, the potential or actual locations of any training, and any other relevant details.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAB307DF979AA430EAD28BA6C089746E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Quarterly reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 105 days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits the report required in subsection (b), and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the activities carried out under this Act. Such report shall include a description of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H176B1A2558D84D6EA82DC52836C8B3E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Updates or changes to the plan required under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9503615F46F4103A08F785B61C068A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the forces provided with training, equipment, or other assistance under this Act during the preceding 90-day period.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E00767EB6E64EDBB95EB174893A0AA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the equipment provided under this Act during the preceding 90-day period, including a detailed breakout of any lethal assistance provided.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D4D0BF1DD2748148B7E345C9E82EE70"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A statement of the amount of funds expended during the preceding 90-day period.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB8F10D4D4B54DED952169C50AA266E7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Vetting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall ensure that all assistance provided under this Act is carried out in full accordance with the provisions of section 2249e of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D9DBC375244470C872E6490F601DEA1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HC6D40A2BA72F4833B8F724C440DA3CA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25F894AEAA334D0193CCE30C0867E290"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAA236CC5FC046FB967BE675AD3499EF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out the provisions of this Act, there are authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000,000. Amounts authorized to be appropriated under this subsection are authorized to remain available until September 30, 2017.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6DAA6BB25FFA452BB263D298E0A65982"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authority To accept contributions</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may accept and retain contributions, including in-kind contributions, from foreign governments, to provide assistance authorized under subsection (a). Any funds so accepted by the Secretary may be credited to the account from which funds are made available to provide assistance authorized under subsection (a) and may remain available to provide assistance authorized under subsection (a) until September 30, 2017.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H95A23B38E0F9471A9C2A10C46F3C99FA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to constitute a specific statutory authorization for the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities or into situations in which hostilities are clearly indicated by the circumstances.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


