<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E28DCAEF6664358B95DACDD95B90C88" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 913 IH: Genetically Engineered Food Right-to-Know Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 913</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require that genetically engineered food and foods that contain genetically engineered ingredients be labeled accordingly.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0B8DFA5909944C108C7E88B69C04605C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H614676D65BD84BEAB280B43F1C19D803" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Genetically Engineered Food Right-to-Know Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6FC5A94065B4462EA20898E929D84D6F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose and findings</header> <subsection id="H9916EE82A2AA4C538615F1A3C5D11780"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purposes of this Act are to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0E7B315CF75242C4809251436A78403B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a consistent and enforceable standard for labeling of foods produced using genetic engineering, thereby providing consumers with knowledge of how their food is produced; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF274394519F74B69A5726AF3C7424D3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent consumer confusion and deception by prohibiting the labeling of products produced from genetic engineering as <quote>natural</quote>, and by promoting the disclosure of factual information on food labels to allow consumers to make informed decisions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB53C29469AF54BE6BF7DC0664679748C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H3633CF6E72A941068673FBFADE2474E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the process of genetically engineering food organisms results in material changes and the fact that foods are genetically engineered is of material importance to consumers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4575675D5A9D4A2CBE3B33173EF8C1F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Food and Drug Administration requires the labeling of more than 3,000 ingredients, additives, and processes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DB9C631EE524EFC9F81C637A2FBD53C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>individuals in the United States have a right to know if their food was produced with genetic engineering for a variety of reasons, including health, economic, environmental, religious, and ethical;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H185A75FAACF24090AC72DF86FF26947C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>more than 60 countries, including the United Kingdom and all other countries of the European Union, South Korea, Japan, Brazil, Australia, India, China, and other key United States trading partners have laws or regulations mandating disclosure of genetically engineered food on food labels;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFD696E0F0C442C29C8723D7739626B2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in 2011, Codex Alimentarius, the food standards organization of the United Nations, adopted a text that indicates that governments can decide on whether and how to label foods produced with genetic engineering;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6589B9496AA40EC8843673CEE20378A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>mandatory identification of food produced with genetic engineering can be a critical method of preserving the economic value of exports or domestically sensitive markets with labeling requirements for genetically engineered foods; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBC5BCCE9A314423B156794EE447BD7E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the cultivation of genetically engineered crops can have adverse effects on the environment in the form of cross-pollination of native plants, increased herbicide usage, and impacts on non-target and beneficial organisms, including the Monarch butterfly.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H65DE7C2B805343E6BFF3FD4F6EEB3BFB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</header> 
<subsection id="H6FE6C4D6714F4A49A7FAE31065A71BD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 403 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1383940713E04519A7B9BF673EC237E3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H24B867C2C2E64020B677D34C7C177508"><enum>(z)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF05C9D27D7C94A32AD139840B1F092F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If it is a food that has been genetically engineered or contains 1 or more genetically engineered ingredients, unless the ingredients label clearly states that the food has been genetically engineered or identifies any genetically engineered ingredients, as applicable.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A5BD45DFDAD41ECA6B3960C7D4A4BEE" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This paragraph does not apply to food that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCDD8F80A31344F94A27F85415375FC4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is served in restaurants or other similar eating establishments, such as cafeterias and carryouts;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49FD9CF8752744E3AC286B5D4B7FD092"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a medical food (as defined in section 5(b) of the Orphan Drug Act);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1357577381184F6A829F79966F773802"><enum>(C)</enum><text>would be subject to this paragraph solely because it was produced using a genetically engineered vaccine or drug;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H69B8A58BD703433C985503BB0A21EEB8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is a food or processed food that would be subject to this paragraph solely because it includes the use of a genetically engineered processing aid (including yeast) or enzyme; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE94732A13444A3B8E58E7427F61A0B7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is a packaged food consisting of materials produced through genetic engineering that do not account for more than nine-tenths of 1 percent of the total weight of the packaged food.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAA855495F7A4C51A81390323EF745A8" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this paragraph and in paragraph (aa):</text> <subparagraph id="H1256FB51E5404436827489C24F87C9CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>genetic engineering</term> means a process—</text> 
<clause id="H187054ABF55B4AE588124B49062EEA06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involving the application of in vitro nucleic acid techniques, including recombinant deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) and direct injection of nucleic acid into cells or organelles;</text></clause> <clause id="H642DF86696F442FE8EA344AC530E6ED1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>involving the application of fusion of cells beyond the taxonomic family; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5C6F3FC6D25842C38EC2D016E7C6B690"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that overcomes natural physiological, reproductive, or recombinant barriers and that is not a process used in traditional breeding and selection.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC1F303F40E74B328641C507A8B7CBB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>genetically engineered</term>, used with respect to a food, means a material intended for human consumption that is—</text> 
<clause id="HDB4FDAE03ACC4C9B842F8003F534DAA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an organism that is produced through the intentional use of genetic engineering; or</text></clause> <clause id="H6B9D07F9C6754B55AF03E8FC4077FC4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the progeny of intended sexual or asexual reproduction (or both) of 1 or more organisms that is the product of genetic engineering.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31BCE3C0E450496092096C846BE991A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>genetically engineered ingredient</term> means a material that is an ingredient in a food that is derived from any part of an organism that has been genetically engineered, without regard to whether—</text> <clause id="H5A078CCAB1B147B79522819952CC2B9B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the altered molecular or cellular characteristics of the organism are detectable in the material; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H93AD0B6259064A84BACB646657C8834E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the organism is capable for use as human food.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H459704FE51494F6DA9CB59CFCD6A1D3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restrictions on the term <quote>natural</quote></header><text>Section 403 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14BBF74862D349D885C02C714499AEC6" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HEB40E0EDF7FA4C8E9DEA20D4C5E03372"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>If it is a food intended for human consumption that has been produced using genetic engineering or that contains one or more genetically engineered ingredients and it bears a label, or for which there is signage or advertising, containing a claim that the food is <quote>natural</quote>, <quote>naturally made</quote>, <quote>naturally grown</quote>, <quote>all natural</quote>, or using any similar words that would be misleading to a consumer.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H21619F4E302F453B86801D39250BB312"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guaranty</header> <paragraph id="H6EFD7F039B5A496696FDA1F4FCB9F74B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 303(d) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/333">21 U.S.C. 333(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF71C4CAD524E4E43A5AC5313D1401085"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>(d)(1)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1BD3685809C84C9098010359F6A94215"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF753BDC303E84699ADB7428C23212DAF" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HB33FD6A14A2646289BEED599A73C7594"><enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H45F1412D9A1B457388E33FE129916148"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No person shall be subject to the penalties of subsection (a)(1) for a violation of subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 301 involving food that is misbranded within the meaning of paragraph (z) or (aa) of section 403 if such person (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>recipient</quote>) establishes a guaranty or undertaking that—</text> <clause id="HEC88F0F877BD450899B095A688FB3D30" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is signed by, and contains the name and address of, a person residing in the United States from whom the recipient received in good faith the food (including the receipt of seeds to grow raw agricultural commodities); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2836A2507C7140F4A423C7E8BC5BFFB1" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contains a statement to the effect that the food is not genetically engineered or does not contain a genetically engineered ingredient.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H422F6CA81EE44E79A9DF508C3967E42F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a recipient who, with respect to a food, establishes a guaranty or undertaking in accordance with subparagraph (A), the exclusion under such subparagraph from being subject to penalties applies to the recipient without regard to the manner in which the recipient uses the food, including whether the recipient is—</text> 
<clause id="H7492A11B82854C87994B1EE95D540815"><enum>(i)</enum><text>processing the food;</text></clause> <clause id="H57A45399CF7C4BF69028ED3D3BF399B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>using the food as an ingredient in a food product;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6AA36D8C829540698E6EB7CEEF5C1647"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>repacking the food; or</text></clause> <clause id="H80D9F7A39AD04208B555B8D48ABE9F0B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>growing, raising, or otherwise producing the food.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8462E2F3B374FC5811022D22FB4C2A5" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>No person may avoid responsibility or liability for a violation of subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 301 involving food that is misbranded within the meaning of paragraph (z) or (aa) of section 403 by entering into a contract or other agreement that specifies that another person shall bear such responsibility or liability, except that a recipient may require a guaranty or undertaking as described in this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50A583700C4F4BE7B923239AAFFC2EA2" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For purposes of this Act, food will be considered not to have been produced with the knowing or intentional use of genetic engineering if—</text> 
<clause id="H445570D7176C474F9599A77F1A7B2C06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such food is lawfully certified to be labeled, marketed, and offered for sale as <quote>organic</quote> pursuant to the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990; or</text></clause> <clause id="H93AC05DE5C3A4DBB8F07EB11591728D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an independent organization has determined that the food has not been knowingly or intentionally genetically engineered and has been segregated from, and not knowingly or intentionally commingled with, foods that may have been genetically engineered at any time, if such a determination has been made pursuant to a sampling and testing procedure that—</text> 
<subclause id="H287FE5CEFF6B4184A6DDF82BDF0CEFE0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is consistent with sampling and testing principles recommended by internationally recognized standards organizations; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H129EEEE5AA8F4CCB90525A9CFDA2C24E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not rely on testing processed foods in which no DNA is detectable.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1497094D28D7428990CD41651C99DAC6" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In this subsection, the terms <quote>genetically engineered</quote> and <quote>genetically engineered ingredient</quote> have the meanings given the terms in section 403(z).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3756AECEF8484A77A3F321F5A2BBF51D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>False guaranty</header><text>Section 301(h) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331(h)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or 303(d)(2)</quote> after <quote>section 303(c)(2)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H566C795BD4554C88B4A070DADFD1B360"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unintended contamination</header><text>Section 303(d) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/333">21 U.S.C. 333(d)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H477CED73C96F4971BD4CFB7C0D7871C5" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H7206FC518D134CE697779FDB35324F5A"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC04EF2178CE74B7F9C817A63D8920998"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No person shall be subject to the penalties of subsection (a)(1) for a violation of subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 301 involving food that is misbranded within the meaning of section 403(z) if—</text> 
<clause id="H251C7B9DBB4D49C896AECBC0EF249A4C" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such person is an agricultural producer and the violation occurs because food that is grown, raised, or otherwise produced by such producer, which food does not contain a genetically engineered material and was not produced with a genetically engineered material, is contaminated with a food that contains a genetically engineered material or was produced with a genetically engineered material; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9580BC364F5E49AD959BCACCF49FD17B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such contamination is not intended by the agricultural producer.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42E902CCF2224E208CB246990DEF777F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subparagraph (A) does not apply to an agricultural producer to the extent that the contamination occurs as a result of the negligence of the producer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H31ED08FE85DF48228F6AE4C10B4ED0CD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Promulgation of regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate proposed regulations establishing labeling requirements for compliance in accordance with section 403(z) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


