<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAE2950C11679439B8423AE1A20BFF44C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2684 IH: Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2684</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150604">June 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000213">Mr. Barton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To restore tribal economic development opportunity for the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas on
			 terms that are equal and fair, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8AC9258FB2E44099AE4EC9C38FD8B678" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2451C0AE2F8342F79876F358F100D18E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBB567CA801CA4FCDB2A9DF4EA0C7DD21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings and declaration of policy</header> <subsection id="H57B0C0F209C64929A3FE7C8B200C5401"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings and declarations</header><text>Congress finds and declares the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB8055AFA14504FB5BD91FA8DC7035E6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It is the policy of the United States to promote tribal self-determination and economic self-sufficiency and to support the resolution of disputes over historical claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E67A65D58A44BE0B0A092079C5E3515"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Sam Houston, as a leader in the Texas Revolution and the President of the Republic of Texas, established friendly relations with the tribes, expressed his personal appreciation for the assistance of the tribes during the fight for Texas independence, and endeavored to protect their lands and rights.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB794EA7BE2254F58ACF1ED29524E765B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States, pursuant to Federal law and in accordance with several Federal court decisions, has affirmed the rights of the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas (Alabama-Coushatta Tribe), to free and undisturbed use and occupancy of its aboriginal lands, including the right to compensation when those rights are violated.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5F6FB561AEE4EB784D334C8F6F88AB0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Alabama-Coushatta Tribe’s lands in southeastern Texas have been subject to illegal trespass and use, depriving the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of critical economic development opportunities, including valuable timber production and oil and gas leasing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B73FDA606B4417D8442E8CF84F0F6E9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In June 2000, the United States Court of Federal Claims ruled that—</text> <subparagraph id="HFA3E14AC93E14FB78886D5027D08B242"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States violated its fiduciary obligations to the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe by knowingly failing to protect 2.85 million acres of the aboriginal lands of the Tribe in southeastern Texas;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FAD97BAAD1F42B2A1284C58965C502A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>this failure would have constituted a claim eligible to be heard by the Indian Claims Commission established by the first section of the Act of August 13, 1946; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34F5F9E654B84EC6953C6EFD48B475DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as described in House Resolution 69 (98th Congress), which was passed on November 1, 1983, it was the sense of the House of Representatives that the Federal Government should pay full monetary compensation to the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe for the loss of the 2,850,000 acres of aboriginal lands illegally occupied by non-Indian settlers after 1845.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A7E0AA1E65D463F904A85FF48820C0B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In October 2002, the United States Court of Federal Claims adopted $270,600,000 as the jointly stipulated amount of economic damages to be recovered by the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe from the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3535F7BB0C84B41B1C3D7E5B99D9128"><enum>(7)</enum><text>While the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe is asserting outstanding claims regarding its aboriginal lands, the Tribe has elected to forego, relinquish, waive, and otherwise extinguish any such claims, on the condition that Congress amend the Tribe’s 1987 Restoration Act, as hereinafter described.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD744ABDBAA34F14B4AFA1435394126D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Congress desires to empower the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe to govern its own economic future and appreciates the Tribe’s willingness to forego these land claims in exchange for improved economic self-sufficiency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6AF40733E3747D8B769F1FA6BC43098"><enum>(9)</enum><text>This Act is a good faith effort on the part of Congress to compensate the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe for the loss of its aboriginal lands by providing the Tribe with the same economic development opportunity, under the same terms and conditions, that is available to other federally recognized Indian tribes, in exchange for the Tribe’s agreement to relinquish its land claims as described above.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC14F6302FD39464098E5A9AAB1B0C3C3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In the absence of Congressional action, these land claims will likely be pursued through the courts, a process that would take many years and thereby promote divisiveness and uncertainty in the State of Texas, to the ultimate detriment of the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe, its members, and all other citizens of the State of Texas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C68ED2E616747D3B0A66A63D4F16BFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HF261D69C2A084946B63B1BAA5D17EAB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To recognize and compensate the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe for the loss of its aboriginal lands and the resulting loss of economically productive use of those lands for decades.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84A40637B8FE43FE8151DD3241894943"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To restore economic development opportunity to the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe on terms that are equal and fair.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F5B0BB2889D413D9AC14BC5DC66F349"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To resolve claims by the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe regarding the loss of its aboriginal lands.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD4F0F93A1CA4939B11118AD34C8A173"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To insulate the Federal Government and taxpayers from the potential for greater and ongoing liability stemming from these claims.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBE0BDFA4045E443AAFA367C23675D978"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restoration Act amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purpose of restoring economic development opportunity on terms that are equal and fair, section 207 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/89">Public Law 100–89</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/737">25 U.S.C. 737</external-xref>) is hereby repealed.</text>
 </section><section id="HB20B807E2C88490B96193D681BE2C4E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Dismissal of land claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States and the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe shall execute and file in each applicable court a motion for dismissal of any pending claim arising out of, or relating to, the aboriginal lands, or an interest in the aboriginal lands, of the Tribe.</text>
		</section><section id="H97E301D9321D461EA6880751233BBDB4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Extinguishment of claims</header>
 <subsection id="H264C6177D1084C218EB396EF36E4347B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extinguishment of claims</header><text>Any claim (including any claim for damages for trespass or for use and occupancy) by, or on behalf of, the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas, or any predecessor in interest or any of its members, against the United States, the State of Texas, or any landowner, which is based on any interest in, or right involving, any land or natural resources, shall be regarded as extinguished.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9051C3649A04FB8BA36356C1CFC4D33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> <paragraph id="H0BF989B9B4D94E7BB243AF8D36040849"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affects or limits the personal claim of an individual Indian (except for a Federal common law fraud claim) which is pursued under any law of general applicability that protects non-Indians as well as Indians; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AC95FE7C3114999A2A88DAD65447548"><enum>(2)</enum><text>alters the status of lands held in trust by the United States on behalf of the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


