<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1B3F025CA78D4B51810662A120A4DCEF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 41 IH: David Ray Hate Crimes Prevention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 41</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To enhance Federal enforcement of hate crimes, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1CF44AE7468D4EB599099E34DA723D85" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEECA02EA2D94F9FAFE29297E6C9726D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>David Ray Hate Crimes Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>David’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H979734D222B94001A89A336155C1D67F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
			<paragraph id="HE3659AF7259C4379BC547ED04AD04E18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the incidence of violence motivated by the actual or perceived race, color, national origin,
			 religion, sexual orientation, gender, or disability of the victim poses a
			 serious national problem;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H40CEC274CDB54FFF9DBE1D9BB8F57B14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such violence disrupts the tranquility and safety of communities and is deeply divisive;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB3568363C41644EABA693FC117C721E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>existing Federal law is inadequate to address this problem;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H581ADEAB11FC4568A3FB31394F71208B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such violence affects interstate commerce in many ways, including—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H0F65928877A74517B4A697B775CD335F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by impeding the movement of members of targeted groups and forcing such members to move across
			 State lines to escape the incidence or risk of such violence; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H174D714A24B64B96A9704207F9630E78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by preventing members of targeted groups from purchasing goods and services, obtaining or
			 sustaining employment or participating in other commercial activity;</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7EFDCEAB84846748AD0656CCB51BF82"><enum>(5)</enum><text>perpetrators cross State lines to commit such violence;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H883EC5A140D244FAB08642D4DB6BB51F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>instrumentalities of interstate commerce are used to facilitate the commission of such violence;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC895A57DD84F45608BF25023545EC9AB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>such violence is committed using articles that have traveled in interstate commerce;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HF4EBFB3996D44D74A31EA3A77B40C21A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>violence motivated by bias that is a relic of slavery can constitute badges and incidents of
			 slavery;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HFED15E8EF5AB421B8EF0876432D9FF50"><enum>(9)</enum><text>although many local jurisdictions have attempted to respond to the challenges posed by such
			 violence, the problem is sufficiently serious, widespread, and interstate
			 in scope to warrant Federal intervention to assist such jurisdictions; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H4F6BEA3BACF94A00ADD94F7C315C7E04"><enum>(10)</enum><text>many States have no laws addressing violence based on the actual or perceived race, color, national
			 origin, religion, sexual orientation, gender, or disability, of the
			 victim, while other States have laws that provide only limited protection.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H9EDD0235A6A740EE8E52D0680F0FCAF9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition of hate crime</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>hate crime</term> has the same meaning as in section 280003(a) of the <act-name parsable-cite="VCCLEA94">Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/994">28 U.S.C. 994</external-xref> note).</text>
		</section><section id="HA0E585C7ECD24C3981D0A9F366437282"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition of certain acts of violence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/245">Section 245</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="HB14A4BDCD6E64C90A8FB0B6DA55443FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HAD4BEB31F0ED49D5904D9D504CAC88D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H531301C9358A481AB768129F298AC732">
					<subsection id="HB75EA5404E414DA9B79E113060B9E8B3"><enum>(c)</enum>
						<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB11D37C7645448E4A1ED2558F8F05356"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whoever, whether or not acting under color of law, willfully causes bodily injury to any person or,
			 through the use of fire, a firearm, or an explosive device, attempts to
			 cause bodily injury to any person, because of the actual or perceived
			 race, color, religion, or national origin of any person—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H24E91679104D4CB5AD7F309A1A46CE11" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be imprisoned not more than 10 years, or fined in accordance with this title, or both; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05A4AB13BD17423F804E633037428699" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life, or fined in accordance with this title, or
			 both if—</text>
								<clause id="H1BBFFCD3967B4D7F8F7630D5F5CCEB8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>death results from the acts committed in violation of this paragraph; or</text>
								</clause><clause id="H1014092307FA48F797FD596C288DBA0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the acts committed in violation of this paragraph include kidnapping or an attempt to kidnap,
			 aggravated sexual abuse or an attempt to commit aggravated sexual abuse,
			 or an attempt to kill.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H665D81FD0A8B4EF0AEA821F50A1FACA2" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
							<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3463475B9D494BA1AE842C9F934C6979"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whoever, whether or not acting under color of law, in any circumstance described in subparagraph
			 (B), willfully causes bodily injury to any person or, through the use of
			 fire, a firearm, or an explosive device, attempts to cause bodily injury
			 to any person, because of the actual or perceived religion, gender, sexual
			 orientation, or disability of any person—</text>
								<clause id="H1A037A77068D415F857F12C0E115045F" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be imprisoned not more than 10 years, or fined in accordance with this title, or both; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="H57370EB4FD5E4F7AA72AC38126CE8F46" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life, or fined in accordance with this title, or
			 both, if—</text>
									<subclause id="HBE684B9D4AE04B4CA633F5AAD8655195"><enum>(I)</enum><text>death results from the acts committed in violation of this paragraph; or</text>
									</subclause><subclause id="H5741DA91A5E84A4BB7C7C9AECFF80E39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the acts committed in violation of this paragraph include kidnapping or an attempt to kidnap,
			 aggravated sexual abuse or an attempt to commit aggravated sexual abuse,
			 or an attempt to kill.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFABE8BEE1B04F92B679F5236B3ABFB0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the circumstances described in this subparagraph are that—</text>
								<clause id="HFEEE0D31726B4615B7D515791A918437"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in connection with the offense, the defendant or the victim travels in interstate or foreign
			 commerce, uses a facility or instrumentality of interstate or foreign
			 commerce, or engages in any activity affecting interstate or foreign
			 commerce; or</text>
								</clause><clause id="H08AAB5BD4DD248E7BF9419E8DEF21604"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the offense is in or affects interstate or foreign commerce.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HB720EA4B5A994C68A07FA63B50ED7F94"><enum>5.</enum><header>Duties of Federal sentencing commission</header>
			<subsection id="H7A54ACBAC61542CDA59BED876904136F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment of Federal sentencing guidelines</header><text>Pursuant to its authority under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/994">section 994</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, the United States
			 Sentencing Commission shall study the issue of adult recruitment of
			 juveniles to commit hate crimes and shall, if appropriate, amend the
			 Federal sentencing guidelines to provide sentencing enhancements (in
			 addition to the sentencing enhancement provided for the use of a minor
			 during the commission of an offense) for adult defendants who recruit
			 juveniles to assist in the commission of hate crimes.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H032463BC734544A9BEC39715ABA13024"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consistency with other guidelines</header><text>In carrying out this section, the United States Sentencing Commission shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="H3B89F0B4347D4452982D9377B60EA3D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that there is reasonable consistency with other Federal sentencing guidelines; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H8D5B2E637AFA4D7AA31BEEB1DE051FDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>avoid duplicative punishments for substantially the same offense.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7755053AFF714E3FABD419258EEE491C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Grant program</header>
			<subsection id="H7079EDF4AF2349B09E04233A990E690E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To make grants</header><text>The Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention of the Department of
			 Justice shall make grants, in accordance with such regulations as the
			 Attorney General may prescribe, to State and local programs designed to
			 combat hate crimes committed by juveniles.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7FD769C3088C4419BC71197B738F3A62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HEA7A5329E35447B0A870F2C8AF0F9DF8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization for additional personnel to assist State and local law enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of the Treasury and the Department of
			 Justice, including the Community Relations Service, for fiscal years 2015,
			 2016, and 2017 such sums as are necessary to increase the number of
			 personnel to prevent and respond to alleged violations of section 245 of
			 title 18, United States Code (as amended by this Act).</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


