<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H17C6713C483545879EB72324E5A84074" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3150 IH: One Social Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3150</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150722">July 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000287">Mr. Becerra</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title II of the Social Security Act to merge the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance
			 Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9DC3133FCAD8408D80907EEF3A696F1D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDBAB967819644F3AB7C83B9285E64CF1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>One Social Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6599CC0BB15B4D78834D49FB309771B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Social Security Trust Fund established</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBFB88EB21F54042A82D3B72D3162E38" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HBFD78D9A3CBE4C4DB73471D46BC9806D"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>. The Social Security Trust Fund shall consist of the securities held by the Secretary of the Treasury for the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund and the amount standing to the credit of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund on the books of the Treasury on January 1, 2016, which securities and amount the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to transfer to the Social Security Trust Fund, and, in addition, such gifts and bequests as may be made as provided in subsection (i)(1), and such amounts as may be appropriated to, or deposited in, the Social Security Trust Fund as hereinafter provided. There is hereby appropriated to the Social Security Trust Fund for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for each fiscal year thereafter, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, amounts equivalent to 100 percent of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF44F3C6FAF0F453680FF48E3EF71FD5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the taxes imposed by chapter 21 (other than sections 3101(b) and 3111(b)) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to wages (as defined in section 3121 of such Code) reported to the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to subtitle F of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury by applying the applicable rates of tax under such chapter (other than sections 3101(b) and 3111(b)) to such wages, which wages shall be certified by the Commissioner of Social Security on the basis of the records of wages established and maintained by such Commissioner in accordance with such reports; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67280450F94448DD96F7D25C5A18C041"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the taxes imposed by chapter 2 (other than <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1401">section 1401(b))</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to self-employment income (as defined in section 1402 of such Code) reported to the Secretary of the Treasury on tax returns under subtitle F of such Code, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury by applying the applicable rate of tax under such chapter (other than section 1401(b)) to such self-employment income, which self-employment income shall be certified by the Commissioner of Social Security on the basis of the records of self-employment income established and maintained by the Commissioner of Social Security in accordance with such returns.</text>
					</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The amounts appropriated by paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be transferred from time to time from the
			 general fund in the Treasury to the Social Security Trust Fund, such
			 amounts to be determined on the basis of estimates by the Secretary of the
			 Treasury of the taxes, specified in paragraphs (1) and (2), paid to or
			 deposited into the Treasury; and proper adjustments shall be made in
			 amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates were in
			 excess of or were less than the taxes specified in such paragraphs (1) and
			 (2). All amounts transferred to the Social Security Trust Fund under the
			 preceding sentence shall be invested by the Managing Trustee in the same
			 manner and to the same extent as the other assets of the Trust Fund.
			 Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, in any case in which the Secretary
			 of the Treasury determines that the assets of the Trust Fund would
			 otherwise be inadequate to meet the Trust Fund's obligations for any
			 month, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Trust Fund on
			 the first day of such month the total amount which would have been
			 transferred to the Trust Fund under this section as in effect on October
			 1, 1990; and the Trust Fund shall pay interest to the general fund on the
			 amount so transferred on the first day of any month at a rate (calculated
			 on a daily basis, and applied against the difference between the amount so
			 transferred on such first day and the amount which would have been
			 transferred to the Trust Fund up to that day under the procedures in
			 effect on January 1, 1983) equal to the rate earned by the investments of
			 the Trust Fund in the same month under subsection (d).</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H0A0F6967D9684AA8BCD44F2D7DD023BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Required actuarial analysis</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201(c) of the Social Security Act is amended by striking the fourth sentence in the matter following paragraph (5) and inserting the following: <quote>Such report shall also include actuarial analysis of the benefit cost with respect to disabled beneficiaries and their auxiliaries, to retired beneficiaries and their auxiliaries, and to survivor beneficiaries.</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HC5E4008D42D14F99AF7DFC870B3DBA5C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Board of Trustees</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H107B33AED18B46F4AFB919AAF4B9AF57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of Trustees of Social Security Trust Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201(c) of the Social Security Act, as amended by section 3, is further amended in the matter preceding paragraph (1) by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund (hereinafter in this title called the <quote>Trust Funds</quote>)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund (in this title referred to as the <quote>Trust Fund</quote>)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBCF97A61CA90491FAFA3346C69B1EF89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuity of Board of Trustees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Trustees of the Social Security Trust Fund created by the amendment made by section (2) shall be a continuous body with the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund in operation prior to the effective date of such amendment. Individuals serving as members of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund as of the effective date of such amendment shall serve the remainder of their term as members of the Board of Trustees of the Social Security Trust Fund.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HAB6647BF5AE14286889AAEBA9E04B2D4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Conforming amendments related to Social Security Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="HAB9F316316F34C1484B4F0BFE9062D23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to section heading</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The section heading for section 201 of the Social Security Act is amended to read as follows: <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBD5029FA8B764016A5CBF296608AC2EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Board of Trustees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201(c) of such Act, as amended by sections 3 and 4(a), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H416CBFB0BA2648A8AF864EFBBEC571E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Board of Trustees of the Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Board of Trustees of the Trust Fund</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AE291ABD62A48328460FF5D71BC72DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA24F9CA4B6F4591AF6CA910BF79DD70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H38C0812F758D4A8C8D065A5AD2F9430B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4B779811E654C788B516215DA5F8D0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>their</quote> and inserting <quote>its</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F2637648D2A41278E9382E5F9050571"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>either of the Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>the Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8A56EFA49849198233866EDC9C1276"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD83DA76784E041CFAF485A42775E88B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>managing the Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>managing the Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89AF78C92C524A4DA48B0447E1DE014B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Trust Funds are</quote> and inserting <quote>Trust Fund is</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF601594FB3F3492B9851AD44D7FF36F1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter following paragraph (5), by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB136255FDFD842B8AC5565A7F503F1E9"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the second sentence in the matter following paragraph (5), by striking <quote>whether the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, individually and collectively, are</quote> and inserting <quote>whether the Social Security Trust Fund is</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E6E2029027B4BF183CFCF012BAD2DD2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investments</header><text>Section 201 of such Act is amended in subsections (d) and (e) by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H08356BDF5A234904AECF46775465EA06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Crediting of interest and proceeds to Trust Funds</header><text>Section 201(f) of such Act is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5440DAB0D46C4B459DA6D0EFA83C2FF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Disability Insurance Trust Fund, respectively</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F3AD12FFAE8406C9B47F4ABA2279D8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>either of the Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>the Trust Fund</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E85C93E10AD4F27919920A2238DDF04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE00E5E10C9D4361BC8C28483AE37593"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Section 201(g) of such Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H94E3346183E546D5865C6F6FCFE19224"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H70726C744BAB4F768FAABB8A4D7D32C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Of the amounts authorized to be made available out of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund under the preceding sentence</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/296">Public Law 103–296</external-xref>).</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74C9564CCE484FA7BFB16B5C0C3995A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i)—</text> <clause id="HC38BF1AEE12C419891C7D72D1A1EBEDB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subclauses (II) and (III) and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A6E0454AF094341BBAD18506DEE0139" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="H7B69ED1DA03B4BAB86E46D5991D173ED" indent="up2"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the portion of such costs which should have been borne by the Social Security Trust Fund,</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause><clause id="H5BC82A39132B4B1E89FC84787412DF3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (IV) and (V) as subclauses (III) and (IV);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE274246156AC461F8432405263E650F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD41EB9B227054153AF9C9317CECAB2E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23427B020F84466785BCC0117D01BBDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the last sentence; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0172F37B16F34147A65CECE8A02DAF85"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CA027891DB742F890D37D84D8ACAB30"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Benefit payments</header><text>Section 201(h) of such Act is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6F32EAAF4084EF49E85960166398ED8" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HBF693514610746638421A885EA2F199F"><enum>(h)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All benefit payments required to be made under this title shall be made only from the Social Security Trust Fund.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDBF5C174B2BE43E1BAA95058C6EA3EDF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Gifts</header><text>Section 201(i) of such Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HED17A635A92641BA8DEC1A38AFA10874"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA35CCED4737146B9801C1FAE886C0ACE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF960943CE406469282436F335CB64437"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Section 201(j) of such Act is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund (as determined appropriate by the Commissioner of Social Security)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1A332D589D2D4CB7815526A02D69ECDD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Demonstration projects</header><text>Section 201(k) of such Act is amended by striking <quote>the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, as determined appropriate by the Commissioner of Social Security</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBC789F68716E4A2B8C5E5B7E1C74C5D2"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Benefit checks</header><text>Section 201(m) of such Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF8E7FFCC935449A28F83998C7C02C44A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>each of the Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D397F4385D49FE9A3B8DA8E623DFF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>one of the Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>the Trust Fund</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF964DF5B9280450598E4C782D060C94F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such Trust Fund</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7BAD1DDF3667428D9F21319F2261D8A8"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Conforming repeals</header>
 <paragraph id="H43DF29DE9E424428AEC2C4054B9EEB7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 201 of such Act is amended by striking subsections (b), (l), and (n).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC98CFBBD198D4BBC8718DA7294EEF376"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Redesignations</header><text>Section 201 of such Act is further amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9A749C86C0FD46E9B6A032C44291564C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (j) as subsections (b) through (i), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AB64B8590124EDCA96468E81950AC00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (k) as subsection (j); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48E5D9B4FEDE43E2AD460CD4B86EF04B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (m) as subsection (k).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H429B0E9F1C954F578824482812D9E0DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>References to redesignated sections</header> <subparagraph id="HEE0DBA96BA11442AA26E61AFDA91490E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 201(a) of such Act, as amended by section 2, is further amended—</text>
 <clause id="H4536740892C748718DE0863BC4B72043"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (i)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (h)(1)</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6D48DD86615B48ADBE7CF6F84018AD03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (c)</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5624835C7F4645228AFAC107BC2BB756"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1131(b)(1) of such Act is amended by striking <quote>section 201(g)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 201(f)(1)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0236C2DA983F4B10AD978D8AAF69A983"><enum>6.</enum><header>Other conforming amendments to Social Security Act</header> <subsection id="H72FDEA8CBDF646469412D2376F48DEDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title II</header><text>Title II of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1E3A71D16DAA43AAB304507B6C71D272"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 202(x)(3)(B)(iii), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, as appropriate,</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H091392A5831B4D79B61479AB432C0FEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 206(d)(5), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, as appropriate</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H064E898B48974240B3AF40768D101CA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 206(e)(3)(B), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E704EDF2AA2441DB50C310419527865"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 208(b)(5)(A), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, as appropriate</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AE911AD3C2245D6B23DBEBAC40FA49E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 215(i)(1)(F)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5984752CE91D4338B339F6B9167D9062"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text>
 <clause id="HD885CA3002C54302A13CBBE9B24AE018"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the combined balance in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the balance in the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9051FA8430AB4D4197B4F63071C7FA3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and reduced by the outstanding amount of any loan (including interest thereon) theretofore made to either such Fund from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under section 201(l)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B121EEC88AA4A3896FBDE3FFFA2245A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <clause id="HD4E0D310C60F43CE9233F7DB27FE47AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H636CD15AD0D4463CB9C33A997062EA0E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(other than payments</quote> and all that follows through <quote>from that Account</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE916702489714545936E97CDE69088B8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 217(g)(2), by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>For purposes of any such revision of the amount determined under paragraph (1) that occurs in a year after 2015, any reference in such paragraph to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund shall be deemed to be a reference to the Social Security Trust Fund.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FBCECE83219418EB57540E62D3A8EED"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 221(e)—</text> <subparagraph id="HAC5B6F97133242B09E20EC49FC854884"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAF83D0D718F4675932712FCABE72A59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the last sentence;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC8996A878D44E5A923FC07E7B53D4E7"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 221(f), by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H974538FBDAD644CEAE0CBEAA5A503C2D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in section 222(d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H68037BE8B31C4350AF233C38FA94124E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the section heading, by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42A6142E7BF846A38CF815E4F2C9F4B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>to the end that savings will accrue to the Trust Funds as a result of rehabilitating such individuals, there are authorized to be transferred from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>to the end that savings will accrue to the Trust Fund as a result of rehabilitating such individuals, there are authorized to be transferred from the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F74863C3576402E902065F63F7EBAD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (4) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H635CE322FA7546D5BCC67F93DE235383" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H71E26F66745248CDBF051374F6998A42" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall determine according to such methods and procedures as the Commissioner may deem appropriate the total amount to be reimbursed for the cost of services under this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8FFC876CB2C4CE3A479305BB89C38ED"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in section 228(g)—</text> <subparagraph id="H195477A8F44B4143BEC7E49DF3C3532F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC8B7945A19348908A67C30E0837F945"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H960D502E6A574919B87F09D807F93379"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 231(c), by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1A615DAC32F42C59101E3D24010F284"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 234(a)(1), by striking <quote>Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Trust Fund</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C83422755B343B6AB5DD2226D63D3F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Title VII</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/901">42 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC62B1417DDDF42AA8B685981BCB805C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 703(j), by striking <quote>Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund,</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE218DED9F3BA48EF8C069E2D01BC3F7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 708, by striking <quote>the <quote>OASDI trust fund ratio</quote> under section 201(l),</quote> after <quote>computing</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88199E5E4685405A9C123B9469791F80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 709—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDF031754E774AC0A23DA84A412F8356"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF72EDA18AEB4A71B46AFB50C278ACEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="H35064B9A31014A9884A6F710F1D6EBE1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>section 201(l) or</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H932BFC34C1B84A6596DA6FD85B8871F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12C66B102350488BA146B44261AC9253"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 710—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8BADBCEB3C6B41DA8B66A9131E8D5EEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDC640F3D01B4CEFBC366F4362C9C749"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <clause id="HC8897C6326544585B19EA3D399F62838"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>any Trust Fund specified in subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA1FC470E1BBE44BFA07CE43B18E1C54E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>payments from any such Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>payments from the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H150F48F514B04642BABE3941B7EE1398"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Title XI</header><text>Title XI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H169C7C5EDF6546B592A46571B6BC9A6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1106(b), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19AB9B6448C84FB1A3A9590A022164E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1129(e)(2)(A), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, as determined appropriate by the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC425533F4BA14EFA90EE626C8F88E7DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in sections 1131(b)(2) and 1140(c)(2), by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC53514D804B34CC88A36D010F386F62C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 1145(c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA822402900484902AB7C988947ED267D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1) and (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE8B42AFD8F84326A601D7D1D6F645D4" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HF1FD79E0B4DD404882105A8C732F4DD0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Social Security Trust Fund;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFF9F687375142BD9B6A4D4505561DA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFCC4D06520C413A8D0F9FE9D8F70CCA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 1148(j)(1)(A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE2DA474FA42B415BA1FD15C9D0CCADF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35069B3266C540DCABCAEADCC7AC5557"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8CA9BB231F144160ABEB55D95680FF7C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Title XVIII</header><text>Title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD8E4BE424AB24FB29BB2D1183258BA93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1817(g), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and from the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5D3C308F0A545A6899D545784FE607E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1840(a)(2), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6906CADD09EE4ADEB87924AAB339EDB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 1841(f), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and from the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H34ADB8890E4E44D991C6712BB9CC99AD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Conforming amendments outside of Social Security Act</header>
			<subsection id="H32B772ED16CF4EB990B3E149E8460FBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Budget</header>
 <paragraph id="H3BB5F595AF44494495A346F0783521A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Off-budget exemption</header><text>Section 405(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/655">2 U.S.C. 655(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance and Federal Disability Insurance Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F1CFC0BF65C4B7DBF4855BEB3D1B4BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sequestration exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 255(g)(1)(A) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/905">2 U.S.C. 905(g)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Payments to Social Security Trust Funds</quote> and inserting <quote>Payments to the Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE27E15804144C6DB61D42AA0AF39141"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tax</header>
 <paragraph id="H4C282EC5C5944E7F9BBA840D10AFEFAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Taxable wages</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3121">Section 3121(l)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF62ED9EC5F40B6B78FC790F12F6366"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Overpayments</header> <subparagraph id="H6E7A154FBE1542F289A845640D95AFDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6402">Section 6402(d)(3)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, whichever is certified to the Secretary as appropriate by the Commissioner of Social Security</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80408728ECF046D893F053A111BF6F55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subsection (f)(2)(B) of section 3720A, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, whichever is certified to the Secretary of the Treasury as appropriate by the Commissioner of Social Security</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7D374B0075842D3B8CCDFA3F66A67F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>False claims penalties</header><text>Subsection (g)(2) of section 3806 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA40C2DFE369E44BCB3F0E624CF004F78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA142E35E7BD44303BF629370C3CB5337"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Secretary of Health and Human Services</quote> and inserting <quote>Commissioner of Social Security</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63C9C52657E2476E8BCFE73B4F14B323"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E212DEE9AE64C36BA23952B26B66709"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <subparagraph id="H843E1A4C1FCB45E39DACB548C972E9A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Secretary of Health and Human Services</quote> and inserting <quote>Commissioner of Social Security</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82EF43DFF2354219A579B2CCA48E81F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF316E97CB9A439BA99AFBF249BFA87C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Railroad Retirement Board</header><text>Section 7 of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/231f">45 U.S.C. 231f</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4B59C379781446A38E31BDF2427A8E70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E9C6DFDF3044C67B72F5188B22B02C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0BD0F53C690041CFA7C9EB2EAC0322C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare</quote> each time it appears and inserting <quote>Commissioner of Social Security</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2422F4C6D1274571941065D697EFDDE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund,</quote> each time it appears and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB83A34AD8C9E4FC08E11C7C06A4FD52D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(4), by striking <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund,</quote> and inserting <quote>Social Security Trust Fund</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA87CB167B0724374B0138B13219DDFE1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective beginning January 1, 2016, any reference in law to the <quote>Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund</quote> or the <quote>Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund</quote> is deemed to be a reference to the Social Security Trust Fund.</text>
 </section><section id="H9EAD5EB5B6BC49839FAED8496E87D090"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect on January 1, 2016.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

