<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC542C13461954E08B7369020D570CA42" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3863 IH: Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3863</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151029">October 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide assistance
			 for common interest communities, condominiums, and housing cooperatives
			 damaged by a major disaster, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCA18689B05B947C9A236E55DA9EF072D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7714DA62DAD44A189BCBB6807990CDB9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H22C922DB97F848CF923A4AE2EF903916"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H17B5356C49C849EFA1854598B5D101BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of private nonprofit facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102(11)(B) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(11)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The term also includes any facilities (including roads, walkways, bridges, culverts, canals, sewer and wastewater systems, hazard mitigation systems, power, and other critical community infrastructure) owned or operated by a common interest community that provide essential services of a governmental nature.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H43155CF9015A4C51A30A015DD4F1466F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD21300C9E134E7390C45D15F33AD898" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H203F6448BB1744488232AA302CB9F525"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Common interest community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>common interest community</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H82ABBF5BED4C4B94B2FC241F273D4F4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any nonprofit mandatory membership organization comprised of owners of real estate (other than a condominium or housing cooperative) described in a declaration or created pursuant to a covenant or other applicable law with respect to which a person, by virtue of the person’s ownership of a unit, is obligated to pay for a share of real estate taxes, insurance premiums, maintenance, or improvement of, or services or other expenses related to, common elements, other units, or any other real estate other than that unit described in the declaration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4739D7CB04264757BFE654D047350B6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a condominium project—</text> <clause id="H4C2E7D336F644C0C8ED1BA657175BEB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>comprised entirely of detached single family units; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5285DE10AF044825B651E9699D67BCEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>comprised of 4 or more multi-unit housing structures, that owns or operates facilities (including roads, walkways, bridges, culverts, canals, sewer and wastewater systems, hazard mitigation systems, power, or other critical community infrastructure) that provide essential services of a governmental nature.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55B5EA00FE0944E49801E2FE7BA96D5A"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Condominium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>condominium</quote> means a multi-unit housing project in which each dwelling unit is separately owned, and the remaining portions of the real estate are designated for common ownership solely by the owners of those units, each owner having an undivided interest in the common elements, and which is represented by a condominium association consisting exclusively of all the unit owners in the project, which is, or will be responsible for the operation, administration, and management of the project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75ABB666F1FE46B4A244AB4F9D52B30C"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Housing cooperative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>housing cooperative</quote> means a multi-unit housing project in which each dwelling unit is subject to separate use and possession by one or more cooperative members whose interest in such unit, and in any undivided assets of the cooperative association that are appurtenant to such unit, is evidenced by a membership or share interest in a cooperative association and a lease or other document of title or possession granted by such cooperative as the owner of all cooperative property.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H92C946F2049648458D28D833B2CDB918" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Condominiums and housing cooperatives damaged by a major disaster</header>
 <subsection id="H25BC851427AE47CD8205CD39B0783C9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Individuals and Households Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(b)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB25546B99B44428A88EB7A877E7394F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The President</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63AFF24120BE4FEC9E14E68F27C91B34" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC88CC257FEBB48A295BC79D8163461BD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA62EDE03CC34CACAA0CA1C90290E44D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA760AB549E2845288857A6AE7670BC43" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H5B454899B1944561884F14F82CB22313"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Condominiums and housing cooperatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of providing financial assistance under subsections (c)(2) and (c)(3) with respect to residential elements that are the legal responsibility of an association for a condominium or housing cooperative, the terms <quote>individual</quote> and <quote>household</quote> include the association for the condominium or housing cooperative.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CD7639C9AC8401E95FDE2D175545AFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header> Maximum amount of assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(h) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57ECA72DA1E546AEA965B73A4934D521" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H990E656509E44DFA8B202D4E83E686CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for condominiums and housing cooperatives</header> <subparagraph id="H1588179F98D04A76B96E93B57CEE53CF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In lieu of the limit established under paragraph (1), the maximum amount of assistance that an association for a condominium or housing cooperative may receive under this section with respect to a single disaster shall be an amount to be determined by the President by regulation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0749D0B417854455B5A6AEF3A849BAB7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjustment of limit</header><text>The amount determined by the President under subparagraph (A) shall be adjusted annually in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H51747B6E1BFC41F7A50A3C0D66040B28"><enum>4.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply to a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


