<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4860B763F71E44D487EFE86A89447946" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1622 IH: National Fab Lab Network Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1622</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150325">March 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide a Federal charter to the Fab Foundation for the National Fab Lab Network, a national
			 network of local digital fabrication facilities providing community access
			 to advanced manufacturing tools for learning skills, developing
			 inventions, creating businesses, and producing personalized products.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD488284BD66F4C63A0039440909EE9F2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H234D9110232B4A0EA20667577D9E6E18" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Fab Lab Network Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H89947EFE653B4DCFBED96DB57FDFC8D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB733D306439E49F087072C000C9BDDB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Scientific discoveries and technical innovations are critical to the economic and national security of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D0089F9182740A0947880D996477CF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Maintaining the leadership of the United States in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics will require a diverse population with the skills, interest, and access to tools required to advance these fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF41B8E3FC3344032B4E3FF67C9490D58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Just as earlier digital revolutions in communications and computation provided individuals with the Internet and personal computers, a digital revolution in fabrication will allow anyone to make almost anything, anywhere.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE52BDC84DBCC483896616FB6D893BACE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>These creations include communications devices, solar powered housing, consumer products, and new kinds of machines and tools for advanced manufacturing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H236D0F978033498596CDBFD33203AFE8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Center for Bits and Atoms of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (CBA) has contributed significantly to the advancement of these goals through its work in creating and advancing digital fabrication facilities, or <quote>fab labs</quote> in the United States and abroad.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C83E23EC2704987B8718356281A40B8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>MakerSpaces, TechShops, and other creative platforms also facilitate access to digital fabrication capabilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB477764992174DD0AF5DC23EF6366A75"><enum>(7)</enum><text>CBA’s fab labs provide a model for a new kind of national laboratory that links local facilities for advanced manufacturing to expand access and empower communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD52C1EE4B290460F86D3C4F6C5E04C11"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A coordinated national public-private partnership will be the most effective way to accelerate the provision of this infrastructure for learning skills, developing inventions, creating businesses, and producing personalized products.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H9D196727DB9B4541B2F0CD97E5BA6AB3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal charter for National Fab Lab network</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title 36, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new chapter:</text> <quoted-block id="H90B363FD1A9A437181C4EF06519210AB" style="USC"> <chapter id="H71C1C77F4A094E40AC28289F7D6BDF1D"><enum>3011</enum><header>NATIONAL FAB LAB NETWORK</header> <section id="H4CBB90F723B64734B26F587B4C526941"><enum>301101.</enum><header>Organization</header> <subsection id="H44B1B6C182994C56A86635B67D037366"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal charter</header><text>The Fab Foundation is hereby granted a Federal charter as the National Fab Lab Network (in this chapter referred to as the <quote>NFLN</quote>). Except as otherwise provided, the NFLN shall have perpetual succession.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6069CC671DEB403EA724469371F7482D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of fab lab</header><text>In this chapter, the term <quote>fab lab</quote> refers to a facility that is—</text> <paragraph id="HB7423AAD7BEA443CBE9D241F60EFE8B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>equipped with a standard integrated suite of fabrication tools that can convert digital designs into functional physical things;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H965999BB5580498EA95D8FD60531AB4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>equipped with scanning tools to convert physical things into digital designs; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H93643536ADDA4906A1E5A57E13421D36"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made freely accessible to the general public, allowing for necessary fees.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6427702124CA4A35928551ECF2C1488F"><enum>301102.</enum><header>Purposes and goals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes and goals of the NFLN are—</text> <paragraph id="HC58275EB857B4130AC8951563E7BC107"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to create a national network of connected local fab labs to empower individuals and communities in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE03933D02D04391BCED4F44920FBBBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to foster the use of distributed digital fabrication tools to promote science, technology, engineering and math skills, increase invention and innovation, create businesses and jobs, and fulfill personal, professional, and community needs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8144FB4FD8F34009A46C471EDA25879E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to serve as a resource to assist stakeholders with the effective operation of fab labs;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FB609C989FA4C41B83A8ACFFBF3F577"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide a platform for education, research, and for catalyzing new methods in STEM education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H009F1898532A43828AA83E03D0858D85"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to create new ways of educating the workforce that will enable workers to compete in a 21st Century global marketplace; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF3EC67BE614667988FC44A1112C6C5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to seek to establish at least one fab lab per every 700,000 individuals in the United States in the first ten years of its operation, corresponding to availability in all 435 Congressional districts and to provide guidelines for their sustainable operation.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HDC8B067345C14F35AEA54E6901CC5443"><enum>301103.</enum><header>Membership and organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in this Act, eligibility for membership in the NFLN and the rights and privileges of members are as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the NFLN.</text>
 </section><section id="HDB7DE3D4B2D841E9911E335D0A81AA0F"><enum>301104.</enum><header>Governing body</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Directors, officers, and other staff of the NFLN, and their powers and duties are as provided in the bylaws of the NFLN.</text>
 </section><section id="H429FF95505444C25A5F7A844B1F8BDCD"><enum>301105.</enum><header>Powers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The NFLN may—</text> <paragraph id="HCE02EC4FFF994571B5CD69C6D1F561CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate the creation of a national network of local fab labs in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1A339D42AAE4067868BFA886B337C6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue guidelines for the sustainable operation of fab labs;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A86853A8E81490A863253129DB2CDA9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serve as a resource for organizations and communities seeking to create fab labs by providing information, assessing suitability, advising on the lab lifecycle, and maintaining descriptions of prospective and operating sites;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H894ACFF8F2FD414094B76F2F2EE54FA3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>accept funds from private individuals, corporations, government agencies, or other organizations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC3F29823F5A4EA1854C3D0BE1D1861A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>distribute funds to other non-profit organizations to establish and operate fab labs as members of the NFLN;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53FE86728E5046DEBFCF98798EA0BE51"><enum>(6)</enum><text>facilitate communication between other non-profit organizations seeking to join the NFLN with operational entities that can source and install fab labs, provide training, assist with operations, account for spending, and assess impact;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B5707BF0966444391805A6A74F5500C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>communicate the benefits available through membership in the NFLN to communities and the public;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC999A40AA6B4900980799B347576349"><enum>(8)</enum><text>facilitate and participate in synergistic programs, including workforce training, job creation, research broader impacts, and the production of civic infrastructure;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H594A5D0571024B3BA16AC2B9D8259197"><enum>(9)</enum><text>amend a constitution and bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86C898644C2F411FAA1628F6756234B7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>choose directors, officers, trustees, managers, employees, and agents as the activities of the NFLN require;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6059E134E89A46D98C17885B2714FCFE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>make contracts;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H70F464B5773B41468665BCA463EADFA8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB19C3AB2FB27499D803A489E3EF19E26"><enum>(13)</enum><text>borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9906D1BB8BCC40049931E4FD57501A61"><enum>(14)</enum><text>charge and collect membership dues and subscription fees; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FEB039EB6684860BF30EA02E253E9BE"><enum>(15)</enum><text>sue and be sued.</text>
						</paragraph></section><section id="H98F302560B0B49399FB3F9CBC819626F"><enum>301106.</enum><header>Restrictions</header>
 <subsection id="H2C2FA741714D4DBBB8710F9C916DF238"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Stock and dividends</header><text>The corporation may not issue securities of any kind or declare or pay a dividend.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBEBEAAABE0904807899F3F9FDEA7E3AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution of income or assets</header><text>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director, officer, or member during the life of the charter granted by this Act. This paragraph does not prevent the payment of reasonable compensation to an officer or reimbursement for actual necessary expenses in amounts approved by the board of directors.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H045246FE6F9E41DAA5E46BF3CEBBD32D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loans</header><text>The corporation may not make a loan to a director, officer, or employee.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7274AC9E8CC5441A888AA655E2331889"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Claim of governmental approval or authority</header><text>The corporation may not claim congressional approval or the authority of the United States Government for any of its activities.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H864CE59B3F734854AE0482D5D3A4F0D7"><enum>301107.</enum><header>Records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The NFLN shall keep—</text> <paragraph id="H6EEB176979384CB59D22AF1C02EA9E1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>correct and complete records of account;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48683099E8874ED7BA0DCBDC2026655B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>minutes of the proceedings of its members, board of directors, and committees having any of the authority of its board of directors; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD23EE28356014385879DA96534318966"><enum>(3)</enum><text>at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HA734E41BA3A843679DBEF7DFC4A91A1F"><enum>301108.</enum><header>Duty to maintain tax exempt status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The NFLN shall exist as a nonprofit entity under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">Section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </section><section id="HB4FF4B68F4CD43BD873BB46CA9EECE42"><enum>301109.</enum><header>Inspections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A member entitled to vote, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</text>
 </section><section id="HEE593CDFD43B48728BA6D3D1C33B66D0"><enum>301110.</enum><header>Liability for acts of officers and agents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The NFLN is liable for the acts of its officers and agents acting within the scope of their authority.</text>
 </section><section id="H6CDF701460FF4A1B830EDB86EFB43A92"><enum>301111.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The NFLN shall submit an annual report to Congress, including specifically to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, on the activities of the corporation during the prior fiscal year. The report shall be submitted at the same time as the report of the audit required by section 10101 of this title. The report may not be printed as a public document.</text></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


