<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H14806BF0AC30432A96E44455EDC190CF" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3931 IH: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 620 Central Avenue Suite 1A in Hot Springs National Park, Arkansas, as the “Chief Petty Officer Adam Brown United States Post Office”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3931</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20151104">November 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 620 Central Avenue Suite 1A in Hot Springs National Park, Arkansas, as the <quote>Chief Petty Officer Adam Brown United States Post Office</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H613C9EE9043A4FA2B420A552D95F39EC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC42CCC1D732B40E1860B77BEF0D3D670" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Chief Petty Officer Adam Brown United States Post Office</header>
<subsection id="HAEC676A07E1A440CAF090F857895C36C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 620 Central Avenue Suite 1A in Hot Springs National Park, Arkansas, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Chief Petty Officer Adam Brown United States Post Office</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H554299A5FFF44B68B4555495BF76A614"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Chief Petty Officer Adam Brown United States Post Office</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


