<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7BD8CBC119234120B53A827CABFCAF58" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2093 IH: Space Leadership Preservation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2093</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150429">April 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To preserve American space leadership, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB1654DF42F284BF49896E3203D256269" style="OLC">
 <section id="H087F7CA9586D448781223D87D97E0425" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Space Leadership Preservation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8BB49E4F882B45B6A42F26B704850341"><enum>2.</enum><header>Administrator and Deputy Administrator</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 20111 of title 51, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9A395944E02544A195F7FB433335E7CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B4F2188181947B3868843DCEC413A9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Administrator.—</header-in-text>There is established</quote> and inserting</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H03121F42A6F94EB19073F8F24002CDA0" style="OLC">
 <text><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Administrator.—</header-in-text></text><paragraph id="HF14A750ACCAE49D8B087A65E32243722"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6E3F777DA864452B9D2581256E32721"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), as so designated by subparagraph (A) of this paragraph—</text>
 <clause id="HA84C3F8DAA714E66A39181B735BA546C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, pursuant to paragraph (2),</quote> after <quote>who shall be appointed</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H7875F8CA875942E59DD660220282308E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>The Administrator shall serve for a term of 10 years.</quote> after <quote>and activities thereof.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2193D3F282ED47BBBE230F6690C0483E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE41E6F4F2E24793BFB6DEC47C1DBEFA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD552D06417464EBEB7385D60BD47F4C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board of directors nominations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall appoint the Administrator under paragraph (1) from among the list of nominees provided by the Board of Directors pursuant to section 20118(l)(2)(A). The President shall appoint a new Administrator not later than 3 months after the first set of nominees is so provided by the Board of Directors. The sitting Administrator may serve in the position until a new Administrator appointed pursuant to this paragraph is confirmed by the Senate.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H610415E8865B45D7897C7FE8A1A6C8DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H89C77FAADF0542029DB02C735CD15575"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Administrator.—</header-in-text>There shall be</quote> and inserting</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9E21DC688B1347BE85D6CBAD847FB065" style="OLC">
 <text><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Administrator.—</header-in-text></text><paragraph id="HB58B7543436D4D6A899B612CE663B8BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12C5B1B5E557472BA16D127C3C115A71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), as so designated by subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, by inserting <quote>, pursuant to paragraph (2),</quote> after <quote>who shall be appointed</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19654DD2740A48CFBE0B2FA447B46A04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD6E29B1114548F1B8247BB6441AAA3B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H66BD2F865EAC45F987AC8DFC48D4D8BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board of directors nominations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall appoint the Deputy Administrator under paragraph (1) from among the list of nominees provided by the Board of Directors pursuant to section 20118(l)(2)(B).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HB6AADD20186247558932B4BAC56BB04C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Board of Directors</header>
 <subsection id="H0EC43ED61AF0470995053259B67B7C57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AF21606D77E4FD1A7B6790ECD6D7B36" style="USC">
					<section id="HD81B0E8F67064F0EB3D03BD4A8DC665A"><enum>20118.</enum><header>Board of Directors</header>
 <subsection id="H95578E422AEF44DCA85D79A04EC250A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be established a Board of Directors for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration in accordance with this section, not later than 9 months after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Space Leadership Preservation Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6E6A58050C784B41A2D726DC16AAEA34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership and appointment</header><text>The Board shall consist of 11 members to be appointed as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H51DB757921174BA09F9374C529E97022"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Three members shall be appointed by the President.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H938927D5EADE4F4D814C4F7F23CC4540"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Three members shall be appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0210ACC63E5455B81EE5469D507F547"><enum>(3)</enum><text>One member shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29FC4CBFF86745869BC5FE869865642E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Three members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA24B004ED9D24B0FB7EFC4C603DAA39D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One member shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text>
							</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">In addition to the members appointed under paragraphs (1) through (5), the Administrator shall be
 an ex officio, nonvoting member of the Board.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H11C32C1B53514D82BA92B93E31B68DC7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individuals appointed as members of the Board shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H34DFC2547B7E4A21A8D5A4E0451FFB72"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">former astronauts or scientists or engineers eminent in the fields of human spaceflight, planetary science, space science, Earth science, and aeronautics, or other scientific, engineering, business, and social science disciplines related to space and aeronautics;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45182F71BCAB4E54A3CDCEB27D2D5FD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>selected on the basis of established records of distinguished service; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C5D6A18A0044AF99F63870F916E1990"><enum>(3)</enum><text>so selected as to provide representation of the views of engineering, science, and aerospace leaders in all areas of the Nation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H670366D6671046D9978BAB40F4DFE5AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual employed by or representing an organization with which the Administration has a contract is not eligible to serve on the Board, except for scientists employed by or representing not-for-profit colleges and universities and other not-for-profit organizations. A former Board member may not take employment with or represent an organization with which the Administration has a contract, or which is seeking such a contract, for a period of 2 years following completion of service on the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC74FFB88149A438BBA33A9B36C6F3460"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The term of office of each member of the Board shall be 3 years, except that any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. Any person who has been a member of the Board for 12 consecutive years shall thereafter be ineligible for appointment during the 2-year period following the expiration of such 12th year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H04474D5A5E9B4492A0BAA98B597F8570"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member of the Board shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9AF7F6E91477466FB1DED854C8042458"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Board shall meet quarterly and at such other times as the Chairman may determine, but the Chairman shall also call a meeting whenever one-third of the members so request in writing. The Board shall adopt procedures governing the conduct of its meetings, including delivery of notice and a definition of a quorum, which in no case shall be less than one-half plus one of the members of the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6CFB14BCC4714BFD8C0022C80305FF0A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Chairman and Vice Chairman</header><text>The election of the Chairman and Vice Chairman of the Board shall take place at each first quarter meeting occurring in an even-numbered year. The Vice Chairman shall perform the duties of the Chairman in his absence. In case a vacancy occurs in the chairmanship or vice chairmanship, the Board shall elect a member to fill such vacancy.</text>
						</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H67F6B6D140644DACB3430BC8CB31A9B9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Staff</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H348B974161A14878AE5326926563EF8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman may, with the concurrence of a majority of Board members, appoint professional staff, technical and professional personnel on leave of absence from academic, industrial, or research institutions for a limited term, and operations and support staff. The duties of such staff shall be assigned at the direction of the Board as necessary to assist the Board in exercising its powers and functions under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD02B954D3C63469F89C81B8499483D2E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Competitive service; compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Professional staff and limited-term technical and professional personnel may be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and the provisions of chapter 51 of such title relating to classification, and shall be compensated at a rate not exceeding the maximum rate payable under section 5376 of such title.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H207FF0AC44DE4E31BD24272172541425"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Special commissions</header><text>The Board is authorized to establish such special commissions as it may from time to time deem necessary for the purposes of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8203D3D270644E78A2F629DD1F124DE1"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Committees</header><text>The Board is authorized to appoint from among its members such committees as it deems necessary, and to assign to committees so appointed such survey and advisory functions as the Board deems appropriate to assist it in exercising its powers and functions under this section.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H3326774553E74F17B4792FBF21304839"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Functions</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H590527A086174131A468D48874EE33DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Budget proposal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than November 15 of each year, the Board shall provide to the President, the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, a proposed budget for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for the next fiscal year. Such budget shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA06D0599949D451AA2B6DFCD028B30FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out the purpose described in section 20102(h);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37D3480623AE42BE84E3B862E2CB677F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be based on—</text>
 <clause id="H030CFF674C8E453AA407B66D6762B00C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the best professional judgment of the Board;</text> </clause><clause id="H7BA99C85CF754AE1BA0472E506CCF483"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations from the scientific, engineering, and other technical experts communities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC65F2EE8DD9E4DE18146439165B397F3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the recommendations of the most recent National Research Council decadal surveys; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F7FD1D6D9394729B4684F3097F4BC9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">follow such decadal survey’s recommended decision rules regarding program implementation, including a strict adherence to the recommendation that the National Aeronautics and Space Administration include in a balanced program a flagship class mission, which may be executed in cooperation with one or more international partners.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EC695E8012F4118A21F42EDB0948E73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nominees for Administrator, Deputy Administrator, and Chief Financial Officer</header><text>The Board shall provide to the President—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2A9ABC89A5A4A8BB704A1C1EEBA402E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of 3 nominees from which the President shall appoint an Administrator pursuant to section 20111(a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H210CEF536D3A45CFAE5159667ED5FFBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of 3 nominees from which the President shall appoint a Deputy Administrator pursuant to section 20111(b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE72948533EB4DD6B03BDB8EE0E3C6A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of 3 nominees from which the President shall appoint a Chief Financial Officer pursuant to section 205(a) of the Chief Financial Officers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/901">31 U.S.C. 901(a)</external-xref>).</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The Board shall provide the first set of nominees under this paragraph not later than 15 months
			 after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Space Leadership Preservation Act of 2015</short-title>.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6285DDBB45D4BBFBC33D33095285286"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8DAF2C8E3D0845D38C0EB7C5EC0E1057"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual infrastructure, capabilities, and workforce assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall provide to the President and the Congress annually a report assessing the status of United States spaceflight infrastructure, unique space capabilities, and the availability of qualified United States workers necessary to maintain such infrastructure and capabilities. The assessment shall also identify areas of concern, gaps in capability compared to foreign spaceflight capabilities, and recommendations on how to strengthen or improve United States capabilities and workforce.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H420395D694144C0183361AE04AEB3848"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specific policy matter reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall provide to the President and the Congress reports on specific, individual policy matters within the authority of the Administration (or otherwise as requested by the Congress or the President) related to human spaceflight, planetary science, Earth science, aeronautics, and science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education, as the Board, the President, or the Congress determines the need for such reports.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H498173F9A9234AC8A013BDC9BB5124C6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall provide to the President and the Congress, not later than the later of 180 days after the establishment of the Board or the third quarterly meeting of the Board, and once every 4 years thereafter, a review of current space programs and a vision for future space exploration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE38A548068534C4DAFE8791040FB7116"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Removal of Administrator for cause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may provide to the President and the Congress a report recommending the removal of the Administrator for cause. Any such report shall include the reasons for such recommendation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6FF74B092D749A3A72D76994F636B8E"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Budget meetings</header><text>Portions of Board meetings in which the Board considers the budget proposal required under subsection (l)(1) for a particular fiscal year may be closed to the public until the Board submits the proposal to the President and the Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H21FD88B3B3154A05BDB279FD2CF95217"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Financial disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Board shall be required to file a financial disclosure report under title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App. 92 Stat. 1836), except that such reports shall be held confidential and exempt from any law otherwise requiring their public disclosure.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8A112BA97195488E8644246E8D924A48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end of the items for subchapter II the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BC44077542F4E7D93ADB201C8B02C8C" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">20118. Board of Directors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HF580F94CA6E94D3ABDCD030E4931AE86"><enum>4.</enum><header>Budget proposal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 30103 of title 51, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9775D776EB38412C808FEAECC0F2B158" style="USC">
				<subsection id="HE27E10A0F6C84676BE63545562186EE2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Board of Directors proposal</header>
 <paragraph id="HB4019923814446CCB95F085CE508023F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inclusion in President’s proposed budget</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The proposed budget for the Administration submitted to the Congress by the President for each fiscal year shall include a description of, and a detailed justification for, any differences between the President’s proposed budget and the budget provided by the Board of Directors under section 20118(l)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF29577FC1D814BB78256E159CF2B4641"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements of budget proposal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a) through (d) of this section shall apply to the proposed budget provided by the Board of Directors under section 20118(l)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H2BA0D4FA453B457BA1778D268E135D13"><enum>5.</enum><header>Long-term contracting</header>
 <subsection id="HD1A19188814D47F792E24F37756D4B4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 20142 of title 51, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0C3ACADE4C5345AFA34CA17115F238E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Contracts regarding expendable launch vehicles</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Long-term contracting</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H115047E4831E471589D73CBFDBA8AC6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE8A009F1B184EF2902F17027AF60EB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>striking <quote>expendable launch vehicle services</quote> and inserting <quote>rocket propulsion systems and manned and unmanned space transportation vehicles and payloads, including expendable launch vehicles, and any other infrastructure intended for placement or operation in space or on celestial bodies, and services related thereto,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F9D6BB360DC470BA40AA798F519F0B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>striking <quote>related to launch</quote> and inserting <quote>related to</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H561AF28B1C6E4F41ABE32D6CB99E7863"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>launch services</quote> and inserting <quote>the goods and services to have been provided under the contract</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DC32E23A6714322AD8AA8DB3C9CA51B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of sections amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The item relating to section 20142 in the table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2222D9A52BA43469A36F8A6EBA33FEF" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">20142. Long-term contracting.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


