<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA52811A0EB7E449B825168C8C4FE68FB" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1314 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a right to an administrative appeal relating to adverse determinations of tax-exempt status of certain organizations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1314</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a right to an administrative appeal
			 relating to adverse determinations of tax-exempt status of certain
			 organizations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB17F9808113E4BBF91943403EBE0BD40" style="OLC">
		<section id="H38C92EEB813D4E63841B1FADD1340181" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Administrative appeal relating to adverse determinations of tax-exempt status of certain
			 organizations</header>
 <subsection id="H0F39FC48B0F94198AB6FF3FD89E1EBC7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7123">Section 7123</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end of the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H0B2131CD8F32441FB31A5E9B1499F88E" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HF2B70E83A7A54FB3A1BDA1325182F743"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative appeal relating to adverse determination of tax-Exempt status of certain organizations</header> <paragraph id="HF1675A0E16BA4EFFA00CB9724E7602B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe procedures under which an organization described in section 501(c) may request an administrative appeal (including a conference relating to such appeal if requested by the organization) to the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals of an adverse determination described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11B1E94275964562B78619776F1BF5C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adverse determinations</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), an adverse determination is described in this paragraph is such determination is adverse to an organization with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2F670FE282124557860A8993FE05A285"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the initial qualification or continuing qualification of the organization as exempt from tax under section 501(a) or as an organization described in section 170(c)(2),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1221063BAE844DFBD22EB61AF1E9F45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the initial classification or continuing classification of the organization as a private foundation under section 509(a), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D151DDFF2B8414390FCB10BC5F2FCD1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the initial classification or continuing classification of the organization as a private operating foundation under section 4942(j)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8EF954A3F704F3AB9A0C90BB4483FB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to determinations made on or after May 19, 2014.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

