<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9200F135554742DB83A8B06E4AFEE609" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1129 IH: Veterans’ Whistleblower and Patient Protection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1129</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish within the Department of Veterans Affairs an Office of Whistleblower and Patient Protection.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3634020678FD46298E3A7745A673F230" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H65EB48DC46354F91B202AB789F120FDC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans’ Whistleblower and Patient Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1A37A53EE1674931B9619F3C0112E8E8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Office of Whistleblower and Patient Protection</header> <subsection id="HB4EDDFE6F14A46A8970F166136069218"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/319">section 319</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFD8AE86D4AF4BA285B9BC318C860D63" style="USC">
<section id="H3C9592CE59EB43C0B8741F190A432857"><enum>319A.</enum><header>Office of Whistleblower and Patient Protection</header>
<subsection id="H6601C073F07543D385A84BE2F711B8A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEEF68FC5CB304EB5A7096FED5E4A0980"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in the Department an Office of Whistleblower and Patient Protection (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>). There is at the head of the Office a Director appointed by the Secretary solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8A916A49334C4A4EBF89314A0C1E636F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall be a career appointee in the Senior Executive Service.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H17B4FB7D5CF84E0DB798454CEC2C1097" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director reports directly to the Secretary concerning matters within the responsibility of the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D95FF3ACDDC492FA3C281C40A05F21F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Complaints</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2A02B618C58E40F1981D228B907F339A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall establish a dedicated Internet website and toll-free telephone number for an individual, regardless of whether the individual is an employee of the Department, to file a covered complaint directly to the Office.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD787B4E9D8F4490EA087B7D3FF5C83FA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9896E3E1EB754D258E93DAB554B0011C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to covered complaints filed directly with the Office pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall refer to the Director any covered complaint that the Secretary receives directly, including pursuant to the Patient Advocacy Program of the Veterans Health Administration or other similar program, or that is transmitted to the Secretary pursuant to section 1213 of title 5. In accordance with subsection (c), the Director shall investigate each such complaint.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H73681C005FA047AEA8A86FA98A0072E8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not refer a covered complaint that the Secretary receives as described in subparagraph (A) to any element of the Department, including the Office of Medical Inspection, other than the Office.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HDFB50C3E40BA4CDE8219021A3DA78C30" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that employees of the Department who are located at a medical facility are able to efficiently refer to the Director any covered complaints received at such medical facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A5556B60428421B8AD4FFEFCB6916BB" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The identity of any individual who files a covered complaint may not be disclosed by the Director without the consent of such individual unless the Director determines that the disclosure of the identity of the individual is necessary because of an imminent danger to public health or safety or imminent violation of any criminal law.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H884987AD91754D0EA2A728593892FB36"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investigation and determination</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA8E4BC75C1B34E78BAAA33FAA1B17634"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall investigate each covered complaint that the Office receives directly pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (b) or that the Secretary refers to the Director as described in paragraph (2)(A) of such subsection to determine whether there is a substantial likelihood that the covered complaint discloses a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or gross mismanagement, gross waste of funds, abuse of authority, or substantial and specific danger to public health and safety. The Director shall make such determination not later than 240 days after the date on which the Director receives the covered complaint. The Director is the only official of the Department of Veterans Affairs who may conduct an investigation that is required to be conducted by the Department pursuant to section 1213 of title 5.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75623D545ED8421B8AC08EE12EC5E7FA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Director makes a positive determination under paragraph (1) regarding a covered complaint, the Director shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H492BC92466E442589342D43D77C704EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the Secretary of such determination, including the basis for such determination and recommendations for actions to address such covered complaint; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5579A03A9B104AC889A4E80B4CE65BCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as appropriate, refer the covered complaint to the head of the appropriate department or agency of the Federal Government, including the Attorney General, Special Counsel, or the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC4661827D4ED4451A25DF2B478099611" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEECF9BC65DCD4645AFC74C52C3E1CE0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Director does not make a positive determination under paragraph (1) regarding a covered complaint, the Director—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HF5F244ABDEE543F7BDC6EA50BC99E7BC" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>upon the consent of the individual who filed the complaint, may transmit the complaint to the Secretary; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H83B1A71D00EE4366B25FF0AE9B4D3C7B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the Director does not transmit the complaint under clause (i), shall inform the individual of—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H010F2EAA082C40A483B8CA091F57123E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reasons for such determination; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="HB6B0CA7309A243F3A3E7B7DDD826685C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other offices of the Federal Government available for receiving such complaints if the individual wishes to pursue the matter further.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H39BE7469AF264DF7A8050B96E8712155" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within a reasonable time after a covered complaint is transmitted under subparagraph (A)(i), the Secretary shall inform the Director in writing of what action has been or is being taken and when such action will be completed. The Director shall inform the individual who filed the complaint of the report of the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HE9F46F859BC64F6B8E5AED328A70E1AF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Staff and resources</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF73B341A96984188ADBCC988DFBC2305"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Office shall employ a sufficient number of attorneys, investigators, and other personnel as are necessary to carry out the functions of the Office, including personnel with expertise in health care matters. Attorneys shall be compensated at a level commensurate with attorneys employed by the Office of the General Counsel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HDA8FFE644B7D4D12BC51C15D0030F78E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the Director is furnished sufficient resources in addition to personnel under paragraph (1) to enable the Director to carry out the functions of the Office in a timely manner.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HC0F21C28D99846B1B45A3E83F784A3B0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties of the Office, the Director shall coordinate with the Inspector General of the Department and the Special Counsel to ensure that the actions of the Director are not duplicative with the Inspector General or the Special Counsel.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H51ADA952DF0244B6B03FD38DD39298D2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H57F116DFCBD54A0EB99839BAFFCEF27A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>During each 90-day period, the Director shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H7163E3A93B464D60A13DCBD1CA83A819" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The findings and recommendations made by the Director to the Secretary during the previous 90-day period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4704E12461D54FFE8C3717D6DD222ABB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to such recommendations, whether the Secretary has made any actions based on such findings during such period.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H546F342ABEB4476E941D6F185DE920C5" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>During such period—</text> <clause id="HAC0ADA267EC3453CA533C4C25A7F30D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of covered complaints received by the Director;</text></clause>
<clause id="H01AA86EF5EE94F1791CB1CBCCBEB82A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of investigations commenced;</text></clause> <clause id="H9AF55FB7ECBB47BE9D0F2BAFE1EFEC8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of positive determinations made under paragraph (2) of subsection (c);</text></clause>
<clause id="H3A6C99E148BB41A1B5C2C4B538731911"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of covered complaints for which a positive determination was not made pursuant to paragraph (3)(A) of such subsection; and</text></clause> <clause id="H192A2B5DD9CB4B498B0937B2578F3D81"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of covered complaints transmitted to the Secretary under such paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4C9798E2158B411DADD686F5128C8ACC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During each 180-day period, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes each report described in paragraph (1) submitted during the previous 180-day period and any legislative recommendations of the Secretary to address problems or concerns regarding the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HAF76D5F12854480C99FD65077CB7A7F6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Covered complaint defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered complaint</term> means a complaint regarding—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC84DE263064E40C786A6F6681B9CB23A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an alleged prohibited personnel practice committed by an officer or employee of the Department and described in section 2302(b)(8) or 2302(b)(9)(A)(i), (B), (C), or (D) of title 5; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H93879DD6658B4D37ACC601B1857F2978"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the safety of a patient at a medical facility of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HB8DBF51BF7BD49C782F39F3C9F5227C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 319 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21041D8D461C4DA6AD23925452A630C2" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">319A. Office of Whistleblower and Patient Protection.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

