<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB4B483B4C17A437A910842CC6EE55B3D" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 70 IH: Deficit Reduction, Job Creation, and Energy Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 70</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the National
			 Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to initiate immediate action to
			 create jobs in America, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9E190105487247EF8CDB9CE5CC4DB60E" style="OLC">
		<section id="HBC4AA9D3D54F4C66A2E4F4B9283E4DF4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
			<subsection id="H2AFCD379FD1E46AB80B15C134CA1BF8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Deficit Reduction, Job Creation, and Energy Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE7A8FF0078B74B68B0CB881DCC988094"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HBC4AA9D3D54F4C66A2E4F4B9283E4DF4" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HAD05AD62122E45EC9987AAE8273551E4" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H54D284585F854DDE86EF694FDBB331A3" level="section">Sec. 3. Purposes.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H01C847F710014777A2B88115EC0315C2" level="section">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBBDD2DB7CC8D4475AEFB574D58641207" level="title">Title I—Deficit Reduction Energy Security</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H45485B049A1C45A4A54EC32B83180351" level="section">Sec. 101. Deficit Reduction Acreage.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H03439141ED5B440BAF988C9BD84F9BDA" level="section">Sec. 102. Deficit Reduction Energy Security Fund and Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health
			 Fund.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8CB1121B880B4F7B95D93D4D326112E4" level="section">Sec. 103. Coastal and Ocean Disaster Grant Program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA2DE596D5BC54584ADF2C297DF2CF35B" level="section">Sec. 104. National Grant Program for Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H19F24ECCA70F42E2B0390E11D6ADDBEB" level="section">Sec. 105. Eligible uses of grants.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD03F892E509741AFB2B8D75DBCF2ACDE" level="section">Sec. 106. Grant application.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC31EA490F99149D0A836D3D52C484CE1" level="title">Title II—Timely issuance of offshore oil and gas leases</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1044B60C28BE4B14A02244A8784ECBAF" level="section">Sec. 201. Reinstatement of offshore oil and gas leases.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC99C7FF47F6140C99DA1393B06669EC4" level="section">Sec. 202. Effective and efficient environmental review.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H341E47825CEC4075B40F87840D630EAA" level="title">Title III—Office of Energy Employment and Training and Office of Minority and Women Inclusion</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4DCA0C10C66644A190DB49E12BFB7CB9" level="section">Sec. 301. Establishment of Office of Energy Employment and Training.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEC9AD55DEB8D4595851707B288A1F7E7" level="section">Sec. 302. Office of Minority and Women Inclusion.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HAF44C92A978B4748B47F8091941D8590" level="title">Title IV—Miscellaneous provisions</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H619E9A40739E426FBD666D1A9FED142D" level="section">Sec. 401. Reporting.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="HAD05AD62122E45EC9987AAE8273551E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds and declares the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H1B5E53C2DC3C4FC49E23FFFD66EE6D02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Nation is currently experiencing a national employment emergency, and urgent action is needed
			 to put Americans back to work in well-paid, long-term jobs.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H2B3BD2E60CFF4D98BF43BF4F84E2AD1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Federal Government distributed over $10,000,000,000 to Federal, State, and Indian accounts from
			 energy production during fiscal year 2009, primarily from oil and natural
			 gas production.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HE53A70D67C7C4790A56C34D0D404B47B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The domestic oil and natural gas industry is responsible for approximately 9.2 million jobs.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H82CD3C493F4A4A5F8FB501ADB7D4AA07"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The approximately 43 million leased Outer Continental Shelf acres currently account for about 15
			 percent of America’s domestic natural gas production and about 27 percent
			 of America’s domestic oil production.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H6B19241942B54520A01F1C147A0B9B72"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The leasing of these domestic offshore areas for oil and natural gas development provides
			 significant economic benefits to the Federal Government, as well as to
			 States and localities, through the creation and sustenance of jobs and
			 domestic product.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H3435F700CC1B49CD9D260F8260C5D34F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of the Interior’s Bureau of Ocean Energy Management currently has authorities under
			 the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>) and related
			 laws that can be effectively utilized to create jobs and revitalize the
			 Nation’s economy.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H85A7E8AD8C1D4880B8D3FE63C38D5462"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Effective and expedited development of Gulf of Mexico oil and natural gas resources could generate
			 thousands of new jobs, many of which could be created almost immediately.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB918D81C79F94A159F2BE05ACFC8838D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The coastal regions of the United States have high productivity and contribute approximately 50
			 percent of the gross domestic product of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC644FD56142D4C8997E728DDF2871DBC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The economies and social structure of many communities are dependent on resources from ocean,
			 coastal, and Great Lakes ecosystems.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HE4D72EB0F12640E4ABEEFB2F67F04CFA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Supporting science, research, monitoring, modeling, forecasting, exploration, and assessment will
			 continue to improve our understanding of the ocean, coastal, and Great
			 Lakes ecosystems as well as their long-term economic sustainability.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H8983218161194C439EAC07BFA55A3DC3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Safeguarding these ecosystems is crucial to protecting the environment and waters of the United
			 States.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HD0FF2BDC46724462942C2FD4E5E0F14E"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The growth of our energy domestic resources is vital to America’s national security.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H54D284585F854DDE86EF694FDBB331A3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="HC76C5B0CF21542C997012D703C3BEE7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Require the Secretary of the Interior to utilize its authorities regarding the leasing and
			 development of offshore oil and gas resources to accelerate job creation
			 and economic revitalization to the fullest extent practicable, taking into
			 account the Department of the Interior’s responsibilities regarding
			 conservation, safety, and protection of the environment.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H0E3A3114A366452E8D4CE08382C1E276"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Promote expansion of domestic employment opportunities.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H28ED2112F75E4CDF8EBF1B3F5B6A0EA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Respond to the Nation’s increased need for domestic oil and natural gas resources.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC76B5C6B6A415786BA99BCF4523A77"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Support the utilization of the Outer Continental Shelf for oil and gas production and transmission.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H82D4338A73C74C67B910818A9BFD4953"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Protect, conserve, restore, and understand the oceans, coasts, and Great Lakes of the United
			 States, ensuring present and future generations will benefit from the full
			 range of ecological, economic, educational, social, cultural, nutritional,
			 and recreational opportunities and services those resources are capable of
			 providing.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H98E03E3D32CA477FB3FC2B94A2C8273D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Confirm and ensure the validity of appropriate oil and gas leases issued under the Final Outer
			 Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program, 2007–2012.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HF4C6090D1C814F87B43047B209D175F4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ensure the continued leasing of Outer Continental Shelf areas pursuant to the Final Outer
			 Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program, 2007–2012.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H01C847F710014777A2B88115EC0315C2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H3838F011C8164F96AC07F0AE552D69B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>Act</term> means the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HBCDAAC5946EB414884E2F507B0701FE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>coastal State</term> has the same meaning that the term <quote>coastal state</quote> has in the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1451">16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H88180BF198F6438EBB79F2CE465E9FEE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>DRES Fund</term> means the Deficit Reduction Energy Security Fund.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB99DC88CB870492D90F71CC207625E7A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>COSH Fund</term> means the Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health Fund established by section 102.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H72BEAC2ABF224DF1900B3F3D7B932625"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>program</term> means a Final Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program issued under section 18 of the
			 Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H4B8DE9482715459786F8512536086081"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric
			 Administration.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H5EDBDA252B1A4AFD94246BB2B7C423A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Other terms shall have the same meaning such terms have under the Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="HBBDD2DB7CC8D4475AEFB574D58641207"><enum>I</enum><header>Deficit Reduction Energy Security</header>
			<section id="H45485B049A1C45A4A54EC32B83180351"><enum>101.</enum><header>Deficit Reduction Acreage</header>
				<subsection id="HF3E30D6598204875958500A6B8954FD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall, during the period covered by the Proposed Outer Continental
			 Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program for 2012–2017 issued by the Department
			 of the Interior, and in addition to the acreage proposed to be leased
			 under such program, conduct oil and gas lease sales under the Outer
			 Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>) for additional
			 acreage of the outer Continental Shelf (as that term is used in that Act)
			 that total 10 percent of the acreage proposed to be leased under such
			 program. The acreage for which lease sales are required under this section
			 shall be known as the Deficit Reduction Acreage.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H411BFD412FFD465FB17C39510ABA7BBE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In each year in such period, the Secretary shall lease 20 percent of the Deficit Reduction Acreage.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H03439141ED5B440BAF988C9BD84F9BDA"><enum>102.</enum><header>Deficit Reduction Energy Security Fund and Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health Fund</header>
				<subsection id="H156D04C164C94B61869AE881F61C6815"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deficit Reduction Energy Security Fund</header>
					<paragraph id="H518B64410B0C4CA3B2CE8DF08262C723"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby established in the Treasury a separate account to be known as the Deficit Reduction
			 Energy Security Fund, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or
			 credited to it.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H6F75432219C54637A226B7CD9819B5C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposit of Deficit Reduction Acreage lease revenues</header>
						<subparagraph id="HF4735A5CAA8645D7B88D3D405636A001"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), all rentals, royalties, bonus bids, and other sums due and
			 payable to the United States under Deficit Reduction Acreage lease sales
			 during the 15-fiscal-year period beginning with the first fiscal year in
			 which such sums are received by the United States shall be deposited in
			 the DRES fund.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8E92A9459324B67A84AFD73222816FC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Holding of oil and gas revenues</header><text>Any amount deposited into the DRES Fund under subparagraph (A)—</text>
							<clause id="HB697169FADD44F79A4EB63AAF02053A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall remain in DRES Fund and be invested in accordance with paragraph (2) until the end of the
			 second full fiscal year after the amount is deposited into the DRES Fund;
			 and</text>
							</clause><clause id="H171B1DFAE4FB4BCFB1C70DFD49CDCC17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon the end of such fiscal year, shall be transferred to the general fund and applied solely to
			 reduce the annual Federal budget deficit.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD644F2B126314DD3861830B51D08AE78"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Payments to States not affected</header><text>This Act shall not affect any requirement under other law to pay to States amounts received by the
			 United States as such royalties, bonus bids, and other sums due and
			 payable to the United States.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC2D29AA7690475C9780044734DDDEFA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investment</header>
						<subparagraph id="HC659DEDDD11F4744A3757C3B1BEA729C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the DRES Fund shall be invested by the Secretary of the Treasury in accordance with
			 <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9602">section 9602</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE23874934F0045D49DB84FFF04FE9831"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of interest in DRES Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All interest earned on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in
			 the DRES Fund—</text>
							<clause id="HEEEFE0E3DF154920B1E3ED278D276A0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be credited to and form part of the DRES Fund; and</text>
							</clause><clause id="HD250528C7EE04A02A3CB53C2E9CBA859"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall remain in the DRES Fund until transferred under paragraph (5), without regard to paragraph
			 (2)(B)(ii).</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE16DFC03E9C645B19DC6F608B0D8A64E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Availability of proceeds of deposits</header><text>Amounts credited to the DRES Fund under paragraph (3)(B) in excess of the amounts deposited into
			 the DRES Fund under paragraph (2) shall—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H838D23B056EA4192B0AA185D52DDA351"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be available for expenditure, without further appropriation, solely for the purpose of and
			 activities eligible under this Act; and</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H039A8F2E791D400EA3E44845BF4176C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>remain available until expended, without fiscal year limitation.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H166C0D2387FA4ABFAF41CF0D13557CBA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transfer of interest to Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the transfer of an amount under paragraph (2)(B)(ii), the interest earned on such amount shall
			 be transferred to the Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health Fund
			 established under subsection (b).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9BD034E07254758BB1F84C9F0F1D085"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health Fund</header>
					<paragraph id="HEB179CCC55734791997BD8AEB343DEF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby established in the Treasury a separate account to be known as the Coastal and Ocean
			 Sustainability and Health Fund, consisting of such amounts of interest as
			 are transferred to it under subsection (a)(5).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H950D4FF5B70F40B590199F3F48BC9B37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Of the amounts transferred to the COSH Fund under subsection (a)(5) each fiscal year—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HE1A6482B0BCD42ABBF74A3D242918A3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 5 percent shall be available to the Secretary of Commerce to administer this title;
			 and</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3349BBA16754BFFA34F21926ACA6631"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the remainder shall be available to the Secretary of Commerce until expended and without fiscal
			 year limitation, for use for—</text>
							<clause id="H94E33C47527C44FE98A753A691168AFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Coastal and Ocean Disaster Grant Program under section 102; and</text>
							</clause><clause id="HC89EB36CB15E4B6B95DD0D583064D9AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Grant Program under section 103.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE96052B83A64D158F57E9CEB115A3C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allocation of funding for grant programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of amounts available under paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary of Commerce shall allocate—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H539E1A392F21445FBB6CEB2D41110313"><enum>(A)</enum><text>40 percent for the Coastal and Ocean Disaster Grant Program under section 103, of which—</text>
							<clause id="H4FC5BB36525C41EDAE8542C9D9989F8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>50 percent shall be allocated equally among impacted coastal States;</text>
							</clause><clause id="HD35B82D72B8D4B949F5D56762B80CDA0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>20 percent shall be allocated based on intensity of impact of disasters on impacted coastal States;</text>
							</clause><clause id="H9A62C22D904E4939A9CC9B5E00109E29"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>15 percent shall be allocated based on tidal shorelines of impacted coastal States; and</text>
							</clause><clause id="H84AB1925040544B59C50C525BB249169"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>15 percent of the funds shall be allocated based on the coastal population of impacted coastal
			 States.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E0CB1842845431D9BF28F6FF04D1729"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Sixty percent for the National Grant Program for Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health under
			 section 104, of which—</text>
							<clause id="H2B09F0BF7B2E435F886D55FB06A8763C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>50 percent shall be allocated to coastal States;</text>
							</clause><clause id="H50AD0D3A618945ED92CB698B62A27D26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>50 percent shall be allocated to any State, local, territory, and tribal governments, institutions
			 of higher learning, and non-profit and for-profit organizations that may
			 receive and expend Federal funds as legal entities; and</text>
							</clause><clause id="HC8F7ACB9E0184E57835C8875639927ED"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>no more than 10 percent of the total amount of funds available shall be allocated to a single State
			 or entity in a fiscal year.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DC28AD563EC4135B9C0E794CDBE6F0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>General administrative charges prohibited</header><text>Grants issued under this Act shall not be subject to a general administrative charge.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HEEBEE999769C48CAA51E4810974B7042"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Redeposit of unused funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds provided as a grant under this title that are not used by the grantee by the end of the
			 fiscal year following the first fiscal year for which they were allocated
			 shall be redeposited into the COSH Fund and be reallocated in accordance
			 with this section.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H8CB1121B880B4F7B95D93D4D326112E4"><enum>103.</enum><header>Coastal and Ocean Disaster Grant Program</header>
				<subsection id="HF24184BD05504642BD6629171205D550"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall use amounts allocated under section 102(b)(2)(B)(i) to make grants
			 to coastal States and Indian tribes impacted by coastal or ocean disasters
			 for the purposes of restoring, mitigating, monitoring, or otherwise
			 managing coastal and ocean natural resources impacted by such disasters.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H2C04B05061A940E1AB9EBF3AEA6FFC00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header>
					<paragraph id="H9569FD7D90DC4064A1F9AE3F16D33D65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First 5 years</header><text>During the 5-fiscal year period beginning with the first fiscal year for which amounts are
			 available for grants under this section, a coastal State or Indian tribe
			 shall be eligible for a grant under this section only if—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HDCB1877B07E4438094284CC56B5ADB10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>it is one of the States of Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, and Florida, or an Indian tribe
			 in such State; or</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECECACCE105F413AA63A4E87A0758B18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>it is determined by the Secretary, in that period, to be a coastal State that has been impacted by
			 a coastal or ocean disaster.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AB62E69354C40728FFFA7870E05D9DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>After first 5 years</header><text>After the end of such 5-fiscal-year period, if the Secretary determines for a fiscal year that
			 there is no coastal State that has been so impacted, the amount allocated
			 for that fiscal year for grants under this section shall be added to the
			 amounts allocated for that fiscal year under section 102(b)(2)(B)(ii) for
			 the National Grant Program for Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and
			 Health.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HB0AEB09493EE401289A12AAA62A3F89C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A coastal State or Indian tribe shall not be eligible for a grant under this section if it is
			 receiving assistance under another Federal law for an activity described
			 in section 105(b) conducted for a purpose referred to in subsection (a).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA2DE596D5BC54584ADF2C297DF2CF35B"><enum>104.</enum><header>National Grant Program for Coastal and Ocean Sustainability and Health</header>
				<subsection id="H001C3C502D204FAABC347CF24ACB17E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall use amounts allocated under section 102(b)(2)(B)(ii) (including
			 amounts added under section 103(b)(2)) to make grants to coastal States
			 that are eligible under subsection (b).</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HBC8DECCB2EE3489595197CAE55C48E64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this section, a person—</text>
					<paragraph id="HE74B7BCC65B741AAA8A68843E9E7EF79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>must be—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H867B11A3106348CD9BBA5254C8E1EEC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a coastal State that has a management program approved by the Secretary under section 306 of the
			 Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1455">16 U.S.C. 1455</external-xref>); or</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB67BD500CE9243B88B254A0BE1CB8DB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State, local, territory, or tribal government, institution of higher learning, or nonprofit or
			 and for-profit organization that may receive and expend Federal funds as a
			 legal entity; and</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4897492ABEB447FBB95041A00EB6A0C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>must submit to the Secretary a multiyear plan for use of the grant that—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HDA0B6A7F12D64CFDB51D91B5A8C3E66A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifies how the grant funds will be allocated;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AC25B805CD84992B952F42DC18AD9DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is sufficiently flexible to allow the coastal State to respond to emerging needs; and</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D33A7283D594058BE605AF5564D0950"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is approved by the Secretary.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H19F24ECCA70F42E2B0390E11D6ADDBEB"><enum>105.</enum><header>Eligible uses of grants</header>
				<subsection id="HB1537055C7B34E78886A62FAD5A5D14C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts provided as a grant under this title shall be used for activities described in subsection
			 (b) that are intended to restore, protect, maintain, manage, or understand
			 marine resources and their habitats and resources in coastal and ocean
			 waters, including baseline scientific research and other activities
			 carried out in coordination with Federal and State departments or
			 agencies, that are consistent with Federal environmental laws, and that
			 avoid environmental degradation.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H347C1F2D2FD54FAFBA807DA2D9FAD43D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Included activities</header><text>Activities referred to in subsection (a) include—</text>
					<paragraph id="HF97101A5C0C94BDEB09EDC068F306F85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coastal management planning and implementation under the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HD841C005FAD241A789365D9712A6F58B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coastal and estuarine land protection, including the protection of the environmental integrity of
			 important coastal and estuarine areas, such as wetlands and forests, that
			 have significant conservation, recreation, ecological, historical, or
			 aesthetic values, or that are threatened by conversion to other uses;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HDDB3AFE045E34D57B4D20C2D20C7D79C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>efforts to protect and manage living marine resources, including fisheries, coral reefs, research,
			 management, and enhancement;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H10DE262BB7604471829E684EF4A2B204"><enum>(4)</enum><text>programs, activities, and new technology designed to improve or complement the management and
			 mission of national marine sanctuaries, marine monuments, national
			 estuarine research reserves, and marine protected areas;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HB30EB7CDE84D448FB91A2691F049AC90"><enum>(5)</enum><text>mitigation, restoration, protection, and relocation of coastal communities threatened by the
			 impacts of climate change;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H06172C5D207B490BBB882898DD21265F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>mitigation of the effects of offshore activities, including environmental restoration;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H17BD15E87EDD4C5A8448F691C04A6654"><enum>(7)</enum><text>efforts to acquire, protect and restore coastal lands and wetlands, and to restore or prevent
			 damage to wetlands in the coastal zone, coastal estuaries, and lands,
			 life, and property in the coastal zone;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H1FBD7971D40F4F6DB18948B011FE8E79"><enum>(8)</enum><text>management of non-point sources of coastal and marine pollution;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H5201D6FE9D954BCEB5D0F3F1698E02FB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>long-term coastal and ocean research and education, monitoring, and natural resource management;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H4B50DC5F98264A609D824B7713359E4C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>regional multi-State management efforts designed to manage, protect, or restore the coastal zone
			 and ocean resources; or</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H32A67473C0534BE5ACBC821531D32982"><enum>(11)</enum><text>management and administration of authorized activities.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD03F892E509741AFB2B8D75DBCF2ACDE"><enum>106.</enum><header>Grant application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A person seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such
			 time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary
			 determines to be appropriate.</text>
			</section></title><title id="HC31EA490F99149D0A836D3D52C484CE1"><enum>II</enum><header>Timely issuance of offshore oil and gas leases</header>
			<section id="H1044B60C28BE4B14A02244A8784ECBAF"><enum>201.</enum><header>Reinstatement of offshore oil and gas leases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 18 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the
			 end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EEC5EAF0F224204B7F178958483F219" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H4BC3F3BE0EA74BD9AB907E5C8FE432B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized, upon petition of a prior leaseholder, to reinstate any Expired
			 Producible Lease in the offshore Gulf of Mexico if such reinstatement
			 furthers the purposes and objectives of this Act. The Secretary shall act
			 on such petitions as soon as possible after receipt thereof, and in any
			 event, within 90 days of receipt of such petition or prior to the next
			 scheduled lease sale in which such lease would be included, whichever is
			 earlier. Any lease application pending for more than 90 days shall be
			 reported to Congress, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Assistant
			 Secretary for Land Management every 15 days until the application is acted
			 upon.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="HC99C7FF47F6140C99DA1393B06669EC4"><enum>202.</enum><header>Effective and efficient environmental review</header>
				<subsection id="HF973732796A6441E98A17A9DF5EFA0DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Completion of analyses for lease sales</header><text>The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, complete all analyses, processes, and
			 procedures required by section 18 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) or under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>; referred to in this section as <term>NEPA</term>), in connection with exploration and development under any lease to be offered for sale under this
			 Act, prior to the annual lease sale in which such lease is first offered.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HC112DDFC518D4D99878210C168D9129C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of Secretary’s actions</header><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the Secretary’s actions, after any initial lease
			 sale, in approving and enforcing safety requirements and spill prevention
			 and response requirements in individual plans or permits shall be deemed
			 to be actions for the purpose of conserving and protecting the environment
			 that are not subject to NEPA review requirements.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H341E47825CEC4075B40F87840D630EAA"><enum>III</enum><header>Office of Energy Employment and Training and Office of Minority and Women Inclusion</header>
			<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DCA0C10C66644A190DB49E12BFB7CB9"><enum>301.</enum><header>Establishment of Office of Energy Employment and Training</header>
				<subsection id="H54D6FF29036041759F70E0948ABD47C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall establish an Office of Energy Employment and Training, which
			 shall oversee the efforts of the Department of the Interior’s energy
			 planning, permitting, and regulatory activities to carry out the purposes,
			 objectives, and requirements of this Act.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H53E637225437483B90B520BE930CD546"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header>
					<paragraph id="HDA2244938A3E46BEBD4FCF86BA639DFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be directed by an Assistant Secretary for Energy Employment and Training, who
			 shall report directly to the Secretary and shall be fully employed to
			 carry out the functions of the Office.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HF67815175A874E89A66DBDDD0AC32E77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Energy Employment and Training shall perform the following functions:</text>
						<subparagraph id="H593AC83B89C04178B1DD80F608270FCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Develop and implement systems to track the Department’s compliance with the purposes, objectives,
			 and requirements of the Act.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C863AB5412422A913FA68737867146"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Report at least quarterly to the Secretary regarding the Department’s compliance with the purposes,
			 objectives, and requirements of this Act, including but not limited to
			 specific data regarding the numbers and types of jobs created through the
			 Department’s efforts and a report on all job training programs planned or
			 in progress by the Department.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H952A5A33B60448478BB866B5F4AC2B15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Design and recommend to the Secretary programs and policies aimed at ensuring the Department’s
			 compliance with the purposes, objectives, and requirements of this Act,
			 and oversee implementation of such programs approved by the Secretary.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DD63BC420BA42508DE9A3F863E48D83"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Develop procedures for enforcement of the Department’s requirements and responsibilities under this
			 Act.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7840D708EE0640CEA800DBDA60EF9D04"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Support the activities of the Office of Minority and Women Inclusion and any other offices or
			 branches established by the Secretary within the Office of Energy
			 Employment and Training.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FB63F5A2D114680B3741A00C5951AB0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Assist the Secretary in complying with the reporting requirements of title V of this Act.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEC9AD55DEB8D4595851707B288A1F7E7"><enum>302.</enum><header>Office of Minority and Women Inclusion</header>
				<subsection id="H198B199638A24BFE91E9650CAEE2F730"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of Minority and Women Inclusion</header>
					<paragraph id="HD0BA62D5B65D4E73856F35455CF12FCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall establish an Office of Minority and Women Inclusion not later
			 than 6 months after the effective date of this Act, that shall be
			 responsible for all matters of the Department of the Interior relating to
			 diversity in management, employment, and business activities.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HD63CD57976604145AB7D0362913E7988"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer of responsibilities</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall ensure that the responsibilities described in paragraph (1) (or
			 comparable responsibilities) that are assigned to any other office,
			 agency, or bureau of the Department on the day before the date of
			 enactment of this Act are transferred to the Office of Minority and Women
			 Inclusion.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HF78F52600328472E8026604B6326E0AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties with respect to civil rights laws</header><text>The responsibilities described in paragraph (1) do not include enforcement of statutes,
			 regulations, or Executive orders pertaining to civil rights, except each
			 Director shall coordinate with the Secretary, or the designee of the
			 Secretary, regarding the design and implementation of any remedies
			 resulting from violations of such statutes, regulations, or Executive
			 orders.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF733D9A81EF5407A937D952A40E38625"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header>
					<paragraph id="H1D3D3EA3A7594AD4B8498AB59E3FFEFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall have a Director who shall be appointed by, and shall report to, the Secretary of
			 the Interior. The position of Director shall be a career reserved position
			 in the Senior Executive Service, as that position is defined in section
			 3132 of title 5, United States Code, or an equivalent designation.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H9C5314F434AA4541B2F3C60B53E63135"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director shall develop standards for—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H628D771F57714D7CA4E437B33C507C8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>equal employment opportunity and the racial, ethnic, and gender diversity of the workforce and
			 senior management of the Department;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B4B5234C6E04806A0CC98B052D14E8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increased participation of minority-owned and women-owned businesses in the programs and contracts
			 of the Department, including standards for coordinating technical
			 assistance to such businesses; and</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8A09DECDD0947A1AE533C9B7ABABF29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assessing the diversity policies and practices of entities regulated by the Department.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC8B8807C1464F8ABFDFB54C0EE206D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other duties</header><text>The Director shall advise the Secretary of the Interior on the impact of the policies and
			 regulations of the Department on minority-owned and women-owned
			 businesses.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H7A2D47AD455A494FB8EA6A3255CD7FA3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (2)(C) may be construed to mandate any requirement on or otherwise affect the
			 lending policies and practices of any regulated entity, or to require any
			 specific action based on the findings of the assessment.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE85D6AAB63B4DF29317AB4C161EC71A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion in all levels of business activities</header>
					<paragraph id="H564FEC5E57C64AA2AF621EE24DDF74BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall develop and implement standards and procedures to ensure, to the maximum extent
			 possible, the fair inclusion and utilization of minorities, women, and
			 minority-owned and women-owned businesses in all business and activities
			 of the Department at all levels, including in procurement, insurance, and
			 all types of contracts.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD11DF604E741878D033860BD0D65C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text>The procedures established by the Department for review and evaluation of contract proposals and
			 for hiring service providers shall include, to the extent consistent with
			 applicable law, a component that gives consideration to the diversity of
			 the applicant. Such procedure shall include a written statement, in a form
			 and with such content as the Director shall prescribe, that a contractor
			 shall ensure, to the maximum extent possible, the fair inclusion of women
			 and minorities in the workforce of the contractor and, as applicable,
			 subcontractors.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H4D63C84206D74135BFD0B012D0BC1DFA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header>
						<subparagraph id="H6FA3E2B91FE84491955FAD95761E1E31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The standards and procedures developed and implemented under this subsection shall include a
			 procedure for the Director to make a determination whether a Department
			 contractor, and, as applicable, a subcontractor has failed to make a good
			 faith effort to include minorities and women in their workforce.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AC25C99F1DB42DC941AA2802D84D88B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of determination</header>
							<clause id="H8D233111FE12499E82B5C8A2301CDFD5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Recommendation to Secretary</header><text>Upon a determination described in subparagraph (A), the Director shall make a recommendation to the
			 Secretary that the contract be terminated.</text>
							</clause><clause id="H2AACA315FA364188999732DDC0D7D37A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Action by Secretary</header><text>Upon receipt of a recommendation under clause (i), the Secretary may—</text>
								<subclause id="H6E67A86E8F8C4A75AEEAD8F4BC7443B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>terminate the contract;</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="H6ADC88124A4846BAACBE934C94BB109F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>make a referral to the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs of the Department of Labor;
			 or</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="HB98C2F63A4314DA6B501C709CCE0B5C3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>take other appropriate action.</text>
								</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38A68938171D417C94262C02C2931E3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report regarding the actions taken by the
			 Department of the Interior agency and the Office pursuant to this section,
			 which shall include—</text>
					<paragraph id="HC939AC886EAC4BE8AF01E2C60C57DB03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement of the total amounts paid by the Department to contractors since the previous report;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H5783C5FE891E40D8AEBE602DBFC2E830"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the percentage of the amounts described in paragraph (1) that were paid to contractors described in
			 subsection (c)(1);</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HDC3B50C8D39D4D8CA9EB2654FAB80DB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the successes achieved and challenges faced by the Department in operating minority and women
			 outreach programs;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HDAF2CFB6D01241028402F767FA36832B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the challenges the Department may face in hiring minority and women employees and contracting with
			 minority-owned and women-owned businesses; and</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H369615FC4BC84F3088126CBF9FAC8492"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other information, findings, conclusions, and recommendations for legislative or Department
			 action, as the Director determines appropriate.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6BFBB0544054C5FB7E8DF686521B161"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Diversity in Department workforce</header><text>The Secretary shall take affirmative steps to seek diversity in the workforce of the Department at
			 all levels of the Department in a manner consistent with applicable law.
			 Such steps shall include—</text>
					<paragraph id="H694C062D60CE4757827678882818565E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recruiting at historically black colleges and universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, women’s
			 colleges, and colleges that typically serve majority minority populations;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H3EFD7921073D43FA8EE9A665F2586553"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sponsoring and recruiting at job fairs in urban communities;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HBEE63DF90A4A4E32847CA4C15C2F897C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>placing employment advertisements in newspapers and magazines oriented toward minorities and women;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H20328C38AEDE41FDA2568AC38554A11E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>partnering with organizations that are focused on developing opportunities for minorities and women
			 to be placed in energy industry internships, summer employment, and
			 full-time positions;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H62E004D121DE4A2887320C628571C429"><enum>(5)</enum><text>where feasible, partnering with inner-city high schools, girls’ high schools, and high schools with
			 majority minority populations to establish or enhance financial literacy
			 programs and provide mentoring; and</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HF49624BBA85B45D7B75B6F548671358E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other mass media communications that the Office determines necessary.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8887BE412A534DD281A5768589CCD9FC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text>
					<paragraph id="H3376C6FAA83941A8A593372F773A4C71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minority</header><text>The term <term>minority</term> means United States citizens who are Asian Indian American, Asian Pacific American, Black
			 American, Hispanic American, or Native American.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H65AB0AA2F15F45C5AD34965A61BD1941"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minority-owned business</header><text>The term <term>minority-owned business</term> means a for-profit enterprise, regardless of size, physically located in the United States or its
			 trust territories, which is owned, operated, and controlled by minority
			 group members. <quote>Minority group members</quote> are United States citizens who are Asian Indian American, Asian Pacific American, Black American,
			 Hispanic American, or Native American (terminology in NMSDC categories).
			 Ownership by minority individuals means the business is at least 51
			 percent owned by such individuals or, in the case of a publicly owned
			 business, at least 51 percent of the stock is owned by one or more such
			 individuals. Further, the management and daily operations are controlled
			 by those minority group members. For purposes of NMSDC’s program, a
			 minority group member is an individual who is a United States citizen with
			 at least <fraction>1/4</fraction> or 25 percent minimum (documentation to support claim of 25 percent required from applicant) of
			 one or more of the following:</text>
						<subparagraph id="H2EB438B819AC49C5835C247AAA4E35EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Asian Indian American, which is a United States citizen whose origins are from India, Pakistan, or
			 Bangladesh.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC51962128504233B55591D7C69D9CAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Asian Pacific American, which is a United States citizen whose origins are from Japan, China,
			 Indonesia, Malaysia, Taiwan, Korea, Vietnam, Laos, Cambodia, the
			 Philippines, Thailand, Samoa, Guam, the United States Trust Territories of
			 the Pacific, or the Northern Marianas.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A5719F9D4F14B358EA3D4A3E00993CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Black American, which is a United States citizen having origins in any of the Black racial groups
			 of Africa.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA88F4E8AEDB04CFE95660FE3077EEB5A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Hispanic American, which is a United States citizen of true-born Hispanic heritage, from any of the
			 Spanish-speaking areas of the following regions: Mexico, Central America,
			 South America, and the Caribbean Basin only.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D64BBB1B0974DC484E4DA095462663F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Native American, which is a person who is an American Indian, Eskimo, Aleut or Native Hawaiian, and
			 regarded as such by the community of which the person claims to be a part.
			 Native Americans must be documented members of a North American tribe,
			 band, or otherwise organized group of native people who are indigenous to
			 the continental United States and proof can be provided through a Native.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H543D5640D2ED43048631148C5531BA2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>NMSDC</header><text>The term <term>NMSDC</term> means the National Minority Supplier Development Council.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H6292B9BA329C453CA83BE6391A36B024"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Minority and Women Inclusion established under subsection (a).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H9F5CBA7FA3984116A966D9E53CCD96D6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Women-owned business</header><text>The term <term>women-owned business</term> means a business that can verify through evidence documentation that 51 percent or more is
			 women-owned, managed, and controlled. The business must be open for at
			 least 6 months. The business owner must be a United States citizen or
			 legal resident alien. Evidence must indicate that—</text>
						<subparagraph id="HD7D355BF19414CD08FC2C703BB48FA39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contribution of capital or expertise by the woman business owner is real and substantial and in
			 proportion to the interest owned;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34539BFC120E49EFA57D144847E78AF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the woman business owner directs or causes the direction of management, policy, fiscal, and
			 operational matters; and</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62E8FB4C4D704AD28FC812B005FE5F3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the woman business owner has the ability to perform in the area of specialty or expertise without
			 reliance on either the finances or resources of a firm that is not owned
			 by a woman.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HAF44C92A978B4748B47F8091941D8590"><enum>IV</enum><header>Miscellaneous provisions</header>
			<section id="H619E9A40739E426FBD666D1A9FED142D"><enum>401.</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 12 months of the effective date of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the
			 Interior, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Energy
			 Employment and Training, shall submit a report to Congress on the
			 Department’s compliance with the requirements of titles III and IV,
			 including but not limited to specific information regarding the numbers
			 and types of jobs created through the Department of the Interior’s
			 efforts, the results of the Department’s efforts to enhance the quality
			 and efficiency of planning and permitting processes, and of any actions
			 taken to increase total production and to encourage production early in
			 lease terms.</text>
			</section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


