<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H33B8DA006DA64E5796EEDE56B4CBDBCF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3893 IH: Areawide Integrated Pest Management Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3893</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151103">November 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000596">Mr. Pierluisi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 with respect to
			 grants for certain areawide integrated pest management projects, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7E6B5E8A6E3A4E5980EC9190977250BF" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFB39EFA0D97D4E6196D84EE922DADC3C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Areawide Integrated Pest Management Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AIPM Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDFFF9779158749E5972CA238D66C9CD6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Qualified areawide integrated pest management projects</header> <subsection id="H514BB496BEFC41FE8E6DC6D970457119"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Qualified areawide integrated pest management projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 406 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7626">7 U.S.C. 7626</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H911A28B367CC42CEA537A6DA42E52B81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3AA05EAD6EE547F99924985A367EF7A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture,</quote> after <quote>Secretary of Agriculture</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F67730810E64DEF933ED4D9E11F087F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and qualified areawide integrated pest management projects</quote> before the period at the end;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB9E692612434896BA45C9F57B29AB1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8B02D6AA04044EDBAE77C692A72C11F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture,</quote> after <quote>Secretary</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H723EDB34EC9545A4B143077BA3284174"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and qualified areawide integrated pest management projects</quote> after <quote>extension projects</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1EE5DA2714E4A10A59D574A9C22E62E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>With respect to a grant under this section providing funding for a qualified areawide integrated pest management project, the Secretary may renew such grant for an additional term of a duration to be determined by the Secretary.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0012049EE944D3BBD9064DEDBED9462"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (h); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E5D4E32818F438F92AB0B65D3113688"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following new subsections:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A1EB9F9C170465586068E9490C2F1BA" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H260047CA4CD24F58B274609771A641D3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants providing funding for qualified areawide pest management projects</header>
 <paragraph id="HBEA114DD018C470BB8D0E5EB1676B19A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity seeking a grant under this section providing funding for a qualified areawide integrated pest management project shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time and in such manner and that contains such information as the Secretary may require, including detailed information on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H534A3C80957B4A878AEDC06384C195B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the goals of the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A56BFB261CF47F7A46B18AAC53C563A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any individuals or entities involved in the project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51E4635B33A742F293933FEEC4AC8AD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the projected benefits of the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4119BA21A9E848C4955C7DF5B6DD46BF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">details of the membership of the committee described in subsection (f)(2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81D0526FC6CB4933B3A0504CC8167A5B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how the project may be continued after grant funds are no longer available for such project; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1835E9797634E51915FBFE0623CA101"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the return on investment for the grant funds awarded to fund the project.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0A68CC988E542A2B78E64721095DA6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requests for applications</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF7B1E444ED5D411898E56607F047D002"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Development of requests for applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in consultation with the integrated pest management committee established under section 1408C and other relevant stakeholders, develop requests for applications for qualified areawide integrated pest management projects that are consistent with the priorities established by such committee under such section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EE624BA90C54E63869C051B88D85469"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall solicit proposals for qualified areawide integrated pest management projects under this section by issuing requests for applications on an annual basis. The Secretary may not select new projects to receive funding through a grant under this section if, on the date on which the request is issued, there is not sufficient funding available to fund projects that, as of such date, are not complete and with respect to which grants were awarded under this section for the previous year.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1D0ED260F74941A532CE8F5183853D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection<italic></italic></header>
 <subparagraph id="HE05D0644E8D7441CB98B7460C143A69E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, using a peer-review process, select qualified areawide integrated pest management projects to receive funding through a grant under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FE9722117104669A0AB68540919E8D1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Lead entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting projects under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall designate the college or university or other entity referred to in subsection (b) submitting the application for such project as the lead entity for the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACAA06B763B74C40A0929BA0A15AFA73"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Condition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receiving a grant under this section providing funding for a qualified areawide integrated pest management project, the college or university or other entity referred to in subsection (b) that is the recipient of the grant shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H764CFAFB5C1A42F0B1920CA4EEADA72C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify to the Secretary that the recipient will be carrying out the project in collaboration with—</text> <clause id="H3AB017898F934D4B9EDC62E1F4F989BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Agricultural Research Service of the Department of Agriculture through a subcontractual arrangement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0B7CB1890C5B4427A79A60C78B449EBD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one or more of any of the following entities:</text> <subclause id="HCC50C2BFA50D4680A116AC95354D7258"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A college or university.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H992AFC0F441D40E4900071DFC5EB46DF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A State department of agriculture.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H0796BF2B30EB4BCE981DE30DA7C06DAF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Another Federal agency.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H40D7CC94B11049659E9D7FE6A276DED3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or a regional entity representing a crucial element of the project, such as a State department of natural resources.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7F8281F597D94CA4BA2D471FB4C73655"><enum>(V)</enum><text>A nongovernmental organization;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E89D76A232E47DBB4EBB88613526809"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify that the recipient will transfer the appropriate amount of funds to all entities involved in the project so that research, extension, and education activities carried out under the project are funded as needed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08D9F3FE2D464D48951A1E6E7D03C1C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in cooperation with the Secretary, coordinate efforts conducted by all entities involved in the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54AD6A50B3F94DA8B7BB70D63F929ABB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prepare and submit annual and final reports to the Secretary with respect to the project.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E02E2A68457481DA9145B6A6C1B8228"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualified areawide integrated pest management project defined</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3699EDA3E88F491EBD380B894EFE5E38"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>areawide integrated pest management project</term> means a project that is designed and implemented on a landscape scale or larger—</text> <subparagraph id="HF99E6B606A554E69BAA3F21C6B45BBB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to prevent the spread of pests and invasive species through prevention, avoidance, monitoring, and suppression;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A19E224A37849A5B9625D1852635135"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide educational programs on best management practices with respect to pests and invasive species;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE04095C3294499F91F59152CFE1404C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to control pests and invasive species using physical, mechanical, or cultural controls;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09615F117B9747439F07FB0DD693CF37"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to manage pests and invasive species using biologically-based controls; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54EB0F022A164A3F982EB228D352ADA1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>where appropriate, to manage pests using chemical controls, such as pesticides.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H931819ED05954978BD193BF2FDF0B706"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>qualified areawide integrated pest management project</term> means an areawide integrated pest management project that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFDEFD7990B5740E798290985D9AF1D35"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for significant benefits (as determined by the Secretary) for the prevention, eradication, or management of pests and invasive species;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEF1DCADBD9F45A2840D9D5FA79942D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for economic and environmental benefits to agriculture, individuals, wildlife, and the environment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BB5558503DE43B8BE9F8AE425CE0BB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addresses the annual priorities established by the integrated pest management committee established under section 1408C;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H420A39BD123249F68E44F3103F0B7744"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has a projected duration of not more than 5 years;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H413D1C8DCAEA4F36ACA825777DE36BEA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for the establishment of a regional advisory committee responsible for the oversight of the project in the community, region, or area in which the project is to be carried out; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66C735D6383F4E928628673A691D500F"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for the active involvement of the cooperative extension services (as defined in section 1404 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3103">7 U.S.C. 3103</external-xref>)) to translate the results of the research conducted under the project into practical information and pest management tools for purposes of sharing such results with farmers, foresters, and producers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01789EDD85DE48C3964BB301683C70DF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Ongoing areawide integrated pest management projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of subsection (e) shall not apply with respect to a grant providing funding for integrated agricultural research, education, and extension projects related to integrated pest management awarded before the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Areawide Integrated Pest Management Act of 2015</short-title>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50641FC9292F4232927537D01A39BA47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Areawide integrated pest management committee</header>
 <paragraph id="HE02616306E334070AF7B2F9C501074AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 is amended by inserting after section 1408B (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3123B">7 U.S.C. 3123B</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65BEDAEEE0324AD1AFAC46F8DB94E064" style="OLC">
						<section id="HCBF38FA830A84120AB90C7FF4DBFD7F7"><enum>1408C.</enum><header>Areawide integrated pest management committee</header>
 <subsection id="HC866CFCD814F4DA8A85CA9D9F84C8C7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the executive committee of the Advisory Board shall establish and appoint the initial members of a permanent areawide integrated pest management committee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H35C556BF17CE4036A7206C356AAC8F80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The permanent areawide integrated pest management committee shall, with respect to areawide integrated pest management programs, activities, or projects carried out by the Secretary of Agriculture—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD971FB4DF16E4D5E9A991EB9F7DAE6E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consider stakeholder feedback; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FA2AEE0149E459FA466F463CAE2B03E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the annual and long-term priorities for such programs, activities, or projects.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20B34B921D794C0AAA4FA040FC9E29CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Members</header>
 <paragraph id="HB39509B2353F4600BD03C3067243EAE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals who are not members of the Advisory Board may be appointed as members of the areawide integrated pest management committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E08BC5650404FE9B6AB3962F245B393"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The areawide integrated pest management committee shall be composed of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD2E20994E4F24A6D8051891847BAD48C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Three ex officio members consisting of the following individuals:</text>
 <clause id="H25348ACFB08A4577B7D5CB41001CBE0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Senior Invasive Species Coordinator of the Department of Agriculture. <italic></italic></text> </clause><clause id="H55FA49CEAEFC47B8A34A15BC283374A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Program Leader for Bio-based Pest Management of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA905DB8AE1C548839974822D705F9129"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The National Program Leader for the Invasive Pests of Crops of the Agricultural Research Service.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC7FDCD7855443F48A2EE1D7AD7141D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nine voting members, representing stakeholder groups with experience in areawide research programs carried out by Federal, State, or private entities, to be appointed by the Secretary.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D822405B15442CE8892DB7ADFD8A5B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1413(b) of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3128">7 U.S.C. 3128(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF8C7D9DCA6041899B6290920E6DFAB6" style="traditional">
						<subsection id="HBE11F846EB574568805BF2076DB24C06"><enum>(b)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H161957D960BD47E4863D8533A80F9AF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), members of the Advisory Board who are not otherwise officers or employees of the United States shall serve without compensation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D2C09D157D94EA291F3599EB80F00BB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Members of the Advisory Board who are members of the areawide integrated pest management committee established under section 1408C and who are not otherwise officers or employees of the United States may receive compensation for serving on the committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04484C95B1B942F699348C90E310EE95" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Advisory Board and members of the areawide integrated pest management committee established under section 1408C shall, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services under this title, be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under sections 5701 through 5707 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE558A2FC792B498C9F9662FE6EA5F758"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall transfer to the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, effective not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the authorities (including all budget authorities, available appropriations, and personnel), duties, obligations, and related legal and administrative functions prescribed by law or otherwise granted to any other agency or official of the Department of Agriculture under section 406 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7626">7 U.S.C. 7626</external-xref>). <italic></italic></text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


