<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD01B780FB77347418010E2ED583C4F08" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1843 IH: To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to improve access to supportive services and community coordination for families of disabled veterans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1843</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to improve access to supportive services and community coordination for families of disabled veterans.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H440E7DA06B12449799F3562D32754861" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF7BE9537134A497AAE17DD2AF41D631F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Pilot program for greater direct access to supportive services and community coordination for disabled veterans families</header> 
<subsection id="H00D7EF4C08614BF49C2A8586C706B2EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Commencing not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) shall carry out a three year pilot program with community partners to provide intensive community care coordination and supportive services to disabled veteran families who lack access to VA or other direct wellness services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H07BA3D188A86462198F0259B0C453302"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreements with community partners</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary shall enter into partnership agreements with community partners described in subsection (d) using a competitive and merit-based award process for individual grants and for multi-service site grants to test service delivery efficiencies and generate best practices.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE3E0C927FF974FC782C1C39973E553C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Community care coordination and supportive services</header><text>The focused community care coordination and supportive services referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H683BB7B936CB4FCE85657B9DF5D55432" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Services provided by a community partner to improve the well-being and address the needs of disabled veteran families who otherwise lack access to adequate VA or other direct wellness services. Such assistance and services may include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFB18BA2ED80C433E9A58FB91D5D26EC8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Care coordination and case management services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB77F13A42854338893BF840412024B1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Outreach services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13F65B382ED24B5285EB6027E2074000" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Assistance in obtaining any benefits from the VA which the veteran may be eligible to receive, including, but not limited to, vocational and rehabilitation counseling, employment and training service, educational assistance, and health care services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46A455A745CF46A09FC04A88CE06CA04" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Assistance in obtaining and coordinating the provision of other public benefits provided in federal, state or local agencies or other community partners, defined in subsection (d), including—</text> 
<clause id="H62C32D9843694E0BBEA2DEC8517B3571" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>marriage counseling;</text></clause> <clause id="H3E729B42DCF74DCAB1EA699F133A674E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>services for children;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H77B10A259A1846B18546920D7C995496" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>suicide prevention;</text></clause> <clause id="HD2BDA0BC63F44192AC294211C17CB30D" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>substance abuse awareness and treatment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD08C74CC468D423C908FC27B2CD7A3E6" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>mental health awareness and treatment;</text></clause> <clause id="HD454A7C1A1E8450C9310BB8411960AF8" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>financial counseling;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H04582F5A4AA14074AA714C55018F6500" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>anger management counseling;</text></clause> <clause id="HB150C2AF2D5F419591CB263C12A86CEB" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>domestic violence awareness and prevention;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6BCE3FB164FD4A3A9931AE167D8C9E08" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>employment assistance;</text></clause> <clause id="H325D5854C66049BFB1660B36B942EB7F" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>transportation services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H37B4159209134F3F9E294DFAB8B61F39" commented="no"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>child care;</text></clause> <clause id="H793AF76C6C0145508C48760484FE190F" commented="no"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>housing counseling;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9E4F3AF21F1C4CB2BAD8DF6D7C113AF5" commented="no"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>preparing and updating family care plans;</text></clause> <clause id="HA0040D115D854FE680E3C879358426DF" commented="no"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>development of strategies for living with a veteran with post-traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H24464FDB980F4328AB92D613CA5141CE" commented="no"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>accessing emergency financial assistance through philanthropic efforts; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA6CDF6A5612A4D1EB0A88B884DBD15F0" commented="no"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>other services that are deemed appropriate to improve the well-being and address the unique needs of disabled veteran’s families who lack access to adequate VA or other direct wellness services and supports.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82268B15EB064A10B4169065C2D2B6DC" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Providing direct services, described in subparagraph (D), that are necessary to improve the well-being and address the needs of the disabled veteran families but are otherwise unavailable through existing public or private programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H2566D8EA76AB4AAFA4B15426D7283C3C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H18F50F192ACF4230814C2A5ACCB41CC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>community partner</term> is a private nonprofit organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93925D94025B4E3886A806F778B7EC68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>disabled veteran</term> is as defined a United States citizen or United States national with an honorable discharge from the United States Armed Forces; and is entitled to disability compensation (or who but for the receipt of military retired pay would be entitled to disability compensation) under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, or was discharged or released from active duty because of a service-connected disability.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33388CAD456F452C9D6F7F031D8CABC4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>family</term> is defined as a dependent of the disabled veteran.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H190B130D7A824F88846CDBD1832AB0FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Veterans Affairs $2,500,000 for each fiscal year to carry out the pilot program authorized by this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4859E0E7C2CA44E1A510C009A7437257"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days before the completion of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the pilot program, including the number of disabled veteran families served and service linkages or referrals and a description and assessment of the effectiveness and achievements of the pilot program with respect to services and treatments and mitigation of risks, including homelessness, unemployment and suicide as well as recommended best practices for improving access to supportive services and coordination of care for disabled veteran families.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

