<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H428B8D320ECC4E239D314A3A3B7DCE64" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2265 IH: VOW to Hire Heroes Extension Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2265</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the work opportunity credit for hiring veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H68E10E4A4184466C98F435681E706D4F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDCFCCD6585844BFEA39A5BB4307F9385" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VOW to Hire Heroes Extension Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4EAB28322753470BB275E505D406B6D8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of work opportunity credit for veterans</header> <subsection id="HC2F3800F937D46A4B923C864B9C7B1B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (4) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">section 51(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>2014</quote> and inserting <quote>2014 (December 31, 2018, in the case of a qualified veteran).</quote>. </text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7804D4799BB942F0BF56E1A3A1CEAD58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to individuals who begin work for the employer after December 31, 2014.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCC19A063921B4236B7790CE621D09EDA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Simplified certification of veteran status</header> <subsection id="HED4919401FDF4E088615EC288D040BEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (D) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">section 51(d)(13)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block act-name="" id="H99FC53B5C75946FFBE6D7194BDE4E3EA" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H4FAECCD850374675AF042DF345524D12"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Pre-screening of qualified veterans</header> 
<clause id="H4C59A0167BC14C909462F814F170EC5F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall be applied without regard to subclause (II) of clause (ii) thereof in the case of an individual seeking treatment as a qualified veteran with respect to whom the pre-screening notice contains—</text> <subclause id="HA42AACF085A446FBBFC245D0CEA66D45"><enum>(I)</enum><text>qualified veteran status documentation,</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H54178E88B0AA4AFF83A98B6267192EB1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>qualified proof of unemployment compensation, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2163D80FFBE244A99FD9ED5129CB1605"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an affidavit furnished by the individual stating, under penalty of perjury, that the information provided under subclauses (I) and (II) is true.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1E755EC88A474259B9E19DAEA053BB3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified veteran status documentation</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>qualified veteran status documentation</term> means any documentation provided to an individual by the Department of Defense or the National Guard upon release or discharge from the Armed Forces which includes information sufficient to establish that such individual is a veteran.</text></clause> <clause id="HC91E0622AE26498EA4F21FAE9D302664"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified proof of unemployment compensation</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>qualified proof of unemployment compensation</term> means, with respect to an individual, checks or other proof of receipt of payment of unemployment compensation to such individual for periods aggregating not less than 4 weeks (in the case of an individual seeking treatment under paragraph (3)(A)(iii)), or not less than 6 months (in the case of an individual seeking treatment under clause (ii)(II) or (iv) of paragraph (3)(A)), during the 1-year period ending on the hiring date.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD49D4D2D93664A6594634B568C186AFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to individuals who begin work for the employer after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8DFA20E987D24BCEB02F10AB1C01C43A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Credit made available against payroll taxes in certain circumstances</header> <subsection id="HBAD0FC3E54CC4ECD85923B851501D704"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/52">section 52(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF13C05E6A3EC48ACADBF80DC56979718"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">qualified tax-exempt organizations</header-in-text></quote> in the heading and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">certain employers</header-in-text></quote>, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD18CE59CBC9646FBBAD28240C9C71ADB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>by qualified tax-exempt organizations</quote> in the text and inserting <quote>by certain employers</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H81CAE1889ACF48ABBBD0FDC0A7ABE422"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed to certain for-Profit employers</header> 
<paragraph id="HD4F9BA3AE26749459FEC30934856961A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">section 3111(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>or a qualified for-profit employer</quote> after <quote>If a qualified tax-exempt organization</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A26BFDFCCE74B3F86E2AAD81F005B5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified for-profit employer defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (5) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">section 3111(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A), by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C), and by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86DA3B414D1B4AB9A5FDEA2FFB31F120" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H04CBF297408346EB9FEF8EA83168AD80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>qualified for-profit employer</term> means, with respect to a taxable year, an employer not described in subparagraph (A), but only if—</text> <clause id="H41F5C6C1F5414893AAD7BC605CBB15FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such employer does not have profits for any of the 3 taxable years preceding such taxable year, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H88F37118CD4742AA994FF52208A82618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such employer elects under section 51(j) not to have section 51 apply to such taxable year, and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84F6660F88094BE3AC012CD3493B83CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subparagraph id="H57535CF0515248BEAD44008D4ABDC1DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">Section 3111(e)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>with respect to whom a credit would be allowable under section 38 by reason of section 51 if the organization were not a qualified tax-exempt organization</quote> in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA49B416034584A85913245C14702E8A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (1) and (2) of are both amended by inserting <quote>or for-profit employer</quote> after <quote>employees of the organization</quote> each place it appears.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19673DBAF5544205B5C5F5F73EE96C8D"><enum>(C)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">Section 3111(e)(3)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>in the case of a qualified tax-exempt organization,</quote> before <quote>by only taking into account</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C4578A841F244C4A7C48EE83458BF1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">Section 3111(e)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>or for-profit employer</quote> after <quote>the organization</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5F7894DA36D45CCA11C541B487D0358"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">Section 3111(e)(5)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as redesignated by paragraph (2), is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE68D3285488A4F05982BE8B3AAEEC1A2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H8D9C1FBCFBD64F5399453674DBA44ED5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>qualified veteran</term> means a qualified veteran (within the meaning of section 51(d)(3)) with respect to whom a credit would be allowable under section 38 by reason of section 51 if the employer of such veteran were not a qualified tax-exempt organization or a qualified for-profit employer.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H32642A29FA49480EA9A9C7F4F9432CCD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfers to Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund established under section 201 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401</external-xref>) amounts equal to the reduction in revenues to the Treasury by reason of the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b). Amounts appropriated by the preceding sentence shall be transferred from the general fund at such times and in such manner as to replicate to the extent possible the transfers which would have occurred to such Trust Fund had such amendments not been enacted.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABA2BEBAE1D0489D82DACDB79455C544"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply to individuals who begin work for the employer after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H61A5D9F1DFC54D06BAA6FDB7DB1C1706"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall report to the Congress on the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of the amendments made by sections 2, 3, and 4 in increasing the employment of veterans. Such report shall include the results of a survey, conducted, if needed, in consultation with the Veterans' Employment and Training Service of the Department of Labor, to determine how many veterans are hired by each employer that claims the credit under section 51, by reason of subsection (d)(1)(B) thereof, or 3111(e) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></section> 
<section id="HD054E0422FC64FAE89E287DE37086CF0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Treatment of Possessions</header> 
<subsection id="H3DD7F395EDFD45329B6325A51508BF37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payments to possessions</header> 
<paragraph id="H2E5F79B3C50447D0AEBBD97F2E558E84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mirror code possessions</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to each possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system amounts equal to the loss to that possession by reason of the amendments made by this Act. Such amounts shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B68090FB5E7427A9F7FF67648B8B58E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other possessions</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to each possession of the United States which does not have a mirror code tax system the amount estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the loss to that possession that would have occurred by reason of the amendments made by this Act if a mirror code tax system had been in effect in such possession. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to any possession of the United States unless such possession establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the possession has implemented (or, at the discretion of the Secretary, will implement) an income tax benefit which is substantially equivalent to the income tax credit in effect after the amendments made by this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB4082CF34BA6436793D05002E9052112"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against United States income taxes</header><text>The credit allowed against United States income taxes for any taxable year under the amendments made by this Act to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">section 51</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to any person with respect to any qualified veteran shall be reduced by the amount of any credit (or other tax benefit described in subsection (a)(2)) allowed to such person against income taxes imposed by the possession of the United States by reason of this section with respect to such qualified veteran for such taxable year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6FFE070EC30D4EA6B590781F6F9A098A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header> <paragraph id="H52B5C37A58974BE5853DFC2DAAAF9D4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Possession of the united states</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>possession of the United States</term> includes American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the United States Virgin Islands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H766A3CDFEB414860BD97C96CE3E09265"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mirror code tax system</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>mirror code tax system</term> means, with respect to any possession of the United States, the income tax system of such possession if the income tax liability of the residents of such possession under such system is determined by reference to the income tax laws of the United States as if such possession were the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C007B2069D34641ADC146616DC844BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text>For purposes of section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, the payments under this section shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from credit provisions described in such section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

