<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3A39218CFC2C462B8D0F6D1AF4558071" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1079 IH: Counseling for Career Choice Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1079</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150225">February 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to States to
			 establish a comprehensive school counseling program.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE4004CFCE3D34FFF91519633C3CC8A4A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD0FD2255D3C743C7AA535C98E0F8D83F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Counseling for Career Choice Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAD126CBF03944458A3C37996AF1C169E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7201">20 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BFE3D41EB5A4C67A298C6A286E38C72" other-style="education" style="other">
				<part id="H80F8DCB10FE045E997768BABEE863803"><enum>E</enum><header>Counseling for Career Choice</header>
 <section id="H41B85C2A39F543A383E95FA28CBB8A5E"><enum>5701.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text> <paragraph id="HDF87781BD85C4320B0C753264CA6794C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community college</header><text>The term <quote>community college</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA693143B1CE5463681F41EB9BEFC4F85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a junior or community college (as defined in section 312(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(f)</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EB202DEC27D40B69548EC728AA69129"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a 4-year public institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)) that awards a significant number of degrees and certificates, as determined by the Secretary, that are not—</text>
 <clause id="HD7DDB29EAA3645B287E9475DA411A452"><enum>(i)</enum><text>baccalaureate degrees (or an equivalent); or</text> </clause><clause id="H48DBC78639164CD6A6E60890F61C68B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>master’s, professional, or other advanced degrees; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H879448E5C6BB4CBB9803DFB9DE9D4704"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an area career and technical education school (as defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H627E7BEF1A2244CC8F9B7D27FA977974"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H693A2388112F4980B07E3939AE3D7132"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local educational agency, including an educational service agency; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E27794F25274F5695F3AF0FAE6641FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a consortium that must consist of one local educational agency in combination with one or more local educational agencies, educational service agencies, non-profit organizations with demonstrated expertise in counseling or career and technical education, postsecondary institutions, or tribal organizations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DE6054AF9C74161A34B2F7A71BB01C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local workforce investment board</header><text>The term <quote>local workforce investment board</quote> means a local workforce investment board established under section 117 of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2832">29 U.S.C. 2832</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF806A85BE3F7402B92021F0EC7BCAE21"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School counselor</header><text>The term <quote>school counselor</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 5421.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B6C176D33694339A52BB537AB59C1AB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Stakeholders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>stakeholders</quote> includes local educational agencies, school counselors, secondary schools, institutions of higher education (including community colleges), eligible agencies as defined under section 203 of the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9202">20 U.S.C. 9202</external-xref>), the State workforce investment board, the State agency responsible for labor market information, other applicable State agencies as determined by the Secretary, local workforce investment boards, area career and technical education schools (as defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006), local businesses and industries, organizations offering apprenticeship programs, tribal organizations, labor organizations, programs leading to post-secondary credentials, including industry-recognized credentials, other programs for career and technical education (as defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>)), and any other organizations, individuals or persons that the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out the purposes of this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F3890D3866140CE8CD7CB82EB3AB026"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Statewide counseling framework</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>statewide counseling framework</quote> means a framework that encompasses grades 6 through 12 and postsecondary education and that includes information on career awareness, skills assessment, skills training, student interest surveys, postsecondary education entrance requirements, secondary school graduation requirements, high school equivalency, adult education programs and services, financial aid, institutions of higher education, community colleges, programs leading to industry-recognized credentials, career and technical education programs, internships, dual enrollment programs, apprenticeships, and professional development opportunities or career development training for school counselors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H215A6319D99243DDA1DB0430C433DEC4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State workforce investment board</header><text>The term <quote>State workforce investment board</quote> means a State workforce investment board established under section 111 of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2821">29 U.S.C. 2821</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41810AEF09D9423896FDC9C762104931"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <quote>tribal organization</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B8E702538144767AE93C8D3946ECABE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Industry recognized credential</header><text>The term <quote>industry-recognized,</quote> used with respect to a credential, means a credential that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC7D5D21AA3BA495492ABAB8F35092DA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is sought or accepted by employers within the industry or sector involved as a recognized, preferred, or required credential for recruitment, screening, hiring, retention or advancement purposes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C39D5BCE5064292B9B9187106E81F89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>where appropriate, is endorsed by a nationally recognized trade association or organization representing a significant part of the industry or sector.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H2F761CA4A854498093BD9DD4628CAF9C"><enum>5702.</enum><header>Establishment and capacity-building grants</header>
						<subsection id="H9A5A0E13CE994C55B4C82CAF6FE21EB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment grants</header>
 <paragraph id="H8C9A21E5814B4B6DAF44C1191C9138A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>From amounts appropriated to carry out this part and not reserved by the Secretary under subsection (b), the Secretary shall award establishment grants, on a competitive basis, to State educational agencies to enable the State educational agencies to carry out the activities described in section 5704.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H3E8732F6E4754294A7D9D9E3CBA85B90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration; extension</header>
 <subparagraph id="H102FA3F151294364BC0F3C618DEC5E3D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each establishment grant under this subsection shall be for a period of not more than 2 years.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D52C2E55DF34665A5E11BD692E14E95"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>Each grant shall be of an amount not less than $2,000,000 and not more than $5,000,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63689FABF7B6465D832A53A0E82D30DA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Secretary may extend a grant awarded under this subsection for additional 3-year periods if the State educational agency—</text>
 <clause id="HC7949A47D65C4665884B2F50BB5B184A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is achieving the intended outcomes of the grant;</text> </clause><clause id="H7FD823BBD8794A3CB9B920ABD81C351C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shows continued engagement with stakeholders; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD23B45437DFD4A86B21B95AD1983661A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has established a statewide counseling framework.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03233C06B66B41279263111659FF8B79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State capacity-Building grants</header> <paragraph id="H6C45B0087AD447D49F4E3E665010557C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve not less than 10 percent and not more than 20 percent of the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for any fiscal year to award capacity-building grants, on a competitive basis, to State educational agencies that do not receive an establishment grant under subsection (a) for such year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89C91012856F41D48860E05F3F1D3E1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>A State educational agency that receives a capacity-building grant under this subsection shall use grant funds to carry out 1 or more of the activities from the State educational agency’s application under section 5703 that the Secretary determines is an acceptable use of funds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0DBD1F80C231432D9E9619F243781E9B"><enum>5703.</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State educational agency desiring a grant under this part shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. The application shall include—</text>
						<paragraph id="H142463EC93664B38940B7E9BB9A5F106"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA70DC72C706D496799D2C95F0DA0C542"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of a proposed statewide counseling framework that is developed in consultation with not less than 5 stakeholders, of which at least 1 stakeholder shall be a local business or industry or statewide industry organization and 1 stakeholder shall be a local educational agency or secondary school;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F85CBE7D9664DD1B6B8F2993AE129A8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a detailed plan to implement a statewide counseling framework that is developed in consultation with not less than 5 stakeholders, of which at least 1 stakeholder shall be a local business or industry or statewide industry organization and 1 shall be a local educational agency or secondary school; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6280FCE75C6B453786F3FFFE6B268EF0" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evidence of an existing statewide counseling framework and implementation plan supported by not less than 5 stakeholders, of which at least 1 stakeholder shall be a local business or industry or statewide industry organization and 1 shall be a local educational agency or secondary school; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3ECE9023FD044CE9C413F9E2F7ED469"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of how the State educational agency will award subgrants and ensure that the activities described in section 5704 are carried out.</text>
						</paragraph></section><section id="H17A03D20E95449BE8E5EF3B220D1C196"><enum>5704.</enum><header>Activities</header>
 <subsection id="H572AA332FC3A4FA58465ED7BBC8C88BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State educational agency receiving an establishment grant under section 5702(a) shall use grant funds to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC475E9953A78448497B848B21302FC37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement comprehensive school career counseling programs that align with the statewide counseling framework proposed or described in the State educational agency’s application;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83D969771B74458CB8ED7A816A116617"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify and assess school counseling activities and postsecondary options available within the State, and outside the State as applicable;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08707F3A0AE3442396635656D196FF94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hire additional school counselors to effectively serve more students in postsecondary education and adult education planning and career guidance activities, where applicable;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC605A02CBE6C42E5810ACDFC6E49F046"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify regional workforce trends in collaboration with entities at the State and regional level with expertise in identifying such trends, such as State workforce investment boards, local workforce investment boards, regional economic development organizations, or State employment agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB56356D2056241D4B8CD5AC2E506A960"><enum>(5)</enum><text>train school counselors effectively to provide students with current and relevant workforce information, financial aid assistance, personal counseling, and academic advising relevant to students’ individual career and postsecondary education goals;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCBBDA4BDB674256BF96F4E3E64D45AD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop and implement a process and infrastructure for school counselors and school counselor programs to access the statewide counseling framework and information regarding the regional workforce trends identified in paragraph (4);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD45992F6ABD8457D82078FD50E74E90D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and implement professional development or career development training certification programs for counselors and other educators involved in preparing students for postsecondary opportunities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E0B5BB5439B4850B8025CF21D1790D3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>develop a searchable method by which counseling professional development opportunities from around the State are collected, maintained, and disseminated to school counselors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F397CF8023B47B3ADDA8A158900EBAA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>establish, improve, or coordinate postsecondary opportunities, which may include individual career planning, personalized learning plans, registered apprenticeships, internships, dual enrollment programs, programs leading to industry-recognized credentials (including programs at a secondary school), 2-year degree programs, 4-year degree programs, and other applicable postsecondary opportunities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7C5399EE4AA4062A43A9B07EB99FBF1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>provide recommendations and improve a local educational agency’s and other education service program providers to out of school youth and adults curricula to better align with workforce trends and available postsecondary opportunities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB144009CB3C8400CB03C3E88BDFE0234"><enum>(11)</enum><text>conduct other activities pertaining to the administration of the statewide framework;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A61C5CEEE654A4BBEB5DB494514DDFB"><enum>(12)</enum><text>establish partnerships with American Job Centers, which may include co-locating an American Job Center in a high school, transporting students to local American Job Centers, or having American Job Center career counselors and business liaisons assist school counselors in hosting job fairs, career days, or other such similar tasks; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF65F4C9F015F4F53BF85282E22B840F0"><enum>(13)</enum><text>leverage resources and emerging technologies that are being developed by stakeholders to support the counseling framework.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD2733E60154412FA81700341F13EED0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subgrants</header>
 <paragraph id="HFE8A1D1AE6E146D78670ACDDABF3FD75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State educational agency that receives an establishment grant may carry out the activities described in subsection (a) directly or through awarding subgrants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out any of the activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85BA14CA308B42FC8BA1EE2ECBD57BC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity that desires a subgrant under this subsection shall submit an application to the State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may reasonably require, including a description of the comprehensive school counseling program for participating schools and students that the eligible entity proposes to develop and implement using subgrant funds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59BF26F665EB4F3481EBC53EFB19D6FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hiring of personnel</header><text>An eligible entity that receives an establishment grant under section 5702(a) may use grant funds to hire additional school personnel to carry out the activities described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H9C149194599D4980B40776EDA90D48D5"><enum>5705.</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds made available under this part shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, and local funds available to carry out the activities supported under this part.</text>
 </section><section id="HC33D251FCF854B1D93ED6AD848221DEA"><enum>5706.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the Counseling for Career Choice Act, and every 3 years thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the progress made by the eligible entities receiving grants under this part in implementing grant activities.</text>
 </section><section id="H454C4685C2DE46B0ABDF29C7C5656AEC"><enum>5707.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2016 and $40,000,000 for each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


