<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AF666B61B6C44D8BF4B5DB6510067C0" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3404 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow tax free distributions from health savings accounts for fitness facility membership and classes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3404</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow tax free distributions from health savings accounts for fitness facility membership and classes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA197B789079E467F9F0662D7158DB6AE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD2A4354F5CCF49A39C44B0584971EFE9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Tax free distributions from health savings accounts for fitness facility memberships and classes</header> 
<subsection id="H07068B2F2A6646F6AF18A6FA830007E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223(d)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9D3BEF64349B4E1FA1253CB76208C15E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H97F4F792A5A04ED7B2C0F02D7AA09105"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Fitness facility memberships and classes treated as medical expense</header> <clause id="H5D769461656645F0A55A49D779EB04DD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), amounts paid for membership at (or for participation or instruction in a program of physical exercise or physical activity conducted at or by) a fitness facility shall be treated as amounts paid for medical care.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H82DBF24C62DD460FA3BA4C8610EFA80B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Fitness facility defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>fitness facility</term> means a facility—</text> <subclause id="H78DBB77AB13A48D5A0554B4635AB916E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>providing instruction in a program of physical exercise, offering facilities for the preservation, maintenance, encouragement, or development of physical fitness, or serving as the site of such a program of a State or local government,</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5E3B6F2B392145E9A31D8F5C7CA47B71"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which is not a private club owned and operated by its members,</text></subclause> <subclause id="H89A5243CAD32492A988AC32142A6C443"><enum>(III)</enum><text>which does not offer golf, hunting, sailing, or riding facilities,</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD61471DE3D4E42EABADEB3FB94022A20"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>whose health or fitness facility is not incidental to its overall function and purpose, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF62198E03EDD4966A9DE26B6B20989EA"><enum>(V)</enum><text>which is fully compliant with the State of jurisdiction and Federal anti-discrimination laws.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H376E39583F71459F978C8A02099D5177"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

