<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2E4AED49180D4AD2ACA7D1539498BDB2" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1137 IH: PAID for Progress Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1137</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for an 8.7 percent reduction in the annual rate of basic pay for certain employees, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3284D014AC6241519B5D40DF761E6878" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3B12D6F9E5154469BDC6361A69A71025" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Accountability in Decisions for Progress Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>PAID for Progress Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA55B9A5E137A4F219BEB951500619F1E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Initial pay decrease</header> <subsection id="HCD65CED73F4940768E2397B3634754C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for any covered employee occupying a position within the Federal Government or a covered enterprise on the date of enactment of this Act that has an annual rate of basic pay greater than $100,000, such rate of basic pay shall be reduced by 8.7 percent.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8F4808B1B11F45839C2100210B69E5AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="H20F5E2101A324CE19D03684E690E5B7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text>In the case of a Federal employee, subsection (a) shall be effective with respect to the first pay period beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC1D2CB0C2684F0192C91D5C0EB51B51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members of Congress; the President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Member of Congress or the President, subsection (a) shall apply with respect to the first pay period beginning on or after the commencement date of the first term for which such Member or the President is elected that begins after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H915162F495C848C9ADB4D6623C3254F6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Real median household income adjustments</header>
 <subsection id="HC4C23CEE75374069984B7BBD8F4F49CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Periodic pay adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for any covered employee with an annual rate of basic pay greater than $100,000 on the date of application in subsection (c), such rate of basic pay shall be adjusted by the rate of the percent change in the real median household income, pursuant to the calculation in subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD002F63952B9429B86E32E15A72E612B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Calculation of adjustment</header>
 <paragraph id="HC8C41B378F2F49288EBE0062A27DBB93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Federal employee, the adjustment in subsection (a) shall be a percent equal to the percent difference between the real median household income in the most recent publication such income and the real median household income in the previous publication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0723434930EA41DA84A5DE1F1CE6FCC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Member of Congress; the President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Member of Congress or the President, the adjustment in subsection (a) shall be a percent equal to the percent difference between the real median household income in the most recent publication such income and the real median household income in the first publication after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50CE9B05E57146E58F52D71999D30A11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Date of application</header>
 <paragraph id="HF7E54A4738F9479ABC6D20D01DB7B11E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Federal employee, the adjustment in subsection (a) shall be periodically applied beginning with the first pay period beginning after the date of each annual publication of the real median household income.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0378FC76A8DC45F7983BB260302C7AE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Member of Congress; the President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Member of Congress or the President, the adjustment in subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to the first pay period beginning on or after the commencement date of each term after such date of publication for which such Member or the President is elected.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H315813E1723742D9A7F3388D7400E1B2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE8A1364BCDCE4CCE84858BA0035C76F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered employee</header><text>The term <quote>covered employee</quote> means a Federal employee, a Member of Congress, and the President.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21E38C521AF443A492386E0D74120867"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered enterprise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered enterprise</quote> means the Federal National Mortgage Association and any affiliate thereof during any period that the enterprise is federally chartered under the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1716">12 U.S.C. 1716 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation and any affiliate thereof during any period that the enterprise is federally chartered under the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1451">12 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD46DBB452BC446EBAF4EEA343B590192"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal employee</quote> has the meaning given the term <term>employee</term> in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code, and includes a director, officer, or employee of a covered enterprise.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D4CFD97E7B54A32BB082E9855FD60ED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Member of Congress</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2106 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H27BAAC8BD074488EB0BF9181A76FD021"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Real median household income</header><text>The term <quote>real median household income</quote> means the real median household income of the United States as published by the Bureau of the Census.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


