<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF94A6180A81946C3AAEE79A3DEA4B762" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1959 IH: College Options for DREAMers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1959</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide Dreamer students with access to student financial aid.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H82DBF64FC77049EDA84BD4AA5E5E80F4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1336D726DA1D455985495D5DCC5147F8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>College Options for DREAMers Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1CC69EF4B718437A829EE4F98D5F3C8E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to invest in highly motivated college students who came to the United States, grew up in our churches and schools, and want to contribute to the Nation by earning a college degree, making more money and paying higher taxes, starting businesses, hiring American workers, and spending more to strengthen the Nation's economy.</text>
 </section><section id="H48FEBBF0B2584FE88B2F5A2943BDEB2B"><enum>3.</enum><header>College options for Dreamer students</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 484 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1091">20 U.S.C. 1091</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H094B710B5D654053A06C1A5EB03AA053"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(5), by inserting <quote>or be a Dreamer student, as defined in subsection (u)</quote> after <quote>becoming a citizen or permanent resident</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9887196B911144C1ACD9292D01376BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCEB9D2265624D3CB1D7B8E1E320CEE6" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H4CF16C2528CD4DF89D499D4CCDB39ED3"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Dreamer students</header> <paragraph id="HD8BF40F5A41C4BDE803C9638D6C45D68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Dreamer student</term> means an individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H47BA87982D954C7D8AA6748BB81A4FC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was younger than 16 years of age on the date on which the individual initially entered the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7080C97B85844FCD827AF767280787FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has provided a list of each secondary school (as that term is defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965) that the student attended in the United States; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H261DCB654C6F46AFA2FEB41900CF655B"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB58BC09AA3E648629CD2CBC807CF6225"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has earned a high school diploma, the recognized equivalent of such diploma from a secondary school, a high school equivalency diploma in the United States, or is scheduled to complete the requirements for such a diploma or equivalent before the next academic year begins;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H327C4DE6C59B4DA7BFAC29643B7D186C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has acquired a degree from an institution of higher education or has completed not less than 2 years in a program for a baccalaureate degree or higher degree at an institution of higher education in the United States and has made satisfactory academic progress, as defined in subsection (c), during such time period;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC5DF304AFBD1457A8AB3547A20DFE82A" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a beneficiary of the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program pursuant to the Department of Homeland Security Secretary’s memorandum on June 15, 2012, or November 20, 2014; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEA237CFEAA934ECFB6AFADF3FB05C308" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has served in the uniformed services, as defined in section 101 of title 10, United States Code, for not less than 4 years and, if discharged, received an honorable discharge.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6282847997C3492CBA155DF5CA674C2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hardship exception</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall issue regulations that direct when the Department shall waive the requirement of subparagraph (A) or (B), or both, of paragraph (1) to qualify as a Dreamer student under such paragraph, if the individual—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4BBDE4A2422348D68ECB7E3FA32D19B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrates compelling circumstances for the inability to satisfy the requirement of such subparagraph (A) or (B), or both; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD32434DC1E6248D699E3D93B72D15529"><enum>(B)</enum><text>satisfies the requirement under paragraph (1)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="HD2447EAFF2A94FEEAA952E76AD1C7006"><enum>4.</enum><header>Restoration of state option to determine residency for purposes of higher education</header> <subsection id="HD0CED2C590524E39868E36692C9BEDD3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Section 505 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1623">8 U.S.C. 1623</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7BB086914E7457FAD9DE95DC7F9B66C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The repeal under subsection (a) shall take effect as if included in the original enactment of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


