<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H894197EF891A4CF89549498A9330FC70" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3988 IH: Military and Veterans Education Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3988</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To count revenues from military and veteran education programs toward the limit on Federal revenues
			 that certain proprietary institutions of higher education are allowed to
			 receive for purposes of section 487 of the Higher Education Act of 1965,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB9943151CE3F4433A0D80D50DF7073B5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9E789E53C9254772B6BD9CF6BD87DA1E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military and Veterans Education Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7E2E3C93ECCC44AEB3F5389EE43F4B45"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program participation agreements for proprietary institutions of higher education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H79C91E7DD18C4F01A047E2BB20AF9EDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(24)—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDBDAD8BBBAF4F88A3774B5C3107F6C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>that receives funds provided under this title</quote> before <quote>, such institution</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46BBAB66486E4FB6889F63749208706E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>other than funds provided under this title, as calculated in accordance with subsection (d)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>other than Federal educational assistance, as defined in subsection (d)(5) and calculated in accordance with subsection (d)(1)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DC00B4617224C8BB84849B7D0CEA55E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFBC8A87E694C4D688939BC25FD37D15F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Non-Title IV</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Non-Federal educational</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57239CEB0D9B4317AD9AA37BFC705F23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H7ED376A82159490697582B1DD6EB092E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>that receives funds provided under this title</quote> before <quote>shall</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2EF8369976D94FA2B2A7A812A43AF6B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subclause id="H22A2053EE83844F38BF9B61F93C7C322"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>assistance under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal educational assistance</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H560917E012084C68B9FB2F80C134EA8A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (ii)(I), by inserting <quote>, or on a military base if the administering Secretary for a program of Federal educational assistance under clause (ii), (iii), or (iv) of paragraph (5)(B) has authorized such location</quote> before the semicolon;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HFA2B43F0876D4A36AB998074FEA31A74"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>program under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>program of Federal educational assistance</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H529372348A274BA49D0B2A498BA7A3FC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>funds received under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal educational assistance</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5F5C36028D1446FC8DAC1B255078BA0C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)—</text> <subclause id="H216DD8278C794138B15ECA005DEEAF97"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>of Federal educational assistance</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9CF7BA2D674A42E9BA46C2A177957520"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>of Federal educational assistance</quote>;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D96F2BE71EB4842ABF553B7C55A95B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause id="HB90E66F3687C408E8C7FE97FB3439BED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B0B1E59F0DD45A3BAB395424C30B48A" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H867DCF13624B4248BD42FEA22D1FB53F"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ineligibility</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08053940CCE849488591FF577240EA6A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a proprietary institution of higher education receiving funds provided under this title that fails to meet a requirement of subsection (a)(24) for two consecutive institutional fiscal years shall be ineligible to participate in or receive funds under any program of Federal educational assistance for a period of not less than two institutional fiscal years.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H683B18BFE7544AD5A5D9C4C4A9931E23"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Regaining eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To regain eligibility to participate in or receive funds under any program of Federal educational assistance after being ineligible pursuant to clause (i), a proprietary institution of higher education shall demonstrate compliance with all eligibility and certification requirements for the program for a minimum of two consecutive institutional fiscal years after the institutional fiscal year in which the institution became ineligible. In order to regain eligibility to participate in any program of Federal educational assistance under this title, such compliance shall include meeting the requirements of section 498 for such 2-year period.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D5972D4153B4E159DA179F8DCF4E48C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notification of ineligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall determine when a proprietary institution of higher education that receives funds under this title is ineligible under clause (i) and shall notify all other administering Secretaries of the determination.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DF48B84406045C89C42ECD99EB889C4"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each administering Secretary for a program of Federal educational assistance shall enforce the requirements of this subparagraph for the program concerned upon receiving notification under clause (iii) of a proprietary institution of higher education's ineligibility.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="HD7DE532A481E456C841917FDBDBA45CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subclause id="H69FB075AAAAA424E8B48879F7D499853"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i)—</text>
 <item id="H4FE413B69F544AD39DFD94388469D083"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In addition</quote> and all that follows through <quote>education fails</quote> and inserting <quote>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in addition to such other means of enforcing the requirements of a program of Federal educational assistance as may be available to the administering Secretary, if a proprietary institution of higher education that receives funds provided under this title fails</quote>; and</text>
 </item><item id="HD14398AE24554156BFE1B8EE25A70D80"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the programs authorized by this title</quote> and inserting <quote>all programs of Federal educational assistance</quote>; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HBD4F0C4D2A534FFAB96556AB32AF9FA9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>with respect to a program of Federal educational assistance under this title,</quote> before <quote>on the expiration date</quote>;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC34BB9A09274487A071E1F3DCBE431C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A), by striking <quote>sources under this title</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal educational assistance</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H841932AD08E944FEB7C768D1DB3D074D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54A034107A684E3689895FE8AE8CF652" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H03AB6E04DD60485FA9828A8B0C7AECAA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HDDCD12CC837F4F1FB92FC134FA123560"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Administering Secretary</header><text>The term <term>administering Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Homeland Security, or the Secretary of a military department responsible for administering the Federal educational assistance concerned.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H049EC2B87DA740949E246CA4AF57CA08"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal educational assistance</header><text>The term <term>Federal educational assistance</term> means funds provided under any of the following provisions of law:</text> <clause id="H574D6D6DD2A7453196441729D70DC020"><enum>(i)</enum><text>This title.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H99F87F8CCCB7403F8F5F52B593EBD1D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Chapter 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, or 35 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </clause><clause id="H7C9BD296FE3A47D29ECA3BDE3DD95E39"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Chapter 101, 105, 106A, 1606, 1607, or 1608 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4EB0F2BBB7C34BC089C07E39F0C37307"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Section 1784a of title 10, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H2484DAA2D4B44B3DA82C96F52516759D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs actions on ineligibility of certain proprietary institutions of higher education for participation in programs of educational assistance</header> <subsection id="H0109F5CDD0D24B28A1F5E952C985E967"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Defense</header> <paragraph id="H8E2273BE56CD4952878E6132C6D05896"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/101">Chapter 101</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2008">section 2008</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC34929CE392459BACE96A370275CA3A" style="USC">
						<section id="HC37669AFBB7848A9931055EFEF7343B2"><enum>2008a.</enum><header>Ineligibility of certain proprietary institutions of higher education for participation in
			 Department of Defense programs of educational assistance</header>
 <subsection id="H2570732A335E4DE4B87B7E99BB33FE63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of a notice from the Secretary of Education under clause (iii) of section 487(d)(2)(A) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(d)(2)(A)</external-xref>) that a proprietary institution of higher education is ineligible for participation in or receipt of funds under any program of Federal educational assistance by reason of such section, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that no educational assistance under the provisions of law specified in subsection (b) is available or used for education at the institution for the period of institutional fiscal years covered by such notice.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF660E8E4D4F647D5A9B2761E652A7D11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered assistance</header><text>The provisions of law specified in this subsection are the provisions of law on educational assistance through the Department of Defense as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC0663B9139FF41F88A0244888A34300E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>This chapter.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EC395C0988D47C89169176D02276F05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Chapters 105, 106A, 1606, 1607, and 1608 of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CD7EDC88AD94DE2A2E8CB22A3E226F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 1784a of this title.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADAEDB1B450D40E1A863F7574EB6CDD5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice on ineligibility</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB43AC6F966EF4C2E8D21AE1E672DB94E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense shall take appropriate actions to notify persons receiving or eligible for educational assistance under the provisions of law specified in subsection (b) of the application of the limitations in section 487(d)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to particular proprietary institutions of higher education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF852C76E9BD4B2CB79E6822A3B9EA14" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The actions taken under this subsection with respect to a proprietary institution shall include publication, on the Internet website of the Department of Defense that provides information to persons described in paragraph (1), of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFCD2B14F84A941B3903BDDA60BDDE5FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name of the institution.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H234FD94A9B684E9FB9501342AE2CB600"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The extent to which the institution failed to meet the requirements of section 487(a)(24) of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA85DA8C82296450688AE3C7D508CA03D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The length of time the institution will be ineligible for participation in or receipt of funds under any program of Federal educational assistance by reason of section 487(d)(2)(A) of that Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B9ACD1A80FF4DEA85D5619F1B5BE3BB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The nonavailability of educational assistance through the Department for enrollment, attendance, or pursuit of a program of education at the institution by reason of such ineligibility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BB4ECCE882F44EFB561D7799AA46566"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 101 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2008 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H2DB6D41BE47D45EEB080D980C6556382" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="HC37669AFBB7848A9931055EFEF7343B2" level="section">2008a. Ineligibility of certain proprietary institutions of higher education for participation in
			 Department of Defense programs of educational assistance.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86930E6C1535452AA1DB8570977E45F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <paragraph id="H1F6612328CD44C3B8908B19E07042A5B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/36">chapter 36</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3681">section 3681</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AB0D330440A486FB794DCF6B7BC8A58" style="USC">
						<section id="H767D18DD88464FC39E36C3CC7C1A18FB"><enum>3681A.</enum><header>Ineligibility of certain proprietary institutions of higher education for participation in
			 Department of Veterans Affairs programs of educational assistance</header>
 <subsection id="H4F6AC4277B884158A9F0D2BD6F441408"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of a notice from the Secretary of Education under clause (iii) of section 487(d)(2)(A) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(d)(2)(A)</external-xref>) that a proprietary institution of higher education is ineligible for participation in or receipt of funds under any program of Federal educational assistance by reason of such section, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that no educational assistance under the provisions of law specified in subsection (b) is available or used for education at the institution for the period of institutional fiscal years covered by such notice.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83E8F3C7157C417D8BE446E0313A4009"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered assistance</header><text>The provisions of law specified in this subsection are the provisions of law on educational assistance through the Department under chapters 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, and 35 of this title.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H15D75A5B0FB942A6BE26539956B43629"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice on ineligibility</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H12848697B4D04749A90378045CAA9EB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall take appropriate actions to notify persons receiving or eligible for educational assistance under the provisions of law specified in subsection (b) of the application of the limitations in section 487(d)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to particular proprietary institutions of higher education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H300ABEF7BE994D978A4F3B959EEF8323" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The actions taken under this subsection with respect to a proprietary institution shall include publication, on the Internet website of the Department that provides information to persons described in paragraph (1), of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB23340D7CAB84199915C7B6B031F3869"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name of the institution.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC02853A7E4584319AE6350329E8ABECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The extent to which the institution failed to meet the requirements of section 487(a)(24) of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE3616A0F2A1445FB38418F9FB395223"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The length of time the institution will be ineligible for participation in or receipt of funds under any program of Federal educational assistance by reason of section 487(d)(2)(A) of that Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0986E514E5014D3BAFEE1BED07189C8C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The nonavailability of educational assistance through the Department for enrollment, attendance, or pursuit of a program of education at the institution by reason of such ineligibility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H541F0D4C0F9040758D5A8EF289FDBCA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 36 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3681 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H824776B3960C40878BC138613CCD5FBB" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="H767D18DD88464FC39E36C3CC7C1A18FB" level="section">3681A. Ineligibility of certain proprietary institutions of higher education for participation in
			 Department of Veterans Affairs programs of educational assistance.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


