<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9E0FB9E286934CF496EFA03732AFEB39" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3427 IH: Payroll Fraud Prevention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3427</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to ensure that employees are not misclassified as
			 non-employees, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H75A097C90C4A417AB1E879F5BB7A5339" style="OLC">
 <section id="H061DCB03EAEC422CB47A4E4792F9A245" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Payroll Fraud Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC8E83C550FF1493FB5D3C35DCCF07A34"><enum>2.</enum><header>Classification of employees and non-employees</header> <subsection id="H3CEA2927F74C45619EC53C2524B22058"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HB5D2FC3850A94473955789BE6928AFD9" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HEB5968F9825C4A17A468B639D052C201"><enum>(z)</enum><text><quote>Non-employee</quote> means an individual who—</text> <paragraph id="HEBBCB1F75D78408CB9488157F20E28EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has been engaged, in the course of the trade or business of the person, for the performance of labor or services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEED4726F4C1D4B18A7D98251D5413F12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is not an employee of the person.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEF4773932D0436B93943661620A6E5F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text><quote>Covered individual</quote> when used with respect to an employer or other person means—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2218E9AD01004D98BE26D69455AD2F81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an employee of the employer; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7E65F22FAF045A9B4F1EFCAD4ADCFCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a non-employee of the person (including a person who is an employer)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3AE654E6213B475F8ECC02E26B61F050"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whom the person has engaged, in the course of the trade or business of the person, for the performance of labor or services; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF99040E3F664FAC93E51521A4B16C2C"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF6C6C852DA394B88ABDB222278D52C45"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to whom the person is required to file an information return under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6041A">section 6041A(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H70B7B9B9B0A54ADA8CAE4EC1F9D5DDFA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who is providing labor or services to the person through an entity that is a trust, estate, partnership, association, company, or corporation (as such terms are used in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) if—</text>
 <subclause id="HBBDD2F9860C64CDCA4FF43DA4CFC5761"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such individual has an ownership interest in the entity;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H0ACBB558FF3D4AD2978235D3BDC4B550"><enum>(II)</enum><text>creation or maintenance of such entity is a condition for the provision of such labor or services to the person; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDB53EB00A283498687172CB171FF2AEF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the person would be required to file an information return for the entity under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6041A">section 6041A(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 if the entity were an individual.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H14A66D3AC6A04716987A2ECF7E717F17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Classification as employees</header><text>Section 11(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/211">29 U.S.C. 211(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H57CA3F56742C422C91DFA4E650A84689"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(c) Every employer subject to any provision of this Act or of any order issued under this Act</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HF56550FE69A84A7CA8F18A1102500470" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H1E980D6D09A34DC5A33ACC544FE759F9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recordkeeping; classification; notice</header>
 <paragraph id="H8BE82929F1CF4C149BC9B8EFCEA758F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text>Every person subject to any provision of this Act or of any order issued under this Act</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE358BB7FE84A4539859616C2C384BC38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H5BE5F91B063747D68D8F780D93C863E4" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB5566DAB68C6430A976D35307FE6E3A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Classification</header><text>Every person (including every employer and enterprise), who employs any employee engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce or engages any non-employee engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, shall accurately classify each covered individual as an employee or a non-employee (as the case may be).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H5462B9A1B2954705B8CFB9D4BE6865E8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9207B2F228E640B08419B97575C3A3E9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every person subject to any provision of this Act or of any order issued under this Act shall provide the notice described in subparagraph (C) to each employee of the person and each individual classified by the person as a non-employee under paragraph (2) and maintain a copy of such notice as a required record under paragraph (1).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40377C8017084BF187412A334FBD90F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing of notice</header>
 <clause id="H77EFF86FDDD84A98BCA08061D8CD765D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The notice described in subparagraph (A) shall be provided, at a minimum, to each covered individual not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Payroll Fraud Prevention Act of 2015</short-title>, and thereafter—</text>
 <subclause id="HED9E2761D0E7434CA68E768B433D135B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for each new employee, upon employment; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDB97DCEB27DC47AAB24398673A5E1C6A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for each new non-employee, upon commencement of the labor or services provided by the non-employee.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0DADFFAD7F4F47F388F0AC9E3A1685E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Change in status</header><text>Each person required to provide a notice under subparagraph (A) to a covered individual shall also provide such notice to such individual upon changing the status of such individual as an employee or a non-employee.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3D551FC51484DC4B70C3F1F9C858A60"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The notice required under this paragraph shall be in writing and shall—</text> <clause id="HDBD959E8F7734B25A247E127DB54A679"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inform the covered individual of the classification of such individual, by the person submitting the notice, as an employee or a non-employee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H02FF1DF2C2064EB1987C44467B0ACFFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include a statement directing such individual to the Department of Labor website established under section 3 of the <short-title>Payroll Fraud Prevention Act of 2015</short-title>, for the purpose of providing further information about the legal rights of an employee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC1DABCC3F8FF40B3B8DC3FD3A65C8DEB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>include the address and telephone number for the applicable local office of the Department of Labor; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H757D88DD8FC549A6AF6AC8952599A18A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>include for each covered individual classified as a non-employee by the person providing the notice, the following statement: <quote>Your rights to wage, hour, and other labor protections depend upon your proper classification as an employee or a non-employee. If you have any questions or concerns about how you have been classified or suspect that you may have been misclassified, contact the U.S. Department of Labor.</quote>.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H013345B3063A46C3B12885F7E4BDBDCC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Presumption</header>
 <clause id="HF40D9DAEDA6B40FA99FE98E06DAC85AD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this Act and the regulations or orders issued under this Act, a covered individual to whom a person is required to provide a notice under subparagraph (A) shall be presumed to be an employee of the person if the person has not provided the individual with such notice within the time required under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEAF807876B484F4C8839151931779D6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rebuttal</header><text>The presumption under clause (i) shall be rebutted only through the presentation of clear and convincing evidence that a covered individual described in such subparagraph is not an employee of the person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E3BB1775F0A447E9953E8EC7464C120"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special prohibited acts</header><text>Section 15(a) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/215">29 U.S.C. 215(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4073AAC28E6D481C9DE0F4E18DE378A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H7264C1360FC945A7A74FDD430CEBB040" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H5B53CB2939F1497CBB0764F7FC01B090"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to discharge or in any other manner discriminate against any covered individual (including an employee) because such individual has—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H08FFF3EE1F034F3BBA005DADF7858E3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>opposed any practice, filed any petition or complaint, or instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding—</text>
 <clause id="H35A31170DB97492393EAD59C51A867A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under or related to this Act (including concerning the status of a covered individual as an employee or a non-employee for purposes of this Act); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A858D466B2747AEB44083026FD79AB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>concerning the status of a covered individual as an employee or a non-employee for employment tax purposes within the meaning of subtitle C of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8CBCB1BC0E0462CB152B05E23116E67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>testified or is about to testify in any proceeding described in subparagraph (A); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF95444FA737406093A220B9AF00787A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>served, or is about to serve, on an industry committee;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H964F37E857E947DB87DA13DB5ACE25A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB3C2610E2364B92BA89F4A2EB618D00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H16F1C3A8B50D4F9280D375580280E4AB" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB69799043B03471586F571C4C89998B0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to wrongly classify an employee of the person as a non-employee in accordance with section 11(c)(2).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H18649238D4704715B79E046DF069DB75"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special penalty for certain misclassification, recordkeeping, and notice violations</header><text>Section 16 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/216">29 U.S.C. 216</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HAE3BABBE9A0D45389363AAB30C909FF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2316E2699E3F45B1AA7CB0F2D322ABCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the sixth sentence, by striking <quote>any employee</quote> each place the term occurs and inserting <quote>any covered individual</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BA3BFF788604F7BA3041F1A1CAE30B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the fourth sentence—</text>
 <clause id="HE2790EF00D84442BA3763505246F7A8D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>employees</quote> and inserting <quote>covered individual</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA3CA070BE76C4F99BC678775EB49AC4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he gives his consent</quote> and inserting <quote>such covered individual consents</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F16FEB829D44D57885D38889DDE5438"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the third sentence—</text> <clause id="H662479BF384245438FCF073CB043C684"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>either of the preceding sentences</quote> and inserting <quote>any of the preceding sentences</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDF9A94E8C1074F6387CDE97B4C596EBE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>one or more employees</quote> and inserting <quote>one or more covered individuals</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H3272AAF171E44D25B7F06AFD0C6B39A6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in behalf of himself or themselves and other employees</quote> and inserting <quote>on behalf of such covered individual or individuals and other covered individuals</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AEC062173354C9EA03C38C036CDF676"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>Such liquidated damages are doubled (subject to section 11 of the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/260">29 U.S.C. 260</external-xref>)) where, in addition to violating the provisions of section 6 or 7, the employer has violated the provisions of section 15(a)(6) with respect to such employee or employees.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C050267BCC24BA9B9F51318AAA1D6CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HF69AE1BD50FB4A98A40FD9D7723C9A70" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0E92A5BAEFF74841B904EE9C6062A7F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any person who violates section 6, 7, 11(c), or 15(a)(6) shall be subject to a civil penalty, for each employee or other individual who was the subject of such a violation, in an amount—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAD4B57C5916E4507AC1E82D694E1666B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not to exceed $1,100; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05044D6EFCE340B1BEF970AC8AAC3E0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a person who has repeatedly or willfully committed such violation, not to exceed $5,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H16D952EFAC2543A48E5B40C9E9B071B4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Employee rights website</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall establish a single webpage on the Department of Labor website that summarizes in plain language the rights of employees and non-employees under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>), including the rights described in the amendments made by section 2.</text>
		</section><section id="HEFFEC2B082F946C29578BA57BF84CBA0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Misclassification of employees for unemployment compensation purposes</header>
 <subsection id="HA4C9270A4C204A658AC4E6446F9D11F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 303(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/503">42 U.S.C. 503(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6F76365E11C641589E7DEC146E1B8D9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (11)(B), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7B1635F44DF49DC928F8C635A94BA8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC937647D427C40E89807C7456693F1CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding after paragraph (12) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HD033E141700E43BFB1B06AF17AB254C9" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H34FC0841E74B4DDF8BF504B029604828"><enum>(13)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD1E9071FE752414395415954256D88AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Such auditing and investigative procedures as may be necessary to identify employers that have not registered under the State law or that are paying unreported wages, where these actions or omissions by the employers have the effect of excluding employees from unemployment compensation coverage; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF651A354F9D34DB58538600526B067C8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The making of quarterly reports to the Secretary of Labor (in such form as the Secretary of Labor may require) describing the results of the procedures under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39013A2BF1D44253B97B12DCBFFAADA3"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The establishment of administrative penalties for misclassifying employees, or paying unreported wages to employees without proper recordkeeping, for unemployment compensation purposes.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAD9DDC5AEF34A37A0F26A5216348746"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of auditing programs</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall include, in the Department of Labor’s system for measuring the performance of States in conducting unemployment compensation tax audits, a specific measure of the effectiveness of States in identifying the under reporting of wages and the underpayment of unemployment compensation contributions (including the effectiveness of States in identifying instances of such under reporting or underpayments despite the absence of cancelled checks, original time sheets, or other similar documentation).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3C9697861B324C5DAF6E347DC3FE172E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H66129586A24A4E3EA3921427E9CAD371"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DD2DF84B6F4E1BA168DEAD2BA5E613"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the Secretary of Labor finds that legislation is necessary for the unemployment compensation law of a State to comply with the amendments made by subsection (a), such amendments shall not apply with respect to such law until the later of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H42085804D65D447CBC8A74B849A01341"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the day after the close of the first regular session of the legislature of such State that begins after the date of enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41D0B07FE8B94FA9BDE467CE7BBB2ACF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>12 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3282AA77664F4DD9B3EF3B95A102DCD7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of state</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3306">section 3306(j)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H74602D989DE44BA88AB2A8B4EA4FB80C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Department of labor coordination, referral, and regulations</header>
 <subsection id="H84B6897885A74F2FA5B377179E3EE760"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordination and referral</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any office, administration, or division of the Department of Labor that, while in the performance of its official duties, obtains information regarding the misclassification by a person subject to the provisions of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>), or any order issued under such Act of any individual regarding whether such individual is an employee or a non-employee engaged in the performance of labor or services for purposes of section 6 or 7 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206</external-xref>, 207), or in records required under section 11(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/211">29 U.S.C. 211(c)</external-xref>), shall report such information to the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor. The Wage and Hour Division may report such information to the Internal Revenue Service as the Wage and Hour Division considers appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H12F38C99AC1F47CDADEBEE53C9CB67BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall promulgate regulations to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H614636D91AFF4436ADB85306DCE99068"><enum>6.</enum><header>Targeted audits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The audits of employers subject to the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) that are conducted by the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor shall include certain industries with frequent incidence of misclassifying employees as non-employees, as determined by the Secretary of Labor.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


