<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H170BA7FADE4F44C08EE180F981FE0036" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 599 IH: Stop Targeting of Political Beliefs by the IRS Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 599</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150128">January 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000570">Mr. Ryan of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit the Internal Revenue Service from modifying the standard for determining whether an organization is operated exclusively for the promotion of social welfare for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6217C5ABAFC14AEE818C24DCF64B8FD9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H040865FDA01E4F20B06904B50C337895" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Targeting of Political Beliefs by the IRS Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9C802D46514845E3816C72BE324D43E1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Applicable standard for determinations of whether an organization is operated exclusively for the promotion of social welfare</header> <subsection id="H36C7C52B6D8A41DDB71BA4741C6F1DE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standard and definitions as in effect on January 1, 2010, which are used to determine whether an organization is operated exclusively for the promotion of social welfare for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall apply for purposes of determining the status of organizations under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H986DDC00F716442AA5209E6D78DC2DF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on modification of standard</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury may not (nor may any delegate of such Secretary) issue, revise, or finalize any regulation (including the proposed regulations published at 78 Fed. Reg. 71535 (November 29, 2013)), revenue ruling, or other guidance not limited to a particular taxpayer relating to the standard and definitions specified in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0BF6768A991B433A93B791FE4F7A083B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application to organizations</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d), this section shall apply with respect to any organization claiming tax exempt status under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which was created on, before, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB55F5AD3A079473FA81569126EBD7FDF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall not apply after December 31, 2017.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

