<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAE4AE38763154FA4A5E8C8277D7CCFFB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 307 IH: Buyback Our Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 307</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a gun buyback grant program.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD195CE586F384C4E9293CA54F2C192E3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3FC28E9F146D4274B9584E37031C67E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Buyback Our Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4E8B80D7DCA447149FE9A83830D76F87"><enum>2.</enum><header>Gun buyback grant program</header> <subsection id="H97EF2191CF2B43FEA2DE346DDD90356A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, through the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice, shall establish a gun buyback grant program under which the Assistant Attorney General may make grants to law enforcement agencies of States, units of local government, and Indian tribal governments to assist in funding gun buyback programs carried out by such agencies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7DDD5C29D7694DD09430ECBEA4896BC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gun buyback program defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>gun buyback program</term> means, with respect to a law enforcement agency of a State, unit of local government, or Indian tribal government, a program carried out by such agency under which guns are purchased or surrendered to such agency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H12E1EBD708914C61A36B64826E54BAE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>A law enforcement agency described in subsection (a) desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs an application for the grant, in accordance with subsection (d) and which shall be in such form and contain such information as the Assistant Attorney General may require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H13EB655CCA144B9482A6E28201CF18AD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Attorney General may make a grant under this section to a law enforcement agency described in subsection (a), with respect to a gun buyback program, only if the application submitted under subsection (c) by such agency provides assurances that—</text> <paragraph id="H21385D20CE4C4A97B11BAD90464B57EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the law enforcement agency will adequately advertise such program to the public;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC08298813D94FCA825E6EFB26A25494"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such program will be administered by law enforcement personnel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF69C5A29FBF4410CBBE755A515E99DCC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all guns received through such program will remain in the possession of law enforcement personnel;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AEA382697F646D485774165A2D36E0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adequate safeguards will be established and followed to prevent the occurrence of fraud in such program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC96727A2D094144B9E2C8C21C09227B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the law enforcement agency will have in place a process to test on site a gun purchased from an individual through such program before payment is provided to such individual; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF78A70ADBCCF4663960B82E8408A7083"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an adequate process will be in place to destroy all guns received through such program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD18ED7DFC5B646AE8A06EBC09DC5D1F4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header> <paragraph id="HEC4D5D4DD32B4890A6923D94060E8347"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), to be eligible for a grant under this section, a law enforcement agency must certify that the law enforcement agency will match all Federal funds provided under such grant with an equal amount of cash or in-kind goods or services from other non-Federal sources.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13101CAFB04B47ABA5DC4D34A4612DF0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs may waive, wholly or in part, the matching requirement under paragraph (1) with respect to a grant made under this section to a law enforcement agency for a gun buyback program if such program provides for obtaining only the guns identified by the National Academy of Sciences pursuant to subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8571ECCBAAAD481FA7AE214C6C927B3C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>National Academy of Sciences Standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, through the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs, shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to develop standards for identifying, and identify, guns that are the most likely to be used in violent crimes and establish a pricing scale for purchasing guns so identified through gun buyback programs receiving grants under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CE531F5E50A4F3195E5EF73D731412F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE9C475D750534E60A0B6B9E4AB6CDBB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports required by grantees</header><text>In the case of a law enforcement agency described in subsection (a) receiving a grant under this section with respect to a gun buyback program, such agency shall submit to the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs—</text> <subparagraph id="HBC480DAE8F144EA9A00DC21CA1BED527"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after receipt of such grant and every 90 days thereafter during the period for which the program is carried out, a report including—</text> 
<clause id="H534C467A497D4665869FCC1955ADDB35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number and types of guns collected and destroyed through such program during such period; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB8C2A848AAC941D08618B318A3A35105"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations for improving future gun buyback programs in the jurisdiction of such agency; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E828C280D884FDEA108CC16A3CCA0EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the last day of such program, a final report including the information described in each of subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (i) with respect to the duration of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H339CE65B50984378A578F6885CA936AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports by the Office of Justice Programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs shall submit to Congress a report on—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H491C7DB8CC614142BEF682CE75A4E0F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of gun buyback programs that received funding under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4DF470B134784710A75C1338EE08FD63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of guns received through each such gun buyback program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H13B3FFAB854748A697521F677106097D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total number of guns purchased through all such gun buyback programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H231AEBDD1AF441439A1453F7F3E10AAE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations on improving the grant program under this section and gun buyback programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54F7A4894B064576AFE0D8473D3F48CF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H3CCA399AB3864302A48F6607F47D0DA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D305D8579524CE4B0809128A879D995"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unit of local government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unit of local government</term> means a county, municipality, town, township, village, parish, borough, or other unit of general government below the State level.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7BAEE6241594CCC81B357CDC21C8864"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Violent crime</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>violent crime</term> means murder, non-negligent manslaughter, forcible rape, robbery, and aggravated assault, as reported by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for purposes of the Uniform Crime Report.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H283C7EF8EF0F4424902556FBD62177F7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

