<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4AF92629822C441A942402C5850B861E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1976 IH: Nuclear Weapons Abolition and Economic and Energy Conversion Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1976</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for nuclear weapons abolition and economic conversion in accordance with District of Columbia Initiative Measure Number 37 of 1992, while ensuring environmental restoration and clean-energy conversion.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HEDB507ED30FE4D78B4BFE810341752C8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H117AC327C2984E95964E52AF0E3790A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nuclear Weapons Abolition and Economic and Energy Conversion Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB456CE03AB3C4D7BB5A2CD5036DE601D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement for nuclear weapons abolition and economic and energy conversion</header> <subsection id="H81430ECF0D64455BBC08AF928787DCAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Government shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H68491D49FAFC4562BF4C1F1AAC53F178"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide leadership to negotiate and enter into a multilateral treaty or other international agreement by the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act that provides for—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B90281FCC71409FA0FD21F2C2C3B540"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the dismantlement and elimination of all nuclear weapons in every country by not later than 2022; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35419F2F137749EFB498EDA3FEE7ECB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strict and effective international control of such dismantlement and elimination;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A4AE89FD3C2493FB1A38AC38826A00C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>redirect resources that are being used for nuclear weapons programs to use—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3C16BB20B7834267BEA8409D95AFD71D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in converting all nuclear weapons industry employees, processes, plants, and programs smoothly to constructive, ecologically beneficial peacetime activities, including strict control of all fissile material and radioactive waste, during the period in which nuclear weapons must be dismantled and eliminated pursuant to the treaty or other international agreement described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4C12A5A900D4E3283D0FAEB7F705550"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in addressing human and infrastructure needs, including development and deployment of sustainable carbon-free and nuclear-free energy sources, health care, housing, education, agriculture, and environmental restoration, including long-term radioactive waste monitoring;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF019C8C7F8E47FA88217D8D06FB5C67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>undertake vigorous, good-faith efforts to eliminate war, armed conflict, and all military operations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85C6FA26AA4F4AE583EAB9DC79889ED8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>actively promote policies to induce all other countries to join in the commitments described in this subsection to create a more peaceful and secure world.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7E758EFB6F244D1B90D515DE86D3085A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subsection (a)(2) shall take effect on the date on which the President certifies to Congress that all countries possessing nuclear weapons have—</text> <paragraph id="H81D3892F3E7A4AD9A2F77B89F0FBAC3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>eliminated such weapons; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FB6AFDD62D943049E906BA218F8271D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>begun such elimination under established legal requirements comparable to those described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

