<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC43848DBF58E4AAC8D4A83C85BB30296" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4026 IH: Nondiscriminatory Transportation Screening Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4026</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151117">November 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide that a concealed handgun license shall be treated as a verifying identity document for
			 purposes of aircraft passenger security screening, and to prohibit the
			 Federal Government from collecting or storing information about an
			 individual relating to a concealed handgun license.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2D4A5E8A1AE4432182AA199DC108AEBC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H09C8A6CE060C45E0B69D87BF551E4EFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nondiscriminatory Transportation Screening Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TSA Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H87377831411844F9A23BD4B416587FBB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of concealed handgun license as verifying identity document for purposes of aircraft passenger security screening</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of part 1560 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, a concealed handgun license shall be treated as a verifying identity document.</text>
 </section><section id="HF631D0606FDE4AF095D7E4F26FDEAE6F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal recordkeeping relating to concealed handgun licenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Government may not collect or store information about an individual relating to a concealed handgun license.</text>
 </section><section id="H468F7866A83146D1BD322997CF99C8DD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Concealed handgun license defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act the term <quote>concealed handgun license</quote> means a license, permit, or other document issued by a State or a political subdivision of a State that authorizes an individual to carry a concealed handgun.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


