<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0F4DB73F66084B4E8588681BE4C12635" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3771 IH: Terms of Credit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3771</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151020">October 20, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a procedure in the House of Representatives and the Senate to accomplish the policies
			 contemplated by the Concurrent Resolution on the Budget for Fiscal Year
			 2016, to encourage the timely completion of fiscal policy work in
			 Congress, and to provide for regulatory relief to grow the economy, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB04574AB8A164F4F9085DF9D83039C37" style="OLC">
		<section id="HCBBAE8890229495C8E20AC871956F2C7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HC5F5F24081284CF2A5D971C1B323D31B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terms of Credit Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H2FCDCC9906E344FCAF9965DFCA88607C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HCBBAE8890229495C8E20AC871956F2C7" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8D707D43AD0C4437BA104B096F002639" level="title">Title I—Budget</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE83BB42DF3C84D2E86625C2E6AA3044D" level="section">Sec. 101. Procedure in the House of Representatives to reduce direct spending.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFAC9482AD8E741F8ABFF416724669FD2" level="section">Sec. 102. Consideration of alternative proposals.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H26D0C8E352A44E0CB7B4792BFCA00235" level="section">Sec. 103. Expedited procedures in the Senate.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H12A999FCEC114981A5F1FEF740E44865" level="section">Sec. 104. Balanced budget constitutional amendment.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB085033A9D554E0FAB640E976BF29CDB" level="title">Title II—Work</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H867C866A30334AA2889160797ED8BC2A" level="section">Sec. 201. Prohibiting consideration of legislation until passage of budget enforcement legislation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD89376B260A54D45B48426EA812F29C5" level="section">Sec. 202. Prohibiting adjournment of House until passage of budget enforcement legislation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD755A11F885E4D6AAB7BCFA740DDC9CE" level="section">Sec. 203. Prohibiting adjournment of House until passage of appropriation bills.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF49C4966A25E43A28C34D42C74976948" level="section">Sec. 204. Appropriations procedures in the Senate.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H574CDD6827BE4E20989B2466B21E1F9A" level="section">Sec. 205. Effective dates.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9F3BCF9E1F184C0480FFA7213D7634CF" level="title">Title III—Grow</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF2F1AD1A90BB4E96AF7C4D97EA5043E2" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Regulatory Freeze for Jobs</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H01063EB9369C4145A389847B967C0F60" level="section">Sec. 301. Short title.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEB4652FE9A8C4E44BB7558A887884203" level="section">Sec. 302. Moratorium on significant regulatory actions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H182CA328C3294F26A93D3864B849D230" level="section">Sec. 303. Waivers and exceptions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H503D0A34FE9948B1B9F2F3D2876453C3" level="section">Sec. 304. Judicial review.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB949FBFC34A8431C86BD8B777D6F8B56" level="section">Sec. 305. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD18CE4C55EA544FA99B191E24A2B95C0" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Midnight Rule Relief</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4A4ECEE809CA43D5A3D779A28E223346" level="section">Sec. 311. Short title.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H216E702C138D4B98A462152D495E8EF3" level="section">Sec. 312. Moratorium on midnight rules.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE08AB0E823134397B51DCDC3F3360F42" level="section">Sec. 313. Exception.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0C82EE891DCC44D8B9378A5906320DB8" level="section">Sec. 314. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H98BA51AADB9E4D44A4F309B8B0872BD7" level="title">Title IV—Debt Limit</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA373695D866A4F50BB4C959F4C10B791" level="section">Sec. 401. Increase in the public debt limit.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><title id="H8D707D43AD0C4437BA104B096F002639"><enum>I</enum><header>Budget</header>
			<section id="HE83BB42DF3C84D2E86625C2E6AA3044D"><enum>101.</enum><header>Procedure in the House of Representatives to reduce direct spending</header>
 <subsection id="HAEDA486B75244ABEBBFF414373CD5511"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Spending reduction directives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the chair of each committee of the House of Representatives listed in paragraphs (1) through (11) shall submit to the chair of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives recommendations with respect to changes in laws within the committee’s jurisdiction to reduce direct spending, over the period of fiscal years 2016 through 2025, equal to or greater than the dollar amount applicable to such committee, as follows:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H4B1D066B472142DF9CA1CE1377249748"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Agriculture, $300,022,000,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAA494AD5F394E00BD654BF1EE2259F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Education and the Workforce, $229,658,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7463DCAC56844A67BA37A4A378C2437B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Energy and Commerce, $1,369,266,000,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9851EE3F3EC417388439873115D3B58"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Financial Services, $62,056,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA582BA8DFA994E968D6E8F54301DA85B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Homeland Security, $19,470,000,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD084A714E8B442FA06BB8B8B50A2F15"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on House Administration, $53,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2659C08981946A188DE3BE445EC41D0"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on the Judiciary, $23,055,000,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0C0BAD2DDF140FABCCDB4EF088BB7A5"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Natural Resources, $32,483,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD057250020B343F881F0438BC711425F"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, $193,896,000,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3515BE37B26D4A3C9422AF8AFD34BCA2"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs, $2,569,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7724A6391FF94AE28EB03E8A88EEF1D3"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Ways and Means, $1,594,658,000,000.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2EFF0D1EA2544FF8F7CD713E00A5DA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legislative procedure</header> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8E7AE671E5F4AAF8860442975ECEDAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each committee so directed under subsection (a) shall, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, submit the recommendations described in such subsection to the chair of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives, which upon receiving all such recommendations, shall report to the House of Representatives, not later than 30 days thereafter, the bill described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H289D559B83FF480FAC55EC68C955F756"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bill described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A bill described in this paragraph is a bill—</text> <subparagraph id="HC279DF03EC694F4F888C3416A9A81989"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consisting of legislation carrying out the recommendations described in subsection (a) without any substantive revision; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1EDE8DC09294EA9ACA84443890AD102"><enum>(B)</enum><text>entitled <quote>A bill to provide for reductions in direct spending to meet the direct spending targets provided for in the Terms of Credit Act.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14403055F6424DE9875D82BD9C4BFC7E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Failure to submit recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Rules of the House of Representatives may make in order amendments to carry out the recommendations described in subsection (a) if a committee of the House fails to submit recommendations to the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives consistent with paragraph (1).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7A092E5621C24537B3C41665EBE154CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited consideration in the House of Representatives</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HBA14659C02FF4BC39A14FA3C6D3C7CB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than five legislative days after the bill described in subsection (b) or section 102(a) is reported or the committees of referral have been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the bill in the House. Such a motion shall be in order only at a time designated by the Speaker in the legislative schedule within two legislative days after the day on which the proponent announces an intention to the House to offer the motion provided that such notice is provided after such bill is reported. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed with respect to that bill. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H43C22C7037024416AC916759B0C92861"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (3), if the motion to proceed is agreed to, the House shall immediately proceed to consider the bill referred to in paragraph (1) in the House without intervening motion. Such bill shall be considered as read. Except as provided in paragraph (3), all points of order against such bill and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on such bill to its passage without intervening motion except 2 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent and one motion to limit debate on the bill.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0A88DA34E634DC896005A0573B9FEC6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extraneous matter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A provision containing an extraneous matter may not be reported in a bill considered pursuant to this subsection, and may not be considered as an amendment thereto. When the House is considering a bill pursuant to paragraph (2), upon a point of order being made by any Member against material extraneous to the directives to a committee which is contained in any title or provision of the bill or offered as an amendment to the bill, and the point of order is sustained by the Chair, any part of said title or provision that contains material extraneous to the instructions shall be deemed stricken from the bill and no provision deemed extraneous may be offered as an amendment from the floor. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a provision of a bill considered pursuant to paragraph (2) shall be considered extraneous if such provision does not produce a net decrease in outlays or produces a net increase in revenue. In making a determination as to the extraneous nature of a provision, material, or part, the Chair shall rely on estimates from the Committee on the Budget.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4389EDA77C844564BEE6B69BFBBF9E30"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the House adopts a special order of business for the consideration of the bill referred to in paragraph (1), including a special order of business which may make amendments to the bill in order, the bill shall be considered under the terms and conditions of that special order of business, except that such special order of business may not provide for debate for a period of time to exceed 10 hours, equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H085A3234DB68482EBEFD22EBD4577C28"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Termination of expedited procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the House has passed a bill or bills that meet the total amount of each spending reduction directive under subsection (a) as estimated by the Chairman of the Committee on the Budget, the expedited procedures under this subsection shall no longer apply.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFAC9482AD8E741F8ABFF416724669FD2"><enum>102.</enum><header>Consideration of alternative proposals</header>
 <subsection id="HF928EC18B69A4F8AB02651CB66EC3AD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Committee on the Budget fails to report the bill required under section 101(b) prior to the deadline set forth under such section for reporting the bill, any Member of the House of Representatives may introduce a bill to accomplish spending reduction directives under section 101(a)(1).</text>
				</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H413341879BB84655B40D202443E92722"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration in the House of Representatives</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H35EB645638FE46018AFD388B9AC41B68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Referral and reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), any committee of the House of Representatives to which a bill introduced pursuant to subsection (a) is referred shall report it to the House without amendment not later than the fifth legislative day after the date of its introduction. If a committee fails to report the bill within that period or the House has adopted a concurrent resolution providing for adjournment sine die at the end of a Congress, such committee shall be automatically discharged from further consideration of the bill and it shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1F8CFD1EF8854666B64619F9735E7DDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requiring minimum reduction in direct spending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A committee of the House to which a bill is referred under this section is not required to report the bill to the House if the bill does not reduce direct spending by at least 5 percent of the directive applicable to the committee under section 101(a), as estimated by the Congressional Budget Office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBACB22DA3DA4427EA9AB118CF2C8D778"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expedited procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any bill reported or discharged pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be considered under the expedited procedures described under section 101(c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H710B9FC445F54D4CAB726DA034DA0CBE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination of expedited procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the House has passed a bill or bills that meet the total amount of each spending reduction directive under section 101(a) as estimated by the Chairman of the Committee on the Budget, the expedited procedures under paragraph (3) shall no longer apply.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H26D0C8E352A44E0CB7B4792BFCA00235"><enum>103.</enum><header>Expedited procedures in the Senate</header>
 <subsection id="HE7D632C3B58C4BCA8E13CE56D7F4F312"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Committee Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the Senate, upon receipt of a bill passed in the House pursuant to section 101 or 102 shall be jointly referred to the committee or committees of jurisdiction, which shall report the bill without any revision and with a favorable recommendation, an unfavorable recommendation, or without recommendation, not later than 5 legislative days after receipt in the Senate. If any committee fails to report the bill within that period, that committee shall be automatically discharged from consideration of the bill, and the bill shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H81CD992534EE4B18AB2A8233AF6BF2F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Motion To proceed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order, not later than 2 days of session after the date on which a bill under paragraph (1) is reported or discharged from all committees to which it was referred, for the majority leader of the Senate or the majority leader's designee to move to proceed to the consideration of the bill. It shall also be in order for any Member of the Senate to move to proceed to the consideration of such bill at any time after the conclusion of such 2-day period. A motion to proceed is in order even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to. All points of order against the motion to proceed to the bill are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the bill is agreed to, the bill shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC23067EF6CC744718624B085B716E976"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All points of order against the bill and against consideration of the bill are waived. Consideration of the bill and of all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith shall not exceed a total of 30 hours which shall be divided equally between the Majority and Minority Leaders or their designees. A motion further to limit debate on the bill is in order, shall require an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members duly chosen and sworn, and is not debatable. Any debatable motion or appeal is debatable for not to exceed 1 hour, to be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the motion or appeal. All time used for consideration of the bill, including time used for quorum calls and voting, shall be counted against the total 30 hours of consideration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H16925D2C700A4E66A7D0E898502221D4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Senate has voted to proceed to the bill, the vote on passage of the bill shall occur immediately following the conclusion of the debate on the bill, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6BA4AD152ECC4AF190726EA50C175F43"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulings of the Chair on procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to the bill shall be decided without debate.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H12A999FCEC114981A5F1FEF740E44865"><enum>104.</enum><header>Balanced budget constitutional amendment</header>
 <subsection id="H602FCDCB11B248F5A871CCF4760C494C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vote on the balanced budget amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2015, the House of Representatives and Senate, respectively, shall vote on passage of a joint resolution, the title of which is as follows: <quote>Joint resolution proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</quote>.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H9F182290F2DF4CBAA57C37F4060E1B0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration by the other house</header>
					<paragraph id="H644B35287B99420B8816F41210FDC012"><enum>(1)</enum><header>House consideration</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC7DF0D6EC8A24C37897858833E78E956"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the House receives a joint resolution described in subsection (a) from the Senate, such joint resolution shall be referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. If the committee fails to report the joint resolution within five legislative days, it shall be in order to move that the House discharge the committee from further consideration of the joint resolution. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to discharge the joint resolution. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion except twenty minutes of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. If such a motion is adopted, the House shall proceed immediately to consider the joint resolution in accordance with subparagraph (C). A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8633C83012B74051B15CB9E725E080F5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the joint resolution has been referred to the appropriate calendar or the committee has been discharged (other than by motion) from its consideration, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed with respect to the joint resolution. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6294F9524064AFE9F67AEE8C25BF552"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to its passage without intervening motion except two hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent and one motion to limit debate on the joint resolution. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H132CC24449294371A909E3C7498A8A37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Senate consideration</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC3C0AD82A2DF40AC8D4F5D564ABC5809"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Senate receives a joint resolution described in subsection (a) from the House of Representatives, such joint resolution shall be referred to the appropriate committee of the Senate. If such committee has not reported the joint resolution at the close of the fifth session day after its receipt by the Senate, such committee shall be automatically discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and it shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1990360D568E47FA89C5320623E478B5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consideration of the joint resolution and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 20 hours, which shall be divided equally between the majority and minority leaders or their designees. A motion to further limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the joint resolution is not in order. Any debatable motion or appeal is debatable for not to exceed 1 hour, to be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the motion or appeal. All time used for consideration of the joint resolution, including time used for quorum calls and voting, shall be counted against the total 20 hours of consideration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H080F17958C9943FD81A285CCA5CA86BE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Senate has voted to proceed to a joint resolution, the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall be taken on or before the close of the seventh session day after such joint resolution has been reported or discharged or immediately following the conclusion of consideration of the joint resolution, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title commented="no" id="HB085033A9D554E0FAB640E976BF29CDB"><enum>II</enum><header>Work</header>
			<section commented="no" id="H867C866A30334AA2889160797ED8BC2A"><enum>201.</enum><header>Prohibiting consideration of legislation until passage of budget enforcement legislation</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H4F8706E0E4E742D3941EC4BA015EA801"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the House has not passed a bill or bills that meet the total amount of each spending reduction directive under section 101(a) as estimated by the Chairman of the Committee on the Budget, it shall not be in order in the House of Representatives to consider any bill or joint resolution during the One Hundred Fourteenth Congress, other than legislation under section 101 or 102 or a bill, resolution, concurrent resolution, or joint resolution referenced in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6385C981D1F64850A19A7C167D2D5570"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The point of order under subsection (a) shall not apply at any time after—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H86D85ADEE3CD4ABABC7EC729E7B51CFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the House has adopted a concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2017; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA02ACCE461CD4F6AADCA123B1F442E24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the House of Representatives has passed during fiscal year 2016 legislation containing an authorization of the use of military force or a declaration of war.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HD89376B260A54D45B48426EA812F29C5"><enum>202.</enum><header>Prohibiting adjournment of House until passage of budget enforcement legislation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall not be in order for the House of Representatives to consider a concurrent resolution to provide that the House stand adjourned during the One Hundred Fourteenth Congress unless the House has passed legislation under section 101 or 102.</text>
			</section><section commented="no" id="HD755A11F885E4D6AAB7BCFA740DDC9CE"><enum>203.</enum><header>Prohibiting adjournment of House until passage of appropriation bills</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H3985A5E7105E4E35ABBA09644A33D322"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If by September 1 of any calendar year the House of Representatives has not passed each of the regular appropriation bills (or any combination thereof), a consolidated appropriations bill, or a full-year continuing resolution for the fiscal year which begins on October 1 of that calendar year, it shall not be in order in the House to consider a concurrent resolution to provide that the House stand adjourned during any day occurring during that calendar year until the House has passed each such bill or such continuing resolution.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H245B3F239A5D4C86A61DE02B58790A2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H83288821C9D349D99731F153BAF3FD44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>regular appropriation bill</term> means any annual appropriation bill which is under the jurisdiction of a single subcommittee of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives (as may be provided under the Rules for the fiscal year involved); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65D750CA34A048AC81C99ED7D6AD2641"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>full-year continuing resolution</term> means a bill or joint resolution providing for continuing appropriations for all of the programs and activities of the Federal Government through the end of the fiscal year for which a regular appropriation bill has not been enacted.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HF49C4966A25E43A28C34D42C74976948"><enum>204.</enum><header>Appropriations procedures in the Senate</header>
 <subsection id="HF3CF70D05A7347B18B6AE1718DB4B987"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After October 1 of a fiscal year, a motion to proceed to a regular appropriations bill for that fiscal year shall be nondebatable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C0CA2905316460A8D0111CF6A17D184"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regular appropriations bill defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>regular appropriations bill</term> means any annual appropriations bill which has been reported favorably from the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text>
				</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H574CDD6827BE4E20989B2466B21E1F9A"><enum>205.</enum><header>Effective dates<editorial></editorial><editorial></editorial></header>
 <subsection id="H0B297818BCF24398996F9A5A346D98EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sections 201 and 202</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 201 and 202 shall take effect upon the expiration of the 150-day period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2B07DF8B06344E9BB2B2EA8D94752B3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sections 203 and 204</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 203 and 204 shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="H9F3BCF9E1F184C0480FFA7213D7634CF"><enum>III</enum><header>Grow</header> <subtitle id="HF2F1AD1A90BB4E96AF7C4D97EA5043E2"><enum>A</enum><header>Regulatory Freeze for Jobs</header> <section id="H01063EB9369C4145A389847B967C0F60"><enum>301.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This subtitle may be cited as the <quote>Regulatory Freeze for Jobs Act of 2015</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="HEB4652FE9A8C4E44BB7558A887884203"><enum>302.</enum><header>Moratorium on significant regulatory actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An agency may not take any significant regulatory action during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on July 1, 2017.</text>
				</section><section id="H182CA328C3294F26A93D3864B849D230"><enum>303.</enum><header>Waivers and exceptions</header>
 <subsection id="H7A8B6691848645DC99B886EC535DB76B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, an agency may take a significant regulatory action only in accordance with subsection (b), (c), or (d) during the period described in section 302.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H906DED44FF3D4784A269FEF866A8A6DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presidential waiver</header>
 <paragraph id="HFFAC5F3964D2470FA2BF8FC2D82B6440"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agency may take a significant regulatory action if the President determines by Executive order that the significant regulatory action is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H76A80A984C6E4E7E8C8495AC16985E1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>necessary because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAE0FE25FF2640FF87083EE1289A6386"><enum>(B)</enum><text>necessary for the enforcement of criminal or civil rights laws;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DE2540565194BE9AAA1EAA5659657FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>necessary for the national security of the United States; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H004C666C3FD04F51B384440F0EB24EC3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>issued pursuant to any statute implementing an international trade agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E72D76058A443A2BE97353330D851A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional disapproval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a joint resolution disapproving an Executive order issued under paragraph (1) is enacted into law not later than 30 legislative days after the issuance of the Executive order, an agency may not take a significant regulatory action pursuant to the Executive order, and any significant regulatory action taken pursuant to the Executive order prior to the enactment of the joint resolution shall have no force or effect.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90D96198CCEF4076945927452BE57C73"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deregulatory exception</header><text>An agency may take a significant regulatory action if the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget certifies in writing that the significant regulatory action is limited to repealing an existing rule.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H0F544AE1F3764A148CEAB6BEDAFE9D1E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional waivers</header>
 <paragraph id="HBC097D67D7BE49F29BF75F5F818DBE3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>For any significant regulatory action not eligible for a Presidential waiver pursuant to subsection (b), the President may submit a written request to Congress for a waiver of the application of section 302 for such action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EF2F6B5ABBB4838ADDE5639FBA0D22A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A submission by the President under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8DE8CBBF016460B8D39C0126A166CC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify the significant regulatory action and the scope of the requested waiver;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05DDB030C6504DCA930E0444A0F59D3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe all the reasons the significant regulatory action is necessary to protect the public health, safety, or welfare; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H990E70135195493CA6A6483790459B37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include an explanation of why the significant regulatory action is ineligible for a Presidential waiver under subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2439F867EA7A47E5B6EEF53F95994AC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Congressional action</header><text>Congress shall give expeditious consideration and take appropriate legislative action with respect to any submission by the President under this subsection.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H503D0A34FE9948B1B9F2F3D2876453C3"><enum>304.</enum><header>Judicial review</header>
 <subsection id="HAFF7F056838B4A26961780D8EF581253"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Any party adversely affected or aggrieved by any rule or guidance resulting from a regulatory action taken in violation of this subtitle is entitled to judicial review in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code. Any determination by either the President or the Secretary of Labor under this subtitle shall be subject to judicial review under such chapter.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0BCA401DF4354EFCAC4F2D7AFD75A48D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>Each court having jurisdiction to review any rule or guidance resulting from a significant regulatory action for compliance with any other provision of law shall have jurisdiction to review all claims under this subtitle.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF5297E98D3B42F2A0D7BD966BF051B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In granting any relief in any civil action under this section, the court shall order the agency to take corrective action consistent with this subtitle and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, including remanding the rule or guidance resulting from the significant regulatory action to the agency and enjoining the application or enforcement of that rule or guidance, unless the court finds by a preponderance of the evidence that application or enforcement is required to protect against an imminent and serious threat to the national security of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H226EDDFDAD1747F38D894EF0353B2602"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reasonable attorney’s fees for small businesses</header><text>The court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees and costs to a substantially prevailing small business in any civil action arising under this subtitle. A small business may qualify as substantially prevailing even without obtaining a final judgment in its favor if the agency that took the significant regulatory action changes its position after the civil action is filed. Such award shall be paid out of the administrative budget of the office in the agency that took the challenged agency action.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7C19F614673143E09C21363EE696EA24"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on commencing civil action</header><text>A party may seek and obtain judicial review during the 1-year period beginning on the date of the challenged agency action or within 90 days after an enforcement action or notice thereof, except that where another provision of law requires that a civil action be commenced before the expiration of that 1-year period, such lesser period shall apply.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H04DB2C9E4EAD4B839FE094A3ECA6785B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Small business defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>small business</term> means any business, including an unincorporated business or a sole proprietorship, that employs not more than 500 employees or that has a net worth of less than $7,000,000 on the date a civil action arising under this subtitle is filed.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HB949FBFC34A8431C86BD8B777D6F8B56"><enum>305.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subtitle:</text> <paragraph id="H231148F3D3524BBFBA4A27F4CF0130DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term under section 551 of title 5, United States Code, except that such term does not include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H46B5EC7C8FB041709B4F2E322D6EA7D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H927C439224D449AEABACBBEB6EF6E465"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Open Market Committee; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82B300F42E334B9E90ADCA26476BD24E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Postal Service.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BB23B427C484800BB38023924A50B7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulatory action</header><text>The term <term>regulatory action</term> means any substantive action by an agency that promulgates or is expected to lead to the promulgation of a final rule or regulation, including a notice of inquiry, an advance notice of proposed rulemaking, and a notice of proposed rulemaking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A11E5248F3F4770B2E858D1CC6AE334"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule</header><text>The term <term>rule</term> has the meaning given that term under section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H04758EC5A28546A887410FC1A2FAE6A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Significant regulatory action</header><text>The term <term>significant regulatory action</term> means any regulatory action that is likely to result in a rule or guidance that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget finds is likely to have an annual cost to the economy of $50,000,000 or more or adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, small entities, or State, local, or tribal governments or communities. In determining the annual cost to the economy under this paragraph, the Administrator shall take into account any expected change in revenue of businesses that will be caused by such regulatory action, as well as any change in revenue of businesses that has already taken place as businesses prepare for the implementation of the regulatory action. If meeting that definition, such term includes any requirement by the Secretary of the Treasury, except to the extent provided in Treasury Regulations as in effect on February 21, 2011, that a payor of interest make an information return in the case of interest—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H34B642D61E234263910F77B0D8BB9394"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/871">section 871(i)(2)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21077E034B8442048276D3B15A6990A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is paid—</text>
 <clause id="HC91591687243494D8DF999AACF785E87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to a nonresident alien, and</text> </clause><clause id="HA1560B1B3157492E9A4276DD13750908"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on a deposit maintained at an office within the United States.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F10D298810E4A9686E80432A9979F13"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small entity</header><text>The term <term>small entity</term> has the meaning given that term under section 601(6) of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></section></subtitle><subtitle id="HD18CE4C55EA544FA99B191E24A2B95C0"><enum>B</enum><header>Midnight Rule Relief</header> <section id="H4A4ECEE809CA43D5A3D779A28E223346"><enum>311.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This subtitle may be cited as the <quote>Midnight Rule Relief Act of 2015</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="H216E702C138D4B98A462152D495E8EF3"><enum>312.</enum><header>Moratorium on midnight rules</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided under section 311, during the moratorium period, an agency may not propose or finalize any midnight rule that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget finds is likely to result in an annual cost to the economy of $50,000,000 or more or adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, small entities, or State, local, or tribal governments or communities.</text>
				</section><section id="HE08AB0E823134397B51DCDC3F3360F42"><enum>313.</enum><header>Exception</header>
					<subsection id="HC8486EB3A7D349EB99C3F6E87BB542F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emergency exception</header>
 <paragraph id="HD68CE0863F4E430D8126753795110186"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 312 shall not apply to a midnight rule if the President determines that the midnight rule is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H451D9BF53DB14204B6BD938000B369F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>necessary because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E99440D70D54B818171C90574D78196"><enum>(B)</enum><text>necessary for the enforcement of criminal or civil rights laws;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1070E90F10234B48808C1CE7CF700DA9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>necessary for the national security of the United States; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H243C9FD533CF432F909131CA551824C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>issued pursuant to any statute implementing an international trade agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23B450427257489FBBE5069B2315B26B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional disapproval</header><text>If a joint resolution disapproving a midnight rule described in paragraph (1) is enacted into law not later than 30 legislative days after the determination made by the President under paragraph (1), an agency may not propose or finalize that midnight rule, and any midnight rule finalized pursuant to that determination under paragraph (1) prior to the enactment of the joint resolution shall have no force or effect.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H943E21CD0D88458FA0ABB540BB947EF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deregulatory exception</header><text>Section 312 shall not apply to a midnight rule that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs within the Office of Management and Budget certifies in writing is limited to repealing an existing rule.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8BA51A2EFA4043538D946C5AAA5C7273"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of exceptions</header><text>Not later than 30 days after a determination under subsection (a) or a certification is made under subsection (b), the head of the relevant agency shall publish in the Federal Register any midnight rule excluded from the moratorium period due to an exception under this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0C82EE891DCC44D8B9378A5906320DB8"><enum>314.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subtitle:</text> <paragraph id="H33BED241587545ADBC66F7D121231D22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term under section 551 of title 5, United States Code, except that such term does not include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F76E4B31F3E4184AF631A2CCB225339"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC169B3D57D4242F0BAC96D3D34589982"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Open Market Committee; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB494D159E97644C89E8C391908C0D646"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Postal Service.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H428DFD05AB564872B4B7A82D620519C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Moratorium period</header><text>The term <term>moratorium period</term> means the day after the day referred to in section 1 of title 3, United States Code, through January 20 of the following year, in which a President is not serving a consecutive term.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD745DA3A62E645588D878F97D2A4C198"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Midnight rule</header><text>The term <term>midnight rule</term> means an agency statement of general applicability and future effect, issued during the moratorium period, that is intended to have the force and effect of law and is designed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03D2D496707745DEBCA182D7C48F7763"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to implement, interpret, or prescribe law or policy; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20A1B16E56A94BC4B1842A4E08FB5455"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to describe the procedure or practice requirements of an agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H632591ECF6C34C9487F916489A3C5296"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule</header><text>The term <term>rule</term> has the meaning given that term under section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H56EBA0576041416D95C7EB611DCB20C8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small entity</header><text>The term <term>small entity</term> has the meaning given that term under section 601(6) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
					</paragraph></section></subtitle></title><title commented="no" id="H98BA51AADB9E4D44A4F309B8B0872BD7"><enum>IV</enum><header>Debt Limit</header>
 <section commented="no" id="HA373695D866A4F50BB4C959F4C10B791"><enum>401.</enum><header>Increase in the public debt limit</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3101(b) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking the dollar amount contained therein and inserting <quote>$19,600,000,000,000</quote>.</text>
			</section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


