<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3FDFC92ED1A247AEBEB3122DBC952A57" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3358 IH: Prevent Repeat Offenders Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3358</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to ensure that sex offenders to be released from the
			 custody of Immigration and Customs Enforcement are registered on sex
			 offender registry, and relevant State, tribal, and local authorities are
			 notified of their release, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF18B3D1B6D7C4F1F87AA5C7BE93B3A13" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2175DD829D99443DAC722EEC3B5C80DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prevent Repeat Offenders Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7F0EF1D7ACF64C2BB5445FD915B76D06"><enum>2.</enum><header>Registration of certain aliens</header> <subsection id="H2A0BEC2D0F1E451284320162FFBE896D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle A of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H110B130A27124161BF7C3D981D07B0DE" style="OLC">
					<section id="H8830293D775C47F98D8532449A338B2C"><enum>132.</enum><header>Registration of certain aliens in custody of Immigration and Customs Enforcement on sex offender
			 registry and notification to State, tribal, and local authorities</header>
 <subsection id="H411CDA59EF3042FA8524C42D2D3A9B56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take appropriate actions to ensure that, prior to the release of an alien in the custody of United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (hereinafter in this section referred to as <quote>ICE</quote>) who is required to register under this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF22BAA930D48498383E537A36AB4FCF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in coordination with the Attorney General, such alien is registered in the National Sex Offender Registry; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D1FA5DA31C74898B6617907486DEF70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such alien is informed of their registration requirements under this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF422B85113D24744BC0F2B0F1E5EF1E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Condition of release</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take appropriate actions to ensure that the release of an alien who is required to register under this Act is conditioned on such alien’s registration in each jurisdiction required by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H11EE8557CEFD4615ADC6A64306D13039"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification of state, tribal, and local authorities</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take appropriate actions to ensure that the chief law enforcement officer of each State, tribal, and local jurisdiction in which the alien resides and the agency responsible for the receipt or maintenance of sex offender registration information in the State, tribal, or local jurisdiction in which the alien resides are promptly notified when an alien who is required to register under this Act is—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB6F34BD533624136980FA78DA4E8A31C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>taken into custody by ICE;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E773C9B203E44869168B92CFC1CDC32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>released from ICE custody; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFC4CEFDE0954D3E972418803A9FC02A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>removed from the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H885C40C1AAE746B199E9909BFBBC56C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act the Secretary of Homeland Security shall report to Congress on the progress made in implementing the amendment made by this Act.</text>
						</subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H812DD9CD01C34BCE9AC27BCFCAB16FD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections in section 1 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 131 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HD3153E34DD1E485D8F8AC94C3882AEA1" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">132. Registration of certain aliens in custody of Immigration and Customs Enforcement on sex
			 offender registry and notification to State, tribal, and local
			 authorities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


