<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8951F9F1322046ABAB7DDCA371061DEC" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2554 IH: Continental Divide Wilderness and Recreation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes"> I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2554</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness
			 Preservation System, to designate the Tenmile Recreation Management Area
			 and Porcupine Gulch Protection Area, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC57BB6645CAD4E80AF5DD1A936DCE910" style="OLC">
		<section id="H52F95FF6EFC64D7B8650A569FB4E93FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H1E8EECCCEC07481CBD8116C5526CACDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Continental Divide Wilderness and Recreation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBF09DACD633D4FBDA428371AD69EAF89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H52F95FF6EFC64D7B8650A569FB4E93FC" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H13C7AB7ED3EC4DE9B3CD365D20576B31" level="section">Sec. 2. Colorado wilderness additions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5EBF34F0E7484A1CBE3E43C61E7D0350" level="section">Sec. 3. Tenmile Recreation Management Area, White River National Forest, Colorado.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H88D2700265244A4C8E8D65B5C095A20F" level="section">Sec. 4. Porcupine Gulch Protection Area, White River National Forest, Colorado.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H13C7AB7ED3EC4DE9B3CD365D20576B31"><enum>2.</enum><header>Colorado wilderness additions</header>
 <subsection id="H14E28284ED7445D187CB07DF564BE4C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">Public Law 103–77</external-xref>; 107 Stat. 756; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5008459312D14630B1A675CF8A2EAD0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (18), by striking <quote>1993,</quote> and inserting <quote>1993, and certain Federal lands in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 6,349 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Proposed Ute Pass Wilderness</quote>, <quote>Proposed Acorn Creek Wilderness</quote>, and <quote>Proposed Ptarmigan Additions Wilderness</quote> on a map entitled <quote>Ptarmigan Peak Wilderness Additions Proposal</quote>, dated July, 2014,</quote> and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H451892588C994CA8AAAB3A3AA767D88B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block id="HC04B2187561048DA87109A7DFDE2DC48" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA9C57B56125D4A5D8D75B19674A11EA8"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Holy cross wilderness addition</header><text>Certain Federal lands in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 3,942 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Proposed No Name Wilderness</quote> on a map entitled <quote>Holy Cross Wilderness Addition Proposal</quote>, dated July, 2014, and which are incorporated in and shall be deemed to be a part of the Holy Cross Wilderness designated by section 102(a)(5) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/560">Public Law 96–560</external-xref> (94 Stat. 3266).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2EE535344B048D786B8A474A10F81CA"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Hoosier ridge wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal lands in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 5,172 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled <quote>Hoosier Ridge Wilderness Proposal</quote>, dated July, 2014, and which shall be known as the <quote>Hoosier Ridge Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25628C5C688141E4817E49E9A10A584B"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Tenmile wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal lands in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 7,577 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Proposed Tenmile Wilderness</quote> on a map entitled <quote>Tenmile Proposal</quote>, dated July, 2014, and which shall be known as the <quote>Tenmile Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7608254C41644DB898A7D004FC391D6"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Williams fork wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal lands in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 9,338 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled <quote>Proposed Williams Fork Wilderness</quote>, dated July, 2014, and which shall be known as the <quote>Williams Fork Wilderness</quote>.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HE3E6643E10D54400BA5950A866DF1136"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Eagles nest wilderness additions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC514A6F3A6FD418BABEFE85816C7EBD9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation of wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal lands in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 7,082 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Proposed Freeman Creek Wilderness</quote> and <quote>Proposed Spraddle Creek Wilderness</quote> on a map entitled <quote>Eagles Nest Wilderness Additions Proposal</quote>, dated July, 2014, and which are incorporated in and shall be deemed to be a part of the Eagles Nest Wilderness designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/352">Public Law 94–352</external-xref> (90 Stat. 870).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD9037E1C7E8457AA1C37AA09EFDA41B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Potential wilderness</header>
 <clause id="HA8E1AA07EF1D452D8E72CE9D3CCD7FCA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act, certain Federal lands in the White River National Forest which comprise approximately 2,338 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Proposed Spraddle Creek Potential Wilderness</quote> on a map entitled <quote>Eagles Nest Wilderness Additions Proposal</quote>, dated July 2014, is designated as a potential wilderness area.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H65976B76B5424E8AAB8A5C240C6C8308"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii) and subject to valid existing rights, the potential wilderness area designated by this subparagraph shall be managed in accordance with the Wilderness Act and this Act.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H50D07D6919144440A79453A046D883E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Ecological restoration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of ecological restoration (including any activity necessary to restore the natural ecosystems and water quality and protect watershed values in the potential wilderness area designated by this subparagraph), the Secretary or an authorized third party may use motorized and mechanized transport and equipment in the potential wilderness area until the date on which the potential wilderness area is incorporated into the Eagles Nest Wilderness.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H543CE588A77D40B5B1C4B442D078568D"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Designation as wilderness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The potential wilderness area designated by this subparagraph shall be designated as wilderness and incorporated in and deemed to be a part of the Eagles Nest Wilderness on the earlier of—</text>
 <subclause id="H0BB3DEF739924FB8BF5C8BDAD94422D3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice that the ecological restoration activities identified in clause (iii) have been completed by the Secretary or an authorized third party; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9E2CD7C7956B4882B4EA120936AC6CAC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Continental Divide Wilderness and Recreation Act</short-title>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F0AB6A9EA1B426EBF3E525DBA088E8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act for purposes of administering the Federal lands designated as wilderness by paragraphs (18) and (22) through (26)(A) of section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">Public Law 103–77</external-xref>), as amended or added by subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE625F75A879C462DB8468E495864132B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fire, insects, and diseases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As provided in section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>), in the case of the Federal lands designated as wilderness by paragraphs (18) and (22) through (26)(A) of section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">Public Law 103–77</external-xref>), as amended or added by subsection (a), the Secretary may take any measure that the Secretary determines to be necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE8BDED8AD4854BADA6D1E6738CC68696"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any land or interest in land that is acquired by the United States within the boundaries of the Federal lands designated as wilderness by paragraphs (18) and (22) through (26)(A) of section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">Public Law 103–77</external-xref>), as amended or added by subsection (a), shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC55A79E6FC904A79957D088D95B823FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the wilderness area of which the Federal lands are a part; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA096855696E435F9A5332C3A7F2EDEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with the applicable provisions of this Act and any other applicable laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H505F4590CC7248A1B5DD6E0C8D5A88E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The grazing of livestock on the Federal lands designated as wilderness by paragraphs (18) and (22) through (26)(A) of section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">Public Law 103–77</external-xref>), as amended or added by subsection (a), if established before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue subject to such reasonable regulations as are considered necessary by the Secretary, in accordance with section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2FF3F8BE8E814295AF72D4CF00BFF70A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No buffer zones</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress does not intend that the designation by this Act of Federal lands as wilderness in the State of Colorado creates or implies the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around any wilderness area. The fact that nonwilderness activities or uses can be seen or heard from within a wilderness area shall not, of itself, preclude such activities or uses up to the boundary of the wilderness area.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H5EBF34F0E7484A1CBE3E43C61E7D0350"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tenmile Recreation Management Area, White River National Forest, Colorado</header>
 <subsection id="H8B5ED0159AD940B68C6FC1DD78629B90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain Federal land in the White River National Forest in the State of Colorado which comprise approximately 11,417 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Proposed Tenmile Recreation Management Area</quote> on a map entitled <quote>Tenmile Proposal</quote>, dated July 2014, is designated the <quote>Tenmile Recreation Management Area</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Recreation Management Area</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7F5136B7541643B3B8AD7E953AEDA003"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Recreation Management Area are to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the recreational, scenic, watershed, habitat, and ecological resources of the area.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HFF73FB9C5FFA4FFAB3889DEC0E1F557E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header>
 <paragraph id="H8FB602E89D7B4A3F9E2C79DE891FACE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall manage the Recreation Management Area—</text> <subparagraph id="HD3E2EF705A314026938EC9EA764C4A51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances—</text>
 <clause id="HD77DB9BBCB974A1FA8F33ACD0BB855B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the purposes of the Recreation Management Area described in subsection (b); and</text> </clause><clause id="H116FEE95D4D64CF6870E2264FBDC7B42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recreation opportunities, including mountain biking, hiking, fishing, horseback riding, snowshoeing, climbing, skiing, camping, and hunting; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44DD0736D94A45CE8F41BDC56FFF7208"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H3310E4D3E78B4871AB34EE84BF193B5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1600">16 U.S.C. 1600 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2405366BF31045D496CFEA6858BAB253"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other applicable laws (including regulations); and</text> </clause><clause id="H707318EAEF02422EA09A5D1C1B819211"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>this section.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC89406B4DED4D6BAD7486C00010680D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCA25ABA701E341E8BC59AE4E049317F3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow such uses of the Recreation Management Area that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (b).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5C1D149359A437FA9899DA04520C740"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vehicles</header>
 <clause id="H64CBBAB5DB4B4D318FEC54AE11F4C7CB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the use of motorized vehicles in the Recreation Management Area shall be limited to those roads, vehicle classes, and periods of use authorized for such use on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H349359436EE546979BA1EC0B4A8D5A91"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>New or temporary roads</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), no new or temporary roads shall be constructed within the Recreation Management Area.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H531C2D5D815E4961A5CAC52F5DE84565"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Nothing in clause (i) or (ii) prevents the Secretary from—</text> <subclause id="H07B1612850C24763BEF6B09D218139D5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>rerouting or closing an existing road or trail to protect natural resources from degradation, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE2B1E572DD0B4B7EA22CD3F3D820CA2D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>authorizing the use of motorized vehicles for administrative purposes;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD1DAE988C7584DF69BE692E892969490"><enum>(III)</enum><text>constructing temporary roads or permitting the use of motorized vehicles to carry out pre- or post-fire watershed protection projects;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H42142D6B338241EB8770DED4888FA93D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>authorizing the use of motorized vehicles to carry out activities associated with subsection (g), (h), or (i); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0572D9306A3A44BEB5C65B56214F01C7"><enum>(V)</enum><text>responding to an emergency.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA303DFB93B164D2FA31DEC114D75E55B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Commercial timber</header> <clause id="H3AD32071623F48BC8418CF435066CBFB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No projects shall be undertaken for the purpose of harvesting commercial timber within the Recreation Management Area.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFE2093CE303646F3865FEDEBDCA9CF6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in clause (i) prevents the Secretary from harvesting or selling merchantable products that are byproducts of activities authorized by this section.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC361132E8F1B441B9C9BB5FEDE76166C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="HDF2D5BB16FB74DADAC5FE924E0FDE5D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Filing</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare a map and legal descriptions for the Recreation Management Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CBE1B76FC4A4618AA77BA591EFF38F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDD0058692CC41E89C52CC390F381A3B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate office of the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA13D5E7F3985446EBC23FB52FAF3CD21"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid rights in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal land within the Recreation Management Area is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3D302328940442FCA3BC0FCABD072521"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H97554C40B1074984ACC7769F57747859"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE384A81E0E84533BFFAB0606888F025"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A98724835154EF3B36371B3E3923BBC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land or interest in land that is acquired by the United States within the boundaries of the Recreation Management Area shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9C3A369EBE5443BAB15D06D70FCB2036"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the Recreation Management Area; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H169DC475CF894B5D8A5A9C9248E058C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with the applicable provisions of this Act and any other applicable laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H638491C553E84F2EAD84692E312A8693"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Fire, insects, and diseases</header><text>The Secretary may take any measure that the Secretary determines to be necessary to prevent, control, and mitigate fire, insects, and diseases, and hazardous fuels, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H75CF0C3EFC724B8A992EB8E71163B1BD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Water management infrastructure</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the construction, repair, reconstruction, replacement, operation, maintenance, or renovation of water management infrastructure existing on the date of enactment of this Act or such future infrastructure necessary for the development or exercise of water rights decreed prior to the date of enactment of this Act within the Tenmile Recreation Management Area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H251A9656165E441990B0EAABBC816B66"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regional transportation projects</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes the Secretary from authorizing, consistent with applicable laws (including regulations), the use or lease of Federal land within the Recreation Management Area for—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBCF20E131DE64CFCA5F2EB83AF859299"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regional transportation projects, including highway widening or realignment and construction of multimodal transportation systems; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8304FCDA89AE4DDE9EF4C616AD8C7CFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>infrastructure, activities, or safety measures associated with the implementation or utilization of those facilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95AD5F8E89044EAFA12C3FDAAF1728CE"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Application of law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall affect the designation of the Federal land within the Recreation Management Area for purposes of section 303 of title 49, United States Code, and section 138 of title 23, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H46D429FF9A164ADFA80C794BD019A8B5"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Permits</header><text>Nothing in this section alters or limits—</text> <paragraph id="H6010CF04BE8D4913A5462AAE1641849F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a permit held by a ski area or other entity; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A36CCBB19AA483085F55E9E4BE68F46"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the acceptance, review, or implementation of associated activities or facilities proposed or authorized by law or permit outside of the Recreation Management Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9340FC6E1E6846329A35E655B0D833CA"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Water</header><text>The provisions of section 3(e) of the James Peak Wilderness and Protection Area Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/216">Public Law 107–216</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 1055) shall apply to the Recreation Management Area established by this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF5FCADA7984E414EA1D155181D7EBD91"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Military activities</header>
 <paragraph id="H8749DEE370854C6DBAF39BAD98B2A72B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Colorado national guard use</header><text>Nothing in this section shall restrict, preclude or otherwise affect the use by the Colorado Army National Guard, a reserve component of the Armed Forces, of the Recreation Management Area for aircraft training, testing, evaluation, emergency response, or other related air operations—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC47E72A7C16C4648B37331DCD858FFBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the manner and degree such uses were authorized to occur on the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8401BB3CFDEF43CFABD2EF4B12A3976A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as authorized under future agreements between the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88188CB7C1CE47138340E158E77E9BF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>military aircraft use</header><text>Nothing in this section restricts or precludes, or should cause any other Federal regulation to restrict or preclude—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H78103A762F144DC3B413D12A91CBB407"><enum>(A)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A87269B9D0844BAB9514F95A5F34AB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the designation, modification, or creation of new units of special use airspace, or the establishment of military flight training routes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF9748451B96A4A22A8B7AD2100CABB02"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State of Colorado with respect to fish and wildlife in the State, including hunting and fishing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCE752ACC39CF462EA9265479BA6F7DF7"><enum>(o)</enum><header>No buffer zones</header><text>The Recreation Management Area shall not create a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Recreation Management Area.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H88D2700265244A4C8E8D65B5C095A20F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Porcupine Gulch Protection Area, White River National Forest, Colorado</header>
 <subsection id="HE56C987D16B545CC9822A920A1D555EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Certain Federal land located in the White River National Forest in the State of Colorado which comprise approximately 5,204 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled <quote>Porcupine Gulch Protection Area Proposal</quote>, dated July 2014, is designated the <quote>Porcupine Gulch Protection Area</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Protection Area</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC7B96D6405F44A28BC8EBFBF65D7A522"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of the Protection Area are to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the scenic, roadless, watershed, and ecological resources of the Protection Area.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE73DB67A725D4B8B95FD44B29B4E8B07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header>
 <paragraph id="H835B9D9734C54F3E895E624DF8078DA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall manage the Protection Area—</text> <subparagraph id="HAD06C836FD9448B4B8039B02D95C6B8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the purposes described in subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41B8F800D072486B8CC4AC98EB51284B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <clause id="HD9C6BAF8D2D542359694C9DC6A1F9E32"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1600">16 U.S.C. 1600 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H814AEA74F30641908232FBD9B9BB8707"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other applicable laws (including regulations); and</text> </clause><clause id="H4A1A3DBDDC304BA596D6825EDE12541B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>this section.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0ECD3CE880746178FF8E88CB9BC507F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header>
 <subparagraph id="H43370352A42348D883673F4A8E5BE991"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow such uses of the Protection Area that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (b).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC930ABB6C6634B518110BE44B5A0EAC0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles</header>
 <clause id="HCB5D2E5D65AD42C9A7DC5C716D844BBB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the use of motorized vehicles and mechanized transport in the Protection Area shall be prohibited.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA735EAE3EAAB4F7DA2B4034A01BB1561"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>New or temporary roads</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), no new or temporary roads shall be constructed within the Protection Area.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3A050605BE8645CA83870D75739F1FF2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Nothing in clause (i) or (ii) prevents the Secretary from—</text> <subclause id="HDE5081A12CA3475F94625C7AE2E1C39B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>authorizing the use of motorized vehicles for administrative purposes;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE124F9AF3A3C4A3A8D3C3EB26D5FDB79"><enum>(II)</enum><text>constructing temporary roads or permitting the use of motorized vehicles to carry out pre- or post-fire watershed protection projects;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA5749A112DE54FDC83C1AD119EF39072"><enum>(III)</enum><text>authorizing the use of motorized vehicles to carry out activities associated with subsection (g) or (h); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE302D37803BC40939220F61F141CF1D2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>responding to an emergency.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF47E82E5662483E9195A9C41ADCC450"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Commercial timber</header> <clause id="H2CC2229BD4B34D128E214096FAE00562"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No projects shall be undertaken for the purpose of harvesting commercial timber within the Protection Area.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H88A5328807CE44B1904F5B51E27F7B79"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in clause (i) prevents the Secretary from harvesting or selling merchantable products that are byproducts of activities authorized by this section.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91DF9510C51B4E458ECDE794C1EA5E25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="H02E172A987D846AEA2523E95EF29752D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Filing</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare a map and legal description for the Protection Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6876E16E71A4555B525A190A985D36C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB0DA2F513D649369F25FA76ED639B5C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate office of the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5CEAB11E06640249B899B996314CFE3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid rights in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal land within the Protection Area is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB5A48610E03D41468EDAD51FD2998E2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DAC9FD17E77440C8FC68C8679277610"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C1EA032C23A4BE4BF1744937FF61E18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A25F92C35464BF2819A1C310A3D4893"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land or interest in land that is acquired by the United States within the boundaries of the Protection Area shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAA0C3A590B9E4C30B7B0774644F4D2B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the Protection Area; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HED06C7FAC1024310896B116FD261B167"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with the applicable provisions of this Act and any other applicable laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C171D8080E446AB915F743E995C7851"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Fire, insects, and diseases</header><text>The Secretary may take any measure that the Secretary determines to be necessary to prevent, control, and mitigate fire, insects, and diseases and hazardous fuels, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD9C2776B06534BD6A8EE73E54BE41531"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regional transportation projects</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes the Secretary from authorizing, consistent with applicable laws (including regulations), the use or lease of Federal land within the Protection Area for—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD704CA96A5894B9490E9182679DCFB3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regional transportation projects, including highway widening or realignment and construction of multimodal transportation systems; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A39C81BA1C341E5BEF3FBE9B783BE40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>infrastructure, activities, or safety measures associated with the implementation or utilization of those facilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF02BD1F21B0D41059A934C8E2D55EBD6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application of law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall affect the designation of the Federal land within the Protection Area for purposes of section 303 of title 49, United States Code, and section 138 of title 23, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H14C65D273B0E451B861E7359A90EB1C0"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Water</header><text>The provisions of section 3(e) of the James Peak Wilderness and Protection Area Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/216">Public Law 107–216</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 1055) shall apply to the Protection Area.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7EA64C0E39514112956BC3C3A46EDC29"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Military activities</header>
 <paragraph id="H63A5E871103547058B75448CB8139318"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Colorado Army National Guard use</header><text>Nothing in this section shall restrict, preclude or otherwise affect the use by the Colorado Army National Guard, a reserve component of the Armed Forces, of the Protection Area for aircraft training, testing, evaluation, emergency response, or other related air operations—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB62098760F4C44E78D0F10D1264928D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the manner and degree such uses were authorized to occur on the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32B0B9BC711A48E9A913B91E1BB6A88A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as authorized under future agreements between the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E4635E5DFD6454CB2CBCF3B385CC432"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Military aircraft use</header><text>Nothing in this section restricts or precludes, or should cause any other Federal regulation to restrict or preclude—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD6E657C8192C47D58A3243E1EAE330F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H989A13C95A134898B9316963404444A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the designation, modification, or creation of new units of special use airspace, or the establishment of military flight training routes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFBF961B481BB496A8A4AC674E3F14A1D"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State of Colorado with respect to fish and wildlife in the State, including hunting and fishing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE1F78D963EA34CA9BDF52F2D6F3B3DCF"><enum>(m)</enum><header>No buffer zones</header><text>The Protection Area shall not create a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Protection Area.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


