<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H56A691DEC3A44005BFB2ED4C9EFE95AF" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 656 IH: Online Communications and Geolocation Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 656</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150202">February 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O’Rourke</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="">Select Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to disclosures to governments by communications-related service providers of certain information consisting of or relating to communications, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H902A0157C0794926A251F6C6E6D6286D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H97F8795C30D04942A148E3E89E86431A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Online Communications and Geolocation Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H82E05880DC1D4E368A9DACCE79FB6EE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Warrant required for contents of communications</header> <subsection id="HEF63459B315F428CAA1410A300ADBFFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compelled disclosure of communication contents</header> <paragraph id="H1A6D228E7179447BBE7B791D1D60256F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2703 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA346C4EBF22443229BD3071D39FE8256"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HE06DA89256124C999ED886B814614A85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">in Electronic Storage</header-in-text></quote> in the subsection header;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H71DEADA5B72A42E79F30766057995365"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or remote computing service</quote> in the first sentence after <quote>electronic communication service</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H73B4DCA94ED54193A85955A5C4640380"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>that is in electronic storage in an electronic communications system for one hundred and eighty days or less,</quote> and inserting <quote>that is stored, held, or maintained by that service,</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H27E763FDEDA6432A876FDC510E6BA40B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking the final sentence and inserting <quote>Within three days after a governmental entity receives such contents from a service provider pursuant to this subsection, the governmental entity shall serve upon, or deliver by registered or first-class mail, or other means reasonably calculated to be effective as specified by the court issuing the warrant to the subscriber, customer, or user a copy of the warrant and a notice that includes the information referenced in section 2705(a)(4)(A) and (B)(i), except that delayed notice may be provided pursuant to section 2705 of this title.</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A21D1AE6A6F4834AC31BB2CE1DEEFE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C89F63C89B94F589252AB5ECEECF58E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 2703(d) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>(b) or</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB9377971343844C09AF0471B62AA669A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Voluntary disclosure of communication contents</header> <paragraph id="H17A84CBC455E4EA7890263DB3C252483"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2702(a)(3) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H955CF69326604CBD961CE8D4831723BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>to any governmental entity the contents of communication covered by subsection (a) of section 2703 or any</quote> after <quote>divulge</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03385A44AD3942FA8878415C49928522"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or user</quote> after <quote>customer</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23D66FE5C5ED4AE39ED73579739ABB35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(not including the contents of communications covered by paragraph (1) or (2))</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EF89D8D938D4D6C9F342EB086A6EC31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 2705 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H156E454FA48846318148C755115B03EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <clause id="HFFE939DD70FB412FA2DC7D778359F538"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote>2703(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>2703(a)</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H653368AA04614BB88C472EDBBEB61002"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>court order</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>warrant</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HAEB8E486EE3E4C3489AFA412122225C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>2703(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>2703(a)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H777E35A5D7E54C63A586F75755DA0FC6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8859BA8645445BABB91ABEDC94E2784"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a)(3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1022ACB4E9FD48999FCB10B96827443C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(4), by striking <quote>or by certification by a governmental entity, but only in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H00D3391C2EB946D8954C617D1EB20F03"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(5)—</text> 
<clause id="HC47F7B6BFF9C410ABE245FD3F1136CFA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>first-class mail,</quote> the following: <quote>or other means reasonably calculated to be effective as specified by the court issuing the warrant</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HD753191DC6F94FA7AD651DE0AC671E4B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the process or request</quote> and replacing it with <quote>warrant</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE0D9A7F402BD4686945565FF821A0803"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (5)(A)(iii), by striking <quote>governmental entity or</quote> and <quote>certification or</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45400D55E410466C8E64D3E2F76250F6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a)(6); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H43E5B28DBD15422FB800D8F5028091F6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="HCF725A5E95584B309CC416FB398E8F19"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>when it is not required to notify the subscriber or customer under section 2703(b)(1), or</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0BACC9FFD981417EB5D1FB71C3CABDC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subpoena or court order</quote> each place it appears.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H1F89E24D93B94F24BA07423F6BE6852B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Geolocation information protection</header> <subsection id="H5CB26060A4FF45E48439945035DE1394"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H4FC50694700742B4BB25AA48C5BE9DE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part 1 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 119 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H420DEA1F8FE042C8A78DA7236BBD73CE" style="USC"> 
<chapter id="H8859EE8ABC514E819AA6B7819A7D376F"><enum>120</enum><header>Geolocation information</header> 
<toc container-level="chapter-container" idref="H8859EE8ABC514E819AA6B7819A7D376F" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="H643E6D34B99B49FDAF09F150F4EA3239" level="section">Sec.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">2601. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAA2D14A0D25D4E8D85887C283A442E26" level="section">2602. Interception and disclosure of geolocation information.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCF7111E46B3F4DFEA4B46AC08F3372E3" level="section">2603. Prohibition on disclosing geolocation information to governmental entities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H422593ADEE004C728A8D74ED624982A9" level="section">2604. Prohibition of use of unlawfully obtained geolocation information as evidence.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4829C939853C4BF79A82B9FCD8F5091D" level="section">2605. Recovery of civil damages and administrative discipline authorized.</toc-entry></toc> 
<section id="H643E6D34B99B49FDAF09F150F4EA3239"><enum>2601.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter:</text> <paragraph id="HE2FEFC936DCA4EF38F792CD1F0EB6875"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Electronic communication service</header><text>The term <term>electronic communication service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2510.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB369FB7D60A046CC947FB08DB5F55A68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Electronic surveillance</header><text>The term <term>electronic surveillance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H162774C69FCF40879B0E3F999D9F3C78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Geolocation information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>geolocation information</term> means, with respect to an individual, any information that is not the content of a communication, concerning the location of a wireless communication device or tracking device (as that term is defined section 3117) that, in whole or in part, is generated by or derived from the operation of that device and that could be used to determine or infer information regarding the present, prospective, or historical location of the individual.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1996CD97AB2747D89541B8086216E619"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Geolocation information service</header><text>The term <term>geolocation information service</term> means a service that generates or uses geolocation information for the provision of a mapping, locational, or directional information service to the public, or to such class of users as to be effectively available to the public, by or through the operation of any wireless communication device.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9738ECA0F71F4C17BA7C4F21512D8823"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Governmental entity</header><text>The term <term>governmental entity</term> means any employee or agent of the United States, or any State or political subdivision thereof.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30119EEB48D9480791CDC9770A49D3FA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Intercept</header><text>The term <term>intercept</term> means the acquisition of geolocation information through the use of any electronic, mechanical, or other device.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H444E2EFFC2654D7FBD29B99BB3D9D4B5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Investigative or law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>investigative or law enforcement officer</term> means any officer of the United States or of a State or political subdivision thereof, who is empowered by law to conduct investigations of, or to make arrests for, offenses enumerated in this chapter, and any attorney authorized by law to prosecute or participate in the prosecution of such offenses.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40765CE7B03E49FC819782BD2DF28752"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Remote computing service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>remote computing service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2711.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1917E5FBD3D44458A20288B34BD27A86"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6DFA42F1476400ABBC15B25C6D0EE53"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Wireless communication device</header><text>The term <term>wireless communication device</term> means any device that enables access to, or use of, an electronic communication system or service, remote computing service, or geolocation information service, if that device utilizes a radio signal or other wireless connection to access or use such system or service, including any mobile telephone, global positioning system receiving device, mobile computer, or other similar or successor device.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89E72586672742BCA54B512B77D3998D"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Covered service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered services</term> means electronic communication service, remote computing service, or geolocation information service.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HAA2D14A0D25D4E8D85887C283A442E26"><enum>2602.</enum><header>Interception and disclosure of geolocation information</header> 
<subsection id="HA480794791CA4C0D822400AA6005FC7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, it shall be unlawful for any governmental entity to—</text> <paragraph id="HF6E5B12C44284159960F47607B547A4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>intentionally intercept, endeavor to intercept, or direct any person to intercept or endeavor to intercept, geolocation information pertaining to an individual;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5066D686ACB6411DA57F7740672007BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>intentionally disclose, or endeavor to disclose, or direct any person to disclose or endeavor to disclose geolocation information pertaining to an individual, knowing or having reason to know that the information was obtained in violation of this subsection; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D34952E2D934DD788F4ED9B994B36F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>intentionally use, or endeavor to use, any geolocation information, knowing or having reason to know that the information was obtained in violation of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4CEB9515F3B424AABFDE5B3BBFC5351"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for conducting foreign intelligence surveillance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, it shall not be unlawful for an officer, employee, or agent of the United States in the normal course of the official duty of the officer, employee, or agent to conduct electronic surveillance, as authorized by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2999A5EA66FC44AD96E1F3455F768889"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for consent</header> <paragraph id="H684E766DDFF54A3CB160379BA0B7EA29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall not be unlawful under this chapter for a governmental entity to intercept, use, or disclose geolocation information pertaining to an individual if that individual has given prior consent to that governmental entity for such interception, use or disclosure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1B0334F5C2446C3B1ED3989F86E8287"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Children</header><text>A parent or legal guardian of a child may consent on behalf of a child for the purposes of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFFA276160F354B0997EE71346583E00A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception for public information</header><text>It shall not be unlawful under this chapter for a governmental entity to intercept or access geolocation information pertaining to an individual through any system that is configured so that such information is readily accessible to the general public.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDD2742140DCB4ADFBA99C99885D4A79B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception for emergency assistance</header><text>It shall not be unlawful under this chapter for any investigative or law enforcement officer or other emergency responder to intercept, access, use, or disclose geolocation information pertaining to an individual if such information is used—</text> <paragraph id="H37E0AFC16923414EB41565D2229873B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to respond to a request made by such individual for assistance; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDFB5FB4AAD442CAACDA9E8196B4E487"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist the individual in circumstances in which it is reasonable to believe that the life or safety of the individual is in jeopardy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0297FD9D41CE4EE78C0481BE00940923"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exception for warrant</header> <paragraph id="H529A57FA3E584145B99A32B376E6E849"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A governmental entity may intercept geolocation information or require the disclosure of geolocation information by a provider of covered services only pursuant to a warrant issued by a court of competent jurisdiction using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures), or as otherwise provided in this chapter or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H181CB5788C0F4752B92EADFCE11359F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Court of competent jurisdiction</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term <term>court of competent jurisdiction</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HD094B60F2C574F51A6B54CFE6C216F9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any district court of the United States (including a magistrate judge of such a court) or any United States court of appeals that—</text> 
<clause id="H648C1B3B1E564E69BEA902A0BFA55015"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has jurisdiction over the offense being investigated;</text></clause> <clause id="H0E83D3A2B70842409C70D9685B8E5163"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in or for a district in which the provider of a geolocation information service is located or in which the geolocation information is stored; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H028290C6D0FB4470BB0D47DD325D04C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is acting on a request for foreign assistance pursuant to section 3512 of this title; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07C3D4C284024C6EBB7D627037978D27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a court of general criminal jurisdiction of a State authorized by the law of that State to issue search warrants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52B5D3C2DB714124AF327C0B6F55CFF3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Emergency situation exception</header> 
<paragraph id="HC66A7DF646E449E893DF3D1C05DAF40E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, any investigative or law enforcement officer, specially designated by the Attorney General, the Deputy Attorney General, the Associate Attorney General, or by the principal prosecuting attorney of any State or subdivision thereof acting pursuant to a statute of that State, may intercept or use geolocation information if—</text> <subparagraph id="H6A874EE087C34522BDA23368E8D74A67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such officer reasonably determines that an emergency situation exists that—</text> 
<clause id="H8A24B7E370F34EC58A3D4401579AC0E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves—</text> <subclause id="H682453A4ECB64A1A8FD74926B705118A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any individual;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA1E6020BAC1541D09054BF09CCF53515"><enum>(II)</enum><text>conspiratorial activities threatening the national security interest; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H42370861EAA9438588694EF483537D34"><enum>(III)</enum><text>conspiratorial activities characteristic of organized crime; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HE6463051DF93428484A0F62C24DF6935"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requires geolocation information be intercepted or used before an order authorizing such interception or use can, with due diligence, be obtained;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H58A74F1711354DC9AC557FCCE71ACD30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there are grounds upon which an order could be entered to authorize such interception or use; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H371BB59D360E4A7BB7CE054E7B1AE28A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an application for an order approving such interception or use is made within 48 hours after the interception or use has occurred or begins to occur.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5FA0C02BDC1445B38F98615D93EBC702"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to obtain court order</header> <subparagraph id="H0F44FAEBB7184FF3B836EA05D6B16F98"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Termination of acquisition</header><text>In the absence of an order, an interception or use of geolocation information carried out under paragraph (1) shall immediately terminate when the information sought is obtained or when the application for the order is denied, whichever is earlier.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8AB531B1E78F4C9C81306AD30BCB6178"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on use as evidence</header><text>In the event such application for approval is denied, the geolocation information shall be treated as having been obtained in violation of this chapter and an inventory shall be served on each individual who is reasonably able to be contacted and to whom any such geolocation information pertains.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HCF7111E46B3F4DFEA4B46AC08F3372E3"><enum>2603.</enum><header>Prohibition on disclosing geolocation information to governmental entities</header> <subsection id="HE5D9A2685B2347C58420D70410911238"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), a person providing covered services shall not intentionally disclose to any governmental entity geolocation information pertaining to an individual.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H135CD3FB6F694199B879CB6C5FD787A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person providing covered services may disclose geolocation information—</text> <paragraph id="HEA6DFF1977E747598D457E638CD6283B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as otherwise authorized in subsections (b) through (g) of section 2602;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90CB54FFC12040C88C54D26027BEBCDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with the lawful consent of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB2F5F9244A8247AB9C9DBECA2B50842E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual to whom the geolocation information pertains; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B90D881B1F640AEBF5AC7E625E5C72D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the parent or guardian of a child to whom the geolocation information pertains;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB845EE58DE224373B3BA51A53777B383"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as permitted under section 222(d)(4) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/222">47 U.S.C. 222(d)(4)</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54BA76BB513F4AF783DD21180092BB5D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>which was inadvertently obtained by the service provider and which appears to pertain to the commission of a crime, if such disclosure is made to a law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H422593ADEE004C728A8D74ED624982A9"><enum>2604.</enum><header>Prohibition of use of unlawfully obtained geolocation information as evidence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any geolocation information has been intercepted, used, or disclosed in violation of this chapter, no part of such information and no evidence derived therefrom may be received in evidence in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, officer, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision thereof, except in a civil action to obtain relief for a violation of this chapter.</text></section> 
<section id="H4829C939853C4BF79A82B9FCD8F5091D"><enum>2605.</enum><header>Recovery of civil damages and administrative discipline authorized</header> 
<subsection id="H37ADE5FC42D8483DAD0A7F1BE75262E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual whose geolocation information is intentionally disclosed or used in violation of this chapter may in a civil action recover such relief as may be appropriate from the person, other than the United States, which engaged in that violation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5A055CF1E9D743AF8E998FDF78BF2B50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an action under this section, appropriate relief includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF5620613E0724A1AAB6108B46D6F1990"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such preliminary and other equitable or declaratory relief as the court may deem appropriate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3DE03D4B7D84CE78ADEF9A943A6F9BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">damages under subsection (c) and punitive damages as the court may deem appropriate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H549C98D612644EF6AEC7B6E3B004F08A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a reasonable attorney's fee and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9FB4A80B110E445C8999D740670FC269"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Computation of damages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court may assess as damages under this section whichever is the greater of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA6CB1D5D94324750846D8D5D2F49AD09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sum of the actual damages suffered by the plaintiff; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA20E53E963D4E9F8CF2DE046F1FAE11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>statutory damages of whichever is the greater of $100 a day for each day of violation or $10,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H42E6CCAB33984C6B87182B3FC28960E9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is a defense against any civil action to obtain relief for a violation of this chapter that the defendant acted in a good faith reliance on—</text> <paragraph id="H2169CF4BD92F4EE3A3FA6567A46F7F2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a warrant or court order, grand jury subpoena, legislative authorization, or statutory authorization; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B972BE5B7C84BFA82E575CFF39BE480"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a reasonable determination that an exception under section 2602 permitted the conduct complained of.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4336E686E1DB437994338690BA3CAAB8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A civil action under this section may not be commenced later than two years after the date upon which the claimant first has a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B8CED080EDA4BAC8D2FB73D2C6422EF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative discipline</header><text>If a court or appropriate department or agency determines that the United States or any of its departments or agencies has violated any provision of this chapter, and the court or appropriate department or agency finds that the circumstances surrounding the violation raise serious questions about whether or not an officer or employee of the United States acted willfully or intentionally with respect to the violation, the department or agency shall, upon receipt of a true and correct copy of the decision and findings of the court or appropriate department or agency promptly initiate a proceeding to determine whether disciplinary action against the officer or employee is warranted. If the head of the department or agency involved determines that disciplinary action is not warranted, such head shall notify the Inspector General with jurisdiction over the department or agency concerned and shall provide the Inspector General with the reasons for such determination.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EC6DD70C6554EE483508A50E529855D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for part 1 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 119 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86BB778CC46E4898AB0128D6714782C9" style="OLC"> 
<toc> 
<multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><toc-enum>120. </toc-enum><level-header level="section">Geolocation information</level-header><target>2601</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CA99953B0F542A6B932EDFF474063E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 3512(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HA22087297A9C429589D350365874A5D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="H5A14B99AB3C04B229ACF71F65257E926"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) as subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E), respectively; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1404D6F55B9843709FB530AC9DCF5A67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD0C87F2739943FC96F75234FFB87DBF" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HE49C55A9E4B9438CA2A886F62C3B5494"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a warrant or order for geolocation information or records related thereto, as provided under section 2602 of this title;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCE0A57A273247B0B5438AE339172570"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for search warrants To obtain geolocation information</header><text>Rule 41(a) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC85581A1AA40446AAD1E0932F034021E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking the period at the end and inserting a comma and <quote>including geolocation information.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC12FE86BDB944F7EAC24BB5E375127D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CA8673ABFCB4F81ADF71B760B13897C" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HDAFC603B9B004F0EA3DCDED69B3BE940"><enum>(F)</enum><text><term>Geolocation information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2601 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB45302C442BE46CD95C0692EB11D6E2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Statement of exclusive means of obtaining geolocation information</header> <paragraph id="HCC71B14B0EA54538AE26DAA3D08FB1B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person may obtain the geolocation information of a person for protective activities or law enforcement or intelligence purposes except pursuant to a warrant issued pursuant to rule 41 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, as amended by subsection (b), or the amendments made by this section, or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H761E71BB3FCD42479B354083915C156C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geolocation information defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>geolocation information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2601 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

