<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6F5176D285DB44F2B48FC30C87E24E6B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4298 IH: Vietnam Helicopter Crew Memorial Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4298</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Army to place in Arlington National Cemetery a memorial honoring the
			 helicopter pilots and crew members of the Vietnam era, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0FC60C7B76414683B0E056DC014386CF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3580EB33A9944CF2AE211BB5B5D86C92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vietnam Helicopter Crew Memorial Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3F36B5E43DE14C96AE2A2B226EC00EE7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Placement of Memorial Honoring Helicopter Pilots during the Vietnam War</header> <subsection id="HA0C2CA6493224DEAA7970A2D49C0F2CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the requirements of section (c), the Secretary of the Army shall place in Arlington National Cemetery a memorial honoring helicopter pilots and crew members who served on active duty in the Armed Forces during the Vietnam era.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4EE77111FD65484487FDEF09FB00A723"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design</header><text>The memorial placed under subsection (a) shall measure 4 feet in height, 5 feet in width, and 1 foot in depth, and shall be based on a design approved by the Secretary of the Army and the Vietnam Helicopter Pilots Association.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H370236F2D1864DCCBCAA234C34CC4549"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agreement for Upkeep and Maintenance</header><text>The Secretary of the Army may only place a memorial under subsection (a) if the Secretary enters into an agreement with the Vietnam Helicopter Pilots Association under which the Association agrees to pay all costs necessary to construct, install, and maintain the memorial, and to such other provisions as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7833669386B5455FBA96EED9246A6AAD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval of Site</header><text>The Secretary of the Army shall approve an appropriate site within Arlington National Cemetery for the memorial under subsection (a) to be placed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5CEF7D8DC59E44B89308C87ACE646D3A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver of environmental assessment</header><text>Section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>) shall not apply with respect to the memorial placed under subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


