<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B6FB8EE21DF493699BC0A1870AEA338" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2488 IH: Medicare Beneficiary Preservation of Choice Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2488</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000755">Mr. Brady of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To preserve Medicare beneficiary choice by restoring and expanding the Medicare open enrollment and disenrollment opportunities repealed by section 3204(a) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H42CE37A96FBA44DC93FDF0B784439975" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5C714D4669B041778200C26DE36CD48C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Beneficiary Preservation of Choice Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC7E513729525492C943E17F5A22DAE91"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preservation of Medicare beneficiary choice under Medicare Advantage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1851(e)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-21">42 U.S.C. 1395w–21(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF42F704E5F5F4F1CB12D022E0DEFC584"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <subparagraph id="HE5D9EE4F973C4CD99081F070B6B96AF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">from 2011 through 2015</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">45-day period</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H98DD18BB5A5D4D57B982DEACD841F01D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and ending with 2015</quote> after <quote>beginning with 2011</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A766DFAAC9942D1A4F21D47F1DC7C06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph: </text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF281F3C044E2411C925CFA35E471EEDC" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H5700FC75007542868FC76B2A0FB0A743"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Continuous open enrollment and disenrollment for first 3 months in 2016 and subsequent years</header> 
<clause id="H9854B1D5064D40F4BB5BF961D8079ADF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii) and subparagraph (D), at any time during the first 3 months of a year (beginning with 2016), or, if the individual first becomes a Medicare Advantage eligible individual during a year (beginning with 2016), during the first 3 months of such year in which the individual is a Medicare Advantage eligible individual, a Medicare Advantage eligible individual may change the election under subsection (a)(1).</text></clause> <clause id="HACC3BF60BFEA4B7AA68874AB9191541C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation of one change during open enrollment period each year</header><text>An individual may change the election pursuant to clause (i) only once during the applicable 3-month period described in such clause in each year. The limitation under this clause shall not apply to changes in elections effected during an annual, coordinated election period under paragraph (3) or during a special enrollment period under paragraph (4).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0A6FE222B13C4431AC250360587D326C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limited application to part D</header><text>Clauses (i) and (ii) of this subparagraph shall only apply with respect to changes in enrollment in a prescription drug plan under part D in the case of an individual who, previous to such change in enrollment, is enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan.</text></clause> <clause id="HF7A064BF013D4705825479EF50434737"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Limitations on marketing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Pursuant to subsection (j), no unsolicited marketing or marketing materials may be sent to an individual described in clause (i) during the continuous open enrollment and disenrollment period established for the individual under such clause. </text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

