<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HACC1DEF6C6F646EE8B48F398F744FA1C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2886 IH: Future TRIP Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2886</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish an Automated and Connected Vehicle Research
			 Initiative, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H96B37DD1F8CF402EB48F436EECA82B9C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H01068BBDAB5A4DF0AB5A2A26F335EB94" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Future Transportation Research and Innovation for Prosperity Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>Future TRIP Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9A77498AD04C47AC86E7003A5FB6337F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Automated and connected vehicle research initiative</header> <subsection id="HA5787AAAF1D8451388B9E34841229F54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall establish an Automated and Connected Vehicle Research Initiative to lay the foundation for the broad scale adoption of automated vehicle technology.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H53E8C70F0090408EA103B7FDB7AADABD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the Initiative established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="H1EB7771CF37E4A049DE82F691AE00F6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83AA8B84D9024508AE356FD4C6CBD4D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Highway Administration;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE94609F88DE743B2B6CB21A76756147A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal Transit Administration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC045F27B2D6A474BBC151AB8F26A629C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B1FDFD75D584DC5B1A911A1C1C10ADE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Railroad Administration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99F6BD46F5734BF48BEBFF6F5F4D4F8C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCF4EBFAE7A04DA8A8414929C9538585"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3432109B8F74019BCF722212B3FF922"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F225F646C6444CFB593D419157EC63D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Office of Science and Technology Policy of the White House; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H445948751F724A1D8100582D8E677809"><enum>(10)</enum><text>other relevant agencies.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6E4C931A707410ABEE81C54923FA7A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Initiative under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9B5E5DF0A9F4FF2958C683BE72EC95D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct collaborative research with private industry and industry associations, other Federal agencies, State and local agencies, university research centers, a national transportation center selected under Section 5505(c)(2) of title 49, United States Code, and national labs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AC868089A7F4DFA8C7F1C95A9EA93EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish automated and connected vehicle technology corridors and related pilot programs.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0367D7123DE34090B4CB01D582E6E2E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research agenda</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with interested parties, shall establish a research agenda for the research conducted under subsection (c)(1) and programs under subsection (c)(2) that, at a minimum, include—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H25557CB5DA6D41A68BEDF96BC15E19BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">quantifying the benefits of advanced safety and vehicle connectivity technologies, including vehicle-to-vehicle communication technologies and vehicle-to-infrastructure communication technologies, advanced driver assistance systems, shared-use services, and other connected and automated vehicle technologies and services, on—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H31DE0F8CC264494581A01110DEF937B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transportation system performance categories including highway fatalities and injuries separately for motorized and for nonmotorized modes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF39888638ED4472882D605C38F78CD1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>traffic congestion;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H16C37652317F445D913D77691AF5353B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>freight movement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H79E7D090A98642E6925B44C0091CDCB4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>fuel economy and harmful emissions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD5535863396F4718806B39B2D75304DC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>vehicle miles traveled; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0436759C888497F8B7AA2BD2BB4280F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing deployment guidance, including for—</text> <subparagraph id="H83FE274145984E228E018CEE692D1745"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reduction of pedestrian, bicycle, and motorcycle fatalities and injuries;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2AFC50122AC4363AD08CD56EFDD42EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>considerations for existing Federal, State, and local regulations and legal frameworks;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEA7F1B447C443C8B4F0D87B6A3F67A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information technology systems and management, including the sharing of public agency traffic information, work zone information, and other transportation data to stimulate innovative new services and products for enhancing safety, fuel efficiency, and quality of life;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDF0BAA713B34A50A7E8282A92509E24"><enum>(D)</enum><text>funding mechanisms and business models;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9856FD6D3D324B0D8D168C6CEE879E46"><enum>(E)</enum><text>mobility for the elderly, disabled, and economically disadvantaged;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H335C92BC6C504B1D993998520805F756"><enum>(F)</enum><text>transit systems;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41C8BBF419C1447E89B5434DD0229512"><enum>(G)</enum><text>cyber-physical security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94207CD09D6B4A819E567B0EA2C0CEE2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>human factors; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E844FDB55E84B3587789AC27291E6B3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>intercity and interjurisdictional applications and challenges.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2BF0D89FCF2F4A4B86EF8F50CE8D6925"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination of research</header><text>In conducting the research under subsection (c)(1), the Secretary shall coordinate with representatives from the Federal Communications Commission, the Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers, and the Intelligent Transportation Society of America regarding viable spectrum-sharing technologies that could enable the safe operation of unlicensed devices in the 5850–5925 MHz band (in this section, referred to as the 5.9 GHz band) without interfering with safety-of-life vehicle-to-vehicle communication technologies and vehicle-to-infrastructure communication technologies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB9BC19CC57B94C1D89A9C328E34E4ADF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a public report identifying any potential signal interference risks that may exist between unlicensed Wi-Fi devices operating in the 5.9 GHz band.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H414ED43027444E2FB82517BE9D88B80F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Letter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall send a letter to the Federal Communications Commission, the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives that contains an explanation of the risks and a determination on whether unlicensed Wi-Fi devices can safely operate in the 5.9 GHz band without creating signal interfere that could jeopardize or delay the deployment of an effective and reliable vehicle-to-vehicle and vehicle-to-infrastructure safety-of-life communications system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA172228AEDBE40EB8772D8D16DFF2C18"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Intelligent Transportation Systems Science &amp; Technology Center</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a competitively selected Intelligent Transportation Systems Science &amp; Technology Center that—</text> <paragraph id="H6AA6FF71C4B74C64AFD3FA7674355F2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>draws on the expertise of researchers from multiple domains to develop intelligent systems capable of perceiving and physically interacting with their environment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H234818424C9B45F9BE9207F2741B52DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develops methods for extending operator efficiency and safety through machine interaction;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5ADCCDFE97C1477CA559C325E129407F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>trains the next generation of the transportation workforce in the cross-disciplinary fields of robotics, machine learning, cybersecurity, and engineering;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB13C13D7A73E427283AAAD504B904EA4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expands standards, codes, and processes to leverage a new generation of intelligent machines; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F546482AEC44EA0AE4492B2F5385C38"><enum>(5)</enum><text>engages in real-world technology deployments and evaluations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H419AD5E18B1C4557BD5BB6CE1C7B5088"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and make available on the Internet website of the Department of Transportation, a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2504ACCAD947499A9998DE0A734FE8B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses the organizational readiness of the Department to address connected and automated vehicle technology challenges;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B4E073CEDD843A483F7DE272BAFD18C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses the status of connected and automated transportation technology, applications, and policies developed by public and private entities in the United States and internationally;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9336B12436E42E5BD414ED40EB6D376"><enum>(3)</enum><text>defines recommended implementation paths for connected and automated transportation technology, applications, and policies that are based on the analysis described in paragraph (1), and the results of paragraphs (1) through (3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAE6615915764FA88481835A3754BDA2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes guidance on the relationship of the proposed deployment of connected and automated vehicles to the national architecture and standards and protocols required under section 517 of title 23, United States Code, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H14399F6A73F945BF847495A07A35F6D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is based on cyber-physical security and privacy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H356F34A365634E5BB3163C5C2493D680"><enum>(B)</enum><text>examines the interaction with other cyber-physical systems.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9650035BA5441798E665597EC3D87D7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary may enter into agreements with, and seek input from, the National Research Council, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the National Science Foundation, and the Department of Energy, and shall seek input from ITS America, the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials, and industry stakeholders, including nonprofit advocacy groups.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7302B3DB39714E62BCE1975B615C69CF"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Report review</header><text>The Secretary may enter into agreements with the National Research Council for the review of the report described in subsection (i).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4B4226AFD2284055B27E3950884E26A9"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5E75A004CBB7497185634C7B9701D59E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vehicle-to-vehicle communication technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>vehicle-to-vehicle communication technology</quote> means a technology that allows wireless communication of data between vehicles, including dedicated short range communication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0413D64646FE4D4F9926DE01CA38F60F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vehicle-to-infrastructure communication technology</header><text>The term <quote>vehicle-to-infrastructure communication technology</quote> means a technology that allows wireless communication of data between vehicles and infrastructure, including dedicated short range communication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D53138914D540779A58D7D66A80E405"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advanced driver assistance system</header><text>The term <quote>advanced driver assistance system</quote> means a system developed to automate, adapt, or enhance vehicle systems for safer driving and improved functionality.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85039A1EBBA14FA68C50890BF52F8978"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Shared-use service</header><text>The term <quote>shared-use service</quote> means a service that shares transportation resources between users.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3F59C30B143C46D98FE9AB0BA2266F02"><enum>3.</enum><header>University Transportation Centers program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5505 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF2F9E02647FF4B09944EB7E0FE7B7CD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(B) by inserting <quote>multimodal</quote> before <quote>transportation knowledge</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H265870D8F33F46A39FCF2C9995AD63E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1FA60F37B80449FC9A37F9976838D93F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CE6CE6DF5F04707B6A3EC07FEB93C0B" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HDD0CFDD9A4274053AD580F0517FE4A0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restriction</header> <subparagraph id="HFF320D32675F4C1BBC9EC0DC11D466B4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A nonprofit institution of higher education or the lead institution of a consortium of nonprofit institutions of higher education, as applicable, may only submit one grant application per fiscal year for each of the transportation centers described under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (c).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H147F51FFF075411D9518A6AAAD25571A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for consortium members that are not lead institutions</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a nonprofit institution of higher education that is a member of a consortium of nonprofit institutions of higher education but not the lead institution of such consortium.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6209553F895F4319A41BEA175A1CFFD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(B)(iii) by inserting <quote>multimodal</quote> before <quote>transportation problems</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB88BB993CD1D48BA92F273E5806F9DB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(4) by striking subparagraph (B) and redesignating accordingly.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H60BC2D467E054964BF310570502E339C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Office of Science and Technology Policy working group</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall, to improve the scientific pursuit and research procedures of the Department of Transportation—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE21DECFC247D4CDE97DD3891A16A0913"><enum>(1)</enum><text>convene an interagency working group to assist the Department of Transportation in—</text> <subparagraph id="HD039268359C648C2890AF3AE6C41E8EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implementing appropriate protocols for the management of research programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C2A3E8B4549428D8E686C991ED25286"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing and implementing effective technology transfer methods;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5147FD46A283455099836657DEFDBC02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>effectively operating intermural research programs, including university transportation centers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE57D91DEF5745E39CC7E281930D6C11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>implementing a strategic research and development plan and national research framework; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D765D77666F4DB793549DD335AEBD02"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identifying appropriate research priorities;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90E278A4E874461191AED579B69318D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop procedures to allow the Secretary of Transportation to solicit the support of and identify opportunities to collaborate with other Federal research agencies, national laboratories, and personnel to assist in the effective and efficient pursuit and resolution of research challenges identified by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H174CAAC6F7A44025A02E1A0151A5A949"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to Congress, not later than 15 months after the date of enactment of this Act, a report about the effectiveness, adherence to standards and protocols, interagency collaboration, and areas of improvement of Department of Transportation and Governmentwide research on transportation-oriented needs.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H6BBDC9396FB64741A1674CE1718AF1D1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Research and technology development and deployment amendments</header>
 <subsection id="HF95902598BAE47DB81E2BFD48A2AC8D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Accelerated innovation deployment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 503(c)(2)(B) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD8729575EB97473785756AF930219A48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking clause (i) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HC0C394786EEE44F7A09238639BB87FF8" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H4D5701B9FD074127835CF1BFF80C7103"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish and carry out demonstration programs and workshops to promote innovations and convene strategic groups of individuals influential in innovation adoption processes;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF84CB0B2EC748C2B3BD60590C33A94C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E89C7787594CD98C587438F28F2DF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (iii) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2068BE24EF0B442AB1CCE6E7876B1C28"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H389DE6C657ED43AD9A650CC0CC722C9A" style="OLC"> <clause id="HDE687802815643F88B844FE422E8858E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide assistance in establishing regional, State, and local technology needs, such as through frameworks developed in the National Cooperative Highway Research Program Report 750.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7B819CF58E64BBD9218A7D2047D6E51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reauthorization of Technology and Innovation Deployment Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 503(c)(3)(C) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>2013 through 2014</quote> and inserting <quote>2016 through 2021</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HEE0AA480F67D43E69553AF9960C9BD88"><enum>6.</enum><header>State planning and research additional purposes</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 505(a) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HE0FE193371884192919DC8E4E2795AE8" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HE086D6782E4E42ACBB9FBE71C6E00DE6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Travel for research and technology purposes, including workshops, conferences, and demonstrations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9356BF573764DFA826126643461CDE3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Activities and training related to developing a culture of innovation and improving organizational readiness for adoption of innovative technologies, such as award programs recognizing innovative individuals.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HA6A84DFEA1E34282B21DD9BB25ABC686"><enum>7.</enum><header>Bureau of Transportation Statistics</header>
 <subsection id="H54BFB8781B8E4D83855DE17A5E5E009B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Travel Data Initiative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Transportation Statistics shall establish a Travel Data Initiative to expand the existing collection of passenger travel data by addressing the most critical gaps in our knowledge and understanding of passenger travel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H65201E3D2C6D4C09B4164ABF89A1AED4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To identify critical gaps in knowledge and data collection approaches, the Director shall seek advice from—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3EFE22D6FB004A0A85449617B26F0935"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Department of Transportation advisory committees;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE941C0C72C85432882C1C2A9886D6AFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Advisory Committee on Supply Chain Competitiveness of the Department of Commerce; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A55A1902151412D84E4A96AC52856AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Transportation Research Board of the National Academies.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20B6201250E64568B41DCB776C52E31C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pilot program</header> <paragraph id="H5876E8FF8E5347138E689E518CB6B54E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director, in coordination with the Office of Freight Management and Operations of the Federal Highway Administration, shall establish a pilot program to evaluate freight fluidity measures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H369AE9BF87744A148BB7CD9124ADD938"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Director shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF99EB48FAA374A2793442074CC1BB26F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect, analyze, and present freight data in a timely and comprehensive manner;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A7890618CD64A479C81B8F55E6903D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish reporting methods that work between States and internationally; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H845B190F02E341148A9A403E9DF33703"><enum>(C)</enum><text>present data with the greatest level of geographic detail that do not compromise confidentiality or statistical reliability.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF21E9DDAEE814633A4595DA8F1AF2206"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stakeholder engagement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in coordination with the Department of Commerce and the freight industry, shall define requirements for the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H155ED4DD0BA1436EA9305CAA6BC90000"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional authority</header><text>Section 6302 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2838BC833A38484A9833E412C2E7E421" style="USC"> <subsection id="H0418BA3EA5BF43158C82FF73E0BCA649"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Decisionmaking authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To ensure ongoing objectivity of the products of the Director, the Director has sole decisionmaking authority in the collection, analysis, and publication of data and statistics for the Bureau to fulfill the purposes of this section, in accordance with Statistical Policy Directive #1 and Statistical Policy Directive #4 of the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB93E2AD7DE284945A0A7259632FDBA6C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Budget Allocation authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall have final authority for the disposition and allocation of the authorized budget of the Bureau to enable fulfillment of the purposes of this section, including all hiring, grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the Bureau, including the disposition and allocation of funds paid to the Bureau for cost-reimbursable projects.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H08CC7502BF8147CEA45B34335C975F94"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Transportation performance management data program</header><text>To support States and metropolitan planning organizations in carrying out the performance management requirements of section 150 of title 23, the Director shall coordinate with other modal administrations to create and maintain data sets and data analysis tools for all performance measures, including—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HBE64B56D51A24065947C3E5FD3A82A8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transportation system resilience;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3E772D169E2F438E90371BC3F6010488"><enum>(2)</enum><text>multimodal freight connectivity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEE4E1F71FF734A0D85A7F6A419A78730"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improved data collection and analysis tools to accommodate performance measures, targets, and related data.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9D43B0F5F5A479CAB5A606D8E2DF950"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information technology decisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the provisions of section 11319 of title 40 shall not apply to the Bureau of Transportation Statistics.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA28787F506634F408DC4DBE8C52D99E5"><enum>8.</enum><header>National Cooperative Freight Transportation Research Program</header>
 <subsection id="H2B8BFC5EF522475DB9C2FF2AE680F4A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/5">Chapter 5</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/508">section 508</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20A4B319204044199120DDFEAA0F89B1" style="OLC"> <section id="H2CE95F32ECB9421E8F76FF44644FED61"><enum>509.</enum><header>National cooperative freight transportation research program</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HC2D9BD1BE15C45C8B9F83B98C5C2D535"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and support a national cooperative freight transportation research program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD6B64DC269B54E21B25342E48F8FC065"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the Transportation Research Board of the National Research Council of the National Academies to support and carry out administrative and management activities relating to the governance of the national cooperative freight transportation research program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H89DC3DFD50DB457593DB15718C701D01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><text>The National Academies shall select an advisory committee consisting of a representative cross-section of freight stakeholders, including the Department of Transportation, other Federal agencies, State transportation departments, local governments, nonprofit entities, academia, the private sector, nonprofit entities, trade associations, transportation coalitions, and other interested parties.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF992E53E9FA8463481025AA89CA7048B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Governance</header><text>The national cooperative freight transportation research program established under this section shall include the following administrative and management elements:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA022CEE065124EBBAA3C1E57E84A71FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National research agenda</header><text>The advisory committee, in consultation with interested parties, shall recommend a national research agenda for the program. The agenda shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H360EB9F1BC97433EB7522E93486DC4F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include an emphasis on the safe and efficient transportation and handling of hazardous materials by all modes of transportation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A2E8B6E26F14AEB9B06ED3AB880C43B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a multiyear strategic plan, recognizing freight research themes and needs identified by the National Freight Advisory Committee established to implement the freight transportation requirements of the MAP–21 and needs identified by the Advisory Committee on Supply Chain Competitiveness of the Department of Commerce;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D15AB873694D97BAFC280C5FDDB3C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be coordinated with the activities, plans, and reports required by sections 5304 and 5305 of title 49, United States Code; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96D855C63D394B45886A46460C45EAE3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>be coordinated with the activities, plans, and reports required by section 508 of title 23, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H391AAB5AF93F4A8D895ECBBE70D378E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Involvement</header><text>Interested parties may—</text> <subparagraph id="HE6219FC71A274433B01106B3EE0468D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit research proposals to the advisory committee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA74FAC74E51F43E18E6AA843DAAA3006"><enum>(B)</enum><text>participate in merit reviews of research proposals and peer reviews of research products; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22954D9A9F264E22ACB2BA393BB2FC46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>receive research results.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB2DFF9BE5554BA4B0B87D35A7CE093A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Open competition and peer review of research proposals</header><text>The National Academies may award research contracts and grants under the program through open competition and merit review conducted on a regular basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80855159E7334676853AC68DE9937A3F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Research coordination</header><text>The National Academies shall ensure that research contracts and grants awarded under this section are not duplicative with research conducted under other cooperative transportation research programs governed by the National Academies, nor with research conducted by the Department of Transportation or any other Federal, State, or local agency.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HFCAA98F859724EA5950609A30232D2D5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Evaluation of research</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9B3535967D3942B99144D67BD4528B48"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Peer review</header><text>Research contracts and grants under the program may allow peer review of the research results.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CE00DFFA8E949C199B077B132D7B871"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Programmatic evaluations</header><text>The National Academies may conduct periodic programmatic evaluations on a regular basis of research contracts and grants.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48EBCC1B4D6F47569B18B366D652AA76"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Dissemination of research findings</header><text>The National Academies shall disseminate research findings to researchers, practitioners, and decisionmakers, through conferences and seminars, field demonstrations, workshops, training programs, presentations, testimony to government officials, the Internet, publications for the general public, collaboration with the National Transportation Library, and other appropriate means.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6BD1706ADE8435F987255E7D3AD5DC8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The national research agenda required under subsection (d)(1) shall at a minimum include research in the following areas:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3BA51265D66447C1AC8DBC648090F561"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Techniques for measuring, estimating, and quantifying public benefits derived from freight transportation projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3564065C040C4BA9AFE73D08FB8FB60A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Alternative approaches to calculating the contribution of truck and rail traffic to congestion on specific highway segments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAF22F4F71054AD4810FC0E47425DCC9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The feasibility of consolidating origins and destinations for freight movement.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H92B6FFB76EBD400598301F578A117838"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Methods for incorporating estimates of domestic and international trade entering via all mode points of entry into landside transportation planning.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF50AE83709604435AD3A64202B95D86A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The use of technology applications, including to intelligent transportation systems applications, to increase capacity of highway lanes dedicated to truck-only traffic.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EC3EE9DF3D545D5AB1FCB49482E4D00"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Development of physical and policy alternatives for separating car and truck traffic.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F6489DB652A4F9B96689B55542D1D50"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Means of synchronizing infrastructure improvement projects with freight transportation demand projections.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04E19E4060FD43D08D8D3FB67923B467"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The effect of changing patterns of freight movement on transportation planning decisions, including accessible private and public commercial vehicle parking and truck-rail crossings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78D121BCE8504A3580E6F75348FAE8B5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Methods for collecting and sharing robust and timely freight data by all modes to inform transportation planning and operations at the local, regional and State levels.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B32746CF34B4F3E97B67B7B0A862AF2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Methods to gain local acceptance of freight development, expansion and growth along existing corridors, terminals and ports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE5BC8D7BCD34EBAB46B1B82B4F2D085"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Workforce development programs to attract more students and the next generation of workers to transportation planning, engineering and operation carriers to improve freight mobility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AA2C553CC184CF69DCBE3676CAF94A1"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Collaboration across multiple jurisdictions and between public and private sector funding partners to develop, maintain and invest in transportation improvements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4156750515784450A74F99380010ECAA"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Impact of the development and transport of new sources of energy on the freight network capacity and performance, as well as the potential for synergistic development of new transportation infrastructure with distribution of energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1729EFBBE8F34030AEEEB92550A28B39"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Funding and financing alternatives for multimodal freight infrastructure development, as well as the cost of inaction on infrastructure needs to system users.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H552DF38824F84050969A487E15CB512D"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Other research areas to identify and address emerging and future research needs related to freight transportation by all modes.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC539B2202A2412A9CC2952B426BD214"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="HCE530D83076C4A3E91F322A6DF1FDA45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of an activity carried out under this section shall be up to 100 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF3157A226E4D25B242985E4E71BA61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of non-federal funds</header><text>In addition to using funds authorized for this section, the National Academies may seek and accept additional funding sources from public and private entities capable of accepting funding from the Department of Transportation, States, local governments, nonprofit foundations, and the private sector.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA8E353D6DED475DB0A8B6B692738099"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period of availability</header><text>Amounts made available to carry out this section shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HE8A9DC85671A4BAA85CD13EA11A8C6F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The analysis for such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 508 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C7C4368167D4E59A805526BE2DFD64C" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">509. National cooperative freight transportation research program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HCFED8CE6F974467DA360E539BB6C5DA5"><enum>9.</enum><header>Commercial remote sensing products and spatial information technologies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5506 of SAFETEA–LU (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/502">23 U.S.C. 502</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE99D52B7B04E41E79B082C1702DBC47C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8B9E2028D48F4B6FB1152CA332982FE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>multimodal</quote> after <quote>national</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2320847279F4B7E9A68DA7DA67A8278"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>construction</quote> and inserting <quote>safety</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBF7EA95283B4528B438BA17D888270A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H20E2590DFE4F4B73A358982D643AD4BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>multimodal</quote> after <quote>in national</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F5ADE89317F480B93CC12939401866A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>construction</quote> and inserting <quote>safety</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4CF6093E1E4AA49F23A3C6C67F2C27"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEF7E45B2D0E4412A6843FBDCAFA4C23" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H05328466E85B4F609A18F31246AF7C6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out this section in cooperation with—</text> <paragraph id="HB9F96E16094F496BA12D715D6A3DCF92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the activities at the test ranges established under section 332 of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFEB770FA1544E69B9B6E334C620DFEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Center of Excellence for Unmanned Aerial Systems of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H795139767B5440B9BC5D12829E55D964"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d) by striking <quote>2006 through 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>2016 through 2021</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HDC2AABF0A3AA47019415069D1BE36865"><enum>10.</enum><header>Transportation research and development strategic planning</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 508(a) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF544271C478D45C8A93940C507DAA3FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by striking <quote>the Transportation Research and Innovative Technology Act of 2012</quote> and inserting <quote>the Future TRIP Act</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H654FA462CD114961A4E2C93C45EDC012"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD9500816C67A47C9A103F30FC2432A86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C5ECCA04F7F47FE9921C9235B45F0FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A5979B3E00A4645A0EC47F2142C8C52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0128603B09434C02A548DBA5FA76F11D" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="H15C58A4547AC4095A0A88F2806984A3A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides an outcome-based assessment of previous strategic plans;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE61D91D3E22B4A31A82B08119E81C323"><enum>(E)</enum><text>includes a description of current, planned, and strategic future collaborations within the Department, with other Federal agencies, and with international entities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7337C68B416645B89D23CEDB1D9A11B9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>includes an evaluation of the value of research, development, and technology to the nation and the Department’s strategic goals.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H8109C5BFED934BD4ADAB0C1BD05E5618"><enum>11.</enum><header>Centers for Surface Transportation Excellence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 504(h) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9BE1BBDC01B84976839F60CA8C646BFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of the Future TRIP Act, the Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8850EF338BD748E18B220603CE3E6A57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by striking <quote>and project finance</quote> and inserting <quote>project finance, and intelligent transportation systems</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

