<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8F74D1CDF03B4FF8BDCC4FF5E4057ED8" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3849 IH: Acupuncture for Heroes and Seniors Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3849</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151028">October 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to ensure access to qualified acupuncturist services for
			 military members and military dependents, to amend title 38, United States
			 Code, to ensure access to acupuncturist services through the Department of
			 Veterans Affairs, to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to
			 provide for coverage of qualified acupuncturist services under the
			 Medicare program; to amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the
			 appointment of qualified acupuncturists as officers in the commissioned
			 Regular Corps and the Ready Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service,
			 and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H42184F28C42A48AD89CE489F818DEAAD" style="OLC">
		<section id="H49A5925B100A40EE9FF8120053060560" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H8C4A8E585E6C4FBDA144570B046D7FD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Acupuncture for Heroes and Seniors Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HB739FD8D57A14DBEB2E792B71B34EF4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H49A5925B100A40EE9FF8120053060560" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE1EEA804308A4917A7A2186E95FDCE8B" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H69FAC855D8324AA797330E966AC54F23" level="section">Sec. 3. Inclusion of acupuncture services through military health care system and TRICARE program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H96B99B54E9FB46E2ABA75138FF972476" level="section">Sec. 4. Acupuncture health services for TRICARE program beneficiaries.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H19DE65605F52476AA9E02B8EE11AE57D" level="section">Sec. 5. Appointment of acupuncturists as commissioned officers.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF5FBED665ADC431CA7F40733A8C222F6" level="section">Sec. 6. Inclusion of acupuncturist services at veterans health facilities.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1B385FB841AA4DC99EBB2AB0A370AD05" level="section">Sec. 7. Coverage for acupuncturist services under the Medicare program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9692B844173444BDA84FB60817B7C4B9" level="section">Sec. 8. Acupuncturists in the Regular Corps and the Ready Reserve Corps of the Public Health
			 Service.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="HE1EEA804308A4917A7A2186E95FDCE8B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, except as otherwise provided:</text> <paragraph id="HC0BA576F695A495FBF7709C55BA13972"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified acupuncturist services</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF6C939A123C8473D947F3E09BF39F12A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acupuncturist services—</text> <clause id="H66B0675257594BF09A6A42CF97CF3095"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that are furnished by a qualified acupuncturist; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD17D0BF7744B42D183275BA93D75A81C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which the qualified acupuncturist is legally authorized to perform under State law; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6966FC03F9CA4F5B9D7F27276A7EF7FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>services and supplies that are furnished by a qualified acupuncturist incident to the services described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84C1667FC0154EAF8939BD27C08369B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified acupuncturist</term> means an individual who is licensed or certified as an acupuncturist by a State or, in the case of an individual in a State that does not provide for such licensure or certification, meets such criteria (such as accreditation through an appropriate nationally recognized certification authority for acupuncturists) as the Secretary of Health and Human Services may specify. In specifying such requirements, the Secretary may use the same requirements as those established by such a certification authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A2458CCCBFA44B5ADDC6B427A882B9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H69FAC855D8324AA797330E966AC54F23"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of acupuncture services through military health care system and TRICARE program</header>
			<subsection id="HDB54F346614F4A4F97EB3A0F05BA120B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Members of the uniformed services</header>
 <paragraph id="HBDDE82E8532949D9ADFFB306072FACA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">Chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1074m">section 1074m</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HCFCF7283773B46A1BB7023FC4D3FCC4F" style="USC">
 <section id="H3AB64CD9863643068FAB7B19A910A4C1"><enum>1074n.</enum><header>Provision of acupuncturist services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In accordance with section 1074(c) of this title, and under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, members of the uniformed services entitled to medical care under section 1074 shall be entitled to qualified acupuncturist services (without the requirement of a referral) provided in a military medical treatment facility or a private facility by an acupuncturist who is licensed or certified in the State in which the facility is located, or, in the case of a facility in a State that does not provide for such licensure or certification, meets such criteria (such as accreditation through an appropriate nationally recognized certification authority for acupuncturists) as the Secretary may specify. In specifying such requirements, the Secretary may use the same requirements as those established by such a certification authority.</text></section><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF4C4A010A6B444BAECA48CB8F23EBF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1074m the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HA6A5FF35588441DCAD26ECE2E921C57A" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">1074n. Provision of acupuncturist services.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEFAC50CC5DC483D821F6B3488A62F32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>TRICARE program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1079(a) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H92BF0E1315C74F56A6243E1D9212981F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by inserting <quote>or paragraph (18)</quote> after <quote>except as authorized in paragraph (4)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6625EF6456464DEFB4C3A80EF32D38A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D391424A7CC4230BBB89DB8A988FEC7" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H597748AB1B0949D98FFA1200B7080FC8"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acupuncturist services may be provided without the requirement of a referral if performed by an acupuncturist who is licensed or certified in the State in which the services are furnished, or, in the case of services furnished in a State that does not provide for such licensure or certification, meets such criteria (such as accreditation through an appropriate nationally recognized certification authority for acupuncturists) as the Secretary may specify. In specifying such requirements, the Secretary may use the same requirements as those established by such a certification authority.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0EEE382DCB424159B6E5222B8D222C15"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H96B99B54E9FB46E2ABA75138FF972476"><enum>4.</enum><header>Acupuncture health services for TRICARE program beneficiaries</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H483B86429F394EBA9F5D0471D5401683"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall develop a plan to provide qualified acupuncturist services, as a permanent part of the TRICARE program pursuant to the amendments made by section 3, for covered beneficiaries (as defined in section 1072 of title 10, United States Code).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB66B9E35F9794151B671499AA808B2EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of plan</header><text>The plan shall require that a contract entered into under section 1097 of title 10, United States Code, for the delivery of health care services shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC1212DEC7D71462181B500841F41D18C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include the delivery of qualified acupuncturist services;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD36372D2AFDA456AABD664A3ED472DC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require that qualified acupuncturist services may be provided only by a qualified acupuncturist; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H782801BD21024FAF85361BD1F82AA169"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide clarity on the process that a covered beneficiary must use to select and have direct access to a qualified acupuncturist (without the requirement of a referral).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H163519F1B9454338A2B6302BF7B26E22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan developed under subsection (a) shall provide for implementation of the plan to begin not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBAB568CF4CB54E85B9907E8E887EC809"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to Congress the plan developed under subsection (a).</text> </subsection></section><section id="H19DE65605F52476AA9E02B8EE11AE57D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Appointment of acupuncturists as commissioned officers in the Armed Forces</header> <subsection id="H596E398C12934C20BF4E4963CEECA163"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Army</header><text>Section 3068 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9BDF59FB34704F1F842CEFFC87F6E1B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">Medical service corps.—</header-in-text></quote> before <quote>There is</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1398C5F3EFDC4B89B27E0E51927C9754"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H307E0C18CE9B472FBC25AE74A54CC923"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H797235529F194E0BA3EA506AECBD5418"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H953E27DBC2BF4D3DB3BDC4F897AAEB83"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E96411724CD46C3B6DE2C3CC384AF66" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD222D50749B74F9487B2FB7D886839AB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Acupuncture Section; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADE3D1F5183E4616B5061BF88C9CD608"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H256BC1E9771C488EBEB0273D58EC1A30" style="USC"> <subsection id="H24C420495A1849A0B3EF7F93DF888B25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment of acupuncturists</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acupuncturists who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Army may be appointed as commissioned officers in the Acupuncture Section of the Medical Service Corps of the Army. Such regulations shall require such acupuncturists to be licensed or certified in the State in which the services are furnished, or, in the case of services furnished in a State that does not provide for such licensure or certification, meets such criteria (such as accreditation through an appropriate nationally recognized certification authority for acupuncturists) as the Secretary of the Army may specify. In specifying such requirements, the Secretary may use the same requirements as those established by such a certification authority.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59C73F4CD88F40C1B148F094C2CA5F6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Navy</header>
 <paragraph id="H9194172D80E04F8E8212661AD69E34D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 513 of such title is amended by inserting after section 5139 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="H8AAACA0313B04AE39D704CD41DF3876B" style="USC"> <section id="HC3B28326D7014722B80ABC918B3B73AD"><enum>5140.</enum><header>Appointment of acupuncturists in the Medical Service Corps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Acupuncturists who are qualified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy may be appointed as commissioned officers in the Medical Service Corps of the Navy. Such regulations shall require such acupuncturists to be licensed or certified in the State in which the services are furnished, or, in the case of services furnished in a State that does not provide for such licensure or certification, meets such criteria (such as accreditation through an appropriate nationally recognized certification authority for acupuncturists) as the Secretary of the Navy may specify. In specifying such requirements, the Secretary may use the same requirements as those established by such a certification authority.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5A7AEDDFDE044BBBFE13FB4998D0244"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5139 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17BAEEBCF9C94B759C2B59BB4BB4000C" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">5140. Appointment of acupuncturists in the Medical Service Corps.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6732BF1864244B4F9D582BC5AE52DC5B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Air force</header><text>Section 8067(f) of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2CE95EAABC314BD392A4D6225AC6B785"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>physician assistant functions and chiropractic functions</quote> and inserting <quote>physician assistant functions, chiropractic functions, and acupuncturist functions</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2A084D91FED40BA986D5BA04A2A78C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Biomedical service officers may be referred to as the specific career designation, including chiropractic services officer and acupuncturist services officer.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAFBC027005B4A9B88493CA678C97991"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The regulations required to be prescribed by the amendments made by this section shall be prescribed not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF5FBED665ADC431CA7F40733A8C222F6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Inclusion of acupuncturist services at veterans health facilities</header>
			<subsection id="H1FFF9BBEA8154CBC8E7F6A97721547E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acupuncturist services</header>
 <paragraph id="H891C9CF62A2A496ABC1C55F61D93921C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H450DA08964AF4FADA1BA8C4D3AC2D1A4" style="USC">
						<section id="H791185E2CD45498395B9D9B91BD36501"><enum>1720H.</enum><header>Provision of acupuncturist services</header>
 <subsection id="H748C9F2EED084077925F166B3187A96A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program to provide acupuncturist services to veterans enrolled in the health care system established under section 1705(a) of this title (without the requirement of a referral).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3A32EC1E5FBD488997BF0D7C181040C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program under subsection (a) shall be carried out at in at least one facility of the Department in each Veterans Integrated Service Network. In selecting such facilities, the Secretary shall ensure that the program is carried out in both urban and rural areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4079FB4A43644E31B7EF24A0FD8A63BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Services available</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the acupuncturist services available under the program are able to address, at a minimum, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4CE380A4664E40AE9EE8CA313D09649B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Chronic and acute pain.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A0E19D70AEF4330B19972245EC7A38F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Cancer pain.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7233545201EC43CDB4E3CAD4B9E3571F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Postoperative nausea and vomiting.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD62E51496E8C402F8B8157CEB2330189"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Postsurgical gastroparesis syndrome.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1D353207648415BA66E170E6EBF50F2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Opioid-induced constipation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB6DE6406C1242CFB5A722151FE5B3BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Opioid-induced pruritus.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5648C866065A4365833C5594D445077F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Chemotherapy-induced neuropathy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H64A7FB0A8DEC4B7889E5705595D3BE52"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Aromatase inhibitor-associated joint pain.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC6E601FFCE04D3091A2BE1E2534FCC7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Neck dissection-related pain and dysfunction.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H449B46091C0A4045977D40B5872EF9D9"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stress management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C8556966A4C4A87B451DE0848485151"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Mental health conditions.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD851BF9B57374E669E0B1A9AA0AECA46"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Substance abuse.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H309FE095DF5A4B6CBE777E2ADCDABC26"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Symptoms relating to traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0FDB21B3AA61432B9D2D4D9FB8EF5D5B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HECD79E0EDD344739A769E95C9366C554"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall carry out the program through—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAE7DDE6996554B2F812F60D127FA7499" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>qualified acupuncturists appointed as employees of the Department located at medical centers and clinics of the Department; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC000D2C0DDD34D1F8E9B7C530AE33426" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through contract qualified acupuncturists if—</text> <clause id="H9143F7998A0A485DBDF807870BA33C0E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary is unable to make appointments described in subparagraph (A);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB082224DD4B345C8AC9AEC113860D97C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a patient requires specialty care that an employee under such subparagraph is not able to provide to the patient; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF8CDCAC40BA7463DB3EE7D912B3699C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>there is an emergency that requires the use of such a contract acupuncturist.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H063D90F0FB334154990E3A8DF35F217C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide training and materials to health care providers of the Department who provide primary care to veterans to explain the benefits of acupuncturist services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5F3CFC0F9864822820DD6C53A7E67F4" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>qualified acupuncturist</term> means, with respect to the furnishing of services in a State, an individual who licensed or certified in the State in which the services are furnished, or, in the case of services furnished in a State that does not provide for such licensure or certification, meets such criteria (such as accreditation through an appropriate nationally recognized certification authority for acupuncturists) as the Secretary may specify. In specifying such requirements, the Secretary may use the same requirements as those established by such a certification authority.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H815F92A7D25B4C63B1D60740EBDFFE7E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B7744C1DAA44901A1E93B947018CF61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1720G the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB5A0111A4534F1AA65454BC65EB4906" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">1720H. Provision of acupuncturist services.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8A4470F546B8409AB641C446FF8B3AF8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1701(6) of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10F6FB38352247529A8B5A0B35474F87" style="USC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE2CCB93AF9464D9C86ED0D1B8EFED945"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acupuncturist services in accordance with section 1720H of this title.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F726ECDAF5E4402B9A2CE3428ABD321"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header>
 <paragraph id="H8B2F9E7C4EC14CA396086BD7654E56C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of chapter 5 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDF56339F6304B9084F418407287A354" style="USC">
						<section id="H81CC457610A0495990F4B5DA1C9C7562"><enum>547.</enum><header>Advisory committee on acupuncturist services</header>
							<subsection id="HE6B26AFA5DD843F986A56001BEFBF3B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acupuncture advisory committee</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA0D14941363D499781429D18F5F2FADE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>Advisory Committee on Acupuncturist Services</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) to provide the Secretary with assistance and advice in the development and implementation of the program established by section 1720H of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4CEA8B64A634F9D925007B2AAC5C2A6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee shall consist of members appointed by the Secretary from the general public, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB05606A240A246DAB7223CDDE616FAD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not fewer than five practicing acupuncturists, of which at least four shall be State licensed acupuncturists;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CB44314A2ED4471A402C3CEECAA197D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one veteran from each of the Armed Forces;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFDB5DA42A02454C893B6B9F596215BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not fewer than two representatives from veterans service organizations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0EC4890C02A4FAC954CAADAAFAC3F17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a representative of the Department of Defense.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3F5F8085A214D3195D1F34CA8F0562D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H01B06432D9DC4EAB8224AB8252EEC483"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review and evaluate the ability of a veteran to access an acupuncturist at facilities of the Department;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB13BA11FA0F431B834EDC788FA6EAE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advise the Secretary with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0497779B9A0749E780000EAE44B8F1D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protocols governing direct access to acupuncture care;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08BFF259893F4B41A17CB8929223A252"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protocols governing the scope of practice of acupuncture practitioners;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7654E7D6C84A4E939A5589C8F28E2F59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the definitions of services to be provided by acupuncturists; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ED7615325DD461C86BD5C8BE35C948D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other matters the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H723369ECFBAC4FF9B3BB966AC316D25D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>upon the determination of the Secretary that the program of acupuncturist services under section 1720H of this title has been fully implemented, submit to the Secretary a report containing the evaluation of the Committee of the implementation of such program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC11EDA3699954010B8B2AF4E7C1F7051"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairman</header><text>The Secretary shall designate one member of the Committee to serve as the chairman of the Committee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H457AFBB3DBEA41BFAF10768A30EFD18B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chairman, but not fewer than three times during each fiscal year, beginning in the fiscal year following the fiscal year in which this section is enacted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC776A4218FA42DFA65A901F84F9AE36"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the date on which the Committee submits to the Secretary the report under subsection (b)(4), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report containing the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA9D0662ED48146599A903C3FA8486CC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A copy of the Committee report, together with the comments of the Secretary on the report.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F0D833BE58442E980216CDA21A89277"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explanation of the criteria and rationale that the Secretary used to determine that the program of acupuncturist services under section 1720H of this title was fully implemented, as described in such subsection (b)(4).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0129BD62B1343969C7DD17AF12CA6CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The views of the Secretary regarding the future implementation of such program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4338C1B8E9F842668D194F3FE04854B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 546 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F1B65BB1B2244748CBF525B22F958CA" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">547. Advisory committee on acupuncturist services.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6E123BF4C7D48198757A887B64FA9EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H03B65336E1BB4B23B4BEFCB47EF5F643"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority for appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7401(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>acupuncturists,</quote> after <quote>chiropractors,</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H32B7572B18224E1E9F6BE3F11945F5AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of appointments</header><text>Section 7403 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B41D780EF6B45B3BEC1D32EBE7BE6A1" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="H5648B03732274C09B64F54A421FD70BA"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acupuncturists.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BAE27E12CF74B1DBA0261DB2C3EB529"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pay</header> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AAF491135B3415BAC456697FCB21DDA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Scale</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7404 of such title is amended—</text>
 <clause id="HCC8A967856084EF4B22F8B9491EFDE65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by inserting <quote>, acupuncturists,</quote> after <quote>physicians</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H833A6FE7568541A2AAEE1F4F9DAE4E0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the list in subsection (b), by inserting <quote>, ACUPUNCTURIST,</quote> after <quote>PHYSICIAN</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC67772EF0DB4408B94D3BEDDA6600C3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text>Section 7431 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93BFC587175641ED819D9707F4EC3B4C" style="USC">
 <subsection id="H575FFEC92B8447FBAB847781D9BD1A17"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Treatment of acupuncturists</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subchapter, an acupuncturist is deemed to be a physician.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB521C96BC2F444C5A46A6182B50D08A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Malpractice and negligence suits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7316(a)(2) of such title is amended by inserting <quote>acupuncturist,</quote> after <quote>chiropractor,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H873BF263C8DF4AA6A99D5ABC0EF34FEE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hours and conditions</header><text>Section 7421(b) of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FBF8F2553A04E908960B62F84D0D466" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H9CE80518F84E49BABF508AB423E470F8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acupuncturists.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16BFDE33BC234FF284752B9DEC997ACB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by paragraph (4) apply with respect to services provided on or after the date that is 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1B385FB841AA4DC99EBB2AB0A370AD05"><enum>7.</enum><header>Coverage for acupuncturist services under the Medicare program</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H6BEA120D89BC44C9A68A405EEBB451AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA4B3B93AEEFE4688A4CCF132A623ED64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (s)(2)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB3DB0949EC794EF8985E62FC18362F51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (EE);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA613FC5C65E246DA9C46D31DBEA91B1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (FF); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4479EDB65BC74C119B3F9AE898E39478"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FD321FE82884196976F491C1FEC325F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HBD3A48151930455B98C0784E3510EC26" indent="up1"><enum>(GG)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualified acupuncturist services (as defined in subsection (iii)(1));</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1655D0A01394386865EBD3A38800601"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BC9E4E5E52F42E9BBD246397F40C9F0" other-style="archaic" style="other"> <subsection id="H32BBBC34933744C287BD92C4C6EF3DEF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified acupuncturist services</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H63B7CB14D47E46C59DD316097006658A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>qualified acupuncturist services</term> means such services furnished by a qualified acupuncturist (as defined in paragraph (2)), and such services and supplies furnished as an incident to services furnished by the qualified acupuncturist, as the qualified acupuncturist is legally authorized to perform under State law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H766BE02E86A74EDAA2101DE359A8D64A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>qualified acupuncturist</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the <short-title>Acupuncture for Heroes and Seniors Act of 2015</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DB38B4FDD2C450BB399397B1FCB1CEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment rules</header> <paragraph id="H220FAF38624244E79B03574AC33E4DF1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment under physician fee schedule</header><text>Section 1848(j)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(j)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(2)(GG),</quote> before <quote>(3),</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H071E777D333B441AA4F5A506C948FEB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Separate payment for services of institutional providers</header><text>Section 1833(a)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HF92A399C7A3244658BC37E05B04B5FB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>and in the case of qualified acupuncturist services,</quote> after <quote>1999,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3E59E9CC74648BAA1C75823D8CD24EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>or in the case of qualified acupuncturist services,</quote> after <quote>1999,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B2D1C126F2F49B29D667A9BE1520B75"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by inserting <quote>(other than qualified acupuncturist services)</quote> after <quote>such services</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7400E59FDD9F4E4EB9ACAFED33D13923"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified acupuncturist treatment as a practitioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1842(b)(18)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395u">42 U.S.C. 1395u(b)(18)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1737ECEC7354BE48A080C5403839D66" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H9DD2A1E13FBA45ACBDB4B9DD356B0ECC" indent="up2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified acupuncturist (as defined in section 1861(iii)(2)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE09006783B004EDB8C5CA7D7713C752E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Separate billing for acupuncturist services furnished in an inpatient hospital setting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861(b)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>qualified acupuncturist services,</quote> after <quote>qualified psychologist services,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BD938EBC89F4D389A796B63CDFB04BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section apply with respect to services furnished on or after the date that is 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9692B844173444BDA84FB60817B7C4B9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Acupuncturists in the Regular Corps and the Ready Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service</header>
 <subsection id="HC8A23FDA8D28466DB316C8F958EE986B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appointment</header><text>Section 207 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/209">42 U.S.C. 209</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7851437FEBDC4B019BF494B4941265C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by inserting <quote>acupuncture,</quote> after <quote>nursing,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CA5AE155E2545C980887E5B0780DD2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H72898D28F966433C964D87997929DE91" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H72370CBAE15942C6BC48D363049C78BB"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Appointment of qualified acupuncturists</header> <paragraph id="H28929BAE474D42DDA1C59244ADC7851D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Acupuncturists shall be eligible for appointment as officers in the commissioned Regular Corps and the Ready Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H935626A9803D48CB8644F41140306CA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualification; training, equipment, and preparation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that acupuncturists in the commissioned Regular Corps and in the Ready Reserve Corps—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5C183FCCACC74E78B3B6E2CA95D7382A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are qualified acupuncturists (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Acupuncture for Heroes and Seniors Act of 2015</short-title>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1ACC71982DE4948830D0B139D5200DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are trained, equipped, and otherwise prepared to fulfill applicable public health and emergency response service responsibilities in the Commissioned Corps.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0379C07E65C46DA8A631778E16F4B99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required placement</header>
 <paragraph id="H8A82C63E86454913AA5FA9114C1FC0D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall ensure the appointment of no fewer than 6 acupuncturists into the commissioned Regular Corps and the Ready Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H839A063A20E944D2B906B9BE6971B3C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter, the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on all measures taken by the President, the Surgeon General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out the provisions of this section, including the amendments made by this section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


