<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD8731FDB24A1451091573EE847C8B0D9" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 850 IH: Academic, Social, and Emotional Learning Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 850</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To support evidence-based social and emotional learning programming.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H19ABC90B64FE409F86B5BDB9502F39B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H72B89AC2025B4A00B5686714833668D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Academic, Social, and Emotional Learning Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD7BEA388632843568D4AEF3463415ED7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD97A6A5B61774D44A74FB2155ECE1647"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To succeed in school, students need to be engaged. They need to know how to maintain focus and effort in the face of setbacks, work effectively with others, and be good communicators and problem-solvers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44C012D8EFE349D9B8E6E99350C2E0A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Social and emotional skills form a foundation for young people’s success not just in school, but as healthy and caring adults, productive workers, and engaged citizens.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E7CB5D39B8B4C689272283BB0963065"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Not only can these skills be taught, they can be taught by regular classroom teachers in schools of every type to students of every background.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31AAA132018F40EDB50BA7AF89704B5D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Academic outcomes resulting from social and emotional learning include greater motivation to learn and commitment to school, increased time devoted to schoolwork and mastery of subject matter, improved attendance, graduation rates, grades, and test scores.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2C2F5E5330448858F7EFF91080038D1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These positive outcomes increase in students who are involved in social and emotional learning programming by an average of 11 percentile points over students who are not involved in such programming.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70C9BA2E26674A21AECBB640A897E0CA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Social and emotional learning programming also results in reduced problem behavior, improved health outcomes, a lower rate of violent delinquency, and a lower rate of heavy alcohol use.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H252C0BC1DDA7414A8C792F627772B23C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to the Elementary and Secondary Education Act</header>
 <subsection id="H1040F8F225EF4E6DA54551B49CF4D789"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Teacher and principal training and recruiting fund</header><text>Part A of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6601">20 U.S.C. 6601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCF1EF94532A845138F5371A1243F8F0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2113(c)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H21B2BCDB8DD94ED58340246CB8CC3EFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB29FB23E0A746E481012688E2C22648"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC95BAD85EED1400799BAB637938E29CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HD79691A5409B4E0C9819507E2E863F32" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H3411A4EBFDB44D78AFCEBA4FCBC3A0FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>train teachers and principals in practices that have demonstrated effectiveness in improving student achievement, attainment, and behavior through addressing the social and emotional development needs of students, such as through social and emotional learning programming.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB564E63C0CE64A5C8F4A4D6D5C9BB184"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2123(a)(3)(B)(iii)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFBEF6E2FF81D43B19A9B6EDFBF4E03A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of (I);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66453C99485D444EB3B7936D4D423285"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subclause (II) as subclause (III); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5FA036A22BA4FDEAD61CFE19906AB1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subclause (I) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C6EB20024CA4367A5C570B3A2494C55" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="HC638B33A22884C1F88E12987C36816D9"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addressing the social and emotional development needs of students to improve student achievement and attainment, such as through social and emotional learning programming; and</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D8D7328590B4A318235AB8233D58FD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08ABF70E7C4849CAB35CB590967EC153" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3414892010D94939BAD3BDBDEE87B3D6"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Social and emotional learning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>social and emotional learning</quote> means the process through which children and adults acquire the knowledge, attitudes, and skills associated with the core areas of social and emotional competency, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H44871295D2F1458EA37545770742D11D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>self-awareness and self-management to achieve school and life success, such as identifying and recognizing strengths, needs, emotions, values and self-efficacy, impulse control and stress management, self-motivation and discipline, and goal setting and organizational skills;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H856B502FC23B43CB8E50799C449988E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>social awareness and interpersonal skills to establish and maintain positive relationships, such as perspective taking and respect for others, communication, working cooperatively, negotiation, conflict management, and help seeking; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56F5376572BA4A28B6F0F0824F6F9680"><enum>(C)</enum><text>decisionmaking skills and responsible behaviors in personal, academic and community contexts, such as situational analysis, problem solving, reflection and personal, and social and ethical responsibility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8035D1747784404947FC156B167BB28"><enum>(45)</enum><header>Social and Emotional Learning Programming</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>social and emotional learning programming</quote> refers to classroom instruction and schoolwide activities and initiatives that—</text> <subparagraph id="H670CD5288C4F4EBA9336F58BFE344D2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>integrate social and emotional learning into school curriculum;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37CB68427D154F7BBC919AE22DE2F915"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide systematic instruction whereby social and emotional skills are taught, modeled, practiced, and applied so that students use them as part of their daily behavior;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBEF4ED632CD4DCDB5E070D3EB3C631D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>teach children to apply social and emotional skills to prevent specific problem behaviors such as substance use, violence, bullying, and school failure, and to promote positive behaviors in class, school, and community activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCD68FC171FC45808B7B481F42A91F64"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish safe and caring learning environments that foster student participation, engagement, and connection to learning and school.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


