<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="appropriations" dms-id="ID34BAC14540CB4BC4ADFBFC96EE9D188A" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3049 RH: Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar>Union Calendar No. 153</calendar> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3049</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 114–205]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150714">July 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Aderholt</sponsor>, from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSAP00" deleted-display-style="bold-brackets">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, reported the following bill; which was committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>Making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="ID3F54C6107CE743A8878D0BC760C31247" style="appropriations"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H34603EE8F08D42D1B0655F6D3A8B236E" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs for fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for other purposes, namely:</text> </section> <title id="ID5351DA38EEDF4F94A3351D86519DF2E3"><enum>I</enum> <appropriations-major id="H6B2C8C09E7F24F2589F89F56C2AE68EB"><header> AGRICULTURAL PROGRAMS</header> </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H07A9024FE1974689AF2042B1ED47DAD1"><header>Production, Processing and Marketing</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="ID024E9F344E8849109F02F696AE8AEAC0"><header>Office of the Secretary</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H1CC1A1BBF7F04772A234E18404AA2D5B"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Secretary, $39,379,000, of which not to exceed $5,051,000 shall be available for the Immediate Office of the Secretary; not to exceed $498,000 shall be available for the Office of Tribal Relations; not to exceed $1,496,000 shall be available for the Office of Homeland Security and Emergency Coordination; not to exceed $1,209,000 shall be available for the Office of Advocacy and Outreach; not to exceed $23,590,000 shall be available for the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Administration, of which $22,786,000 shall be available for Departmental Administration to provide for necessary expenses for management support services to offices of the Department and for general administration, security, repairs and alterations, and other miscellaneous supplies and expenses not otherwise provided for and necessary for the practical and efficient work of the Department; not to exceed $3,064,000 shall be available for the Office of Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations to carry out the programs funded by this Act, including programs involving intergovernmental affairs and liaison within the executive branch; and not to exceed $4,471,000 shall be available for the Office of Communications: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to transfer funds appropriated for any office of the Office of the Secretary to any other office of the Office of the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That no appropriation for any office shall be increased or decreased by more than 5 percent: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not to exceed $11,000 of the amount made available under this paragraph for the immediate Office of the Secretary shall be available for official reception and representation expenses, not otherwise provided for, as determined by the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the amount made available under this heading for Departmental Administration shall be reimbursed from applicable appropriations in this Act for travel expenses incident to the holding of hearings as required by 5 U.S.C. 551–558: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds made available under this heading for the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations may be transferred to agencies of the Department of Agriculture funded by this Act to maintain personnel at the agency level: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That no funds made available under this heading for the Office of Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations may be obligated after 30 days from the date of enactment of this Act, unless the Secretary has notified the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress on the allocation of these funds by USDA agency.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H414E66D436924DAA991EB4E18A8B88BB"><header>Executive Operations</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H9B928B2D1CDE44D0B0D1AB2E6C8E8518"><header>Office of the chief economist</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Chief Economist, $16,777,000, of which $4,000,000 shall be for grants or cooperative agreements for policy research under 7 U.S.C. 3155.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H588C1FF170D043389020AD215C9C24A5"><header>National appeals division</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the National Appeals Division, $12,841,000.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H9127764AE3724DF29B3C65AF171E24D5"><header>Office of budget and program analysis</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Budget and Program Analysis, $9,081,000.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H33A223AED0304154B814AC1C643A1E53"><header>Office of the chief information officer</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Chief Information Officer, $44,031,000, of which not less than $27,000,000 is for cybersecurity requirements of the Department.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H2AEDE3C1F1F84D7595BABEC050AAAECA"><header>Office of the chief financial officer</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, $6,028,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H0E8807147997418887A2555B441C53DA"><header>Office of the assistant secretary for civil rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights, $893,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H097410DF9F524C9ABC49B0138059811F"><header>Office of civil rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Civil Rights, $23,871,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="id4682265D95DB4DBC8562804176B32629"><header>Agriculture buildings and facilities</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="idACED64C1367844AEA1CAF4F1EED69955"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payment of space rental and related costs pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/92/313">Public Law 92–313</external-xref>, including authorities pursuant to the 1984 delegation of authority from the Administrator of General Services to the Department of Agriculture under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/121">40 U.S.C. 121</external-xref>, for programs and activities of the Department which are included in this Act, and for alterations and other actions needed for the Department and its agencies to consolidate unneeded space into configurations suitable for release to the Administrator of General Services, and for the operation, maintenance, improvement, and repair of Agriculture buildings and facilities, and for related costs, $54,730,000, to remain available until expended, for buildings operations and maintenance expenses: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Secretary may use unobligated prior year balances of an agency or office that are no longer available for new obligation for the sole purpose of covering shortfalls incurred in prior or current year rental payments for such agency or office.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="id1BF4490EDC5F42168C50E34923515B0B"><header>Hazardous materials management</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="idF3F485B26A8A4C27B06498233D29EE88"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Department of Agriculture, to comply with the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6901">42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.</external-xref>), $3,600,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That appropriations and funds available herein to the Department for Hazardous Materials Management may be transferred to any agency of the Department for its use in meeting all requirements pursuant to the above Acts on Federal and non-Federal lands.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="id617990396C634A7A833AF83B2ACAEB29"><header>Office of inspector general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Inspector General, including employment pursuant to the Inspector General Act of 1978, $95,643,000, including such sums as may be necessary for contracting and other arrangements with public agencies and private persons pursuant to section 6(a)(9) of the Inspector General Act of 1978, and including not to exceed $125,000 for certain confidential operational expenses, including the payment of informants, to be expended under the direction of the Inspector General pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/452">Public Law 95–452</external-xref> and section 1337 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/97/98">Public Law 97–98</external-xref>.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H86019CD5BA334EC5ABAD7EFDF9B505B1"><header>Office of the general counsel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the General Counsel, $43,313,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H447D092BCFDB495FB605F7CD1ABC0A43"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of ethics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Ethics, $3,440,000.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HEE1D13012562479098907754813FCED4"><header>Office of the under secretary for research, education, and economics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics, $893,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H186F88080DBB448AAC1EA0F5DE5534B9"><header>Economic research service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Economic Research Service, $78,058,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HD3C32237F67B404082DB928BAFD7C226"><header>National agricultural statistics service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the National Agricultural Statistics Service, $161,206,000, of which up to $44,525,000 shall be available until expended for the Census of Agriculture: <italic>Provided</italic>, That amounts made available for the Census of Agriculture may be used to conduct Current Industrial Report surveys subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2204g">7 U.S.C. 2204g(d)</external-xref> and (f).</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H72E1A898E98F47109BEBD1CBECB54DF2"><header>Agricultural research service</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H7E14B5CA1DBA49778DDA5430DE6EF254"><header>salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Agricultural Research Service and for acquisition of lands by donation, exchange, or purchase at a nominal cost not to exceed $100, and for land exchanges where the lands exchanged shall be of equal value or shall be equalized by a payment of money to the grantor which shall not exceed 25 percent of the total value of the land or interests transferred out of Federal ownership, $1,122,454,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That appropriations hereunder shall be available for the operation and maintenance of aircraft and the purchase of not to exceed one for replacement only: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That appropriations hereunder shall be available pursuant to 7 U.S.C. 2250 for the construction, alteration, and repair of buildings and improvements, but unless otherwise provided, the cost of constructing any one building shall not exceed $375,000, except for headhouses or greenhouses which shall each be limited to $1,200,000, and except for 10 buildings to be constructed or improved at a cost not to exceed $750,000 each, and the cost of altering any one building during the fiscal year shall not exceed 10 percent of the current replacement value of the building or $375,000, whichever is greater: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the limitations on alterations contained in this Act shall not apply to modernization or replacement of existing facilities at Beltsville, Maryland: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That appropriations hereunder shall be available for granting easements at the Beltsville Agricultural Research Center: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the foregoing limitations shall not apply to replacement of buildings needed to carry out the Act of April 24, 1948 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/113a">21 U.S.C. 113a</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That appropriations hereunder shall be available for granting easements at any Agricultural Research Service location for the construction of a research facility by a non-Federal entity for use by, and acceptable to, the Agricultural Research Service and a condition of the easements shall be that upon completion the facility shall be accepted by the Secretary, subject to the availability of funds herein, if the Secretary finds that acceptance of the facility is in the interest of the United States: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds may be received from any State, other political subdivision, organization, or individual for the purpose of establishing or operating any research facility or research project of the Agricultural Research Service, as authorized by law: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the appropriations hereunder, $56,123,000 may not be obligated until thirty days after the Secretary of Agriculture certifies in writing to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress that the Agricultural Research Service has updated its animal care policies and that all Agricultural Research Service research facilities at which animal research is conducted have a fully functioning Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee, including all appropriate and necessary record keeping: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such certification shall set forth in detail the factual basis for the certification and the Department’s plan for ensuring these changes are maintained in the future: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such certification shall be subject to prior consultation with the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="id20DDADFF2DFB4487A49520EFFF6F7055"><header>Buildings and facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the acquisition of land, construction, repair, improvement, extension, alteration, and purchase of fixed equipment or facilities as necessary to carry out the agricultural research programs of the Department of Agriculture, where not otherwise provided, $45,000,000 to remain available until expended.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="id8E4694F4CA454194B04876847D523079"><header>National institute of food and agriculture</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HC98F2494D97B4B638F9FCCD85C405586"><header>Research and education activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payments to agricultural experiment stations, for cooperative forestry and other research, for facilities, and for other expenses, $781,510,000, which shall be for the purposes, and in the amounts, specified in the table titled <quote>National Institute of Food and Agriculture, Research and Education Activities</quote> in the report accompanying this Act: <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds for research grants for 1994 institutions, education grants for 1890 institutions, the agriculture and food research initiative, veterinary medicine loan repayment, multicultural scholars, graduate fellowship and institution challenge grants, and grants management systems shall remain available until expended: <italic> Provided further</italic>, That each institution eligible to receive funds under the Evans-Allen program receives no less than $1,000,000: <italic> Provided further</italic>, That funds for education grants for Alaska Native and Native Hawaiian-serving institutions be made available to individual eligible institutions or consortia of eligible institutions with funds awarded equally to each of the States of Alaska and Hawaii: <italic> Provided further</italic>, That funds for education grants for 1890 institutions shall be made available to institutions eligible to receive funds under 7 U.S.C. 3221 and 3222: <italic> Provided further</italic>, That not more than 5 percent of the amounts made available by this or any other Act to carry out the Agriculture and Food Research Initiative under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/450i">7 U.S.C. 450i(b)</external-xref> may be retained by the Secretary of Agriculture to pay administrative costs incurred by the Secretary in carrying out that authority.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HDB5BD0CB087D421B904297BF41C0C61E"><header>Native american institutions endowment fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the Native American Institutions Endowment Fund authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/382">Public Law 103–382</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/301">7 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note), $11,880,000, to remain available until expended.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HEA33165E71844212ABE6E7911D7BFA16"><header>Extension activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payments to States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, Micronesia, the Northern Marianas, and American Samoa, $472,051,000, which shall be for the purposes, and in the amounts, specified in the table titled <quote>National Institute of Food and Agriculture, Extension Activities</quote> in the report accompanying this Act: <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds for facility improvements at 1890 institutions shall remain available until expended: <italic> Provided further</italic>, That institutions eligible to receive funds under 7 U.S.C. 3221 for cooperative extension receive no less than $1,000,000: <italic> Provided further</italic>, That funds for cooperative extension under sections 3(b) and (c) of the Smith-Lever Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/343">7 U.S.C. 343(b)</external-xref> and (c)) and section 208(c) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/471">Public Law 93–471</external-xref> shall be available for retirement and employees’ compensation costs for extension agents.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H547B1BBC26FF4C958B120DB4190286E8"><header>Integrated activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the integrated research, education, and extension grants programs, including necessary administrative expenses, $30,900,000, which shall be for the purposes, and in the amounts, specified in the table titled <quote>National Institute of Food and Agriculture, Integrated Activities</quote> in the report accompanying this Act: <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds for the Food and Agriculture Defense Initiative shall remain available until September 30, 2017.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H3C48C302319E49CB941BBE4ABA8A2B27"><header>Office of the under secretary for marketing and regulatory programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Under Secretary for Marketing and Regulatory Programs, $893,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H8999923EDF8449568B4273CB6EEE1196"><header>Animal and plant health inspection service</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HBEC1574A790A4C73903F31A9B3FC5616"><header>salaries and expenses</header> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7FAC40BE9EED4B819D5527EEDCCF03B0"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, including up to $30,000 for representation allowances and for expenses pursuant to the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4085">22 U.S.C. 4085</external-xref>), $870,945,000, of which $470,000, to remain available until expended, shall be available for the control of outbreaks of insects, plant diseases, animal diseases and for control of pest animals and birds (<quote>contingency fund</quote>) to the extent necessary to meet emergency conditions; of which $11,520,000, to remain available until expended, shall be used for the cotton pests program for cost share purposes or for debt retirement for active eradication zones; of which $35,000,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for Animal Health Technical Services; of which $697,000 shall be for activities under the authority of the Horse Protection Act of 1970, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1831">15 U.S.C. 1831</external-xref>); of which $55,340,000, to remain available until expended, shall be used to support avian health; of which $4,251,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for information technology infrastructure; of which $158,000,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for specialty crop pests; of which, $8,826,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for field crop and rangeland ecosystem pests; of which $45,519,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for tree and wood pests; of which $3,973,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for the National Veterinary Stockpile; of which up to $1,500,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for the scrapie program for indemnities; of which $1,500,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for the wildlife damage management program for aviation safety: <italic>Provided</italic>, That of amounts available under this heading for wildlife services methods development, $1,000,000 shall remain available until expended: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of amounts available under this heading for the screwworm program, $4,990,000 shall remain available until expended: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That no funds shall be used to formulate or administer a brucellosis eradication program for the current fiscal year that does not require minimum matching by the States of at least 40 percent: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That this appropriation shall be available for the operation and maintenance of aircraft and the purchase of not to exceed four, of which two shall be for replacement only: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That in addition, in emergencies which threaten any segment of the agricultural production industry of this country, the Secretary may transfer from other appropriations or funds available to the agencies or corporations of the Department such sums as may be deemed necessary, to be available only in such emergencies for the arrest and eradication of contagious or infectious disease or pests of animals, poultry, or plants, and for expenses in accordance with sections 10411 and 10417 of the Animal Health Protection Act (7 U.S.C. 8310 and 8316) and sections 431 and 442 of the Plant Protection Act (7 U.S.C. 7751 and 7772), and any unexpended balances of funds transferred for such emergency purposes in the preceding fiscal year shall be merged with such transferred amounts: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That appropriations hereunder shall be available pursuant to law (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2250">7 U.S.C. 2250</external-xref>) for the repair and alteration of leased buildings and improvements, but unless otherwise provided the cost of altering any one building during the fiscal year shall not exceed 10 percent of the current replacement value of the building.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In fiscal year 2016, the agency is authorized to collect fees to cover the total costs of providing technical assistance, goods, or services requested by States, other political subdivisions, domestic and international organizations, foreign governments, or individuals, provided that such fees are structured such that any entity's liability for such fees is reasonably based on the technical assistance, goods, or services provided to the entity by the agency, and such fees shall be reimbursed to this account, to remain available until expended, without further appropriation, for providing such assistance, goods, or services.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HC5BE237C0B4E4C72A48ACF1C56F1E5CD"><header>Buildings and facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For plans, construction, repair, preventive maintenance, environmental support, improvement, extension, alteration, and purchase of fixed equipment or facilities, as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2250">7 U.S.C. 2250</external-xref>, and acquisition of land as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/428a">7 U.S.C. 428a</external-xref>, $3,175,000, to remain available until expended.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HF5F1AB6520254D05BD929E261741AB87"><header>Agricultural marketing service</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="id44E07D6AE91D4067AE405CBF9E365698"><header>Marketing services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Agricultural Marketing Service, $80,743,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That this appropriation shall be available pursuant to law (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2250">7 U.S.C. 2250</external-xref>) for the alteration and repair of buildings and improvements, but the cost of altering any one building during the fiscal year shall not exceed 10 percent of the current replacement value of the building.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Fees may be collected for the cost of standardization activities, as established by regulation pursuant to law (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/9701">31 U.S.C. 9701</external-xref>).</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H2B0C4F1FA46845809694E20ADA3934A7"><header>Limitation on administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not to exceed $60,982,000 (from fees collected) shall be obligated during the current fiscal year for administrative expenses: <italic>Provided</italic>, That if crop size is understated and/or other uncontrollable events occur, the agency may exceed this limitation by up to 10 percent with notification to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H9422D63601ED4A80ABE9FA4C0D464574"><header>Funds for strengthening markets, income, and supply (section 32)</header> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H74E454E47229400FA27CDA32F812AD43"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds available under section 32 of the Act of August 24, 1935 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/612c">7 U.S.C. 612c</external-xref>), shall be used only for commodity program expenses as authorized therein, and other related operating expenses, except for: (1) transfers to the Department of Commerce as authorized by the Fish and Wildlife Act of August 8, 1956; (2) transfers otherwise provided in this Act; and (3) not more than $20,186,000 for formulation and administration of marketing agreements and orders pursuant to the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937 and the Agricultural Act of 1961.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HAABD2AD35CA0411993259E616DB100C3"><header>Payments to states and possessions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payments to departments of agriculture, bureaus and departments of markets, and similar agencies for marketing activities under section 204(b) of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1623">7 U.S.C. 1623(b)</external-xref>), $1,235,000.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H6C2ABFEDEC144691B9A81959BD67A083"><header>Grain inspection, packers and stockyards administration</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H6C3D712521C647D7A730BB7CF07E8B11"><header>salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration, $43,048,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That this appropriation shall be available pursuant to law (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2250">7 U.S.C. 2250</external-xref>) for the alteration and repair of buildings and improvements, but the cost of altering any one building during the fiscal year shall not exceed 10 percent of the current replacement value of the building.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H990D684EF1D041E0B553FACE02A417FB"><header>Limitation on inspection and weighing services expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not to exceed $55,000,000 (from fees collected) shall be obligated during the current fiscal year for inspection and weighing services: <italic>Provided</italic>, That if grain export activities require additional supervision and oversight, or other uncontrollable factors occur, this limitation may be exceeded by up to 10 percent with notification to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HFEAABE5E76A64E718627148B6DD5E1E2"><header>Office of the under secretary for food safety</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Under Secretary for Food Safety, $811,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H424B3E1AF7D94F558C625F15CE664E6F"><header>Food safety and inspection service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out services authorized by the Federal Meat Inspection Act, the Poultry Products Inspection Act, and the Egg Products Inspection Act, including not to exceed $50,000 for representation allowances and for expenses pursuant to section 8 of the Act approved August 3, 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1766">7 U.S.C. 1766</external-xref>), $1,011,557,000; and in addition, $1,000,000 may be credited to this account from fees collected for the cost of laboratory accreditation as authorized by section 1327 of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation and Trade Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/138f">7 U.S.C. 138f</external-xref>): <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds provided for the Public Health Data Communication Infrastructure system shall remain available until expended: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That no fewer than 148 full-time equivalent positions shall be employed during fiscal year 2016 for purposes dedicated solely to inspections and enforcement related to the Humane Methods of Slaughter Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That this appropriation shall be available pursuant to law (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2250">7 U.S.C. 2250</external-xref>) for the alteration and repair of buildings and improvements, but the cost of altering any one building during the fiscal year shall not exceed 10 percent of the current replacement value of the building.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H36B0998D178A4725A82FC96A56A593BC"><header>Office of the under secretary for farm and foreign agricultural services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Under Secretary for Farm and Foreign Agricultural Services, $893,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HD1C945A612DF461194242D8A9F5584EE"><header>Farm service agency</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H34EB685308A4441A9BAB1ACB38DEBE51"><header>Salaries and expenses</header> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HB739B8E5F3114B599F968A1E80279B22"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Farm Service Agency, $1,183,025,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not more than 50 percent of the $129,546,000 made available under this heading for information technology related to farm program delivery, including the Modernize and Innovate the Delivery of Agricultural Systems and other farm program delivery systems, may be obligated until the Secretary submits to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress a plan for expenditure that (1) identifies for each project/investment over $25,000 (a) the functional and performance capabilities to be delivered and the mission benefits to be realized, (b) the estimated lifecycle cost, including estimates for development as well as maintenance and operations, and (c) key milestones to be met; (2) demonstrates that each project/investment is, (a) consistent with the Farm Service Agency Information Technology Roadmap, (b) being managed in accordance with applicable lifecycle management policies and guidance, and (c) subject to the applicable Department’s capital planning and investment control requirements; and (3) has been reviewed by the Government Accountability Office and approved by the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Secretary is authorized to use the services, facilities, and authorities (but not the funds) of the Commodity Credit Corporation to make program payments for all programs administered by the Agency: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That other funds made available to the Agency for authorized activities may be advanced to and merged with this account: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds made available to county committees shall remain available until expended: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds available to the Farm Service Agency shall be used to close Farm Service Agency county offices: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds available to the Farm Service Agency shall be used to permanently relocate county based employees that would result in an office with two or fewer employees without prior notification and approval of the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HA6E0B7758E054771A7042D539DB58705"><header>State mediation grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants pursuant to section 502(b) of the Agricultural Credit Act of 1987, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5101">7 U.S.C. 5101–5106</external-xref>), $3,404,000.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HB1447BBBDB494B94BA7D8611D019A7EB"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grassroots source water protection program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out wellhead or groundwater protection activities under section 1240O of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3839bb-2">16 U.S.C. 3839bb–2</external-xref>), $5,526,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HB50ACD30EC6241798FA26C65E7D6FC4A"><header>Dairy indemnity program</header> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4A1439F8F88947029F779D4902BF74A3"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses involved in making indemnity payments to dairy farmers and manufacturers of dairy products under a dairy indemnity program, such sums as may be necessary, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such program is carried out by the Secretary in the same manner as the dairy indemnity program described in the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/387">Public Law 106–387</external-xref>, 114 Stat. 1549A–12).</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H6B288BD5F5844E0D957ACBF6EEB81613"><header>Agricultural credit insurance fund program account</header> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HF19E7B2891CE4C4DAB08423655A79717"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For gross obligations for the principal amount of direct and guaranteed farm ownership (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1922">7 U.S.C. 1922 et seq.</external-xref>) and operating (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1941">7 U.S.C. 1941 et seq.</external-xref>) loans, emergency loans (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1961">7 U.S.C. 1961 et seq.</external-xref>), Indian tribe land acquisition loans (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/488">25 U.S.C. 488</external-xref>), boll weevil loans (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1989">7 U.S.C. 1989</external-xref>), guaranteed conservation loans (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1924">7 U.S.C. 1924 et seq.</external-xref>), and Indian highly fractionated land loans (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/488">25 U.S.C. 488</external-xref>) to be available from funds in the Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund, as follows: $2,000,000,000 for guaranteed farm ownership loans and $1,500,000,000 for farm ownership direct loans; $1,393,443,000 for unsubsidized guaranteed operating loans and $1,252,004,000 for direct operating loans; emergency loans, $34,667,000; Indian tribe land acquisition loans, $2,000,000; guaranteed conservation loans, $150,000,000; Indian highly fractionated land loans, $10,000,000; and for boll weevil eradication program loans, $60,000,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Secretary shall deem the pink bollworm to be a boll weevil for the purpose of boll weevil eradication program loans.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of direct and guaranteed loans and grants, including the cost of modifying loans as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as follows: farm operating loans, $53,961,000 for direct operating loans, $14,352,000 for unsubsidized guaranteed operating loans, and emergency loans, $1,262,000, to remain available until expended.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, for administrative expenses necessary to carry out the direct and guaranteed loan programs, $314,918,000, of which $306,998,000 shall be transferred to and merged with the appropriation for <quote>Farm Service Agency, Salaries and Expenses</quote>.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds appropriated by this Act to the Agricultural Credit Insurance Program Account for farm ownership, operating and conservation direct loans and guaranteed loans may be transferred among these programs: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress are notified at least 15 days in advance of any transfer.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H4CE4B5CD4FDD4EA09704364EFF87EC0C"><header>Risk management agency</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H84C65C4401A648C099BBF4583448CF1B"><header>salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Risk Management Agency, $73,984,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not to exceed $1,000 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses, as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1506">7 U.S.C. 1506(i)</external-xref>.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H575A927E874442CCA35CBE0E2842E166"><header>Corporations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following corporations and agencies are hereby authorized to make expenditures, within the limits of funds and borrowing authority available to each such corporation or agency and in accord with law, and to make contracts and commitments without regard to fiscal year limitations as provided by section 104 of the Government Corporation Control Act as may be necessary in carrying out the programs set forth in the budget for the current fiscal year for such corporation or agency, except as hereinafter provided.</text> </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H96D377013B384E1D98E5631A18BEABE9"><header>Federal crop insurance corporation fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payments as authorized by section 516 of the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1516">7 U.S.C. 1516</external-xref>), such sums as may be necessary, to remain available until expended.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H297BFD7BE3A845F18197AB334DE7918A"><header>Commodity credit corporation fund</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H82708CE568D343979DD3BB64EA2B9B4A"><header>Reimbursement for net realized losses</header> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HFFA3F05739D7495CB77EF153E8FD892C"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the current fiscal year, such sums as may be necessary to reimburse the Commodity Credit Corporation for net realized losses sustained, but not previously reimbursed, pursuant to section 2 of the Act of August 17, 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/713a-11">15 U.S.C. 713a–11</external-xref>): <italic>Provided</italic>, That of the funds available to the Commodity Credit Corporation under section 11 of the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/714i">15 U.S.C. 714i</external-xref>) for the conduct of its business with the Foreign Agricultural Service, up to $5,000,000 may be transferred to and used by the Foreign Agricultural Service for information resource management activities of the Foreign Agricultural Service that are not related to Commodity Credit Corporation business.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H5FBEF0ADBC2F41ADA8F9C2117D64F36B"><header>Hazardous waste management</header> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HB2C0697355344AE78D77A6B9EC3895D7"><header>(limitation on expenses)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the current fiscal year, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall not expend more than $5,000,000 for site investigation and cleanup expenses, and operations and maintenance expenses to comply with the requirement of section 107(g) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9607">42 U.S.C. 9607(g)</external-xref>), and section 6001 of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6961">42 U.S.C. 6961</external-xref>).</text> </appropriations-small></title> <title id="IDABAE494141A24E16A919943B7F21F96A"><enum>II</enum> <appropriations-major id="H2F738698BAA3461A99FAEDB0010A68B8"><header>Conservation programs</header> </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="IDF1FC8500CCA44AF2982B212A9B18C51E"><header>Office of the under secretary for natural resources and environment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Under Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment, $893,000.</text> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H3C373F00254E4805894795FAA8B24155"><header>Natural resources conservation service</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="idF880667FC219442B926F80363E951066"><header>Conservation operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for carrying out the provisions of the Act of April 27, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 590a–f), including preparation of conservation plans and establishment of measures to conserve soil and water (including farm irrigation and land drainage and such special measures for soil and water management as may be necessary to prevent floods and the siltation of reservoirs and to control agricultural related pollutants); operation of conservation plant materials centers; classification and mapping of soil; dissemination of information; acquisition of lands, water, and interests therein for use in the plant materials program by donation, exchange, or purchase at a nominal cost not to exceed $100 pursuant to the Act of August 3, 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/428a">7 U.S.C. 428a</external-xref>); purchase and erection or alteration or improvement of permanent and temporary buildings; and operation and maintenance of aircraft, $832,928,000, to remain available until September 30, 2017: <italic>Provided</italic>, That appropriations hereunder shall be available pursuant to 7 U.S.C. 2250 for construction and improvement of buildings and public improvements at plant materials centers, except that the cost of alterations and improvements to other buildings and other public improvements shall not exceed $250,000: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That when buildings or other structures are erected on non-Federal land, that the right to use such land is obtained as provided in 7 U.S.C. 2250a.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HC7F76C55F130407790B9B358670854D7"><header>Watershed rehabilitation program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under the authorities of section 14 of the Watershed Protection and Flood Prevention Act, $6,000,000 is provided.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title style="appropriations" commented="no" id="HB6ADFC97CFBC4DD99A927B89A7F52299" level-type="subsequent"><enum>III</enum><appropriations-major commented="no" id="H2E8E73E0A05B4A7EA10ECDA78F9F7CEE"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural development programs</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H9B8E53B97E4145C28E056BDD91D5350C"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the under secretary for rural development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Under Secretary for Rural Development, $893,000.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H3F7BAB17B5A94462A24EFF85D829A08A"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural development salaries and expenses</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H1387D6C764AD4CF996DFDB99F95156C1"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for carrying out the administration and implementation of programs in the Rural Development mission area, including activities with institutions concerning the development and operation of agricultural cooperatives; and for cooperative agreements; $222,705,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That no less than $19,500,000 shall be for the Comprehensive Loan Accounting System: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds appropriated under this heading may be used for advertising and promotional activities that support the Rural Development mission area: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That any balances available from prior years for the Rural Utilities Service, Rural Housing Service, and the Rural Business–Cooperative Service salaries and expenses accounts shall be transferred to and merged with this appropriation.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H7FC57F1253864814B58E7C53A800792D"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural housing service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H02E6138564574BD4A8455C44191EA755"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural housing insurance fund program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H580EF7383DB34BEE8C60A609BE6AB385"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For gross obligations for the principal amount of direct and guaranteed loans as authorized by title V of the Housing Act of 1949, to be available from funds in the rural housing insurance fund, as follows: $900,000,000 shall be for direct loans and $24,000,000,000 shall be for unsubsidized guaranteed loans; $26,278,000 for section 504 housing repair loans; $28,398,000 for section 515 rental housing; $150,000,000 for section 538 guaranteed multi-family housing loans; $10,000,000 for credit sales of single family housing acquired property; $5,000,000 for section 523 self-help housing land development loans; and $5,000,000 for section 524 site development loans.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of direct and guaranteed loans, including the cost of modifying loans, as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as follows: section 502 loans, $60,750,000 shall be for direct loans; section 504 housing repair loans, $3,424,000; and repair, rehabilitation, and new construction of section 515 rental housing, $8,414,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That to support the loan program level for section 538 guaranteed loans made available under this heading the Secretary may charge or adjust any fees to cover the projected cost of such loan guarantees pursuant to the provisions of the Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661">2 U.S.C. 661 et seq.</external-xref>), and the interest on such loans may not be subsidized: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That applicants in communities that have a current rural area waiver under section 541 of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1490q">42 U.S.C. 1490q</external-xref>) shall be treated as living in a rural area for purposes of section 502 guaranteed loans provided under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amounts available under this paragraph for section 502 direct loans, no less than $5,000,000 shall be available for direct loans for individuals whose homes will be built pursuant to a program funded with a mutual and self-help housing grant authorized by section 523 of the Housing Act of 1949 until June 1, 2016.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, for the cost of direct loans, grants, and contracts, as authorized by 42 U.S.C. 1484 and 1486, $15,125,000, to remain available until expended, for direct farm labor housing loans and domestic farm labor housing grants and contracts: <italic>Provided</italic>, That any balances available for the Farm Labor Program Account shall be transferred to and merged with this account.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, for administrative expenses necessary to carry out the direct and guaranteed loan programs, $417,854,000 shall be transferred to and merged with the appropriation for <quote>Rural Development, Salaries and Expenses</quote>.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H2407EB8CF1B7429CB72AE37DCCB8286A"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rental assistance program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For rental assistance agreements entered into or renewed pursuant to the authority under section 521(a)(2) or agreements entered into in lieu of debt forgiveness or payments for eligible households as authorized by section 502(c)(5)(D) of the Housing Act of 1949, $1,167,000,000; and, in addition, such sums as may be necessary, as authorized by section 521(c) of the Act, to liquidate debt incurred prior to fiscal year 1992 to carry out the rental assistance program under section 521(a)(2) of the Act: <italic>Provided</italic>, That rental assistance agreements entered into or renewed during the current fiscal year shall be funded for a one-year period: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That rental assistance contracts will not be renewed within the 12-month contract period: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That any unexpended balances remaining at the end of such 1-year agreements may be transferred and used for the purposes of any debt reduction; maintenance, repair, or rehabilitation of any existing projects; preservation; and rental assistance activities authorized under title V of the Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That rental assistance provided under agreements entered into prior to fiscal year 2016 for a farm labor multi-family housing project financed under section 514 or 516 of the Act may not be recaptured for use in another project until such assistance has remained unused for a period of 12 consecutive months, if such project has a waiting list of tenants seeking such assistance or the project has rental assistance eligible tenants who are not receiving such assistance: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such recaptured rental assistance shall, to the extent practicable, be applied to another farm labor multi-family housing project financed under section 514 or 516 of the Act.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H45CF90DDF9BE4092AE24FDF55B51BA38"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Multi-family housing revitalization program account</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the rural housing voucher program as authorized under section 542 of the Housing Act of 1949, but notwithstanding subsection (b) of such section, and for additional costs to conduct a demonstration program for the preservation and revitalization of multi-family rental housing properties described in this paragraph, $24,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That of the funds made available under this heading, $7,000,000, shall be available for rural housing vouchers to any low-income household (including those not receiving rental assistance) residing in a property financed with a section 515 loan which has been prepaid after September 30, 2005: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the amount of such voucher shall be the difference between comparable market rent for the section 515 unit and the tenant paid rent for such unit: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds made available for such vouchers shall be subject to the availability of annual appropriations: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, administer such vouchers with current regulations and administrative guidance applicable to section 8 housing vouchers administered by the Secretary of the Department of Housing and Urban Development: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That if the Secretary determines that the amount made available for vouchers in this or any other Act is not needed for vouchers, the Secretary may use such funds for the demonstration program for the preservation and revitalization of multi-family rental housing properties described in this paragraph: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the funds made available under this heading, $17,000,000 shall be available for a demonstration program for the preservation and revitalization of the sections 514, 515, and 516 multi-family rental housing properties to restructure existing USDA multi-family housing loans, as the Secretary deems appropriate, expressly for the purposes of ensuring the project has sufficient resources to preserve the project for the purpose of providing safe and affordable housing for low-income residents and farm laborers including reducing or eliminating interest; deferring loan payments, subordinating, reducing or reamortizing loan debt; and other financial assistance including advances, payments and incentives (including the ability of owners to obtain reasonable returns on investment) required by the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Secretary shall as part of the preservation and revitalization agreement obtain a restrictive use agreement consistent with the terms of the restructuring: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That if the Secretary determines that additional funds for vouchers described in this paragraph are needed, funds for the preservation and revitalization demonstration program may be used for such vouchers: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That if Congress enacts legislation to permanently authorize a multi-family rental housing loan restructuring program similar to the demonstration program described herein, the Secretary may use funds made available for the demonstration program under this heading to carry out such legislation with the prior approval of the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That in addition to any other available funds, the Secretary may expend not more than $1,000,000 total, from the program funds made available under this heading, for administrative expenses for activities funded under this heading.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H68C3A02CA1BA4EEE8FB0D63FDA74B9FE"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mutual and self-help housing grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants and contracts pursuant to section 523(b)(1)(A) of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1490c">42 U.S.C. 1490c</external-xref>), $27,500,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H59C43E84625D4F44A718CEC8B154D4E0"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural housing assistance grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants for very low-income housing repair and rural housing preservation made by the Rural Housing Service, as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1474">42 U.S.C. 1474</external-xref>, and 1490m, $32,239,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H8E9C4C95487746E6B52942EEAF67244F"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural community facilities program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H47D0D6BD2F5C4E1D8EAD4926DFC5F4F8"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For gross obligations for the principal amount of direct and guaranteed loans as authorized by section 306 and described in section 381E(d)(1) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, $2,200,000,000 for direct loans and $148,305,085 for guaranteed loans.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of guaranteed loans, including the cost of modifying loans, as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, $3,500,000, to remain available until expended.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of grants for rural community facilities programs as authorized by section 306 and described in section 381E(d)(1) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, $26,778,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That $4,000,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be available for a Rural Community Development Initiative: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such funds shall be used solely to develop the capacity and ability of private, nonprofit community-based housing and community development organizations, low-income rural communities, and Federally Recognized Native American Tribes to undertake projects to improve housing, community facilities, community and economic development projects in rural areas: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such funds shall be made available to qualified private, nonprofit and public intermediary organizations proposing to carry out a program of financial and technical assistance: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such intermediary organizations shall provide matching funds from other sources, including Federal funds for related activities, in an amount not less than funds provided: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That $5,778,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be to provide grants for facilities in rural communities with extreme unemployment and severe economic depression (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/387">Public Law 106–387</external-xref>), with up to 5 percent for administration and capacity building in the State rural development offices: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That $4,000,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be available for community facilities grants to tribal colleges, as authorized by section 306(a)(19) of such Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That sections 381E–H and 381N of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act are not applicable to the funds made available under this heading.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H4D9CD3C5EE724929B0775060B0E67535"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural business—Cooperative service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H3FDDAAB4C85D4206B88D104E59648F18"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural business program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H5DD648B605BA487B852AC7544EA6C356"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of loan guarantees and grants, for the rural business development programs authorized by section 310B and described in subsections (a), (c), (f) and (g) of section 310B of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, $59,686,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That of the amount appropriated under this heading, not to exceed $500,000 shall be made available for one grant to a qualified national organization to provide technical assistance for rural transportation in order to promote economic development: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That $4,000,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be for business grants to benefit Federally Recognized Native American Tribes, including $250,000 for a grant to a qualified national organization to provide technical assistance for rural transportation in order to promote economic development: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That for purposes of determining eligibility or level of program assistance the Secretary shall not include incarcerated prison populations: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That sections 381E–H and 381N of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act are not applicable to funds made available under this heading.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H5F884C54AD8149B6B7C5F5C03021B082"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Intermediary relending program fund account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H3CE26543176446ED9DCE780B07CCB582"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the principal amount of direct loans, as authorized by the Intermediary Relending Program Fund Account (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1936b">7 U.S.C. 1936b</external-xref>), $18,889,000.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of direct loans, $5,217,000, as authorized by the Intermediary Relending Program Fund Account (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1936b">7 U.S.C. 1936b</external-xref>), of which $531,000 shall be available through June 30, 2016, for Federally Recognized Native American Tribes; and of which $1,021,000 shall be available through June 30, 2016, for Mississippi Delta Region counties (as determined in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/460">Public Law 100–460</external-xref>): <italic>Provided</italic>, That such costs, including the cost of modifying such loans, shall be as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, for administrative expenses to carry out the direct loan programs, $4,410,000 shall be transferred to and merged with the appropriation for <quote>Rural Development, Salaries and Expenses</quote>.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H6927F01435E945C1B4E8D46CCA09E592"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural economic development loans program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H991038CE1F6248759B9C016BC63135FC"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including rescission of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the principal amount of direct loans, as authorized under section 313 of the Rural Electrification Act, for the purpose of promoting rural economic development and job creation projects, $33,077,000.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the funds derived from interest on the cushion of credit payments, as authorized by section 313 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, $154,000,000 shall not be obligated and $154,000,000 are rescinded.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H8343F91F0D5445D6A29AEB54B535E5D9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural cooperative development grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For rural cooperative development grants authorized under section 310B(e) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1932">7 U.S.C. 1932</external-xref>), $21,300,000, of which $2,500,000 shall be for cooperative agreements for the appropriate technology transfer for rural areas program: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not to exceed $3,000,000 shall be for grants for cooperative development centers, individual cooperatives, or groups of cooperatives that serve socially disadvantaged groups and a majority of the boards of directors or governing boards of which are comprised of individuals who are members of socially disadvantaged groups; and of which $10,000,000, to remain available until expended, shall be for value-added agricultural product market development grants, as authorized by section 231 of the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1632a">7 U.S.C. 1632a</external-xref>).</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H4E79F46A356348FDA2EBAA9B6F44C7ED"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural energy for america program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of a program of loan guarantees, under the same terms and conditions as authorized by section 9007 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8107">7 U.S.C. 8107</external-xref>), $842,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the cost of loan guarantees, including the cost of modifying such loans, shall be as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H67DA9E0A663643DA9A151177CC7DE7B6"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural utilities service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H0DDF3D0F71994012810D820F9DB2A9F9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural water and waste disposal program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HB188D5EDC7E5420CB4EA5CCCD601C420"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of direct loans, loan guarantees, and grants for the rural water, waste water, waste disposal, and solid waste management programs authorized by sections 306, 306A, 306C, 306D, 306E, and 310B and described in sections 306C(a)(2), 306D, 306E, and 381E(d)(2) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, $473,897,000, to remain available until expended, of which not to exceed $1,000,000 shall be available for the rural utilities program described in section 306(a)(2)(B) of such Act, and of which not to exceed $993,000 shall be available for the rural utilities program described in section 306E of such Act: <italic>Provided,</italic> That not to exceed $10,000,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be for grants authorized by section 306A(i)(2) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act in addition to funding authorized by section 306A(i)(1) of such Act: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That not to exceed $54,240,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be for loans and grants including water and waste disposal systems grants authorized by section 306C(a)(2)(B) and section 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, Federally Recognized Native American Tribes authorized by 306C(a)(1) of such Act, and the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands (of the State of Hawaii): <italic>Provided further,</italic> That funding provided for section 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act may be provided to a consortium formed pursuant to section 325 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/83">Public Law 105–83</external-xref>: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That not more than 2 percent of the funding provided for section 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act may be used by the State of Alaska for training and technical assistance programs and not more than 2 percent of the funding provided for section 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act may be used by a consortium formed pursuant to section 325 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/83">Public Law 105–83</external-xref> for training and technical assistance programs: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That not to exceed $19,000,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be for technical assistance grants for rural water and waste systems pursuant to section 306(a)(14) of such Act, unless the Secretary makes a determination of extreme need, of which $6,000,000 shall be made available for a grant to a qualified nonprofit multi-State regional technical assistance organization, with experience in working with small communities on water and waste water problems, the principal purpose of such grant shall be to assist rural communities with populations of 3,300 or less, in improving the planning, financing, development, operation, and management of water and waste water systems, and of which not less than $800,000 shall be for a qualified national Native American organization to provide technical assistance for rural water systems for tribal communities: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That not to exceed $15,919,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be for contracting with qualified national organizations for a circuit rider program to provide technical assistance for rural water systems: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That not to exceed $4,000,000 shall be for solid waste management grants: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That any prior year balances for high-energy cost grants authorized by section 19 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/918a">7 U.S.C. 918a</external-xref>) shall be transferred to and merged with the Rural Utilities Service, High Energy Cost Grants Account: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That sections 381E–H and 381N of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act are not applicable to the funds made available under this heading.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HD8013962648D4751B875B136B0E5E4C7"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural electrification and telecommunications loans program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H0256A8E3CC37444DBD8878E5F91434B7"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The principal amount of direct and guaranteed loans as authorized by sections 305 and 306 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (7 U.S.C. 935 and 936) shall be made as follows: loans made pursuant to section 306 of that Act, rural electric, $5,000,000,000; guaranteed underwriting loans pursuant to section 313A, $500,000,000; 5 percent rural telecommunications loans, cost of money rural telecommunications loans, and for loans made pursuant to section 306 of that Act, rural telecommunications loans, $690,000,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That up to $2,000,000,000 shall be used for the construction, acquisition, or improvement of fossil-fueled electric generating plants (whether new or existing) that utilize carbon sequestration systems.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of direct loans as authorized by section 305 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/935">7 U.S.C. 935</external-xref>), including the cost of modifying loans, as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, cost of money rural telecommunications loans, $207,000. </text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, for administrative expenses necessary to carry out the direct and guaranteed loan programs, $34,247,000, which shall be transferred to and merged with the appropriation for <quote>Rural Development, Salaries and Expenses</quote>.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H8BEE429F146E465FBF88E6EDC8E1BF15"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Distance learning, telemedicine, and broadband program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the principal amount of broadband telecommunication loans, $24,077,000.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants for telemedicine and distance learning services in rural areas, as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/950aaa">7 U.S.C. 950aaa et seq.</external-xref>, $20,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the cost of broadband loans, as authorized by section 601 of the Rural Electrification Act, $5,265,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the cost of direct loans shall be as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, $10,372,000, to remain available until expended, for a grant program to finance broadband transmission in rural areas eligible for Distance Learning and Telemedicine Program benefits authorized by 7 U.S.C. 950aaa.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title style="appropriations" id="H57825B03FDEE45B480DB8B45C7B90ECE"><enum>IV</enum><appropriations-major id="H4C0040A8E9984FC19D829F2E3BDB0081"><header>Domestic Food Programs</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H50015D439D3E4117880D69FB4C35A647"><header>Office of the under secretary for food, nutrition, and consumer services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services, $811,000.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H7E874E36245B4CB6819345566BA93183"><header>Food and Nutrition Service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H9E21EE42589D494BBCF3A7DDF676C69C"><header>Child nutrition programs</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H896DC12F3D0B4FE4BD2058964AEEB7ED"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>), except section 21, and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1771">42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.</external-xref>), except sections 17 and 21; $21,507,426,000 to remain available through September 30, 2017, of which such sums as are made available under section 14222(b)(1) of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/246">Public Law 110–246</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, shall be merged with and available for the same time period and purposes as provided herein: <italic>Provided</italic>, That of the total amount available, $17,004,000 shall be available to carry out section 19 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1771">42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the total amount available, $20,000,000 shall be available to provide competitive grants to State agencies for subgrants to local educational agencies and schools to purchase the equipment needed to serve healthier meals, improve food safety, and to help support the establishment, maintenance, or expansion of the school breakfast program: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the total amount available, $12,000,000 shall remain available until expended to carry out section 749(g) of the Agriculture Appropriations Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/80">Public Law 111–80</external-xref>).</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HE0840BF18E66464C9984BFF98CE73DE9"><header>Special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (wic)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out the special supplemental nutrition program as authorized by section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>), $6,484,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2017: <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding section 17(h)(10) of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786(h)(10)</external-xref>), not less than $60,000,000 shall be used for breastfeeding peer counselors and other related activities, $14,000,000 shall be used for infrastructure, $55,000,000 shall be used for management information systems, including WIC electronic benefit transfer systems and activities: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds provided in this account shall be available for the purchase of infant formula except in accordance with the cost containment and competitive bidding requirements specified in section 17 of such Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds provided shall be available for activities that are not fully reimbursed by other Federal Government departments or agencies unless authorized by section 17 of such Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That upon termination of a federally mandated vendor moratorium and subject to terms and conditions established by the Secretary, the Secretary may waive the requirement at 7 CFR 246.12(g)(6) at the request of a State agency.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HA01E61BB7600430BB21CECF419F146C7"><header>Supplemental nutrition assistance program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), $81,653,207,000, of which $3,000,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2017, shall be placed in reserve for use only in such amounts and at such times as may become necessary to carry out program operations: <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds provided herein shall be expended in accordance with section 16 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the funds made available under this heading, $998,000 may be used to provide nutrition education services to State agencies and Federally Recognized Tribes participating in the Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That this appropriation shall be subject to any work registration or workfare requirements as may be required by law: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds made available for Employment and Training under this heading shall remain available through September 30, 2017: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds made available under this heading for section 28(d)(1) and section 27(a) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 shall remain available through September 30, 2017: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, subject to section 735 of this Act, funds made available under this heading may be used to enter into contracts and employ staff to conduct studies, evaluations, or to conduct activities related to program integrity provided that such activities are authorized by the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H9900F5E3BB38466BB91BAB037CAFB247"><header>Commodity assistance program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out disaster assistance and the Commodity Supplemental Food Program as authorized by section 4(a) of the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/612c">7 U.S.C. 612c</external-xref> note); the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983; special assistance for the nuclear affected islands, as authorized by section 103(f)(2) of the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/188">Public Law 108–188</external-xref>); and the Farmers' Market Nutrition Program, as authorized by section 17(m) of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966, $288,317,000, to remain available through September 30, 2017:<italic> Provided</italic>, That none of these funds shall be available to reimburse the Commodity Credit Corporation for commodities donated to the program: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, effective with funds made available in fiscal year 2016 to support the Seniors Farmers' Market Nutrition Program, as authorized by section 4402 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002, such funds shall remain available through September 30, 2017: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the funds made available under section 27(a) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2036">7 U.S.C. 2036(a)</external-xref>), the Secretary may use up to 10 percent for costs associated with the distribution of commodities.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HD973BC2FD9A74C03BA05615BBA1487C6"><header>Nutrition programs administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary administrative expenses of the Food and Nutrition Service for carrying out any domestic nutrition assistance program, $141,348,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That of the funds provided herein, $2,000,000 shall be used for the purposes of section 4404 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/171">Public Law 107–171</external-xref>, as amended by section 4401 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/246">Public Law 110–246</external-xref>.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title style="appropriations" id="HB16C09C65DC14099AA51DFB25D391A5E"><enum>V</enum><appropriations-major id="H4341DBF4DE004211BBDD64E8B8A63319"><header>Foreign assistance and related programs</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H11B82D2BA1854D248163FC05194125B8"><header>Foreign Agricultural Service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H9A4DEF8B7B0D43B1B1CC610681BD2254"><header>salaries and expenses</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HD701C96B88BF48178BE5A5A605CBD3A2"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Foreign Agricultural Service, including not to exceed $250,000 for representation allowances and for expenses pursuant to section 8 of the Act approved August 3, 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1766">7 U.S.C. 1766</external-xref>), $184,423,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Service may utilize advances of funds, or reimburse this appropriation for expenditures made on behalf of Federal agencies, public and private organizations and institutions under agreements executed pursuant to the agricultural food production assistance programs (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1737">7 U.S.C. 1737</external-xref>) and the foreign assistance programs of the United States Agency for International Development: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds made available for middle-income country training programs, funds made available for the Borlaug International Agricultural Science and Technology Fellowship program, and up to $2,000,000 of the Foreign Agricultural Service appropriation solely for the purpose of offsetting fluctuations in international currency exchange rates, subject to documentation by the Foreign Agricultural Service, shall remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H655EFBCEBD484FD18043C00BBA827480"><header>Food for peace title i direct credit and food for progress program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H990B570F73BA4719A0C732DEB0640136"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For administrative expenses to carry out the credit program of title I, Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/83/480">Public Law 83–480</external-xref>) and the Food for Progress Act of 1985, $2,528,000, shall be transferred to and merged with the appropriation for <quote>Farm Service Agency, Salaries and Expenses</quote>.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H59475D962C1442198935946551A6C069"><header>food for peace title ii grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses during the current fiscal year, not otherwise recoverable, and unrecovered prior years' costs, including interest thereon, under the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/83/480">Public Law 83–480</external-xref>), for commodities supplied in connection with dispositions abroad under title II of said Act, $1,417,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HF942AFC7C71E467E92CDFCCD93161A57"><header>mcgovern-dole international food for education and child nutrition program grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out the provisions of section 3107 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1736o-1">7 U.S.C. 1736o–1</external-xref>), $191,626,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Commodity Credit Corporation is authorized to provide the services, facilities, and authorities for the purpose of implementing such section, subject to reimbursement from amounts provided herein.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H2295615E2AE44442B2BF68084DE1925E"><header>Commodity credit corporation export (loans) credit guarantee program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H9BAC2F5C0F83473899FAD279982F787B"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For administrative expenses to carry out the Commodity Credit Corporation's Export Guarantee Program, GSM 102 and GSM 103, $6,748,000; to cover common overhead expenses as permitted by section 11 of the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act and in conformity with the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990, of which $6,394,000 shall be transferred to and merged with the appropriation for <quote>Foreign Agricultural Service, Salaries and Expenses</quote>, and of which $354,000 shall be transferred to and merged with the appropriation for <quote>Farm Service Agency, Salaries and Expenses</quote>.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title style="appropriations" id="H8AE967FA6BA64FF49648C2733DAAABE0"><enum>VI</enum><appropriations-major id="H88689FC365B542909B2EC0AAFE640814"><header>Related agencies and food and drug administration</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HBAF995B900964F6B8C4148ACFF77C0BD"><header>Department of health and human services</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H51691237C62A409FBF2A9B8F2F4F54D3"><header>Food and drug administration</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HA9B755082EB34414802AD9D3F8E4C28C"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Food and Drug Administration, including hire and purchase of passenger motor vehicles; for payment of space rental and related costs pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/92/313">Public Law 92–313</external-xref> for programs and activities of the Food and Drug Administration which are included in this Act; for rental of special purpose space in the District of Columbia or elsewhere; for miscellaneous and emergency expenses of enforcement activities, authorized and approved by the Secretary and to be accounted for solely on the Secretary's certificate, not to exceed $25,000; and notwithstanding section 521 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/188">Public Law 107–188</external-xref>; $4,549,219,000: <italic>Provided,</italic> That of the amount provided under this heading, $826,072,000 shall be derived from prescription drug user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379h">21 U.S.C. 379h</external-xref>, and shall be credited to this account and remain available until expended; $134,475,000 shall be derived from medical device user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j">21 U.S.C. 379j</external-xref>, and shall be credited to this account and remain available until expended; $320,029,000 shall be derived from human generic drug user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-42">21 U.S.C. 379j–42</external-xref>, and shall be credited to this account and remain available until expended; $21,540,000 shall be derived from biosimilar biological product user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-52">21 U.S.C. 379j–52</external-xref>, and shall be credited to this account and remain available until expended; $22,140,000 shall be derived from animal drug user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-12">21 U.S.C. 379j–12</external-xref>, and shall be credited to this account and remain available until expended; $7,429,000 shall be derived from animal generic drug user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-21">21 U.S.C. 379j–21</external-xref>, and shall be credited to this account and remain available until expended; $599,000,000 shall be derived from tobacco product user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/387s">21 U.S.C. 387s</external-xref>, and shall be credited to this account and remain available until expended: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That in addition and notwithstanding any other provision under this heading, amounts collected for prescription drug user fees, medical device user fees, human generic drug user fees, biosimilar biological product user fees, animal drug user fees, and animal generic drug user fees that exceed the respective fiscal year 2016 limitations are appropriated and shall be credited to this account and remain available until expended: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That fees derived from prescription drug, medical device, human generic drug, biosimilar biological product, animal drug, and animal generic drug assessments for fiscal year 2016, including any such fees collected prior to fiscal year 2016 but credited for fiscal year 2016, shall be subject to the fiscal year 2016 limitations: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That the Secretary may accept payment during fiscal year 2016 of user fees specified under this heading and authorized for fiscal year 2017, prior to the due date for such fees, and that amounts of such fees assessed for fiscal year 2017 for which the Secretary accepts payment in fiscal year 2016 shall not be included in amounts under this heading: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That none of these funds shall be used to develop, establish, or operate any program of user fees authorized by 31 U.S.C. 9701: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That of the total amount appropriated: (1) $938,403,000 shall be for the Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition and related field activities in the Office of Regulatory Affairs; (2) $1,365,691,000 shall be for the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research and related field activities in the Office of Regulatory Affairs; (3) $345,190,000 shall be for the Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research and for related field activities in the Office of Regulatory Affairs; (4) $177,615,000 shall be for the Center for Veterinary Medicine and for related field activities in the Office of Regulatory Affairs; (5) $424,135,000 shall be for the Center for Devices and Radiological Health and for related field activities in the Office of Regulatory Affairs; (6) $59,171,000 shall be for the National Center for Toxicological Research; (7) $564,117,000 shall be for the Center for Tobacco Products and for related field activities in the Office of Regulatory Affairs; (8) not to exceed $164,762,000 shall be for Rent and Related activities, of which $47,218,000 is for White Oak Consolidation, other than the amounts paid to the General Services Administration for rent; (9) not to exceed $229,432,000 shall be for payments to the General Services Administration for rent; and (10) $280,703,000 shall be for other activities, including the Office of the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, the Office of Foods and Veterinary Medicine, the Office of Medical and Tobacco Products, the Office of Global and Regulatory Policy, the Office of Operations, the Office of the Chief Scientist, and central services for these offices: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That not to exceed $25,000 of this amount shall be for official reception and representation expenses, not otherwise provided for, as determined by the Commissioner: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That any transfer of funds pursuant to section 770(n) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379dd">21 U.S.C. 379dd(n)</external-xref>) shall only be from amounts made available under this heading for other activities: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That funds may be transferred from one specified activity to another with the prior approval of the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, mammography user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/263b">42 U.S.C. 263b</external-xref>, export certification user fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/381">21 U.S.C. 381</external-xref>, priority review user fees authorized by 21 U.S.C. 360n and 360ff, food and feed recall fees, food reinspection fees, and voluntary qualified importer program fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-31">21 U.S.C. 379j–31</external-xref>, outsourcing facility fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-62">21 U.S.C. 379j–62</external-xref>, prescription drug wholesale distributor licensing and inspection fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353">21 U.S.C. 353(e)(3)</external-xref>, and third-party logistics provider licensing and inspection fees authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360eee-3">21 U.S.C. 360eee–3(c)(1)</external-xref>, shall be credited to this account, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HEB4BE594E2EE47B3AE8597E2EE12E006"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Buildings and facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For plans, construction, repair, improvement, extension, alteration, and purchase of fixed equipment or facilities of or used by the Food and Drug Administration, where not otherwise provided, $8,788,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major commented="no" id="HE57258F2841F490F87CC0517DB3FA1B5"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Independent agencies</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HED08B4962140442D8753B9C64D1D176F" commented="no"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commodity futures trading commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses to carry out the provisions of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1">7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>), including the purchase and hire of passenger motor vehicles, and the rental of space (to include multiple year leases), in the District of Columbia and elsewhere, and overhead expenses for the Office of the Inspector General such as training, lease of space, utilities, communications, printing, supplies, equipment, and other services, $250,000,000, including not to exceed $3,000 for official reception and representation expenses, and not to exceed $25,000 for the expenses for consultations and meetings hosted by the Commission with foreign governmental and other regulatory officials, of which not less than $50,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2017, shall be for the purchase of information technology and of which not less than $3,000,000 shall be for expenses of the Office of the Inspector General, not to include overhead expenses such as training, lease of space, utilities, communications, printing, supplies, equipment, and other services: <italic>Provided,</italic> That the Commission shall apply the entire Second Refurbishment Credit in the current fiscal year under Section 23 of the Fifth Amendment to the Lease Agreement entered into with Lafayette Centre Property LLC on August 14, 2009: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That as the entire Second Refurbishment Credit is applied to monthly payments of the Commission in the current fiscal year under such Agreement, the sum herein appropriated for the current fiscal year shall be reduced on a dollar-for-dollar basis by not more than $5,000,000, so as to result in a final fiscal year 2016 appropriation from the general fund of $245,000,000.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H1B09CF98794B471BA93EB5F0A474C3EB"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Farm credit administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HDBDF373B6FD54B138333AF603D495BBE"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation on administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not to exceed $65,600,000 (from assessments collected from farm credit institutions, including the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation) shall be obligated during the current fiscal year for administrative expenses as authorized under 12 U.S.C. 2249: <italic>Provided</italic>, That this limitation shall not apply to expenses associated with receiverships: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the agency may exceed this limitation by up to 10 percent with notification to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title style="appropriations" commented="no" id="HFF7C54105E8243459F5D21A735BACADC" level-type="subsequent"><enum>VII</enum><appropriations-major commented="no" id="H41454415A8AC4CF2AE56924E0E958841"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">General provisions</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H3128985FE2524770B45E7D2E1E4AE4B9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including rescissions and transfers of funds) </header></appropriations-small> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E11DB0C7CC64B3FB4B17C8088D451DF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>701.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within the unit limit of cost fixed by law, appropriations and authorizations made for the Department of Agriculture for the current fiscal year under this Act shall be available for the purchase, in addition to those specifically provided for, of not to exceed 71 passenger motor vehicles of which 68 shall be for replacement only, and for the hire of such vehicles: <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding this section, the only purchase of new passenger vehicles shall be for those determined by the Secretary to be necessary for transportation safety, to reduce operational costs, and for the protection of life, property, and public safety.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C5A67B6611A4B54AA9B3CA03DF16C5C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>702.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture may transfer unobligated balances of discretionary funds appropriated by this Act or any other available unobligated discretionary balances that are remaining available of the Department of Agriculture to the Working Capital Fund for the acquisition of plant and capital equipment necessary for the delivery of financial, administrative, and information technology services of primary benefit to the agencies of the Department of Agriculture, such transferred funds to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That none of the funds made available by this Act or any other Act shall be transferred to the Working Capital Fund without the prior approval of the agency administrator: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds transferred to the Working Capital Fund pursuant to this section shall be available for obligation without the written notification and prior approval of the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds appropriated by this Act or made available to the Department's Working Capital Fund shall be available for obligation or expenditure to make any changes to the Department's National Finance Center without written notification to and prior approval of the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress as required by section 717 of this Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of annual income amounts in the Working Capital Fund of the Department of Agriculture allocated for the National Finance Center, the Secretary may reserve not more than 4 percent for the replacement or acquisition of capital equipment, including equipment for the improvement and implementation of a financial management plan, information technology, and other systems of the National Finance Center or to pay any unforeseen, extraordinary cost of the National Finance Center: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the amounts reserved shall be available for obligation unless the Secretary submits written notification of the obligation to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the limitation on the obligation of funds pending notification to Congressional Committees shall not apply to any obligation that, as determined by the Secretary, is necessary to respond to a declared state of emergency that significantly impacts the operations of the National Finance Center; or to evacuate employees of the National Finance Center to a safe haven to continue operations of the National Finance Center.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49861E3AF4FE4152B7141FB7E76B7D3C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>703.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of any appropriation contained in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H201A6729510B48A6A118DFE6FE9AFF52" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>704.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds appropriated by this Act may be used to pay negotiated indirect cost rates on cooperative agreements or similar arrangements between the United States Department of Agriculture and nonprofit institutions in excess of 10 percent of the total direct cost of the agreement when the purpose of such cooperative arrangements is to carry out programs of mutual interest between the two parties. This does not preclude appropriate payment of indirect costs on grants and contracts with such institutions when such indirect costs are computed on a similar basis for all agencies for which appropriations are provided in this Act.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8A1EFEE581C4FF38B4C8B364783D6E2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>705.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations to the Department of Agriculture for the cost of direct and guaranteed loans made available in the current fiscal year shall remain available until expended to disburse obligations made in the current fiscal year for the following accounts: the Rural Development Loan Fund program account, the Rural Electrification and Telecommunication Loans program account, and the Rural Housing Insurance Fund program account.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBE37DB730C3433998975ECFC1434740" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>706.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available to the Department of Agriculture by this Act may be used to acquire new information technology systems or significant upgrades, as determined by the Office of the Chief Information Officer, without the approval of the Chief Information Officer and the concurrence of the Executive Information Technology Investment Review Board: <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be transferred to the Office of the Chief Information Officer without written notification to and the prior approval of the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, notwithstanding section 11319 of title 40, United States Code, none of the funds available to the Department of Agriculture for information technology shall be obligated for projects over $25,000 prior to receipt of written approval by the Chief Information Officer.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29FF8D501A7A4021B466F8D21491760C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>707.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available under section 524(b) of the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1524">7 U.S.C. 1524(b)</external-xref>) in the current fiscal year shall remain available until expended to disburse obligations made in the current fiscal year.</text></section> 
<section id="H82658726BA1D4A909967B9D4317E3348"><enum>708.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any former RUS borrower that has repaid or prepaid an insured, direct or guaranteed loan under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, or any not-for-profit utility that is eligible to receive an insured or direct loan under such Act, shall be eligible for assistance under section 313(b)(2)(B) of such Act in the same manner as a borrower under such Act.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86B07BAEE479412BB53D4C9969F75D5D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>709.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise specifically provided by law, not more than $20,000,000 in unobligated balances from appropriations made available for salaries and expenses in this Act for the Farm Service Agency shall remain available through September 30, 2017, for information technology expenses: <italic>Provided</italic>, That except as otherwise specifically provided by law, unobligated balances from appropriations made available for salaries and expenses in this Act for the Rural Development mission area shall remain available through September 30, 2017, for information technology expenses.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AC6540351E944A887BC844D26FEA2C1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>710.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used for first-class travel by the employees of agencies funded by this Act in contravention of sections 301–10.122 through 301–10.124 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3C246196E0644CA98C37896A5DB3363" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>711.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of each program established or amended by the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/79">Public Law 113–79</external-xref>), other than by title I or subtitle A of title III of such Act, or programs for which indefinite amounts were provided in that Act, that is authorized or required to be carried out using funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03E6FC53E2034A4AAF3F5F1E95B84916"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such funds shall be available for salaries and related administrative expenses, including technical assistance, associated with the implementation of the program, without regard to the limitation on the total amount of allotments and fund transfers contained in section 11 of the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/714i">15 U.S.C. 714i</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9151C0C21C2D492C97ABABA8DF63DB6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of such funds for such purpose shall not be considered to be a fund transfer or allotment for purposes of applying the limitation on the total amount of allotments and fund transfers contained in such section.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H984771DB223A44F6B97F67A5FCC3DE02" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>712.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available by this Act, not more than $2,000,000 shall be used to cover necessary expenses of activities related to all advisory committees, panels, commissions, and task forces of the Department of Agriculture, except for panels used to comply with negotiated rule makings and panels used to evaluate competitively awarded grants.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35348697DE8D46D5864334456672AE02" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>713.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds in this Act shall be available to pay indirect costs charged against any agricultural research, education, or extension grant awards issued by the National Institute of Food and Agriculture that exceed 30 percent of total Federal funds provided under each award: <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding section 1462 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3310">7 U.S.C. 3310</external-xref>), funds provided by this Act for grants awarded competitively by the National Institute of Food and Agriculture shall be available to pay full allowable indirect costs for each grant awarded under section 9 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>).</text></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H993E7E16C74841BA98A94A26C49C25CE"><enum>714.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this or any other Act shall be used to pay the salaries and expenses of personnel to carry out the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE5A3E4EC581F4258A0B664C8F64AF446"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program authorized by section 14(h)(1) of the Watershed Protection and Flood Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1012">16 U.S.C. 1012(h)(1)</external-xref>). Of the funds available under section 14(h)(1) of such Act for fiscal year 2016, $69,000,000 are rescinded.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H902DB6E5045E45A6BE7AE12B43DB5F68"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Environmental Quality Incentives Program as authorized by sections 1240–1240H of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3839aa–3839aa–8) in excess of $1,349,000,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That this limitation shall apply only to funds provided by section 1241(a)(5)(C) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3841">16 U.S.C. 3841(a)(5)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF3123A8BA0EC4130A0897789F4CAF184"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Conservation Stewardship Program as authorized by sections 1238D–1238G of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3838d-3838g">16 U.S.C. 3838d–3838g</external-xref>) in excess of 7,741,000 acres.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HAFD6CC2DD96D484EA072EB1979C86EE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Biomass Crop Assistance Program authorized by section 9011 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8111">7 U.S.C. 8111</external-xref>) in excess of $12,000,000 in new obligational authority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA85082E3782A4DF9A10C7C7321A4B072"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Biorefinery, Renewable Chemical and Biobased Product Manufacturing Assistance program as authorized by section 9003(g)(1) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8103">7 U.S.C. 8103(g)(1)</external-xref>) in excess of $147,000,000.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5AA78737CD3B4EA4A37747E03FF0A1C9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Rural Energy for America Program as authorized by section 9007(g)(1) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8107">7 U.S.C. 8107(g)(1)</external-xref>) in excess of $35,000,000.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H554C864AFE3E48A09374C63CC6373755" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>715.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this or any other Act shall be used to pay the salaries and expenses of personnel to carry out a program under subsection (b)(2)(A)(viii) of section 14222 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/246">Public Law 110–246</external-xref> in excess of $884,980,000, as follows: Child Nutrition Programs Entitlement Commodities—$465,000,000; State Option Contracts—$5,000,000; Removal of Defective Commodities—$2,500,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That none of the funds made available in this Act or any other Act shall be used for salaries and expenses to carry out in this fiscal year section 19(i)(1)(E) of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, as amended, except in an amount that excludes the transfer of $125,000,000 of the funds to be transferred under subsection (c) of section 14222 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/246">Public Law 110–246</external-xref>, until October 1, 2016: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That $125,000,000 made available on October 1, 2016, to carry out section 19(i)(1)(E) of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, as amended, shall be excluded from the limitation described in subsection (b)(2)(A)(ix) of section 14222 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/246">Public Law 110–246</external-xref>: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this or any other Act shall be used to pay the salaries or expenses of any employee of the Department of Agriculture or officer of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out clause 3 of section 32 of the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1935 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/74/320">Public Law 74–320</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/612c">7 U.S.C. 612c</external-xref>, as amended), or for any surplus removal activities or price support activities under section 5 of the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the available unobligated balances under (b)(2)(A)(viii) of section 14222 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/246">Public Law 110–246</external-xref>, $293,020,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H77D08117C0904C47830BB22CA034F324"><enum>716.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated by this or any other Act shall be used to pay the salaries and expenses of personnel who prepare or submit appropriations language as part of the President's budget submission to the Congress for programs under the jurisdiction of the Appropriations Subcommittees on Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies that assumes revenues or reflects a reduction from the previous year due to user fees proposals that have not been enacted into law prior to the submission of the budget unless such budget submission identifies which additional spending reductions should occur in the event the user fees proposals are not enacted prior to the date of the convening of a committee of conference for the fiscal year 2017 appropriations Act.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D7F2E127C624482B9D03F227461C480" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>717.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9E4C7EFFCA0247F1AF62F6DBA7F9BEEE"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided by this Act, or provided by previous appropriations Acts to the agencies funded by this Act that remain available for obligation or expenditure in the current fiscal year, or provided from any accounts in the Treasury derived by the collection of fees available to the agencies funded by this Act, shall be available for obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming, transfer of funds, or reimbursements as authorized by the Economy Act, or in the case of the Department of Agriculture, through use of the authority provided by section 702(b) of the Department of Agriculture Organic Act of 1944 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2257">7 U.S.C. 2257</external-xref>) or section 8 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/89/106">Public Law 89–106</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2263">7 U.S.C. 2263</external-xref>), that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2E46433D390D4E2B92FB86C0673C1C44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creates new programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71C6684B3073449D8D357CAA359FC464"><enum>(2)</enum><text>eliminates a program, project, or activity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2B9CCD6BB0540E687307ECDB5E231C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increases funds or personnel by any means for any project or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46D1CA3E595F47E3AA2173B70C01EF3C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>relocates an office or employees;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF087BEDF111F42CD859FEDD160D2E983"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reorganizes offices, programs, or activities; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DA19D8DD096485AA6AEF08402A7815B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>contracts out or privatizes any functions or activities presently performed by Federal employees;</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">unless the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (as the case may be) notifies in writing and receives approval from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress at least 30 days in advance of the reprogramming of such funds or the use of such authority.</continuation-text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB511D5C2406C4A27B5637E6332E7C3EF"><enum>(b)</enum><text>None of the funds provided by this Act, or provided by previous Appropriations Acts to the agencies funded by this Act that remain available for obligation or expenditure in the current fiscal year, or provided from any accounts in the Treasury derived by the collection of fees available to the agencies funded by this Act, shall be available for obligation or expenditure for activities, programs, or projects through a reprogramming or use of the authorities referred to in subsection (a) involving funds in excess of $500,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less, that—</text> <paragraph id="HA5F8D860638B4F5FAE3B028107F05D4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>augments existing programs, projects, or activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF94192FAAC264B30A28D57C0C315608B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduces by 10 percent funding for any existing program, project, or activity, or numbers of personnel by 10 percent as approved by Congress; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H643AC8AB589541BB85F180E676C6FE37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>results from any general savings from a reduction in personnel which would result in a change in existing programs, activities, or projects as approved by Congress; unless the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (as the case may be) notifies in writing and receives approval from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress at least 30 days in advance of the reprogramming or transfer of such funds or the use of such authority.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2E830B244AA34384805637141EDEDC07"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission shall notify in writing and receive approval from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress before implementing any program or activity not carried out during the previous fiscal year unless the program or activity is funded by this Act or specifically funded by any other Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F8C13A5145245C08614B595B0D27C34"><enum>(d)</enum><text>None of the funds provided by this Act, or provided by previous Appropriations Acts to the agencies funded by this Act that remain available for obligation or expenditure in the current fiscal year, or provided from any accounts in the Treasury derived by the collection of fees available to the agencies funded by this Act, shall be available for—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCF25DBF9B0CA4CED93FDED0056581305"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifying major capital investments funding levels, including information technology systems, that involves increasing or decreasing funds in the current fiscal year for the individual investment in excess of $500,000 or 10 percent of the total cost, whichever is less;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59E8F098E5BD4C8CB6FCE293D8A2A2BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>realigning or reorganizing new, current, or vacant positions or agency activities or functions to establish a center, office, branch, or similar entity with five or more personnel; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA388DB68F04F4194B2711B7EB8DF53E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carrying out activities or functions that were not described in the budget request; unless the agencies funded by this Act notify, in writing, the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress at least 30 days in advance of using the funds for these purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD9A7B24A09974FBEBA9714E0107996B8"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As described in this section, no funds may be used for any activities unless the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission receives from the Committee on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress written or electronic mail confirmation of receipt of the notification as required in this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB020C0CA92CC40978354C9F7906C461E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>718.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 310B(g)(5) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1932">7 U.S.C. 1932(g)(5)</external-xref>), the Secretary may assess a one-time fee for any guaranteed business and industry loan in an amount that does not exceed 3 percent of the guaranteed principal portion of the loan.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H973028611BC84C5F9854ED61AB1B94C8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>719.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Agriculture, the Food and Drug Administration, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, or the Farm Credit Administration shall be used to transmit or otherwise make available reports, questions, or responses to questions that are a result of information requested for the appropriations hearing process to any non-Department of Agriculture, non-Department of Health and Human Services, non-Commodity Futures Trading Commission, or non-Farm Credit Administration employee.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E1CC07F05004717BEE8A97EE8200A31" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>720.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise authorized by existing law, none of the funds provided in this Act, may be used by an executive branch agency to produce any prepackaged news story intended for broadcast or distribution in the United States unless the story includes a clear notification within the text or audio of the prepackaged news story that the prepackaged news story was prepared or funded by that executive branch agency.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A508060784441029DDE9CEAB0C97B1A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>721.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No employee of the Department of Agriculture may be detailed or assigned from an agency or office funded by this Act or any other Act to any other agency or office of the Department for more than 60 days in a fiscal year unless the individual's employing agency or office is fully reimbursed by the receiving agency or office for the salary and expenses of the employee for the period of assignment.</text></section> 
<section id="HF816290831B84C6287C237487C7C66B7"><enum>722.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to pay the salaries and expenses of personnel who provide nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for mohair under section 1201 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/79">Public Law 113–79</external-xref>).</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BDF436920DB451199AEF738634372E3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>723.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Commissioner of the Food and Drug Administration, the Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, and the Chairman of the Farm Credit Administration shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress a detailed spending plan by program, project, and activity for all the funds made available under this Act including appropriated user fees, as defined in the report accompanying this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="H31F0E61039E146DB99135AEA62C8D306"><enum>724.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available under title II of the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1721">7 U.S.C. 1721 et seq.</external-xref>) may only be used to provide assistance to recipient nations if adequate monitoring and controls, as determined by the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development, are in place to ensure that emergency food aid is received by the intended beneficiaries in areas affected by food shortages and not diverted for unauthorized or inappropriate purposes.</text></section> <section id="H9F1212C5ECE2418B84E3260E340C7C54"><enum>725.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall continue the pilot program in effect for fiscal year 2013 for packaging and reviewing section 502 single family direct loans. The Secretary shall continue agreements with current intermediary organizations and not later than 90 days after enactment of this Act enter into additional agreements necessary for a total not less than 10 qualified intermediary organizations. The Secretary shall work with these organizations to increase the effectiveness of the section 502 single family direct loan program in rural communities and shall set aside and make available from the national reserve section 502 loans an amount necessary to support the work of such intermediaries and provide a priority for review of such loans.</text></section> 
<section id="H423C31E5581B4E1F8951E018E6A25A11"><enum>726.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For loans and loan guarantees that do not require budget authority and the program level has been established in this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture may increase the program level for such loans and loan guarantees by not more than 25 percent: <italic>Provided</italic>, That prior to the Secretary implementing such an increase, the Secretary notifies, in writing, the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress at least 15 days in advance.</text></section> <section id="HCBCCE270315A44D5A1EE091737C20E25"><enum>727.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the credit card refunds or rebates transferred to the Working Capital Fund pursuant to section 729 of the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2235a">7 U.S.C. 2235a</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/76">Public Law 107–76</external-xref>) shall be available for obligation without written notification to, and the prior approval of, the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the refunds or rebates so transferred shall be available for obligation only for the acquisition of plant and capital equipment necessary for the delivery of financial, administrative, and information technology services of primary benefit to the agencies of the Department of Agriculture.</text></section> 
<section id="H782DA62E9FFB4108884C29948699D762" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>728. </enum>
<subsection id="HBB99B82988BE4D3F9385861023A4112E" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5b(k)(5) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7a-1">7 U.S.C. 7a-1(k)(5)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8DECB9B50EAF425E8141B302FFD65ACC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H08AB058D08D54044A535D87788A0018B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Confidentiality Agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the Commission may share information with any entity described in paragraph (4), the Commission shall receive a written agreement from each entity stating that the entity shall abide by the confidentiality requirements described in section 8 relating to the information on swaps transactions that is provided.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HD07039E8D10E4299A86AAFB0831FCD17" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 21(d) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/24a">7 U.S.C. 24a(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAE13C1F044EA476A8B2759FC758C8F54" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H7FE5DF00871F4625BA11D2434D5B829E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Confidentiality Agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the swap data repository may share information with any entity described in subsection (c)(7), the swap data repository shall receive a written agreement from each entity stating that the entity shall abide by the confidentiality requirements described in section 8 relating to the information on swaps transactions that is provided.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
</subsection>
<subsection id="H3A6F28A0F1ED40BE9EC89277D06BDBB7" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect as if enacted on July 21, 2010. </text></subsection></section> <section id="HB036C9DC9BDF4C62B93B771CF30580C8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>729.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to procure processed poultry products imported into the United States from the People’s Republic of China for use in the school lunch program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>), the Child and Adult Food Care Program under section 17 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1766">42 U.S.C. 1766</external-xref>), the Summer Food Service Program for Children under section 13 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1761">42 U.S.C. 1761</external-xref>), or the school breakfast program under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1771">42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33F2E4E05AA04E0BAFD28EEB85D84125" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>730.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In response to an eligible community where the drinking water supplies are inadequate due to a natural disaster, as determined by the Secretary, including drought or severe weather, the Secretary may provide potable water through the Emergency Community Water Assistance Grant Program for an additional period of time not to exceed 120 days beyond the established period provided under the Program in order to protect public health.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77E518ECACFB46338362DB7557D58C32" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>731.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds provided by this or any prior Appropriations Act for the Agriculture and Food Research Initiative under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/450i">7 U.S.C. 450i(b)</external-xref> shall be made available without regard to section 7128 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3371">7 U.S.C. 3371</external-xref> note), under the matching requirements in laws in effect on the date before the date of enactment of such section: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/450i">7 U.S.C. 450i(b)(9)</external-xref> shall continue to apply.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE422B7C0366A4413B27BF43240D29945"><enum>732.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act through school year 2016–2017, with respect to the school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>) or the school breakfast program established under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1771">42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.</external-xref>) and final regulations published by the Department of Agriculture in the Federal Register on January 26, 2012 (77 Fed. Reg. 4088 et seq.), the Secretary shall allow States to grant an exemption from the whole grain requirements that took effect on or after July 1, 2014, and the States shall establish a process for evaluating and responding, in a reasonable amount of time, to requests for an exemption: <italic>Provided</italic>, That school food authorities demonstrate hardship, including financial hardship, in procuring specific whole grain products which are acceptable to the students and compliant with the whole grain-rich requirements: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That school food authorities shall comply with the applicable grain component or standard with respect to the school lunch or school breakfast program that was in effect prior to July 1, 2014.</text></section> <section id="HFCE4E0E614E8457482A8B8DC4C840AC4"><enum>733.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this or any other Act shall be used to pay the salaries and expenses of personnel to implement any regulations under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>), the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1771">42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.</external-xref>), the Healthy, Hunger-Free Kids Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/296">Public Law 111–296</external-xref>), or any other law that would require a reduction in the quantity of sodium contained in federally reimbursed meals, foods, and snacks sold in schools below Target 1 (as described in section 220.8(f)(3) of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)) until the latest scientific research establishes the reduction is beneficial for children.</text></section> 
<section id="H39263E5D2D8D44A99DACE9F66B2DE354" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>734.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to release or implement the final version of the eighth edition of the Dietary Guidelines for Americans, revised pursuant to section 301 of the National Nutrition Monitoring and Related Research Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5341">7 U.S.C. 5341</external-xref>), unless the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services comply with each of the following requirements: </text> <paragraph id="HBE4EAF29A1154F9C83BF402D5D2E92BC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each revision to any nutritional or dietary information or guideline contained in the 2010 edition of the Dietary Guidelines for Americans and any new nutritional or dietary information or guideline to be included in the eighth edition of the Dietary Guidelines for Americans—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4D1998EC9B68423BB05AC72ABDCE2188"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be based on scientific evidence that has been rated <quote>Grade I: Strong</quote> by the grading rubric developed by the Nutrition Evidence Library of the Department of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4679960A8A5241F9B8BA6A1C71946F54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be limited in scope to only matters of diet and nutrient intake.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7469D9B6ECBF4F8CA5394DF56641FDF7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretaries shall release a preliminary draft of the eighth edition of the Dietary Guidelines for Americans, including a list of all the scientific studies and evidence supporting each revised or new nutritional or dietary information or guideline, for a period of public comment of at least 90 days.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H597B293330194C7FAD94839059B45FE5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Following the end of the public comment period, the Secretaries shall provide a period for agency review of public comments of at least 60 days.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HA8256B1018D342B7A0517AA50AEF97B0" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>735.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used by the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Food and Nutrition Service, to commence any new research and evaluation projects until the Secretary submits to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress a research and evaluation plan for fiscal year 2016, prepared in coordination with the Research, Education, and Economics mission area of the Department of Agriculture, and a period of 30 days beginning on the date of the submission of the plan expires to permit Congressional review of the plan.</text></section> <section id="H9AD011DD7C124AD1BE71FACB4FD3F0BE" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>736.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unobligated balances identified by the Treasury Appropriation Fund Symbol 12X0113 are rescinded.</text></section>
<section id="H6AB9A9CDDE41413F884AD294AACFAF2C" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>737.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated prior year balance cancellations identified by Treasury Appropriation Fund Symbol 12X1980, $13,000,000 is rescinded.</text></section> <section id="HA84E74A4172B41D7AD573196F2FF1383" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>738.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unobligated balances identified by the Treasury Appropriation Fund Symbol 12X3318, 12X1010, 12X1090, 12X1003, 12X1907, 12X0402, 12X3508, and 12X3322 are rescinded.</text></section>
<section id="HAE05532368214F88A53AA2B97CC47DA7" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>739.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 166 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7286">7 U.S.C. 7286</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H58D55A3291D44FC9A62A0C9738F277DF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, and Subtitle B of title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014</quote>; and </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B996FC894CF4325948713E0D42F863B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3) of subsection (c) to read as follows: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCD77C369B5BC46CFAA305CA613ED12EA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H0D62F093688E4955B7ECF323659EFF50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out paragraph (1) under the same terms and conditions as were in effect for the 2008 crop year for loans made to producers under subtitle B of title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 8701 et. seq.).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="H7A135614AF6F4C84A7BA74D770C90334"><enum>740.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances identified by the Treasury Appropriation Fund Symbol 12X1072, $20,000,000 is hereby rescinded: <italic>Provided,</italic> That no amounts may be rescinded from amounts that were designated by Congress as an emergency requirement or for disaster relief requirement pursuant to a Concurrent Resolution on the Budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></section> <section id="H5A4D41E51EBF478692052B1015F4CCC2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>741.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (h) of section 502 of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1472">42 U.S.C. 1472</external-xref>), the Secretary of Agriculture shall have the same authority with respect to loans guaranteed under such section and eligible lenders for such loans as the Secretary has under subsections (h) and (j) of section 538 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1490p-2">42 U.S.C. 1490p–2</external-xref>) with respect to loans guaranteed under such section 538 and eligible lenders for such loans.</text></section>
<section id="H032C49DAD1FE4CCA8D25345D64719D64" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>742.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances of appropriations in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/199">Public Law 108–199</external-xref>, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/234">Public Law 109–234</external-xref>, and <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/28">Public Law 110–28</external-xref> made available for the <quote>Emergency Watershed Protection Program</quote>, $2,400,000 shall be available for the purposes of such program for any disaster occurring fiscal year 2016 or fiscal year 2017, and shall remain available until expended.</text></section> <section id="HC90C59C6E93F4A31A8D8EE4D6A83FE8E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>743.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to propose, promulgate, or implement any rule, or take any other action with respect to, allowing or requiring information intended for a prescribing health care professional, in the case of a drug or biological product subject to section 503(b)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353">21 U.S.C. 353(b)(1)</external-xref>), to be distributed to such professional electronically (in lieu of in paper form) unless and until a Federal law is enacted to allow or require such distribution.</text></section>
<section id="HA3623338B285442DABDC8CFEFF220934" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>744.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to implement, administer, or enforce the final rule entitled <quote>Food Labeling; Nutrition Labeling of Standard Menu Items in Restaurants and Similar Retail Food Establishments</quote> published by the Food and Drug Administration in the Federal Register on December 1, 2014 (79 Fed. Reg. 71156 et seq.) until the later of—</text> <paragraph id="H2B2B68CC06C04A15A3D1035A435432AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">December 1, 2016; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5EA590A814424FC1BB9E22F231FF2CB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is one year after the date on which the Secretary of Health and Human Services publishes Level 1 guidance with respect to nutrition labeling of standard menu items in restaurants and similar retail food establishments in accordance with paragraphs (g)(1)(i), (g)(1)(ii), (g)(1)(iii), and (g)(1)(iv) of section 10.115 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6C93C4DAC20641BAB93D12CDEE1D2F90" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>745.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to review or approve an application for an exemption for investigational use of a drug or biological product under section 505(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(i)</external-xref>) or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(a)(3)</external-xref>) in research in which a human embryo is intentionally created or modified to include a heritable genetic modification. </text>
</section>
<section id="H2646BA3ED1F64520A14A954672B99C3A" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>746.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this or any other Act may be used to implement or enforce any provision of the FDA Food Safety Modernization Act (P.L. 111–353), including the amendments made thereby, with respect to the regulation of the distribution, sale, or receipt of dried spent grain byproducts of the alcoholic beverage production process, irrespective of whether such byproducts are solely intended for use as animal feed.</text></section> <section id="HFB0E0751C1A1410F9F1B0EC29A49D04A" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>747.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each tobacco product which the Secretary of Health and Human Services, by regulation under section 901(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, deems to be subject to chapter IX of such Act, none of the funds made available in this Act or any other Act may be used to treat any reference in sections 905 and 910 of such Act to February 15, 2007, as other than a reference to the effective date of the regulation under which a tobacco product is deemed subject to the requirements of such Act pursuant to section 901(b)(1) of such Act, and any reference in such sections to 21 months after the date of enactment of the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act as other than a reference to 21 months after the date of such final deeming regulation.</text>
</section>
<section id="H9853FD9E537C4311A9B128B67FD30E61" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>748.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program ineligibility penalty that prohibits payment by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation of any portion of a crop insurance premium, otherwise required by sections 1211(a)(1)(E) and 1221(c) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3811">16 U.S.C. 3811(a)(1)(E)</external-xref>, 3821(c)) as added by section 2611 of the Agricultural Act of 2014, shall not apply or be enforced for the 2016 reinsurance year: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the delay in enforcement imposed by this section shall not be construed to limit the authority of the Department of Agriculture to assist producers, particularly producers subject to sections 1211 and 1221 of the Food Security Act of 1985 for the first time solely due to an amendment made by section 2611 of the Agricultural Act of 2014, to come into compliance with the requirements of such sections in a timely manner: <italic>Provided further,</italic> That a producer that comes into compliance before June 30, 2016, shall not be ineligible for payment of a portion of a crop insurance premium for the 2016 or 2017 reinsurance year on account of non-compliance before that date.</text></section> <section id="H1B5CA786CCD24BFABA89251011658E43"><enum>749.</enum><text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to implement, administer, or enforce the rule entitled <quote>Importation of Beef From a Region in Argentina</quote> published by the Department of Agriculture in the Federal Register on July 2, 2015 (80 Fed. Reg. 37935 et seq.) or the rule entitled <quote>Importation of Beef From a Region in Brazil</quote> published by the Department of Agriculture in the Federal Register on July 2, 2015 (80 Fed. Reg. 37923 et seq.) until the Secretary of Agriculture—(1) conducts a comprehensive risk evaluation that includes a quantitative risk assessment of importing beef produced in Argentina and Brazil; and (2) makes additional site visits to beef slaughtering and processing facilities in Argentina and Brazil and submits to the Committee on Appropriations a report on each such site visit not later than 90 days after the date on which the visit occurs.</text></section>
<section id="H96EA69EE371243C59CFA56383CD888A4"><enum>750.</enum><text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to carry out any activities or incur any expense related to the issuance of licenses under section 3 of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2133">7 U.S.C. 2133</external-xref>), or the renewal of such licenses, to class B dealers who sell dogs and cats for use in research, experiments, teaching, or testing.</text></section> <section id="H60C90C212D8C46C0A2A0FDFDD416FB0B"><enum>751.</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall publish a notice in the Federal Register clarifying that until the compliance date specified in the order published by the Food and Drug Administration in the Federal Register on June 17, 2015 (80 Fed. Reg. 34650 et seq.), partially hydrogenated oils shall be considered generally regarded as safe within the meaning of section 201(s) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(s)</external-xref>).</text></section>
<section id="HDA4323AC7B7D4AF1982E27B1B73605D4"><enum>752.</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text> <paragraph id="H32CEEDBCDB7542A1AF4E8FB30AF03CF7" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture shall implement section 12106 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 and the amendments made by such section (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/601">21 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/79">Public Law 113–79</external-xref>), including any regulation or guidance the Secretary of Agriculture issues to carry out such section or the amendments made by such section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H479144C653EF437EB685EA403FAEE966" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall implement section 403(t) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343(t)</external-xref>), including any regulation or guidance the Secretary of Health and Human Services issues to carry out such section.</text></paragraph></section><appropriations-small id="HD8A16875188C489BB7D46D71C53CA0EA"><header>spending reduction account</header></appropriations-small> <section id="H833648D370E54EC4B6C3A74974296B55"><enum>753.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount by which the applicable allocation of new budget authority made by the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives under section 302(b) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of proposed new budget authority is $0.</text></section> 
<section id="H1736D1F1FC9F4F1392F7E73CB0C75A8E"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016</short-title></quote>.</text></section> </title> </legis-body> <endorsement> <action-date date="20150714">July 14, 2015</action-date> <action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc> </endorsement> </bill> 

