<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA2086FF08EDE4E8BABA73A90D90088C1" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 426 IH: Sanctity of Human Life Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 426</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150121">January 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Hice of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000796">Mr. Westmoreland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000560">Mr. Graves of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide that human life shall be deemed to begin with fertilization.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCCF606E3958549789B39BC06BC29A651" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H287BF962BF68460290D65A48C1415A09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sanctity of Human Life Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H00346E20B6AA4AD7A7BED703F244E3B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Declaration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the exercise of the powers of the Congress, including Congress’ power under article I, section 8 of the Constitution, to make necessary and proper laws, and Congress’ power under section 5 of the 14th article of amendment to the Constitution of the United States—</text>
<paragraph id="H534788DF405E45E18EF4021B4FE765E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Congress declares that—</text> <subparagraph id="H93ABE88FEAE44D80A8197AE60B51039A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the right to life guaranteed by the Constitution is vested in each human being, and is the paramount and most fundamental right of a person; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB0CB6687E2634AB292B92F463DE3F2A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the life of each human being begins with fertilization, cloning, or its functional equivalent, irrespective of sex, health, function or disability, defect, stage of biological development, or condition of dependency, at which time every human being shall have all the legal and constitutional attributes and privileges of personhood; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABFC79E4D99B4A80B1F3612E3958D965"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Congress affirms that the Congress, each State, the District of Columbia, and all United States territories have the authority to protect the lives of all human beings residing in its respective jurisdictions.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HB4AB125EEC8144528C5DA0E619926A1C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HFAA48F20148649BB986BFD842F4911F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fertilization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fertilization</term> means the process of a human spermatozoan penetrating the cell membrane of a human oocyte to create a human zygote, a one-celled human embryo, which is a new unique human being.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H768CA92D08DF462B8225C38E372FF498"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cloning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cloning</term> means the process called somatic cell nuclear transfer, that combines an enucleated egg and the nucleus of a somatic cell to make a human embryo.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBEFF5B2132E47B2AF5A82D277CE67AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Human; human being</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>human</term> and <term>human being</term> include each and every member of the species homo sapiens at all stages of life, beginning with the earliest stage of development, created by the process of fertilization, cloning, or its functional equivalent.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


