<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF1D03BD46DF34C7BAB4FDCFAF21B8707" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3100 IH: Medical Practice Freedom Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3100</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150716">July 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000591">Mr. Tom Price of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit conditioning health care provider licensure on participation in a health plan or the
			 meaningful use of electronic health records.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H80CBA9DF59D54557AAFD8332EB505345" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE6BE01BBE2F44939918E2F3D939DB185" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Practice Freedom Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC8E140B000D946D3A7917701EBDF6FD4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Health care provider licensure cannot be conditioned on participation in a health plan or the meaningful use of electronic health records</header> <subsection id="H8EDE316E6F824BCF82D4A9B5771BE4F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services and any State (as a condition of receiving Federal financial participation under title XIX of the Social Security Act) may not require any health care provider, as a condition of licensure of the provider in any State—</text>
 <paragraph id="H521CAE3BC062468F9F965225A475CC56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to participate in any health plan; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H94C633DCC88243C997685E66BD2453B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to comply with any requirements relating to the meaningful use of electronic health records (including under part 170 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1450C7C7E084101BFB9D248637CDF89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HA62011BD5A2D431DA163351E3B85E45D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Health plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health plan</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1171(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d">42 U.S.C. 1320d(5)</external-xref>), and includes a basic health program established under section 1331 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18051">42 U.S.C. 18051</external-xref>), a qualified health plan offered by a qualified nonprofit health insurance issuer under the Consumer Operated and Oriented Plan (CO–OP) program under section 1322 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18042">42 U.S.C. 18042</external-xref>), a qualified health plan offered under a health care choice compact under section 1333 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18053">42 U.S.C. 18053</external-xref>), a multi-State qualified health plan offered under section 1334 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18054">42 U.S.C. 18054</external-xref>), or other health plan offered under title I of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1B89E587FB4365B2182C7AA754E25D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health care provider</term> means any person or entity that is required by State or Federal laws or regulations to be licensed, registered, or certified to provide health care services and is so licensed, registered, or certified, or exempted from such requirement by other statute or regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H488A21BB37AE44DD80DC79D262FD7790"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term for purposes of title XIX of the Social Security Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

