<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5644294638F643629D68330D59587A50" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 83 IH: CAMPER Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 83</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To assist States and local governments to develop and implement emergency notification systems
			 suitable for use on public recreational lands, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HEE9400DCB0884CDA9949DEF2024EA98C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8F047BDB405E43E69F2952E2C52C4007" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Communication and Alert Maintenance Program for Early Response Act</short-title></quote> or <quote>CAMPER Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBEC21B9B5FE2420990D0186CDFD379AD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security assistance for development and implementation of emergency notification systems for use on State and local government recreational lands</header> <subsection id="H573310CD62AB4A3D9A3317D37FA16FAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical assistance authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may provide technical assistance to a State or local government to develop and implement an emergency notification system suitable for use on public recreational lands administered by the State or local government to warn persons using such lands of emergency situations, including natural disasters and acts of terrorism or other man-made disasters.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4BCE175A0842489196D2CA5FE608B88D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header>
 <paragraph id="H6E8461C40E3E4345984E670E42A41ABA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may make grants, on a competitive basis, to States and local governments to procure and install emergency notification systems on public recreational lands, as described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA71B43E14E884FFD950DD908CEB36140"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum grant</header><text>A grant under this subsection may not exceed $50,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H896238B9580B4E4B93895A9CD295CB4D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost-sharing requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H81F974AF31FF42E1AB68A8F0E78EC156"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Recipient share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant recipient shall provide matching non-Federal funds, either in cash or in-kind support, in an amount equal to not less than five percent of the Federal funds provided in a grant under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79FE24654F48472E85995AF775497BA7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may establish conditions under which the cost-sharing requirements of subparagraph (A) may be reduced or waived.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H562631536A6944CDAFFA2B447185778B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year in which technical assistance and grants are provided under this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4C2CE930C47142069D5EADB59E0A1FCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describing the present state of preparedness of State park and recreation departments to provide adequate emergency notification in the event of emergency situations, including natural disasters and acts of terrorism or other man-made disasters; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1F3221D31DB4183B828BC2FC528C00E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>containing such recommendations for additional legislative action as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


