<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H676A6CFF54BC4C13BEAF76DBDF222B96" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 788 IH: Foreign Earnings Reinvestment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 788</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150205">February 5, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a temporary dividends received deduction for dividends received from a controlled foreign corporation.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H43FCDE92D4124C158D0DC287897088D9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9AB20777D304478996E5BF03AFBC185F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Earnings Reinvestment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H60EEF23CBBDD4396BBEBF2CAE6845A91" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Allowance of temporary dividends received deduction for dividends received from a controlled foreign corporation</header> <subsection id="HFE648B4A67CB4CB288466DCF24B136AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability of provision</header> <paragraph id="HC88001FC0F1847C7BA576294E5C69BA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (f) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/965">section 965</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDF70C209C154B36BA8666D4F8BCD227" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H94018304AC244BE4812B4F103A10FFC5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Election; election year</header> 
<paragraph id="HE880663DF64C427FAF075F16C4B0B9EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The taxpayer may elect to apply this section to—</text> <subparagraph id="H85849F3AD54A46CDB013AA5A04FDC1EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxpayer's last taxable year which begins before the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Foreign Earnings Reinvestment Act</short-title>, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3B97CA7F0B1645B29AFD1CAF3B66BBA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the taxpayer's first taxable year which begins during the 1-year period beginning on such date.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such election may be made for a taxable year only if made on or before the due date (including extensions) for filing the return of tax for such taxable year.</continuation-text> <subparagraph id="HDECEF5B63F394338B2906CBFC4A01B7E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Election year</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>election year</term> means the taxable year—</text> 
<clause id="HB341216068BB4630AA9C85CF99C65BB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which begins after the date that is one year before the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Foreign Earnings Reinvestment Act</short-title>, and</text></clause> <clause id="HB62ACC6DBA094E36B5CE74DB0883122E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to which the taxpayer elects under paragraph (1) to apply this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2ADD0D261441442487C206DC904F87A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2B2B3FDF11E440A8B327F4FB7BDF13E7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Extraordinary dividends</header><text>Section 965(b)(2) of such Code is amended—</text> <clause id="HE3B572A473B747CA974A87997BB993CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>June 30, 2003</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2014</quote>, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5D705E993E4C4EEA8104523566B780A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The amounts described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) shall not include any amounts which were taken into account in determining the deduction under subsection (a) for any prior taxable year.</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB34B4F70497442CA64182542FBE843F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determinations relating to related party indebtedness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 965(b)(3)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>October 3, 2004</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2014</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC487EB36A3A54C5A8A6FFD79A2ABEAEC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determinations relating to base period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 965(c)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>June 30, 2003</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2014</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD00414F1F56C4CDE8F6F727E100B7C28"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deduction includes current and accumulated foreign earnings</header> <paragraph id="HAC0A88EDF0024539BD419A6D72A7C5D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/965">section 965(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84F381636B1B4A1DAFD45E789462E3D5" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HFC33E7FC7E804CFDB63F009A352218F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of dividends taken into account under subsection (a) shall not exceed the sum of the current and accumulated earnings and profits described in section 959(c)(3) for the year a deduction is claimed under subsection (a), without diminution by reason of any distributions made during the election year, for all controlled foreign corporations of the United States shareholder.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E97E0EB53BF4AE69461E5B0F19226C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subparagraph id="H7C278D3305854DA3A22328B4C7769078"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 965(c) of such Code, as amended by subsection (a), is amended by striking paragraph (1) and by redesignating paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5), as paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4), respectively.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BAB53CF359447938A5CB9B427808819"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Paragraph (4) of section 965(c)of such Code, as redesignated by subparagraph (A), is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H474959B193604C658E2AEC781A82F8D5" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H557CBAA2D22F4DFE954A2D9F26E14B88"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Controlled groups</header><text>All United States shareholders which are members of an affiliated group filing a consolidated return under section 1501 shall be treated as one United States shareholder.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB3E7CD3B145C46B591C53340898D6F3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of deduction</header> 
<paragraph id="HA9BE541D0D604720B23952951A7E362E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/965">section 965(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>85 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>75 percent</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C5FBB4F9A744EC787F6A2F67717DE0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bonus deduction in subsequent taxable year for increasing jobs</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/965">Section 965</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1360633FDAB4528B2EEE5C824CA10E4" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H1A890294DEFE41218A18D555C6AF250D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Bonus deduction</header> 
<paragraph id="HE59D4C682A534BF48DEC0FAD47EC1BD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxpayer who makes an election to apply this section, there shall be allowed as a deduction for the first taxable year following the election year an amount equal to the applicable percentage of the cash dividends which are taken into account under subsection (a) with respect to such taxpayer for the election year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1391B1FD2DD3442EBFDF54D1B08CF49F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the applicable percentage is the amount which bears the same ratio (not greater than 1) to 10 percent as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD118E77D0ADC44C9A6D87506D2DCE9C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text> <clause id="H940787BF04404E56BEB40077664A7CDA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the qualified payroll of the taxpayer for the calendar year which begins with or within the first taxable year following the election year, over</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2D129E068BBF4122B7C9DFFCCD7761AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the qualified payroll of the taxpayer for calendar year 2014, bears to</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE140AB2A5B724981A0DCCD046D90EF2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>10 percent of the qualified payroll of the taxpayer for calendar year 2014.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEC59985B4B84A86AD2F2E27A01A0103"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified payroll</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph:</text> <subparagraph id="HC2DBD6979B52453BAE7160EE78AFCD1E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified payroll</term> means, with respect to a taxpayer for any calendar year, the aggregate wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) paid by the corporation during such calendar year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5482E7C75F0C476D9CC7631E32328FEA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for changes in ownership of trades or businesses</header> 
<clause id="HFC9840B786ED4635BF8968A8F393C0DD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Acquisitions</header><text>If, after December 31, 2013, and before the close of the first taxable year following the election year, a taxpayer acquires the trade or business of a predecessor, then the qualified payroll of such taxpayer for any calendar year shall be increased by so much of the qualified payroll of the predecessor for such calendar year as was attributable to the trade or business acquired by the taxpayer.</text></clause> <clause id="H974D4CBB970B414E970D6D7AC059B560"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Dispositions</header><text>If, after December 31, 2013, and before the close of the first taxable year following the election year, a taxpayer disposes of a trade or business, then—</text> 
<subclause id="H9F47ECBAE47441CBB5C891DD19C33685"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the qualified payroll of such taxpayer for calendar year 2014 shall be decreased by the amount of wages for such calendar year as were attributable to the trade or business which was disposed of by the taxpayer, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H40507DEAE0BE49F994C1E8AB3A360DA7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the disposition occurs after the beginning of the first taxable year following the election year, the qualified payroll of such taxpayer for the calendar year which begins with or within such taxable year shall be decreased by the amount of wages for such calendar year as were attributable to the trade or business which was disposed of by the taxpayer.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H944550998E494EF2AB34F630C51FBCC9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>For purposes of determining qualified payroll for any calendar year after calendar year 2015, such term shall not include wages paid to any individual if such individual received compensation from the taxpayer for services performed—</text> <clause id="H81FC2AE00FDA48839F007EC4CE886C45"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H47B3275370B04FB6A8C22A05E47E1CCC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at a time when such individual was not an employee of the taxpayer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7B3570C014149C78E073EABD40F21CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reduction for failure to maintain employment levels</header><text>Paragraph (4) of section 965(b) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58B75F1E8FF140B4A911AE5A277C5E34" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H306672E2915A42AB91343AEC716A04D5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reduction in benefits for failure to maintain employment levels</header> 
<subparagraph id="HCC5CC29E0ABB4052A173AA6FD9A2D81F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, during the period consisting of the calendar month in which the taxpayer first receives a distribution described in subsection (a)(1) and the succeeding 23 calendar months, the taxpayer does not maintain an average employment level at least equal to the taxpayer’s prior average employment, an additional amount equal to $75,000 multiplied by the number of employees by which the taxpayer’s average employment level during such period falls below the prior average employment (but not exceeding the aggregate amount allowed as a deduction pursuant to subsection (a)(1)) shall be taken into income by the taxpayer during the taxable year that includes the final day of such period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB80C2C0F1644111A986A54047FE0FC9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Average employment level</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the taxpayer’s average employment level for a period shall be the average number of full-time United States employees of the taxpayer, measured at the end of each month during the period.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E1AEA3B431F407FBDE85F6EB364B4F5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prior average employment</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the taxpayer’s <term>prior average employment</term> shall be the average number of full-time United States employees of the taxpayer during the period consisting of the 24 calendar months immediately preceding the calendar month in which the taxpayer first receives a distribution described in subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF485A3D6B2BE47818A939AAB48979CBA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Full-time United States employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph—</text> 
<clause id="H02A3E150650144128D6BD0E32E9F306E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>full-time United States employee</term> means an individual who provides services in the United States as a full-time employee, based on the employer’s standards and practices; except that regardless of the employer’s classification of the employee, an employee whose normal schedule is 40 hours or more per week is considered a full-time employee.</text></clause> <clause id="H0C69412860E34D7C981705BD2F9F4925"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception for changes in ownership of trades or businesses</header><text>Such term does not include—</text> 
<subclause id="H6AC8A474A7654322B1C343F80020856D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any individual who was an employee, on the date of acquisition, of any trade or business acquired by the taxpayer during the 24-month period referred to in subparagraph (A), and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H487B08B43943485F872FF026DD4E5D21"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any individual who was an employee of any trade or business disposed of by the taxpayer during the 24-month period referred to in subparagraph (A) or the 24-month period referred to in subparagraph (C).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H434EF0C35D1B42DEAF691BDA0CC50514"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Aggregation rules</header><text>In determining the taxpayer’s average employment level and prior average employment, all domestic members of a controlled group shall be treated as a single taxpayer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0280B32F5395485895D54DC466319F57"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


