<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2DB3BAF1A0A54D1BA8BF45F6478C3335" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2560 IH: Common Sense Waiver Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2560</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to waive any emission
			 standard or other requirement under section 112 of the Clean Air Act (42
			 U.S.C. 7412) applicable to the control of asbestos emissions in the
			 demolition or renovation of a condemned building for which there is a
			 reasonable expectation of structural failure.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H819DC54265664F9795181A409BE3A9E1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9CD0E8D0555243A1BC8B6EA386AC4A7C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Common Sense Waiver Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7053251C04E74CA8BD9E673FADF33A4B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waiver from asbestos NESHAP requirements for demolition or renovation of condemned buildings</header> <subsection id="H56F568180BED41A4A8031F13E3A95F31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of a State or local government, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) may waive any emission standard or other requirement under section 112 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412</external-xref>) applicable to the control of asbestos emissions in the demolition or renovation of a building.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7265FEA420294C13A02A42DFCC9EEF45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standard for approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may approve a request for a waiver under subsection (a) only if the request demonstrates that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF912E1D640C845D8B332F0FBFED55A97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the building has been condemned; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H454340449A794DCA8BDD184B604D53D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there is a reasonable expectation of the building’s structural failure.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13AFB0E5285241E086B27717A3ACD56B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Time period for approval or disapproval of request for waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall approve or disapprove a request for a waiver under subsection (a) within 90 days after the date on which the request is received by the Administrator. If the Administrator fails to approve or disapprove such a request by the end of such 90-day period, the request is deemed to be approved.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


