<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H275325BAAD0B4DB19AFC618CDB6A9F72" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1121 IH: Online Job Training Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1121</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To encourage online workforce training.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE679A380608A417AAA33A65EE8B61734" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H548F02A2FD834533BD09D08CC5D6E36B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Online Job Training Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H98DD52F1881D4142B042D20AAD2CCC3D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Online workforce training programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 169 of the Workforce Investment and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3224">29 U.S.C. 3224</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H2F1A945D8FFC45C9BDD511D103A0D9D1" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H3E2C3D56EDBE4FA288CD158C955EC3FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Online workforce training program</header> 
<paragraph id="H9F9C0C379C4947A0B4D3435EE0873879"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National Online Workforce Training Grants</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE3D922ED07AD4D4494BF9F9F9BA1A2B2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount appropriated under subparagraph (G), the Secretary shall award National Online Workforce Training Grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to enable such entities to carry out workforce training programs using distance-learning technologies, such as the Internet. An entity may leverage such grant with other Federal, State, local, and private resources, in order to expand the participation of businesses, employees, and other individuals in such training programs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B68B6DAB31B43A5A83ED5FEB21796EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means an educational institution, community-based organization, nonprofit organization, State board or local board, or unit of general local government, which provides online workforce training.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF5016BEBDBCA4A989D84D68E539E47D9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>Priority in awarding grants under this paragraph shall be given to eligible entities that—</text> <clause id="HC1399C6D88EF4E508F44A8BCC5FB3616"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have demonstrated experience in implementing and operating online workforce training and education programs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBC51CE6B57284EF19C3A54F6CDC4DC7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have demonstrated experience coordinating activities, where appropriate, with the workforce investment system; and</text></clause> <clause id="H20BB3BDB9BBD476A8E7D262379D8DFF8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conduct training for occupations with national or local shortages.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C9F858C149242F9BE5076399AADCEB2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this paragraph shall collect and report information on—</text> <clause id="HFC2C70BF0602411BBBD10A0DAAA4DBD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of participants in the workforce training program funded under this paragraph;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H960E878E123F4321A8589122487883CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the services received by the participants;</text></clause> <clause id="H581F5F69DDEF43BC81A0C6A08FD52B9F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>program completion rates;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H07187B74584C4137AE965EA38184FABB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>factors determined as significantly interfering with program participation or completion;</text></clause> <clause id="HC9AEF9E977F241118F536768254DA4E9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the rate of job placement; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H416EDDD9E9084982B7E3E61753529D6E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other information as determined as needed by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F7288F7D9B24FD99D23F2214EF922A5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this paragraph shall conduct outreach activities to disseminate information to workforce investment boards, local governments, educational institutions, and other workforce training organizations about—</text> 
<clause id="HA4A7698312CA41C0B6AF79B9B6FADAA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the workforce training program funded under this paragraph; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0738BC55A5CB4F22B39F9CC04155B493"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the results of such, and the best practices with respect to workforce training identified as a result of, program.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5ECE060773464FD4B195D023135ED7B7"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Performance levels</header><text>The Secretary shall establish indicators of performance that will be used to evaluate the performance of eligible entities under this paragraph in carrying out the activities required under this paragraph. Prior to awarding a grant under this paragraph to an eligible entity, the Secretary shall negotiate and reach agreement with the entity regarding the levels of performance expected to be achieved by the entity on the indicators of performance.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C95FFEB95304008BE417DA2CAA88405"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this paragraph $50,000,000 for fiscal years 2016 through 2026.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94234975D480477FA92437F5D3390402"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Online training program clearinghouse</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA20774DB546748939EC3C4415D95C0DE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Description of grant</header><text>From the amounts appropriated under subparagraph (D), the Secretary shall award one grant to an eligible institution of higher education to provide the services described in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA78D7D4D147044E4AFE702E9844776ED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this paragraph, an institution of higher education shall—</text> 
<clause id="H1CAA53BD3FBC4229885720596C1BF9BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have demonstrated the ability to disseminate research on best practices for implementing workforce investment activities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4118CC37D1B149E6884D428EA45DAF73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be a national leader in producing cutting-edge research on technology related to workforce development systems under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEA4DF0C647D480782139288F3593922"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Services</header><text>The postsecondary educational institution that receives a grant under this paragraph shall use such grant—</text> <clause id="H519930E9E0FF4463BE0C62AB862A9549"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance to entities that receive grants under paragraph (1);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC18DBE9BC41D40C8AD38432C2F8CD37B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to collect and nationally disseminate the data gathered by entities that receive grants under paragraph (1); and</text></clause> <clause id="H7E9B5FD7DAA04FFEA84B6378DA732FA8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to disseminate best practices identified by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H853A0F4239014ED593C129A8544B7D7A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $1,000,000 for fiscal years 2016 through 2026.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H4A7A4AB85B6A416C98DBC96234F070B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendment made by section 2 shall take effect as if enacted as part of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

