<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF5B8CFFA50AC444D954056B7BAA77FAF" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3956 IH: VA Health Center Management Stability and Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3956</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to develop and implement a plan to hire directors of the medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H94DDDA045F904177B978ABCC49D4C765" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H35FCE03E0AB943D8AFC7EBA9B2023645" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Health Center Management Stability and Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2A027A6FA2534D6B843F958CD4753284" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8B011F522C6E4B0BB78231699FF8E694"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to data from the Department of Veterans Affairs, several medical centers of the Department are managed by acting or temporary directors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99003BA679114D3E839405950FA0D36D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Some of these medical centers have not been managed by a permanent director for a long period.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB10F3E506BD54343ABC2E296CC3D4ACD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Pursuant to section 317.903 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, a member of the senior executive service who is detailed to a temporary position in a department or agency of the Federal Government may not serve in that position for periods longer than 120-day increments, and no member of the senior executive service may be detailed to an unclassified position for a period longer than 240 days.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D5C6C74594B4E078B0FC0AAC444B315"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The inability of the Department of Veterans Affairs to recruit qualified, permanent candidates as directors of medical centers, combined with the policies described in paragraph (3), leads to frequent turnover of directors at the medical centers which impedes the ability of system management to engage in long-term planning and other functions necessary to improve service delivery to veterans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23B5D5B409BD4368B0EBCC26B1E0F9E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs should develop a comprehensive plan to recruit permanent directors at each medical center that lacks a permanent director.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB807FF2388EA4541BC92EC3E17CC2F6C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Plan to hire directors of medical centers of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HD363D964687E46C1BCE748664C83268E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop and implement a plan to hire highly qualified directors for each medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs that lacks a permanent director as of the date of the plan. The Secretary shall prioritize the hiring of such directors for the medical centers that have not had a permanent director for the longest periods.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H60AD21A245B34D7DB8DA3098FE7DF797"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>The plan developed under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HAB3FE619D54C4B7B9295155F37B0463A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A deadline to hire the directors of the medical centers of the Department as described in such subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2579AD7B7264B449AB7D483B24E6FD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identification of the possible impediments to such hiring.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDAEF7AB946B481D9AECC2AB92BF9A97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identification of opportunities to promote and train candidates from within the Department to senior executive positions in the Department, including as directors of medical centers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF4CDEA2B8CD45E983BEC724810CE8D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate the plan developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60E30102BC144CE6B142C338B2D414C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Semiannual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and each 180-day period thereafter until January 1, 2018, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a list of each medical center of the Department that lacks a permanent director as of the date of the report.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


