<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H14E66C55DCA247B2B6AD15680470B2E1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2538 IH: Lytton Rancheria Homelands Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2538</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To take lands in Sonoma County, California, into trust as part of the reservation of the Lytton
			 Rancheria of California, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H53EC5DFF678C4F23B0BB881C7E65B314" style="OLC">
 <section id="H463B2C7A98A44870873A029BE0B66BB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lytton Rancheria Homelands Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H99117D8245954F23B904B250D26D7FEA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD381F5D961EF43B6AF5E4F647C471B91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Lytton Rancheria of California is a federally recognized Indian tribe that lost its homeland after it was unjustly and unlawfully terminated in 1958. The Tribe was restored to Federal recognition in 1991, but the conditions of its restoration have prevented it from regaining a homeland on its original lands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB6D4FE36B394C8F84E5AF7FE8F59DE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress needs to take action to reverse historic injustices that befell the Tribe and have prevented it from regaining a viable homeland for its people.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E1F44BD6EED421BA25949F96C285EC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prior to European contact there were as many as 350,000 Indians living in what is now the State of California. By the turn of the 19th century, that number had been reduced to approximately 15,000 individuals, many of them homeless and living in scattered bands and communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AA56C9336634B95B0394A50B5862A00"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Lytton Rancheria’s original homeland was purchased by the United States in 1926 pursuant to congressional authority designed to remedy the unique tragedy that befell the Indians of California and provide them with reservations called Rancherias to be held in trust by the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H74ED8E56C78349C1BCA3D09D6030D803"><enum>(5)</enum><text>After the Lytton Rancheria lands were purchased by the United States, the Tribe settled on the land and sustained itself for several decades by farming and ranching.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6688BA33B85047D19A0B0DDB9AAB3437"><enum>(6)</enum><text>By the mid-1950s, Federal Indian policy had shifted back towards a policy of terminating Indian tribes. In 1958, Congress enacted the Rancheria Act of 1958 (72 Stat. 619), which slated 41 Rancherias in California, including the Lytton Rancheria, for termination after certain conditions were met.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB3AD4A1C0614E8C8AF297620F714913"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On August 1, 1961, the Lytton Rancheria was terminated by the Federal Government. This termination was illegal because the conditions for termination under the Rancheria Act had never been met. After termination was implemented, the Tribe lost its lands and was left without any means of supporting itself.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0B26DC1E8E84D63B76395CB62B11154"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 1987, the Tribe joined three other tribes in a lawsuit against the United States challenging the illegal termination of their Rancherias. A Stipulated Judgment in the case, Scotts Valley Band of Pomo Indians of the Sugar Bowl Rancheria v. United States, No. C–86–3660 (N.D.Cal. March 22, 1991), restored the Lytton Rancheria to its status as a federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD62C7833D5544BA38A54E9FC1E0F0E2F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Stipulated Judgment agreed that the Lytton Rancheria would have the <quote>individual and collective status and rights</quote> which it had prior to its termination and expressly contemplated the acquisition of trust lands for the Lytton Rancheria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D5C3603EA14441BBA2216A4E13966E1"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Stipulated Judgment contains provisions, included at the request of the local county governments and neighboring landowners, that prohibit the Lytton Rancheria from exercising its full Federal rights on its original homeland in the Alexander Valley.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H857BDCB40EA64BDD9E261B45F2D35BA4"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In 2000, approximately 9.5 acres of land in San Pablo, California, was placed in trust status for the Lytton Rancheria for economic development purposes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0665601BA88C4164AA09CFBE12B96505"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Tribe has since acquired, from willing sellers at fair market value, property in Sonoma County near the Tribe’s historic Rancheria. This property, which the Tribe holds in fee status, is suitable for a new homeland for the Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FAF0686A2A341B59263C84959C29F3C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>On a portion of the land to be taken into trust, which portion totals approximately 124.12 acres, the Tribe plans to build housing for its members and governmental and community facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E772B3E1B6C440B86111BB6BEF8422B"><enum>(14)</enum><text>A portion of the land to be taken into trust is being used for viniculture, and the Tribe intends to develop more of the lands to be taken into trust for viniculture. The Tribe’s investment in the ongoing viniculture operation has reinvigorated the vineyards, which are producing high-quality wines. The Tribe is operating its vineyards on a sustainable basis and is working toward certification of sustainability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8F29B48046A44B5AA4283E78C187D63"><enum>(15)</enum><text>No gaming will be conducted on the lands to be taken into trust.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4998EDC93454926B6825F0730CA6057"><enum>(16)</enum><text>By directing that these lands be taken into trust, the United States will ensure that the Lytton Rancheria will finally have a permanently protected homeland on which they can once again live communally and plan for future generations. This action is necessary to fully restore the Tribe to the status it had before it was wrongfully terminated in 1961.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FF838D458D0477BA62C23C9B520120A"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tribe and County of Sonoma have entered into a Memorandum of Agreement in which the County agrees to the lands in the County being taken into trust for the benefit of the Tribe in consideration for commitments made by the Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H6E6DD901A2154D8FAC582B24BE7CA376"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purpose of this Act, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H8416B3BFDEEB4331AE96A690089F9FEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>County</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>County</term> means Sonoma County, California.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FE23A4C752E45ABAB42DB616414DCB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H376DAB2F7B63458F9841661F2B70E238"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Lytton Rancheria of California.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H1E38B490112C4EA186EA6AB91BABA74A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Lands to be taken into trust</header>
 <subsection id="H1922F5EF576F43D3BAA736D2C31D7410"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The land owned by the Tribe and generally depicted on the map titled <quote>Lytton Fee Owned Property to be Taken into Trust</quote> and dated May 1, 2015, is hereby taken into trust for the benefit of the Tribe, subject to valid existing rights, contracts, and management agreements related to easements and rights-of-way.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC86FCA2444264640A07DF81518C68841"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Lands To Be Made Part of the Reservation</header><text>Lands taken into trust under subsection (a) shall be part of the Tribe’s reservation and shall be administered in accordance with the laws and regulations generally applicable to property held in trust by the United States for an Indian tribe.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H3EDBB4746B1949C49B77385CF076B028"><enum>5.</enum><header>Gaming prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Land taken into trust for the benefit of the Tribe under this Act shall not be used for gaming under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="HA82B223E16BF45D086A1B238915A21C0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Applicability of certain law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Memorandum of Agreement entered into by the Tribe and the County concerning taking land in the County into trust for the benefit of the Tribe, which was approved by the County Board of Supervisors on March 10, 2015, is not subject to review or approval of the Secretary in order to be effective, including review or approval under section 2103 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/81">25 U.S.C. 81</external-xref>).</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


