<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H39C3ED0ABE4F4A4886203EB4E9566C47" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2241 EH: Global Health Innovation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2241</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to submit to Congress a report on the development and use of global health innovations in the programs, projects, and activities of the Agency.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA8E98E6873864D0AB865818C5BEA659D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD487E6A2AB714EDBAAA836A1DEE6AC95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Health Innovation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H758ACECA8A964142B369A57EE8A22580"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report</header> <subsection id="HC4DC62C3D9C54D1398F89E95422704EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for a period of 4 years, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall submit to Congress a report on the development and use of global health innovations in the programs, projects, and activities of the Agency.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H4F3B859A76034F6F9F864E5737D459CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To Be Included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H6D7ABA578894480AAAA8AA38A3CFD30E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEF41D62AC3724386B0E257FFA85890DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which global health innovations described in subsection (a) include drugs, diagnostics, devices, vaccines, electronic and mobile health technologies, and related behavior change and service delivery innovations;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6CB972A2AD94355BC7867E2646618CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how innovation has advanced the Agency’s commitments to achieving an HIV/AIDS-free generation, ending preventable child and maternal deaths, and protecting communities from infectious diseases, as well as furthered by the Global Health Strategic Framework;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC970CD4249DD447784C8F553A26E481F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how goals are set for health product development in relation to the Agency’s health-related goals and how progress and impact are measured towards those goals;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2AD3AB88E2B48F188D38D0FF6CE9FF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the Agency’s investments in innovation relate to its stated goals; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB0BD18C5CA2F45F38AE6455AE90021AD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>progress made towards health product development goals.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H133327343D6C4DD6A885176269A269AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the Agency both, independently and with partners, donors, and public-private partnerships, is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEC7D5E95B58E4E96937DFD9D8BF7B0E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leveraging United States investments to achieve greater impact in health innovation;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B6DEB60600E466982EF6C489F16054E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engaging in activities to develop, advance, and introduce affordable, available, and appropriate global health products; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8FADA0AD42FC437CA2020375851F7C23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>scaling up appropriate health innovations in the development pipeline.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7057AD57FCBE497CBE8F269D95E20530"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of collaboration and coordination with other Federal departments and agencies, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in support of global health product development, including a description of how the Agency is working to ensure critical gaps in product development for global health are being filled.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBF021A0288804319A1E178E01CA77759"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of how the Agency is coordinating and aligning global health innovation activities between the Global Development Lab, the Center for Accelerating Innovation and Impact, and the Bureau for Global Health.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20151218" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 18, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

