<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H59929AAB2A0F4C26A8F35AB9B24A4343" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1371 IH: Safer Trucks and Buses Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1371</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150316">March 16, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To improve the Compliance, Safety, Accountability initiative of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H43655FC6D38143DFB5889827BEA364AE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4033603E086E4EFB93E656959E6CD84E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Trucks and Buses Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H22770ADB986944329BC4997E96FC2407"><enum>2.</enum><header>Compliance, Safety, Accountability initiative</header> <subsection id="H00DB379E6A9E44DEB3EC45619E44BE90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data availability and use</header> <paragraph id="HE0738D0771494D3B921ACF378EBEB651"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability</header> <subparagraph id="H5CBAE2B02331416D903257161C589F76"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that covered motor carrier data is not made available to the public.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H484813DB68D245FDACD20B7B725B038E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Subparagraph (A) may not be construed to prevent covered motor carrier data from being made available to law enforcement personnel.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF570E85A81A94425BC057F30B0DE59CD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall cease to have effect on the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress the report required under subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D1D518C4FE74A6299ECC1B34F1876EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Covered motor carrier data may not be admitted into evidence or otherwise used in a civil action for damages resulting from an incident involving a motor carrier.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H66AA2E78AC5C4A618EB7BD08188D9E90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header> <paragraph id="HB23E026257A64B09BF3B2747EBB99C96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Public Administration to have the Academy conduct a study on how to improve the Compliance, Safety, Accountability initiative of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, including how to ensure that the initiative—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H061F9885BCB04D708521D16728D13D0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilizes only safety data determined to be predictive of motor carrier crashes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE71C29BBFF0D4184AFE0F93FF3592802"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appropriately addresses concerns relating to the age of utilized safety data, including violations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F2693BE43144BA9BF77219993C103E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not unfairly harm small motor carriers as a result of limited safety data availability;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H656841CDB9564BADA791428F5552B4F0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appropriately addresses differences between motor carriers transporting passengers and motor carriers transporting freight;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1138B7AC99B54E7CB1F53626AB33AB56"><enum>(E)</enum><text>allows individual motor carriers to be effectively compared; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A8A834757E64B4C90F8AE7CBE934E72"><enum>(F)</enum><text>utilizes accurate safety data, including—</text> 
<clause id="H5E49BD4BE4844C14A25BBA8A6F90AC57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by appropriately addressing variations between State- and self-reported data;</text></clause> <clause id="HF9F0080AF6ED4E0BBF9715808BBB9BD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by accounting for geographic differences with respect to enforcement; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB5CF427712F74B9192A60D03D47CF68A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by not utilizing crash data from crashes with respect to which a motor carrier was free from fault.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14C7AF55263E46529FD66F2E02FE233B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Free from fault</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(F)(iii), a motor carrier is free from fault with respect to a crash if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F35B506088F44648301B59680827616"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the vehicle of the carrier was struck by another vehicle that—</text> <clause id="HD9C23540AF9F4CCEAC08DFC49C4BCF0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>crossed the center line or median of a roadway;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2A4F8C843C584E47AB07D5EFA54256B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was driving the wrong way on a roadway;</text></clause> <clause id="HC5D76FA8C1C64101ABFD3D076D22F7EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>struck the rear of the carrier’s vehicle while the vehicle was being lawfully operated;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7FE863E986904C6A9D9B5BD40AE3DE12"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>struck the carrier’s vehicle while the vehicle was legally stopped at a traffic control device or off the traveled portion of a roadway; or</text></clause> <clause id="H9F47CC6671EC47BCAA951A5DABF42496"><enum>(v)</enum><text>was operated by an individual—</text> 
<subclause id="HFBC7BD8C321345EEA0ECFCCE91D282EA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>found to be driving under the influence of alcohol;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCC6EB348235E498EA5978CA5DE62C06A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>found by a law enforcement officer or agency to be responsible for the crash; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE2699709AB6D44D49A0C3EE863D717EB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>who was the sole party cited by law enforcement for an action that contributed to the crash;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5815F926EA9443988EE5FF58FBEB950"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the crash was the result of an individual, other than the driver of the carrier’s vehicle, committing suicide;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF04CF93FF40E4024892A2BA3B18A37EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the vehicle of the carrier was struck by an animal; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H282506E28BBA4D90950B5F99A44AEAE2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the carrier is otherwise determined not responsible for the crash.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H237E84EDD795459B90D5A4434BC59262"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary enters into an agreement under subsection (b), the National Academy of Public Administration shall submit to the Secretary, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (b), including recommendations for improvement based on those results.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAC6810261DE04907A7344B009CC02CA3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation of recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the National Academy of Public Administration submits the report required under subsection (c), the Secretary shall begin implementing the recommendations included in that report.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H854458FC0EA04CB98FC7829C5CDC6BCA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certification of implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary begins implementing recommendations under subsection (d), the Secretary shall complete the implementation of such recommendations and shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="HF49405BD522843AF95FA1CBCDA2A747C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the implementation of such recommendations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2EF8EF751CB46CFA74CF739C41D0F63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains a document in which the Secretary certifies that such implementation is complete; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3665920969A489DB8CB8B19E7F4061B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contains a document in which the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation certifies that such implementation is complete.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA54E69BCF98041B3B957EBEF058166CA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H09C4B1DCE49B4B7680811208448192ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered motor carrier data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered motor carrier data</term> means the Compliance, Safety, Accountability Safety Measurement System scores and performance data of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6C4190E7A0B4A69A936F1B6CC28D8AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Motor carrier</header><text>The term <term>motor carrier</term> has the meaning given that term in section 13102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

