<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H2A98441C7C8D47E1ACB90D66EA5EEF52" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2320 RH: Federal Improper Payments Coordination Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 228</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2320</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 114–299]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150514">May 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000796">Mr. Westmoreland</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20151020">October 20, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000622">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000591">Mr. Tom Price of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000810">Mr. Woodall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action> 
<action-date date="20151020">October 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 14, 2015</action-instruction> 
</action> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To provide access to and use of information by Federal agencies in order to reduce improper payments, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HGO00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H28DFF4F60E204FADA81D919FB920AB28"> 
<section id="H3BA51155541F420CBEEA7ABF8C490027" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Improper Payments Coordination Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H98A88DDB2A0E4E27A3CD54EBC3BD3990"><enum>2.</enum><header>Availability of the do not pay initiative to the judicial and legislative branches and states</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Improper Payments Elimination and Recovery Improvement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3321">31 U.S.C. 3321</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H91D2A380BD564284AEF7E332795393C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2ACA4072DB24078A9457687A23EE9E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">by agencies</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0034049156274DE9A36DA1380E7B6557"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>States and any contractor, subcontractor, or agent of a State, and the judicial and legislative branches of the United States (as defined in paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively, of section 202(e) of title 18, United States Code), shall have access to, and use of, the Do Not Pay Initiative for the purpose of verifying payment or award eligibility for payments (as defined in section 2(g)(3) of the Improper Payments Information Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3321">31 U.S.C. 3321</external-xref> note)) when, with respect to a State, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget determines that the Do Not Pay Initiative is appropriately established for that State and any contractor, subcontractor, or agent of the State, and, with respect to the judicial and legislative branches of the United States, when the Director of the Office of Management and Budget determines that the Do Not Pay Initiative is appropriately established for the judicial branch or the legislative branch, as applicable. To ensure consistency with the principles of section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Privacy Act of 1974) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget may issue guidance that establishes privacy and other requirements that shall be incorporated into Do Not Pay Initiative access agreements with States, including any contractor, subcontractor, or agent of a State, and the judicial and legislative branches of the United States.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7821FF3AC55F457A86555FF9A556B0EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F8EF95FA9944CBB944ABEAEF6A4A396"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5097089A0EC460D9CD1AC02F0B20D50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H54FEF4D120FA457CBE4E018B0220E60D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H572AE9D578324A00B8773BB4A50C9A28" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H96E381385A024A66B2BF418013526275"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may include States and their quasi-government entities, and the judicial and legislative branches of the United States (as defined in paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively, of section 202(e) of title 18, United States Code) as users of the system in accordance with subsection (b)(3).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCBC5C355DF304B65AB97E8EAA20BFDA1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving the sharing and use of data by government agencies to curb improper payments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Improper Payments Elimination and Recovery Improvement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3321">31 U.S.C. 3321</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H06606B329F794D85AF5950D96207A2A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 5(a)(2), by striking subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC97A87E884174A02BBA4C8C7ED0D771C" style="USC"> 
<subparagraph id="H74797E7C903B4B5F94DCF0E76ED3ECB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The death records maintained by the Commissioner of Social Security.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1AB27168FC647A8A280EE5AA4EBCC80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H75DC0347C2894926B1119176E578795A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1FB9AEB76E48424D8F0EA952BF879C71"><enum>7.</enum><header>Improving the use of data by government agencies for curbing improper payments</header> 
<subsection id="HE16EDDEAB06C41FAA66A7D941EA51F52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prompt reporting of death information by the department of state and the department of defense</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense shall establish a procedure under which each Secretary shall, promptly and on a regular basis, submit information relating to the deaths of individuals to each agency for which the Director of the Office of Management and Budget determines receiving and using such information would be relevant and necessary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9B1CE666AE1F4E9CA68216D350F7A3B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance to agencies regarding data access and use for improper payments purposes</header> <paragraph id="HF9378842082940CFA577740F8D11C187"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, the heads of other relevant Federal, State, and local agencies, and Indian tribes and tribal organizations, as appropriate, shall issue guidance regarding implementation of the Do Not Pay Initiative under section 5 to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD7F2F6675EBC4CD697C32E021273F1A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5972578A9574032A4E1A3217D72BC41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each agency or component of an agency—</text> 
<clause id="H9EB46FCF79E14263A4993E20ED5A0461"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that operates or maintains a database of information described in section 5(a)(2); or</text></clause> <clause id="H44C60E9F5F0F4BEA90B6E89C1D4B228F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which the Director determines improved data matching would be relevant, necessary, or beneficial.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB31549AA80074C3AB91EBC6C5CCF35C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The guidance issued under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA5BC7D9E07E34256AB0F7B50DFF4DB58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address the implementation of subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDC466BA898FF4FD681DB8D2992A07BB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include the establishment of deadlines for access to and use of the databases described in section 5(a)(2) under the Do Not Pay Initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H676AE0B8248340E3B66CCD1D97C1EA2D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Data analytics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Improper Payments Elimination and Recovery Improvement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3321">31 U.S.C. 3321</external-xref> note), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H5A42C5A6738F4C9080546DF902FDE02E" style="USC"> 
<subsection id="H204E953A752544F1B80D951C5DE8863A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report on improper payments data analysis</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Federal Improper Payments Coordination Act of 2015, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to Congress a report which shall include a description of—</text> <paragraph id="H2E5B54E5D52143EAAB9882B582032DD0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data analytics performed as part of the Do Not Pay Business Center operated by the Department of the Treasury for the purpose of detecting, preventing, and recovering improper payments through preaward, postaward prepayment, and postpayment analysis, which shall include a description of any analysis or investigations incorporating—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H124565F5429C4C3F83309F20C7BFE04D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review and data matching of payments and beneficiary enrollment lists of State programs carried out using Federal funds for the purposes of identifying eligibility duplication, residency ineligibility, duplicate payments, or other potential improper payment issues;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79395E82F4764D03A2DAEF0F66A55910"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review of multiple Federal agencies and programs for which comparison of data could show payment duplication; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5378776A54D4FEDAD260B143C9ADF00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>review of other information the Secretary of the Treasury determines could prove effective for identifying, preventing, or recovering improper payments, which may include investigation or review of information from multiple Federal agencies or programs;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24D4FDCA52DE41D9ABDE26DB2B3D1567"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the metrics used in determining whether the analytic and investigatory efforts have reduced, or contributed to the reduction of, improper payments or improper awards; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8A52FBDAB2445E7BA65677FFB84A959"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the target dates for implementing the data analytics operations performed as part of the Do Not Pay Business Center.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20151020">October 20, 2015</action-date> <action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

