<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53429EA951074BAA98F369D883D6BB92" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1219 IH: Arbuckle Project Maintenance Complex and District Office Conveyance Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1219</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150303">March 3, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain land and appurtenances of the Arbuckle Project, Oklahoma, to the Arbuckle Master Conservancy District, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H876C87D199014F29B331FEBD97BA044D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB0CF1792422D42D7BDC63D77AA3739B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Arbuckle Project Maintenance Complex and District Office Conveyance Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD70A06C9D2E4446D98D50277D230A78D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance of maintenance complex and district office of the Arbuckle Project, Oklahoma</header> <subsection id="H6D8D44335D2C459D99F9417C3AD0D9B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may convey to the Arbuckle Master Conservancy District, located in Murray County, Oklahoma, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Maintenance Complex and District Office, Arbuckle Project, Oklahoma, consistent with the terms and conditions set forth in the Agreement between the United States and the Arbuckle Master Conservancy District.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H317BD9F739224E93A5C822E18D2027FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<paragraph id="HE70CEC5E4B1744658921BAA0791B3FE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>The term <term>Agreement</term> means the Agreement between the United States and the Arbuckle Master Conservancy District for Transferring Title to the Federally Owned Maintenance Complex and District Office to the Arbuckle Master Conservancy District (Agreement No. 14AG640141).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E6311ACFAC64440875855837C8F09CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>District office</header><text>The term <term>District Office</term> means the headquarters building located at 2440 East Main, Davis, Oklahoma, and the approximately 0.83 acres described in the Agreement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4B7AAC2B6CA4C1E96AF5F804A07FA3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maintenance complex</header><text>The term <term>Maintenance Complex</term> means the caretakers residence, shop buildings, and any appurtenances located on the lands described in the Agreement, to include approximately 2.00 acres, more or less.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H98A76F629F474BEBA5D12F7CE7F929CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>Effective upon the date of conveyance of the Maintenance Complex and District Office under this section, the United States shall not be held liable by any court for damages of any kind arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence relating to the Maintenance Complex and District Office, except for damages caused by acts of negligence committed by the United States or by its employees or agents prior to the date of conveyance. Nothing in this section increases the liability of the United States beyond that provided in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (popularly known as the <quote>Federal Tort Claims Act</quote>) on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5348A2313AD641A8896F4CDF23B5B715" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Benefits</header><text>After conveyance of the Maintenance Complex and District Office to the Arbuckle Master Conservancy District—</text> <paragraph id="HF2E107838D3543E9AE60CDA5EE386A9A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Maintenance Complex and District Office shall not be considered to be a part of a Federal reclamation project; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H210A2075E103459FAD1AAE6D0ABDC6AD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such water district shall not be eligible to receive any benefits with respect to any facility comprising that Maintenance Complex and District Office, except benefits that would be available to a similarly situated person with respect to such a facility that is not part of a Federal reclamation project.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

