<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE27F6A42A7D5499097377737468923BE" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2408 IH: Child Poverty Reduction Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2408</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150519">May 19, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish in the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services the Federal Interagency Working Group on Reducing Child Poverty to develop a national strategy to eliminate child poverty in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2D738C960681441B951FF2D8F69784AE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFECAC6042FF844F89AD3164144F11636" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Child Poverty Reduction Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA9572FEB72104A59BE2A0CDFC7889BEE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header> <toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="HFECAC6042FF844F89AD3164144F11636" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA9572FEB72104A59BE2A0CDFC7889BEE" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H57471DB8881C4E34A67962123C5BD295" level="title">Title I—Federal Interagency Working Group on Reducing Child Poverty</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HDC39D9204BF14E7884383F1CD041F4D7" level="section">Sec. 101. Establishment of Working Group.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H49FA3F6536B444AE869202C40A7955FD" level="section">Sec. 102. National plan to reduce child poverty.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H0C3D966125614C8BBEE62948BFFE787F" level="section">Sec. 103. Other duties.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H0DB2C19458E649DB9F47DE7AA5B17501" level="section">Sec. 104. Membership.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H9BFBF1F3A9F14D878F6F5E0CED5E5B83" level="section">Sec. 105. Director and staff.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD994BAC1B7BF4F789754D5243C742635" level="section">Sec. 106. Reporting requirements.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA1E0B98E45DE4C85B0B40A7D23EE3B10" level="title">Title II—Workshops by National Academy of Sciences</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA8626764EA8C451FA1EDD4BE2F53CB0A" level="section">Sec. 201. Requirement to enter into agreement with National Academy of Sciences.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H116A9E87100E4274A66B9C9FAFB2F577" level="section">Sec. 202. Workshop topics.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H09F66D49B5F74A87A0800C4FD476783D" level="section">Sec. 203. Reporting requirement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H11E6C0CCCEEA4422BE857ED915518241" level="section">Sec. 204. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HFAF947EC0DAC4EC09641A0E4FC629E64" level="title">Title III—Definitions</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4ABF8844715547799127128C31595464" level="section">Sec. 301. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></section> <title id="H57471DB8881C4E34A67962123C5BD295"><enum>I</enum><header>Federal Interagency Working Group on Reducing Child Poverty</header> <section id="HDC39D9204BF14E7884383F1CD041F4D7"><enum>101.</enum><header>Establishment of Working Group</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established in the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services a group which shall be known as the Federal Interagency Working Group on Reducing Child Poverty (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Working Group</quote>). </text></section> 
<section id="H49FA3F6536B444AE869202C40A7955FD"><enum>102.</enum><header>National plan to reduce child poverty</header> 
<subsection id="H7BEAD558440D4D1DA7D3C66396AA8D29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Primary goal</header> 
<paragraph id="H1618B02A4AD4458888557F369B66A8F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development of national plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The primary goal of the Working Group is to develop a national plan—</text> <subparagraph id="HEFD180C61AFC42E7B5371C2ABB3D5B15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to reduce, within 10 years after the date on which funding is made available to carry out this Act—</text> 
<clause id="H917FFEAADBE64B259FE3DD1DABCEA5E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of children living in poverty in the United States to half of the number of such children as reported in the report of the United States Census Bureau on Income, Poverty, and Health Insurance Coverage in the United States: 2013 (issued in September 2014); and</text></clause> <clause id="HF1896028D7B4473DA31CEB9392E0268F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of children living in extreme poverty in the United States to zero; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3328871D43A14AE4B987191BF4BC3569"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce, within 20 years after the date on which funds are made available to carry out this Act, the number of children living in poverty in the United States to zero.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BC839EBC7884C4D82F72BBF2080881D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation with National Academy of Sciences</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the national plan under paragraph (1), the Working Group shall consider all recommendations, research papers, and reports published by the National Academy of Sciences as a result of the workshops conducted pursuant to title II.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58F318670E0342BDB0F3A19B5A8A1328"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Working Group shall make substantial progress toward the development of the national plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7C10B70784A4421A8A4CF097DE5C73DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional goals</header><text>The national plan under subsection (a) shall include recommendations for achieving the following goals:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC78E183E2B5648C69A884C86CEE83B11"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Understanding the root causes of child poverty, including persistent intergenerational poverty, taking into account social, economic, and cultural factors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0129960BCF449E5A8153A37983AB64A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improving the accessibility of anti-poverty programs and increasing the rate of enrollment in such programs among eligible children and families by reducing the complexity and difficulty of enrolling in such programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H393DF0166BB845CBA024AD0E7AB6855B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Eliminating disparate rates of child poverty based on race, ethnicity, gender, and age.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF19CEE35608B436397F33B837639F022"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improving the ability of individuals living in poverty, low-income individuals, and unemployed individuals to access quality jobs that help children and their families rise above poverty.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA56594FB3C5C4A3CBB92772DF1381975"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Connecting low-income children, disconnected youth, and their families to education, job training, work, and their communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4101973FDC8C45F88860A9A1C556E7E2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Shifting the measures and policies of Federal anti-poverty programs from the goal of helping individuals and families living in poverty to achieve freedom from deprivation toward the goal of helping such individuals and families rise above poverty and achieve long-term economic stability.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H87D3153548E74281A78C1F0F96C26538"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Methods</header><text>In developing the national plan under subsection (a), the Working Group shall employ methods for achieving the goals described in subsections (a) and (b) that include—</text> <paragraph id="HD02A94F3A4824DE5A8B5A58CBBF9CEE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entering into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences for a workshop series on the economic and social costs of child poverty, as described in title II; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAEB1DAE4B9F040BDB0018A470FE4B827"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">studying the effect of child poverty on the health and welfare of children, including the access of children living in poverty to health care, housing, proper nutrition, and education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A069DE81BFF4967B8399227E55FBD9A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measuring the effect of child poverty on the ability of individuals to achieve economic stability, including such effect on educational attainment, rates of incarceration, lifetime earnings, access to healthcare, and access to housing;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43817CF1032042EBA530DC9389D41D25"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">updating and applying improved measures of poverty that can meaningfully account for other aspects relating to the measure of poverty, such as the Supplemental Poverty Measure used by the United States Census Bureau; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H554EEF35580945D69152FD802A503EDB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using and applying fact-based measures to evaluate the long-term effectiveness of anti-poverty programs, taking into account the long-term savings and value to the Federal Government and to State, local, and tribal governments of practices and policies designed to prevent poverty.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0C3D966125614C8BBEE62948BFFE787F"><enum>103.</enum><header>Other duties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to developing the national plan under section 102(a), the Working Group shall—</text> <paragraph id="H5C9AB28A2E9B4FF98555DA1648BBBED5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor, in consultation with the Domestic Policy Council and the National Economic Council, all Federal activities, programs, and services related to child welfare and child poverty;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1CDF28A634D408FA51061AA9C9D7162"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish guidelines, policies, goals, and directives related to the achievement of the goals of the national plan, in consultation with non-governmental entities providing social services to low-income children and families, advocacy groups that directly represent low-income children and families, policy experts, and officials of State, local, and tribal governments who administer or direct policy for anti-poverty programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1EBF3CD3C5341A2BC2B5631CE367F13"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise all relevant Federal agencies regarding how to effectively administer and coordinate programs, activities, and services related to child welfare and child poverty and how to resolve any disputes that arise between or among such agencies as a result of such administration or coordination;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67CA1133BA9B4DA3B096C0295DEFCFE5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide recommendations to the Congress regarding how to ensure that Federal agencies administering programs, activities, and services related to child welfare and child poverty have adequate resources to increase public awareness of such programs, activities, and services and how to maximize enrollment of eligible individuals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB659FAFF7B774801A053057BD41B8434"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify methods for improving communication and collaboration among and between State and Federal governmental entities regarding the implementation of State programs related to child welfare and child poverty, such as State programs funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (relating to block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families), and submit recommendations regarding such methods to relevant Federal agencies and congressional committees; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56CDA0A50EDC4D849E5CDB04EF70445E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hold hearings in different geographic regions of the United States to collect information and feedback from the public regarding personal experiences related to child poverty and anti-poverty programs, and make such information and feedback publicly available.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H0DB2C19458E649DB9F47DE7AA5B17501"><enum>104.</enum><header>Membership</header> <subsection id="H1EC355D8E10F47F78574CD6030AC3845"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number of members</header><text>The Working Group shall be composed of no less than 6 members.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H21835CEC657E4011869F583E1CBB3581"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Executive pay rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member shall be an official of an Executive Department who occupies a position for which the rate of pay is equal to or greater than the rate of pay for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H389F333536CC433CAB01C895A76CA852"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required participation of certain Executive departments</header><text>The Working Group shall include at least one member who is an official of each of the following Executive departments:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9AF0AC592D684BB08E802E8A1BF85BCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61B03EF9524C45B1BD198D117AA9636E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7772322D9BD8469095F905872A1677E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Labor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6335DE80B67B471EBD1F777A0055DB9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CE0FB5EDC4B41E28295802922794DA1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6373C1F45C8C4EA3A2301FCD8A3E171F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H83E6626E697E4D61A676536F643A0D1A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member shall be appointed by the head of the Executive department that employs such member.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3588995C8D784CD6BABC6A389158DF5F" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Obtaining official data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On request of the Chairperson, any head of a Federal agency shall furnish directly to the Working Group any information necessary to enable the Working Group to carry out this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H04C4F742D3FD48619D949D00F8ADF7D6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member shall be appointed for the life of the Working Group.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFC92FD6CE1BB4086B22DD81360C2B624"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCED303E6C666441AB0F223256C8D1787"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of members shall constitute a quorum.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1F6CE1AE05D4420FAFB41A42F67AAC95"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairperson of the Working Group shall be appointed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E8BA005704743ED98D9D9D065F928A7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Meetings</header> 
<paragraph id="H427AA3E1295E4C02A3ED6BEBC7945EC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial meeting period</header><text>The Working Group shall meet on a monthly basis during the 180-day period beginning with the date on which funds are made available to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF67FFE4FF3A14CD8904906BD91A9E027"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After such 180-day period, the Working Group shall meet not less than once every 6 months and at the call of the Chairperson or a majority of members.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9BFBF1F3A9F14D878F6F5E0CED5E5B83"><enum>105.</enum><header>Director and staff</header> 
<subsection id="H4572C56AEC6348D79A0E27C7B065AFA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Working Group shall have a Director who shall be appointed by the Chairperson.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H896DF4D2DFE24B1C8895BC6E23F89F03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may appoint and fix the pay of additional personnel as the Director considers appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H880EF6DD3D5F45AFBB579459CDCC5B58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Director and staff shall be to achieve the goals and carry out the duties of the Working Group.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD994BAC1B7BF4F789754D5243C742635"><enum>106.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> <subsection id="H73D220FD32284C2FA06E01664CA0896C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2016, and annually thereafter, the Chairperson shall submit to the Congress a report describing the activities, projects, and plans of the Federal Government to carry out the goals of the Working Group, which shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0D0A340DAD2744B683883647534B2924"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accounting of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0A01887C9544FF6B40AB48D63036C31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any increase in efficiency in the delivery of Federal, State, local, and tribal social services and benefits related to child welfare and child poverty;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7EA01678BD14464DA531A445632E6EF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any reduction in the number of children living in poverty;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE06608A2EB414929BCF553A5DEB1468F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any reduction in the demand for such social services and benefits for which children living in poverty and near poverty are eligible; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD86DF6432FA247FDB6194E3679375E2B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any savings to the Federal Government as a result of such increases or reductions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3BE2819574CB412B8EBE6C822AC00770"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an accounting of any increase in the national rate of employment due to the efforts of the Working Group;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9F8805650AA412D9626832E0021F467"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the efforts of each State to reduce child poverty within such State, including the administration of State programs funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (relating to block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0427A75151CB4455A7672B9FEA1FFEAF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>legislative language and recommendations regarding reducing child poverty and achieving the other goals and duties of the Working Group.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB74FEE3295074D2BB0E7A9BB4DCA19C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public reporting requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HE0DAF8A163F2415FBEF9F38C4CFFB204"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report available to public</header><text>A version of the annual report required by subsection (a) shall be made publicly available.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H223CFF61B9BC431A94DA7575C4930582"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual update from Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each relevant Federal agency shall post on the public Internet Web site of such agency an annual summary of any plans, activities, and results of the agency related to the goals and duties of the Working Group.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title> 
<title id="HA1E0B98E45DE4C85B0B40A7D23EE3B10"><enum>II</enum><header>Workshops by National Academy of Sciences</header> 
<section id="HA8626764EA8C451FA1EDD4BE2F53CB0A"><enum>201.</enum><header>Requirement to enter into agreement with National Academy of Sciences</header> 
<subsection id="H5D3096A00BC6428B80F89B295C52025D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which funds are made available to carry out this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences for 2 public workshops to provide the Working Group with information to assist in the development of the national plan under section 102(a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H04C25892A1704AD3A89E7B81790BF11D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Steering committee</header><text>The agreement under subsection (a) shall include the creation of a steering committee to plan and conduct such workshops.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H21E83601079A4297B6107243FD77299D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Experts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agreement under subsection (a) shall include the commission of experts to prepare research papers that summarize and critique literature on the economic and social costs of child poverty.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H116A9E87100E4274A66B9C9FAFB2F577"><enum>202.</enum><header>Workshop topics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of the workshops required by section 201(a) shall be to collect information and input from the public on the economic and social costs of child poverty, addressing topics that include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H10A83336E1A94E47ADA861840A7F5509"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the macroeconomic costs of child poverty, including the effects of child poverty on productivity and economic output;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB71BFCC38C464D59BFB12A6323751CDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the health-related costs of child poverty, including the costs incurred by the Federal Government and State, local, and tribal governments due to child illnesses, other child medical problems, and other child health-related expenditures;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FB3D6EEC8F2404D9B455F2952CD7831"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the effect of child poverty on crime rates;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1E71277033D42EB9F7CD217CA1BC9CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the short-term and long-term effects of child poverty on the Federal budget, including outlays for anti-poverty programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A591D14B0A4467E90B8E72EC37AAC00"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">poverty metrics such as income poverty, food insecurity, and other measures of deprivation, and the role of such metrics in assessing the effects of poverty and the performance of anti-poverty programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4EDF785F4F4441FAF518F06D8713ECA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the effect of child poverty on certain population groups, including immigrants, single parent families, individuals who have attained the age of 16 but have not attained the age of 25 with large student loans, individuals living in areas of concentrated poverty, and individuals living on Indian reservations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3E9E2B412FA444684D34604B2A20CF6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the effect of child poverty on individuals and families living in extreme poverty, as compared with such effect on individuals and families living in poverty or near poverty. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="H09F66D49B5F74A87A0800C4FD476783D"><enum>203.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header> <subsection id="H4BD24F7F25724642B8FD40441BE9043B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research papers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agreement under section 201(a) shall include the publication of the research papers required under such section on the public Web site of the National Academy of Sciences.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98428C2BE54A4E2AA3A86D5D8A80A8AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Workshop summary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agreement under section 201(a) shall include the publication of a summary of each workshop required under such section on the public Web site of the National Academy of Sciences.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H11E6C0CCCEEA4422BE857ED915518241"><enum>204.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 to carry out this title. </text></section></title> 
<title id="HFAF947EC0DAC4EC09641A0E4FC629E64"><enum>III</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<section id="H4ABF8844715547799127128C31595464"><enum>301.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H7AE8623ACE014AEB9C92BAA5DB673EE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Anti-poverty program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>anti-poverty program</quote> means a program or institution with the primary goal of lifting children or families out of poverty and improving economic opportunities for children or families that operates in whole or in part using Federal, State, local, or tribal government funds.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2341AEB6FD24758BD5204EF66F389D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <quote>child</quote> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA283A93AE31F44E7AE9E9DCB4AEEB5DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deprivation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>deprivation</quote> means, with respect to an individual, that such individual lacks adequate nutrition, health care, housing, or other resources to provide for basic human needs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4CFE7C37B5D4DF98436DF6CF17930DB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disconnected youth</header><text>The term <quote>disconnected youth</quote> means individuals who have attained the age of 16 but have not attained the age of 25 who are unemployed and not enrolled in school.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAE9871259DD420087326AF852E59702"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Economic stability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>economic stability</quote> means, with respect to an individual or family, that such individual or family has access to the means and support necessary to effectively cope with adverse or costly life events and to effectively recover from the consequences of such events while maintaining a decent standard of living.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE66162E7729D4DC0915DC301C6BCCC62"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Extreme poverty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>extreme poverty</quote> means, with respect to an individual or family, that such individual or family has a total annual income that is less than the amount that is 50 percent of the official poverty threshold for such individual or family, as provided in the report of the United States Census Bureau on Income, Poverty, and Health Insurance Coverage in the United States: 2013 (issued in September 2014).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A432E4104794133AEB2CB0215263A2E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Federal agency</quote> means an Executive department, a Government corporation, and an independent establishment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A50EBEAE2794C5E92E2DF09E2BCB3CA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Near poverty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>near poverty</quote> means, with respect to an individual or family, that such individual or family has a total annual income that is less than the amount that is 200 percent of the official poverty threshold for such individual or family, as provided in the report of the United States Census Bureau on Income, Poverty, and Health Insurance Coverage in the United States: 2013 (issued in September 2014).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C94C6593D2D4431B1B46071F35CD69B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Poverty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>poverty</quote> means, with respect to an individual or family, that such individual or family has a total annual income that is less than the amount that is the official poverty threshold for such individual or family, as provided in the report of the United States Census Bureau on Income, Poverty, and Health Insurance Coverage in the United States: 2013 (issued in September 2014).</text></paragraph></section></title> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


