<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCC481F6D31C743DC87BC126F6DDC4A6F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3968 IH: Stop Meth Labs and Enhance Patient Access Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3968</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000570">Mr. Guinta</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Controlled Substances Act to allow the Attorney General to exempt a product from
			 certain requirements if the Attorney General determines that it is not
			 practical by processes known to be employed by clandestine laboratory
			 operators to use the product in the illicit manufacture of
			 methamphetamine.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H74902A9BBCF74A568034CB85AE2675BA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H84675EB07670479F9FAEF55D8C159129" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Meth Labs and Enhance Patient Access Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAB875176E0CD4FEFBB6B7431DA15DAA7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption for products if it is not practical by processes known to be employed by clandestine laboratory operators to use the products in the illicit manufacture of methamphetamine</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 310(e)(3) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/830">21 U.S.C. 830(e)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>if the Attorney General determines that the product cannot be used in the illicit manufacture of methamphetamine</quote> and inserting <quote>if the Attorney General determines that it is not practical by processes known to be employed by clandestine laboratory operators to use the product in the illicit manufacture of methamphetamine</quote>.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


