<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA66188DF0D704728B910C548789DFF6C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1083 IH: Medicaid Physician Self-Referral Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1083</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150225">February 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to apply the Medicare restriction on
			 self-referral to State plan requirements under Medicaid, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H88D0C573B8764D7D8A46885D18517F92" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCFE9FE0FBF484CE881097A50E288647D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Physician Self-Referral Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H15E3A21A5E93460AA4EACF9607FB6909" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adjustments to restriction on self-referral under Medicaid</header> <subsection id="H35DD7F488A874C16BB1948BBA3DF7C83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of restriction on receipt of Federal funds in the case of self-Referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (s) of section 1903 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H67A770A5592E45548498EE8871737763"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement of restriction on self-Referral in State plan requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1902 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H007D97775F9B404EBB08D7325729CF3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H60D3879971A84C968928AD7AE4122FD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (80) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE16A6687C35047DE93F6EC98888EE585"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (81) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F1F68B7FE624AE6B068E664C7D09ABE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (81) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83E031132CF345B5BB0738D20DA949C9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA2409BCFBCDB4146B3E807D052B2344D"><enum>(82)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that no payment may be made under the State plan for a Medicaid designated health service furnished to an individual on the basis of a referral by a physician if the physician (or an immediate family member of the physician) has an ownership or investment interest or a compensation arrangement (as defined in section 1877) with the entity furnishing the Medicaid designated health service that would not comply with section 1877 if the referral were for an item or service otherwise payable under title XVIII.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB48A27CBB994696BF82A0C1763C939A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after the matter immediately following paragraph (82) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98FAFCC29B984F65B501B9C40F2795C3" style="OLC"> <quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="section">For purposes of paragraph (82), subsections (f) and (g) of section 1877 shall apply to a provider of a Medicaid designated health service in a similar manner as such subsections apply to a provider of an item or service for which payment may be made under title XVIII.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6B4F75F4164428A9435A28926E742C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28CE6D1919F94A38827C361E615975DD" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H2B0195CF957B475AB51E26CBD8230785"><enum>(ll)</enum><header>Definition of Medicaid designated health service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a) the term <quote>Medicaid designated health service</quote> means an item or service listed in subsection (h)(6) of section 1877 as covered by a State plan and any other service a State may choose to add for purposes of subsection (a)(82).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H513E4B3AFDE84151AFD1B008458124AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of False Claims Act to violations of self-Referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1877(g) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF374E005859043F99C2B8C33845CDEFF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H06848ABBB8794A3C9C40ADEF9E8DBF80"><enum>(7)</enum><header>False Claims Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claim that includes an item or service resulting from a violation of this section constitutes a false or fraudulent claim for purposes of sections 3729–3733 of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4DA5BE4615B6454CA5C6E056DF452B9B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions for violations of self-Referral limited to Medicaid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1877(h) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC083C7EBD3364D2EAAC2B7AA968B259C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H9DA4A52C3E2A44EAAF356C038AB1337D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Medicaid self-Referral limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any authority of the Secretary to issue regulations under this section shall include the authority to issue regulations limited to the application of self-referral limitations to State plan requirements, as described under section 1902(a)(82) of this Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(82)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9387F7BE6CF04143828AABFC742CF529"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Medicaid self-Referral disclosure protocol</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a protocol consistent with the requirements of the Medicare self-referral disclosure protocol required under section 6409 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn</external-xref> note) that enables health care providers to disclose an actual or potential violation of section 1877 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn</external-xref>) as applied to title XIX of such Act, pursuant to section 1902(a)(82) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(82)</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H53E283F8B84E402D8BC1BD7596D9B19A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H94B21B459BAB4A68B56305198A0EE805"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by this Act shall apply to items and services furnished after the first day of the first calendar year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D6405CFB5384FBD949B598B2EAF517C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for State legislation</header><text>In the case of a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the respective plan to meet any requirement imposed by amendments made by this Act, the respective plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet such an additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


