<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFF1F807FC7944374807E408D8B128D7B" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3249 IH: Mid-Mississippi Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3249</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to the Pat Harrison Waterway District approximately 8,307 acres of National Forest System land within the Bienville National Forests in Mississippi, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0B90FD595E2E4D848DE3659B5611BF26" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAE001954976F47619C5CDF148B013010" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mid-Mississippi Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H68A9729BD11C4F42A9360D5C9614D534"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance to the Pat Harrison Waterway District of the State of Mississippi</header> <subsection id="H592B5275FD14424AB64910052866A698"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall convey to the Pat Harrison Waterway District, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the approximately 8,307 acres of National Forest System land within the Bienville National Forests of Mississippi identified as <quote>Oakohay/Little Oakohay Lake, Smith County, Mississippi</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Mid-Mississippi Conservation, Recreation and Development</quote> and dated April 2, 2014.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0DCF970A144A43F187E1C937F14E0BD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>If determined by the Secretary of Agriculture to be necessary, the exact acreage and legal description of the National Forest System land shall be determined by a survey approved by the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBB52AB9ECA3946EF8F61993522A99B46"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of land</header><text>As a condition of the conveyance under subsection (a), the Pat Harrison Waterway District shall use the land conveyed under subsection (a) only for public purposes consistent with the laws of the State of Mississippi.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H1027D99777724D95A1180DACA8931157"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reversionary interest</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any parcel of land conveyed under this title ceases to be used for the public purpose for which the parcel was conveyed, the parcel shall, at the discretion of the Secretary, based on a determination that reversion is in the best interests of the United States, revert to the United States.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

