<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB1A3526D1B5A4EADB8AABD45ADA8BF1A" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1223 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prevent the retroactive claim of the earned income tax credit after issuance of a social security number.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1223</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150303">March 3, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000449">Mr. Fortenberry</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prevent the retroactive claim of the earned income tax credit after issuance of a social security number.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9C545D12F3A14E5EA1B9CF5475BF3B40" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF7CC04CC52D447BAB85E189E64992138" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prevention of retroactive claims of earned income credit after issuance of social security number</header> 
<subsection id="H52D2A9BDF1DF44CBAB35B819892CEC90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32">Section 32(m)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H13AB789A683840B1B2D9C72362C36E61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>before the close of the taxable year to which the return relates</quote> before the period at the end, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAC4444D8DF24B35B665A155CD12C6E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of the preceding sentence, a social security number issued after the close of any taxable year shall be treated as issued before the close of such taxable year if the taxpayer demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the individual with respect to whom such social security number was issued was eligible for the issuance of such social security number before the close of such taxable year.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H38639D4C2DB14DAA9CC3D99679F67A10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to any return of tax, and any amendment or supplement to any return of tax, which is filed after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


