<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H86C6793785AD49B1B9AD58A3BFAB1EF1" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1029 RH: EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 22</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1029</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 114–33]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150224">February 24, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000182">Mr. Neugebauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20150302">March 2, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="B000213">Mr. Barton</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action> 
<action-date date="20150302">March 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 24, 2015</action-instruction> 
</action> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 to provide for Scientific Advisory Board member qualifications, public participation, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HSY00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HC22A460D067B49BF8530A19083684F3F"> 
<section id="H50B13D2A8B6E4F4A8B7D576BB4FE402E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4DDC814E1BC8443CB85C5D9A8E97A528" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Science Advisory Board</header> <subsection id="HEA760442C9EC426F89B2DE6EAC4D7B5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Independent advice</header><text>Section 8(a) of the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4365">42 U.S.C. 4365(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>independently</quote> after <quote>Advisory Board which shall</quote>. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB27FFA3A2F9B4607B9F469A7EBEA5A13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(b) of the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4365">42 U.S.C. 4365(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C7925F8FD87413297B3861E11518A07" style="traditional"> <subsection id="H3CC7ABE4A1ED4D4284DFD90D9CA5E167"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H783F558121424E0E9FB5B30411B286B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall be composed of at least nine members, one of whom shall be designated Chairman, and shall meet at such times and places as may be designated by the Chairman.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD2A096B1D7E4D48A186130EE0BF6025" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the Board shall be qualified by education, training, and experience to evaluate scientific and technical information on matters referred to the Board under this section. The Administrator shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCCDD239FE16443F08645EBA2FFAB14A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the scientific and technical points of view represented on and the functions to be performed by the Board are fairly balanced among the members of the Board;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD2A75DCC3CC54DEE8E516E0DFD7B1846"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least ten percent of the membership of the Board are from State, local, or tribal governments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7464628E20AC4FD7BD63BF166AD09AC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>persons with substantial and relevant expertise are not excluded from the Board due to affiliation with or representation of entities that may have a potential interest in the Board’s advisory activities, so long as that interest is fully disclosed to the Administrator and the public and appointment to the Board complies with section 208 of title 18, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEEC6EED081C4F029C33479462EBD6CF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a Board advisory activity on a particular matter involving a specific party, no Board member having an interest in the specific party shall participate in that activity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA767B781200B4F138408490970FD630B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Board members may not participate in advisory activities that directly or indirectly involve review or evaluation of their own work, unless fully disclosed to the public and the work has been externally peer-reviewed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71A358B3996A4D199F215BA35D9282E3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Board members shall be designated as special Government employees; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08317EBA186C441C8DA70694E01F4B48"><enum>(G)</enum><text>no registered lobbyist is appointed to the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42DEC37C95114C44932539D82C944B30" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H4006E0404A6D48EC9E76E905ACD249B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicit public nominations for the Board by publishing a notification in the Federal Register;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9D8799D7FDE40E9AF460D0E9FC262C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit nominations from relevant Federal agencies, including the Departments of Agriculture, Defense, Energy, the Interior, and Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H94947D6BD17D4AFAB2DA3477FB8449DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make public the list of nominees, including the identity of the entities that nominated each, and shall accept public comment on the nominees;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C33857774F04F74946E7EB3DFA3B416"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require that, upon their provisional nomination, nominees shall file a written report disclosing financial relationships and interests, including Environmental Protection Agency grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, or other financial assistance, that are relevant to the Board’s advisory activities for the three-year period prior to the date of their nomination, and relevant professional activities and public statements for the five-year period prior to the date of their nomination; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC435F514B6C042B8B726F80E72E43792"><enum>(E)</enum><text>make such reports public, with the exception of specific dollar amounts, for each member of the Board upon such member’s selection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB367B0BE50334CBBA406332DB8825364" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disclosure of relevant professional activities under paragraph (3)(D) shall include all representational work, expert testimony, and contract work as well as identifying the party for which the work was done.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DCE6AEEE67D44FC8E56971DA5E449BD" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except when specifically prohibited by law, the Agency shall make all conflict of interest waivers granted to members of the Board, member committees, or investigative panels publicly available.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC856C99CCCAE4D88BFAF29780FDBB7DF" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any recusal agreement made by a member of the Board, a member committee, or an investigative panel, or any recusal known to the Agency that occurs during the course of a meeting or other work of the Board, member committee, or investigative panel shall promptly be made public by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67810759A190434EA0F6E3C9508738F3" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms of the members of the Board shall be three years and shall be staggered so that the terms of no more than one-third of the total membership of the Board shall expire within a single fiscal year. No member shall serve more than two terms over a ten-year period.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F15A0D3E6FA42109D2B86F89D605E02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Record</header><text>Section 8(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4365">42 U.S.C. 4365(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H41EB6A397739424EBD068649881C1779"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3AC36253918E43CF8E3EFAF0AE3225B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or draft risk or hazard assessment,</quote> after <quote>at the time any proposed</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7087AA60071E4918ACBC16F92A5E2347"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>formal</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05D8B17E104A43E4B6F950F0AD672C49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or draft risk or hazard assessment,</quote> after <quote>to the Board such proposed</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62DBB5B954034D88825890CBCF0A2BE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1FFF966F799D46EFA7A7F5648DBF028B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>or draft risk or hazard assessment,</quote> after <quote>the scientific and technical basis of the proposed</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74E75A8D70FE44CB98A3596F04D96AF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Board’s advice and comments, including dissenting views of Board members, and the response of the Administrator shall be included in the record with respect to any proposed risk or hazard assessment, criteria document, standard, limitation, or regulation and published in the Federal Register.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H534B33AF88924E0485FFFAFD09EED55F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Member committees and investigative panels</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(e)(1)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4365">42 U.S.C. 4365(e)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: “These member committees and investigative panels—</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H112F78AD2D364952B4E44C3CAD1413CC" style="traditional"> <clause id="HAF4511C08D3E41248EECF9A3D7D319FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be constituted and operate in accordance with the provisions set forth in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (b), in subsection (h), and in subsection (i);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5B27650B5BC247549C7DB28E577435CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>do not have authority to make decisions on behalf of the Board; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8AEE8D071AE74597A8137FCB0AFE81DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may not report directly to the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D64F205CE91419DB94EC7D8DB93501C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4365">42 U.S.C. 4365</external-xref>) is amended by amending subsection (h) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34EA2B7731384A5FBA625A630F8F06F8" style="traditional"> <subsection id="H45E1361CF826462FB4EFBEDD68319364"><enum>(h)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H82B2823E20324320AB434F889F321B31"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To facilitate public participation in the advisory activities of the Board, the Administrator and the Board shall make public all reports and relevant scientific information and shall provide materials to the public at the same time as received by members of the Board.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H462EBE033E8B40CFAE39034464C9A3AE" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Prior to conducting major advisory activities, the Board shall hold a public information-gathering session to discuss the state of the science related to the advisory activity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3952C23908B342E0AE01DE962D610BF9" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prior to convening a member committee or investigative panel under subsection (e) or requesting scientific advice from the Board, the Administrator shall accept, consider, and address public comments on questions to be asked of the Board. The Board, member committees, and investigative panels shall accept, consider, and address public comments on such questions and shall not accept a question that unduly narrows the scope of an advisory activity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1276CB32DE6C447F964CEC0016BEF342" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator and the Board shall encourage public comments, including oral comments and discussion during the proceedings, that shall not be limited by an insufficient or arbitrary time restriction. Public comments shall be provided to the Board when received. The Board’s reports shall include written responses to significant comments offered by members of the public to the Board.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H474B639787C441B18D4F2319DBF82198" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Following Board meetings, the public shall be given 15 calendar days to provide additional comments for consideration by the Board.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEADEB0D185A544E181D94A1A70C63C03"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4365">42 U.S.C. 4365</external-xref>) is further amended by amending subsection (i) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5697D5C29424E5CA16E17A3BC838855" style="traditional"> <subsection id="H845B50336BD5493A9BE17AE277D98EA3"><enum>(i)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8D697711E40E415EB644CB78103AEE67"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out its advisory activities, the Board shall strive to avoid making policy determinations or recommendations, and, in the event the Board feels compelled to offer policy advice, shall explicitly distinguish between scientific determinations and policy advice.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FB1F5569FBC4F9FAD526802DB80ADDE" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall clearly communicate uncertainties associated with the scientific advice provided to the Administrator or Congress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AC61B7546FF4496B42841053BB9275B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall ensure that advice and comments reflect the views of the members and shall encourage dissenting members to make their views known to the public, the Administrator, and Congress.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H471D75978C2F4408B042F20333FBE169" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall conduct periodic reviews to ensure that its advisory activities are addressing the most important scientific issues affecting the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA17DA8DB43440A981DF37DE04E48EF4" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Board shall be fully and timely responsive to Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BD6A9FCF9F9425E9F4FEE57803D0E93" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Relation to the Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed as supplanting the requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></section> <section id="HD5E86EF1618C4EA5AC25B3610948247C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Relation to the Ethics in Government Act of 1978</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed as supplanting the requirements of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
<endorsement display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20150302">March 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> 
</bill> 


