<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9DBA6DDDFEE84236805ED3EBEFD6972F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3660 IH: To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 respecting the scoring of preventive health savings.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3660</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151001">October 1, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000445">Mr. Forbes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000064">Mr. Young of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 respecting the scoring of preventive health savings.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5049849C8F8A495896C489FA38471006" style="OLC">
 <section id="H66C25FA4E39443DF8A0E94CFF67653C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Scoring of preventive health savings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/602">2 U.S.C. 602</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA364FAAF3FDD479293AE3B024240B6EB" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H11E5DC96F46E4B64A8DCEDDB559CF7D4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Scoring of preventive health savings</header>
 <paragraph id="H1EBEFB983CF04C16A6BE514AAD1894DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination by the Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon a request by the chairman or ranking minority member of the Committee on the Budget, the Committee on Finance, or the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, or by the chairman or ranking minority member of the Committee on the Budget, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, or the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Director shall determine if a proposed measure would result in reductions in budget outlays in budgetary outyears through the use of preventive health and preventive health services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2732282968AA444ABAF709D47BE36563"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Projections</header><text>If the Director determines that a measure would result in substantial reductions in budget outlays as described in paragraph (1), the Director—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCC72DB2961EE4B93A7AE22EF70F070F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include, in any projection prepared by the Director, a description and estimate of the reductions in budget outlays in the budgetary outyears and a description of the basis for such conclusions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B859F32C1548EAB5EEDB8EDAD83988"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may prepare a budget projection that includes some or all of the budgetary outyears, notwithstanding the time periods for projections described in subsection (e) and sections 308, 402, and 424.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H444EBB0E9BC34C9FA3B318203B25F14F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H38862D91A6734C588EF420C6BD9F9634"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>preventive health</term> means an action that focuses on the health of the public, individuals and defined populations in order to protect, promote, and maintain health and wellness and prevent disease, disability, and premature death that is demonstrated by credible and publicly available evidence from epidemiological projection models, clinical trials, observational studies in humans, longitudinal studies, and meta-analysis; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BC7DC9790284F72B0249CAC5F0C1F2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>budgetary outyears</term> means the 2 consecutive 10-year periods beginning with the first fiscal year that is 10 years after the budget year provided for in the most recently agreed to concurrent resolution on the budget.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


