<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB9D1F26F573046B6BF4107EAF378029C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3241 IH: State-Based Universal Health Care Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3241</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to authorize the establishment
			 of, and provide support for, State-based universal health care systems
			 that provide comprehensive health benefits to State residents, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4249564F6BCD47A5A9890E81F183978C" style="OLC">
		<section id="H8C24707020D142D2B5358B64AAA153FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; purpose</header>
 <subsection id="H2DB87879312745F6950C10E675698FF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State-Based Universal Health Care Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H60AA5DCBC14A4644AB0F7469FC68923B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to establish a flexible framework under which each State can provide comprehensive universal health coverage to all of its residents.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H49401286173C458CBA5633CEED56EC50"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waiver for State universal health care</header>
 <subsection id="H12271FB6870646C2AA1D431B4E0B3BD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle D of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 1332 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18052">42 U.S.C. 18052</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C1682F1B2BA43A680C39B6E0A79842C" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD1672AEF164741AB99A8EE3893309C34"><enum>1332A.</enum><header>Waiver for State universal health care</header>
						<subsection id="HEB39BCBAE3C04DCF97D785FD28C697D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="HD3462434FE5E433DA5C9246EB2511091"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State may apply to the Secretary (as defined in subsection (g)(3)) for the waiver of so much of the requirements described in paragraph (2) with respect to health benefits coverage within that State for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2016, as is necessary to implement a comprehensive State universal health care plan in the State under this section. Such application shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA33B1E1CA07F442EAAA52360E7C95DA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be filed at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4843B0755974A35A1FA40057E8FD26E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contain such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text>
 <clause id="HB5E90E88C60B4A88B8832D00D5C894D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a comprehensive description of the State legislation and program to implement a plan meeting the requirements for a waiver under this section; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H636CD7B9D9894CA39B21B0024B104350"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a 10-fiscal-year budget plan for such plan that is budget neutral for the Federal Government; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05E209BC177849DF8AEF7820430F69F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide an assurance that the State has enacted the law described in subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDAC38764CE5488C9B3D5733B4048E7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The requirements described in this paragraph with respect to health benefits coverage within the State for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2016, are as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H87197ADF40FF4848841716F74CEB2246"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Parts I, II, and III of subtitle D.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F9434D2FD59423281513C3D0C5E167A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1402.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0688938715674B0FB1DE7DB1C0E7A08F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Sections 36B, 4980H, and 5000A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC79B12AB97894C40B77661009791DC95"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Title XI of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC579F6E5565548BBA44AFB68833CBEF4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BB6CE49525044E892139EE285A9E7B8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Title XIX of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H920A6D3907D34D669405425FC5C224EC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Title XXI of the Social Security Act.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CC7C6A3DC1247EAA0855F661537E971"><enum>(H)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">Chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5 of the United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A0301D5068C43C482B7A29081EEEAFD"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">Chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, including coverage under the TRICARE program.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65F1CC09963248B5A6095958ED250D5C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Section 514 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB17C21786D0F47E4A595A03C6A256AB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pass through of funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a State waiver under paragraph (1), under which the State assumes responsibility for health coverage under a specified Federal health program, including under each of the Federal health care or subsidy programs specified in subparagraphs (B), (C), (E), (F), (G), and (H) of paragraph (2), the Secretary shall not spend Federal health funds that would otherwise have been spent for such program and shall provide for an alternative means by which the aggregate amount of such funds shall be paid to the State for purposes of implementing the State plan under the waiver. Such amount shall be determined annually by the Secretary, taking into account the amount that would otherwise have been spent under such Federal health program with respect to residents of such State, if such waiver did not apply. Such amount shall include funds equal to the amount of premium tax credits, cost-sharing reductions, or small-business credits under sections 36B and 45R of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or under section 1402 that would have been available to individuals and businesses in the State if such waiver did not apply.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H6742347AE6C74CA084CED0B5917D375B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver consideration and transparency</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9A2ADD6D334A4762A77E1287553CA0F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An application for a waiver under this section shall be considered by the Secretary in accordance with the regulations described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41E65F62B9DB4F699A9FCBEF3535E4EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>State-Based Universal Health Care Act of 2015</short-title>, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations relating to waivers under this section that provide—</text> <clause id="HA480158821BD4C1A8F7D85B8856BF327"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a process for public notice and comment at the State level, including public hearings, sufficient to ensure a meaningful level of public input;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A05D1BE432B42DBA96CFB3C0B14C495"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a process for the submission of an application that ensures the disclosure of—</text> <subclause id="HE8DC08BA08484BCD8CA7FFEA79C224CD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the provisions of law that the State involved seeks to waive; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H102C513CAD0E44A38203C166059D9B7F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the specific plans of the State to ensure that the waiver will be in compliance with subsection (b);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H794F915E564444BD94DFC2BA145F875D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a process for providing public notice and comment after the application is received by the Secretary, that is sufficient to ensure a meaningful level of public input and that does not impose requirements that are in addition to, or duplicative of, requirements imposed under the Administrative Procedure Act, or requirements that are unreasonable or unnecessarily burdensome with respect to State compliance;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC9F83D9DE4204D0D8299E637492F2EEA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a process for the submission to the Secretary of periodic reports by the State concerning the implementation of the program under the waiver; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE64A1B9B96D04004A7A78DE84B6DDB04"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a process for the periodic evaluation by the Secretary with respect to waivers granted under this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7B4B30F3A214DA5873A7BEA1D42E0D4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall annually report to Congress concerning actions taken by the Secretary with respect to applications for waivers, and programs conducted through waivers granted, under this section.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1F485615FAD4539B38D0AAC4B246CC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Granting of waivers</header>
 <paragraph id="H4D153D2C00754D259623D5906911D205"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may grant a request for a waiver under subsection (a)(1) only if the Secretary determines that the State plan—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H66B524B143714533A816EE2AE93945AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will provide health benefits coverage to State residents that is at least as comprehensive as the health benefits coverage that such residents would have received<italic></italic> under the specified Federal health program for which such residents would have been eligible, absent such waiver;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC3D361F1A284608A2ED568F39A60956"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will provide coverage and cost sharing protections against excessive out-of-pocket spending to State residents that are at least as affordable as the coverage and cost sharing protections under the specified Federal health program for which such residents would have been eligible, absent such waiver;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA77F8EBC4634724ADDA15611430E057"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will provide coverage to substantially all residents of the State, including substantially all those otherwise covered under the Federal health care or subsidy programs specified in subparagraphs (B), (C), (E), (F), (G), and (H) of subsection (a)(2), except individuals who are eligible for benefits through the Indian Health Service or for benefits and services under title 38, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD910752C98BA42EDAE577D1D46E040C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will be publicly administered by an agency of the State; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H065104D1BB574047B41C18E1C11B6C12"><enum>(E)</enum><text>will not increase the Federal deficit.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Subparagraph (D) shall not be construed as limiting a State from contracting with one or more
			 private entities to administer the plan.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5E3FBB126D5433A85393C68BCF2E6A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement to enact a law</header>
 <subparagraph id="H595B6581D10F4B21B07A5A90F901075A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A law described in this paragraph is a State law that provides for State actions under a waiver under this section, including the implementation of the State plan under subsection (a)(1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A2EB3D9AC3E455285393D122F0BAC13"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination of opt out</header><text>A State may repeal a law described in subparagraph (A) and terminate the authority provided under the waiver with respect to the State.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68C19F6A135B480B8A50FE5A5F8EAB77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of waiver</header>
 <paragraph id="H95C3B61C25C942BAB06D57D7AE36DD52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the scope of a waiver of a requirement described in subsection (a)(2) granted to a State under subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BA75696F9654142A83EE17A817E2891"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under this section, the Secretary may not waive any Federal law or requirement that is not listed in subsection (a)(2).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4ED778F50824322BBB45F5C876C4692"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determinations by Secretary</header>
 <paragraph id="HC900B04C2DEE404587B9819318ED507D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Time for determination</header><text>The Secretary shall make a determination under subsection (a)(1) not later than 180 days after the receipt of an application from a State under such subsection.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H17DC0D49A2D448AFAA7C6C6112288A46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of Determination</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC43773A6B96D4BDCA7AAB1B7DE3A9293"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Granting of waivers</header><text>If the Secretary determines to grant a waiver under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall notify the State involved of such determination and the terms and effectiveness of such waiver.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E67024CD586483E82083F82725E70BB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Denial of waiver</header><text>If the Secretary determines a waiver should not be granted under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall notify the State involved and the appropriate committees of Congress of such determination and the reasons therefor.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC179DC8C063C4A508AB2280B9F0647A6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Term of waiver</header><text>No waiver under this section may extend over a period of longer than 5 years unless the State requests continuation of such waiver, and such request shall be deemed granted unless the Secretary, within 90 days after the date of its submission to the Secretary, either denies such request in writing or informs the State in writing with respect to any additional information which is needed in order to make a final determination with respect to the request.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H47332D414E234E5393F5B9929290CEC6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Assuring coordination</header>
 <paragraph id="HE9B0C42EFBA1471D82DE99F6294FD2DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of the <short-title>State-Based Universal Health Care Act of 2015</short-title>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Labor shall, through the execution of an interagency memorandum of understanding among such Secretaries and the Director—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0C25E087D3BC48DABF07E1BDD07BBB7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a process for coordinating and consolidating the State waiver processes applicable under the provisions of this section, and the existing waiver processes applicable under—</text>
 <clause id="HE77C04B531FD488F96BEACCE8B6770EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>titles XI, XVIII, XIX, and XXI of the Social Security Act; and</text> </clause><clause id="H31F0273F41674629A2361174F410FE51"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other Federal law relating to the provision of health care items or services; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H380A31F4F82F4975841289347C97D21A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that—</text> <clause id="H57A295A3ED144790B467910B4C4E4519"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regulations (including regulations required under subsection (a)(4)(B)), rulings, and interpretations issued by such Secretaries and the Director relating to the same matter over which two or more such Secretaries or Director have responsibility under this section are administered so as to have the same effect at all times; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5FE6543877D84601A089D98A584A4B8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordination of policies relating to the granting, implementation, and continuation of waivers through such Secretaries and Director in order to have a coordinated strategy that avoids duplication of effort by the States or Secretaries and Director and ensures clarity about waiver application status and approval.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13D00BFFFC8A4ECA838B64162A7CEEDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Single application</header><text>The process under paragraph (1)(A) shall permit a State to submit a single application for a waiver under all of the provisions of this section and the provisions of law listed under clauses (i) and (ii) of such paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA93AA26BC44246F8A6502F0A7F83863A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of conforming amendments</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the other Secretaries (including the Director of the Office of Personnel Management), shall submit to Congress such recommendations for such technical and conforming amendments to law as may be appropriate to assist in the implementation of this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H163E8A89996442A29A511E0732B3F53F"><enum>(g)</enum><header> Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HAC251B174F2543CAB99AEA7FF8425498"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Health benefits coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health benefits coverage</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4BAA790A28234EA78D40911C7B7E2402"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> <clause id="HEA668034890545FDAD1E91803C879AA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>health insurance coverage, as such term is defined in section 2791(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(b)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HFA4734FB03D34A5F956142A6B23C2D3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coverage under a group health plan, as such term is defined in section 2791(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(a)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3332AAA8B3294B52B676A05E8AD43296"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any medical coverage or health benefits provided under any specified Federal health program described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (4).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H73807F79D87B45DD8E66809C3F7EC8BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resident</header><text>With respect to a State, the term <term>resident</term> means an individual who is a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully residing in the State, and whose primary residence (as defined by the State) is located in the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D366836385E4408B262B5541D6B01EA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB9CB20F6316E47D79D26EDD6F5DA3860"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to waivers relating to the provisions described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (D) through (G) of paragraph (2) of subsection (a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3189B8FBBF844B488D0F860CFD85BDB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury with respect to waivers relating to the provisions described in subparagraph (C) of such paragraph;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3A7434B87E64BDEBADD66596ECA2432"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the Office of Personnel Management with respect to waivers relating to the provisions described in subparagraph (H) of such paragraph;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D736A40F7C42348079C863328842CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Defense with respect to waivers relating to the provisions described in subparagraph (I) of such paragraph; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H405C080208F74BAD9700EF1339282CCD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Labor with respect to waivers relating to the provisions described in subparagraph (J) of such paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4B975916B97A44329B5C042EC32B4CB3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Specified Federal health program</header><text>The term <term>specified Federal health program</term> means all of the following programs:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD5D312DB58DF40DEB5AF3E4B9953E836"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1F5025AAE40E44429D89CD5F0E8D53BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B54269D83914AD9B15749F4E8D0A5C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBACCE2F175BA48EEBDEA46C08FCE9F9C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Employees Health Benefits Plan under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5 of the United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAD45F7CD71464A839336C2740870D696"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Medical coverage under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, including coverage under the TRICARE program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3C07176B5EC3441FBAA3B8E1F3C481B1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An Exchange established under this subtitle.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE72795CAD07545D0886F8ACD0617FB07"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Subsidies under section 1402.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB8C4E15FC6B5467E8AF8FF74EBF7674A"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tax credits under sections 36B and 45R of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H69096F4629A54F598E667B75429071D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1332 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F38535CCDC94DF7ADE96531C4644104" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1332A. Waiver for State universal health care.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


