<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA3A5355CB88843DEB6BCEBA0E37B8AEC" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2677 IH: To require the Secretary of Education to verify that individuals have made a commitment to serve in the Armed Forces or in public service, or otherwise are a borrower on an eligible loan which has been submitted to a guaranty agency for default aversion or is already in default, before such individuals obtain a consolidation loan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2677</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150604">June 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the Secretary of Education to verify that individuals have made a commitment to serve in the Armed Forces or in public service, or otherwise are a borrower on an eligible loan which has been submitted to a guaranty agency for default aversion or is already in default, before such individuals obtain a consolidation loan.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3CC93E0BA88A4D809C2F46D36D65FACD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H43EEE12EDFC84A6E9C201F1D6AFD1EF0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Required verification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 428C of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-3">20 U.S.C. 1078–3</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA7BE7DBEB6FB4674AA9753C3AD323975"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(B)(i)(V)(aa), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>in a case in which the Secretary verifies that the individual is currently eligible for income contingent repayment or income-based repayment and that the loan(s) in question have been submitted to the guaranty agency for default aversion or if the loan is already in default</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEB4CEC4294C4D37BB1FE1B1863B2B87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(B)(i)(V)(bb), by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>in a case in which the Secretary verifies with documentation that the individual is, at the time of the application, employed in a public service job, as that term is defined in section 455(m)(3)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H393CD8B9ED6F481C9F6AB4F3638A03EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(B)(i)(V)(cc), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>in a case in which the Secretary verifies that the individual is a member of a regular or reserve component of the Armed Forces by contacting the Secretary of the military department or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as the case may be, having jurisdiction over the Armed Force in which the individual claims to be a member</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H318595E3EE2D42C6AA64D4DFD1846E30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(5), by inserting after the second sentence the following: <quote>In addition, the Secretary shall not offer any loans offered under this paragraph unless the Secretary has received verification described in subsection (a)(3)(B)(i)(V) (aa)–(cc), as applicable.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

