<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4A2784D4A15746B5ABB522C4F2B5B23C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2284 IH: Point Spencer Land Conveyance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2284</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the retention and future use of certain land in Point Spencer, Alaska, to support
			 the mission of the Coast Guard, to convey certain land in Point Spencer to
			 the Bering Straits Native Corporation, to convey certain land in Point
			 Spencer to the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE3C66E4205284AE5A92D2DF956A426E2" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB6516744DFD34A18B84BDDECACD09999" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Point Spencer Land Conveyance Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA460297A3CF9421BA0B592375D56D9B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3BAA347E33D04CC59223FC4C20FEB0D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Major shipping traffic is increasing through the Bering Strait, the Bering and Chukchi Seas, and the Arctic Ocean and will continue to increase whether or not development of the outer Continental Shelf of the United States is undertaken in the future and will increase further if such outer Continental Shelf development is undertaken.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BBC1CFFC1CC40FB8668E50B4BD504B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>There is a compelling national, State, Alaska Native, and private sector need for permanent infrastructure development and for a presence in the Arctic region of Alaska by appropriate agencies of the Federal Government, particularly in proximity to the Bering Strait, to support and facilitate search and rescue, shipping safety, economic development, oil spill prevention and response, protection of Alaska Native archaeological and cultural resources, port of refuge, Arctic research, and maritime law enforcement on the Bering Sea, the Chukchi Sea, and the Arctic Ocean.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD1E87F99C4343BD83C6C9882CA094AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States owns a parcel of land, known as Point Spencer, located between the Bering Strait and Port Clarence and adjacent to some of the best potential deepwater port sites on the coast of Alaska in the Arctic.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D13D73F7B2B4D03A70A09F711170063"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Prudent and effective use of Point Spencer may be best achieved through marshaling the energy, resources, and leadership of the public and private sectors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8907908CEE014E7CB75EC1B89211B33B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is in the national interest to develop infrastructure at Point Spencer that would aid the Coast Guard in performing its statutory duties and functions in the Arctic on a more permanent basis and to allow for public and private sector development of facilities and other infrastructure to support purposes that are of benefit to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HFE52192740B14BD094AF08F61A3DDD92"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H725C1989D4DD4EA9BC9D3E3AE199910F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Arctic</header><text>The term <term>Arctic</term> has the meaning given that term in section 112 of the Arctic Research and Policy Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4111">15 U.S.C. 4111</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E2F4210ECDA497BBBA221F6108CB1C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>BSNC</header><text>The term <term>BSNC</term> means the Bering Straits Native Corporation authorized under section 7 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1D7045E18A64C4E82F406867F7CFAC9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The term <term>Council</term> means the Port Coordination Advisory Council established under section 5(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6F82D68F6224C5781E6C4CC94C509C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>The term <term>Plan</term> means the Port Management Coordination Plan developed under section 5(c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H221FC5372D584877B1A85C202ECE386D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Point Spencer</header><text>The term <quote>Point Spencer</quote> means the land known as <quote>Point Spencer</quote> located between the Bering Strait and Port Clarence and withdrawn by Public Land Order 2650 (published in the Federal Register on April 12, 1962), and located in Townships 2, 3, and 4 South, Range 40 West, Kateel River Meridian, Alaska.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE39AB08EAF0F4435ACFB97B795498934"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AAABC33F927423EA493E08113468B8A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Alaska.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C4478D54F82425A980519FD022CBD45"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tract</header><text>The term <term>Tract</term> means Tract 1, Tract 2, Tract 3, Tract 4, Tract 5, or Tract 6, as appropriate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6881791E3C93489CACD45D681EBD19C6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tracts 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6</header><text>The terms <term>Tract 1, Tract 2, Tract 3, Tract 4, Tract 5, and Tract 6</term> each mean the land generally depicted as Tract 1, Tract 2, Tract 3, Tract 4, Tract 5, or Tract 6, respectively, and generally depicted as such Tract on the map entitled the <quote>Point Spencer Land Retention and Conveyance Map</quote>, dated January 2015, and on file with the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of the Interior.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H63F94C6AA0E447A59BD6D53CA32FD0D3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authority to convey land in Point Spencer</header>
 <subsection id="H94665F65D875432DAF01D45B07EBF416"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To convey Tracts 1, 3, and 4</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall convey, subject to valid existing rights, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the surface and subsurface estates of Tract 1, Tract 3, and Tract 4 in accordance with subsection (d) if the Secretary notifies the Secretary of the Interior that the Coast Guard no longer needs to retain jurisdiction over any portion of Tract 1, Tract 3, or Tract 4 and the requirements of subsection (f) are met for each such Tract to be conveyed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7C9258F6584346539074F01856DB89BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To convey Tracts 2 and 5</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall convey, subject to valid existing rights, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the surface and subsurface estates of Tract 2 and Tract 5 in accordance with subsection (d) if the requirements of subsection (f) are met for each such Tract to be conveyed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H208EAED5A8FE489F98BFD3FFF86FBBF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To transfer Tract 6</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall convey, subject to valid existing rights, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the surface and subsurface estates of Tract 6 in accordance with subsection (e) if the requirements of subsection (f) are met.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H84F4D7BFF49243229199C474AA005B6C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Order of offer To convey Tract 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5</header>
				<paragraph id="HB2F35A524223437AB3F7762AC796C20A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination and offer</header>
 <subparagraph id="H06D8555FAEF14CBABAC19DBE369840F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Tract 1, 3, or 4</header><text>If the Secretary makes the determination under subsection (a) and the requirements of subsection (f) are met for Tract 1, 3, or 4, or a portion of such Tract, the Secretary of the Interior shall offer such Tract or portion of such Tract for conveyance to BSNC under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AFDF60B2B694F28A50C5E5DCF12C250"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tract 2 or 5</header><text>If the requirements of subsection (f) are met for Tract 2 or Tract 5, the Secretary of the Interior shall offer such Tract for conveyance to BSNC under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50688B0E3D2744E9A30EC0C64C72C0AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offer to BSNC</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF18B5999328042519E545F5FEBBB23E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Acceptance by BSNC</header><text>If BSNC chooses to accept an offer of conveyance of a Tract under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior shall consider such Tract as within BSNC’s entitlement under section 14(h)(8) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1613">43 U.S.C. 1613(h)(8)</external-xref>) and shall convey such Tract to BSNC.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B6E7293FE143AE871BC22B004E6238"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Decline by BSNC</header><text>If BSNC declines to accept an offer of conveyance of a Tract under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior shall offer such Tract for conveyance to the State under the Act of July 7, 1958 (commonly known as the <quote>Alaska Statehood Act</quote>) (48 U.S.C. note prec. 21; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB3605F66B824F24BF94AE5B63CDDAF9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Offer to State</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA816B2BDE8094D91BFC72BA07FA281A6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Acceptance by State</header><text>If the State chooses to accept an offer of conveyance of a Tract under paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary of the Interior shall consider such Tract as within the State’s entitlement under the Act of July 7, 1958 (commonly known as the “Alaska Statehood Act”) (48 U.S.C. note prec. 21; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</external-xref>) and shall convey such Tract to the State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F91A69419DA4E089E56FECA1D90020D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Decline by State</header><text>If the State declines to accept an offer of conveyance of a Tract offered under paragraph (2)(B), such Tract shall be disposed of pursuant to applicable public land laws.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E92069D20A64C3BA5846FD9D4657CD3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Order of offer To convey Tract 6</header>
 <paragraph id="H1DD93CEF19D744C9BDEE7099C8F1C577"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offer</header><text>If the requirements under subsection (f) are met for Tract 6, the Secretary of the Interior shall offer such Tract for conveyance to the State.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H34007505C7654614956553145AFB8132"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offer to State</header>
 <subparagraph id="H875BAEF122834B15A9E04562711A48C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Acceptance by State</header><text>If the State chooses to accept an offer of conveyance of Tract 6 under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior shall consider Tract 6 as within the State’s entitlement under the Act of July 7, 1958 (commonly known as the “Alaska Statehood Act”) (48 U.S.C. note prec. 21; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</external-xref>) and shall convey Tract 6 to the State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H501969E8245346B9962E98F6AEE4D7CB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Decline by State</header><text>If the State declines to accept an offer of conveyance of Tract 6 under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior shall offer Tract 6 for conveyance to BSNC under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C51D15C7D714B8280162DFB9AC3E81E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Offer to BSNC</header>
					<subparagraph id="H8C8F2497833E43C78E768F47508A7D42"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Acceptance by BSNC</header>
 <clause id="H432F2155ED19400BB20E05BE804B8DA5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), if BSNC chooses to accept an offer of conveyance of Tract 6 under paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary of the Interior shall consider Tract 6 as within BSNC’s entitlement under section 14(h)(8) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1613">43 U.S.C. 1613(h)(8)</external-xref>) and shall convey Tract 6 to BSNC.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE5CE1AA4032049DCBE6C1B4E5E1C0254"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Lease by the State</header><text>The conveyance of Tract 6 to BSNC shall be subject to BSNC negotiating a lease of Tract 6 to the State at no cost to the State, if the State requests such a lease.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFCECB583CB74CE396F314D549AED439"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Decline by BSNC</header><text>If BSNC declines to accept an offer of conveyance of Tract 6 under paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary of the Interior shall dispose of Tract 6 pursuant to the applicable public land laws.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E1F466A7A3447179401EC60AC892E7F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Terms of conveyance</header>
				<paragraph id="HE8DCC2D413EE45729593A318EC8A174E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Environmental compliance</header>
					<subparagraph id="HF032E295BC2B4FBDB714F755849AF722"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Tract 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, or 6</header>
 <clause id="H4796446B5CFC472B86951E12925C29D7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall not convey Tract 1, Tract 2, Tract 3, Tract 4, Tract 5, or Tract 6 under this section until—</text>
 <subclause id="HCDEE5579F22344A78F6112299D22DDFF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary certifies that the applicable requirements under section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</external-xref>) and other applicable environmental laws have been satisfied for land in such Tract; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE546457DB73545768DB30BC195FC353C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Board of Directors of BSNC adopts and submits to the Secretary of the Interior a resolution stating that BSNC is willing to accept Tract 1, Tract 2, Tract 3, Tract 4, Tract 5, or Tract 6, as appropriate, <quote>as is</quote> at the time of such conveyance, based on known contamination.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H3AD7303B16E44A93A24AD81DC5F334F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>As is</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>as is</term> means the physical condition of Tract 1, Tract 2, Tract 3, Tract 4, Tract 5, or Tract 6, as appropriate, at the time of the conveyance of such Tract, including with respect to any known contamination by hazardous materials or substances.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34DF32683C9040FD9C79BDBC5A5C3F39"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Land to be conveyed to the State or BSNC</header>
 <clause id="H6F0D2491526941BDBCCC1D3792FE3371"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Environmental compliance</header><text>To the extent cleanup and remediation of hazardous substances on land in a Tract to be conveyed to the State or to BSNC are required by existing law, all environmental compliance activities pursuant to section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</external-xref>) and other applicable environmental laws shall be satisfied.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H45CFD101021445448101B51EE22F23F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Monitoring of known contamination</header><text>Notwithstanding section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 and other applicable environmental laws, any known contamination in a Tract to be conveyed that does not pose an immediate or long-term health or environmental risk may be routinely monitored and managed by the State or BSNC, as applicable, through institutional controls in accordance with the laws of the State.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H36CD53E4335344DA9C3B564898E6ED9C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Later found contamination</header><text>If preexisting contamination from hazardous materials and substances are found to be present in a Tract after the date the Tract is conveyed to the State or BSNC, responsibility for cleanup and remediation of such contamination shall continue to be governed by section 120(h)(3) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)(3)</external-xref>), applicable provisions of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/14/19">chapter 19</external-xref> of title 14, United States Code, and applicable laws of the State.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7D8BE18C36D4BD0BEB56BDCF8C8A338"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Land to be retained by the Coast Guard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to land in Tract 1, Tract 3, or Tract 4 to be retained by the Coast Guard, nothing in this section may be construed to limit the obligation of the Coast Guard to comply with applicable environmental law, including section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70C4BC3EF93D47BE8EE1E46BD7C47B1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Airstrip use</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE1945F3E44D2444B81CA3169C4241DBB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use by coast guard</header><text>All conveyances under this section shall be subject to—</text> <clause id="HDC4DDC3937074BB1B1CFDF346C1260C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an easement granting unlimited use of all existing and future landing pads, airstrips, runways, and taxiways that are located on such Tract conveyed, at no cost to the Coast Guard; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H36FC7AEFAD594C8E90784039848E59A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the right to access such landing pads, airstrips, runways, and taxiways, at no cost to the Coast Guard.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB025D67FA4EC41D482F8862B0F4EAF39"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use by State</header>
 <clause id="H951EEFAC39C64C18A227506F422E2004"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any Tract conveyed to BSNC under this section, BSNC shall provide to the State, if requested and pursuant to negotiated terms with the State, for no compensation—</text>
 <subclause id="HD3BF2C65661A47FFB22DE43EF70B480F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an easement over all existing and future airstrips, runways, and taxiways located on such Tract; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H49764FA6B75D4F389CB4F4DF78275F19"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a right of access to and from such airstrips, runways, and taxiways.</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC64C3CA3C88B4BB3B5BFE1D58F382772"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Right of access</header><text>If the State requests a right of access for a road from the airstrip to the southern tip of Point Spencer, the location of such right of access shall be determined by the State, in consultation with the Secretary and BSNC, so that such access is compatible with other existing or planned infrastructure development at Point Spencer.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62F7075B23144E5BB9876C1DEFD16661"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relationship to Public Land Order 2650</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6AC7814338AB469B9547121FECB59337"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Tracts not conveyed</header><text>Any Tract that is not conveyed under this section shall remain withdrawn pursuant to Public Land Order 2650 (published in the Federal Register on April 12, 1962).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6A6B2F5F6D04619A25794BADEB55367"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tracts conveyed</header><text>For any Tract conveyed under this section, Public Land Order 2650 shall automatically terminate upon issuance of a conveyance document for such Tract.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EE3445154DA4219B94C02F7F8CF2BD3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Archeological and cultural resources</header><text>Conveyance of any Tract under this section shall not affect criminal jurisdiction and responsibilities regarding the potential theft or vandalism of archeological or cultural resources located in or on such tracts.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H8CADD68DA3EC4A81A8D473F4B50C9B5A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Personal property</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8AE2E81A338E410A964CB43996D4DFD7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Cash sales authorized</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized to make cash sales of personal property that is located on Tract 4 to BSNC or to the State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59526EB4B3584CCBAC747F0EED6CA364"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Value</header><text>The total value of the personal property referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be deemed to be $5,580,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75EF4AE1F1F249E78593114F08FE2D4E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Proceeds</header><text>Pursuant to section 559 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/83">Public Law 111–83</external-xref>), the proceeds from the sale of the personal property referred to in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="H18D9B0BBD003468A92D13F14CA0168E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be deposited as offsetting collections into the Coast Guard Environmental Compliance and Restoration Account;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF26459E491904CEAA65B53EDBB2B858C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be available without further appropriation for environmental compliance and restoration activities associated with any tract conveyed or to be conveyed under this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H836E919068C94063AA20EBF89F2793D3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall remain available until expended.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1917A7B98D184725B8F914603237BF9A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Unexpended balances</header><text>If unexpended balances remain in the Coast Guard Environmental Compliance and Restoration Account after the completion of the activities described in subparagraph (C)(ii), such balances may be expended for any other environmental compliance and restoration activities of the Coast Guard.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE8ABAA50C6F43CB8E8689E943C9D9F9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="H87A781390CA64990B596824C3CE93CB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preparation of maps and legal description</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall prepare maps and legal descriptions of Tract 1, Tract 2, Tract 3, Tract 4, Tract 5, and Tract 6. In doing so, the Secretary of the Interior may use metes and bounds legal descriptions based upon the official survey plats of Point Spencer accepted on December 6, 1978.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBFF0C083A6D4CCC8112CBDEFF874A6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Legal effect</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions shall have the same force and effect as if the maps and legal descriptions were included in this Act, except that the Secretary of the Interior may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4BE0D30674849C29AFF2D4A2FFBFD20"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Copies of the maps and legal descriptions shall be available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4C4859F0BCB744DB9A181342338D388B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3154C4A2C9DC46728D614D3592EFAA2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States Coast Guard.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC50AD845088E4D64AC924982F263D5DD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall survey Tracts conveyed and patent the Tracts in accordance with the official plats of survey.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B4156FB0BCF454CB09977FD4FE8EBA0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Public access easements</header><text>No public access easements may be reserved to the United States under section 17(b) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1616">43 U.S.C. 1616(b)</external-xref>) with respect to the land conveyed under this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H30027EB7D72F424EA604606A9EC98CD0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Port Coordination Advisory Council for Point Spencer</header>
 <subsection id="H24E2D63EBB5246C7A8336C703B3C5A8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Port Coordination Advisory Council for the Port of Point Spencer.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H2F3D452684B34EE9ABC7BF0B3F2A12A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall consist of a representative appointed by each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9693400CF8B14E0B9D314622CD46EAC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The State.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H101733911A794CFFBEA4943CF83D46D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>BSNC.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C89C08F80CE409B9F20BB2794BE904F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the Council are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H0E22D25CD6A8480FA67EAD6EDA264446"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To develop a Port Management Coordination Plan to help coordinate infrastructure development and operations at the Port of Point Spencer, that includes plans for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H922FE00EA2D8471187D035040856D453"><enum>(A)</enum><text>construction;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78B69EB8E03E4972BCE23A7DB98ED1DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>funding eligibility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CDFDEBCD49C413E8B6F622E397AED70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>land use planning and development; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C8D503BF31D4C00877CEC579A385437"><enum>(D)</enum><text>public interest use and access, emergency preparedness, law enforcement, protection of Alaska Native archaeological and cultural resources, and other matters that are necessary for public and private entities to function in proximity together in a remote location.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25C7C2CEF7F648E1A83220DCCF3C03CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Update the Plan annually for the first 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act and biennially thereafter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11267E00D1494BF58E9DECC5BB46F34A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Facilitate coordination among stakeholders at Point Spencer, including the Coast Guard, on the development and use of the land and coastline as such development relates to activities at the Port of Point Spencer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0AECFCBEB17442295F7AE44053F2963"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Assess the need, benefits, efficacy, and desirability of establishing in the future a port authority at Point Spencer under State law and act upon that assessment, as appropriate, including taking steps for the potential formation of such a port authority.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA0A5864489342CE83CFC2A0E647FB46"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Plan shall be developed and implemented by the Council in such a manner so as to facilitate and support, and not interfere with nor impede, the statutory missions, duties, and operations of the Coast Guard in the Arctic.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9359A271642343BF9780E49C1C0B7FCE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>Operations and management costs for airstrips, runways, and taxiways at Point Spencer shall be determined pursuant to provisions of the Plan, as negotiated by the Council.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H61F43EAE4C1E423AB195F6AE201E16CE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 229 of the Howard Coble Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/281">Public Law 113–281</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 3040) shall not be construed to prohibit any transfer or conveyance of lands under to this Act or any actions that involve the dismantling or disposal of infrastructure that supported the former LORAN system that are associated with the transfer or conveyance of lands under this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


