<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6925ECCE42164847A1878292A27CE019" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 974 IH: Yellowstone and Grand Teton Paddling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 974</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150213">February 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior to promulgate regulations to allow the use of
			 hand-propelled vessels on certain rivers and streams that flow in and
			 through certain Federal lands in Yellowstone National Park, Grand Teton
			 National Park, the John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Parkway, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0A90C50894504B78A7758824C71942F7" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD1AFC194D9A94CABAA0886403614874E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Yellowstone and Grand Teton Paddling Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA9BFC34D89C6484CA3848EA1C501F2CE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Promulgation of Regulations</header> <subsection id="HEBF91A1547594E56B69540B9C9296BE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available for this section, the Secretary of the Interior shall promulgate regulations to allow the use of hand-propelled vessels on certain rivers and streams within—</text>
 <paragraph id="H99DCFB3C6BA240CFABE32890E3450A20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Yellowstone National Park in the States of Idaho, Montana, Wyoming; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H14D8345B52C8488F9021F4B2FB22963A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Grand Teton National Park and the John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Parkway in the State of Wyoming.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE5BD6C3E5B04574891486F302786ADF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Water excluded</header><text>The regulations promulgated under this section shall not apply to waters that are—</text> <paragraph id="HB6AE0D2D1BBB4CDA973958469EB8F651"><enum>(1)</enum><text>open to use by hand-propelled vessels on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E5A0F1703564D18BC7CFADD6BC4AEAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>within the Teton Range in Grand Teton National Park south of a latitudinal line anchored at Wilcox Point and west of an approximate north-south line that generally defines the base of the mountains following the western shores of Jackson, Leigh, Jenny, Bradley, Taggart, and Phelps lakes, and extending to the southern Grand Teton National Park boundary at the base of Apres Vous Peak.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9226DCA0C56402AAC473E88B5DDA1DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable laws</header><text>The regulations required by subsection (a) shall be promulgated in accordance with—</text> <paragraph id="H3628697A16894FEAAB98922572982580"><enum>(1)</enum><text>laws, regulations, and policies generally applicable to units of the National Park System; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H779DA4EEEDFF4CDDB70082A449758104"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sections 551 through 559 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF72E7236E234D249769D8ABD7BF5C2F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Commercial use</header> <paragraph id="HE0EBCD2C5234499FB50461683C037F6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No expansion of use</header><text>The regulations issued under this section shall not consider any expansion of commercial use of hand-propelled vessels in the parks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62E0F6B6398B40948ED3CA6F36289BFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Savings provisions</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the commercial use of hand-propelled vessels.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA84A55AECD641FEBCE63D704A33076C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination of Recreational Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When promulgating regulations under this section, the Secretary of the Interior shall consult with the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the Director of the National Park Service to help ensure that the regulations provide that recreational use of hand-propelled vessels on the Gros Ventre River within the National Elk Refuge adjacent to Grand Teton National Park is consistent with the requirements of the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/668dd">16 U.S.C. 668dd et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59710C7ADE794214B01E10B9B5B1349A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Previous regulations</header><text>Upon issuance of the final regulations required by subsection (a), the following regulations shall have no force or effect:</text>
 <paragraph id="H525C47BC86C94910A1C1A6969102B183"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 7.13(d)(4)(ii) of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (regarding vessels on streams and rivers in Yellowstone National Park).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA6C5C03B94A43BAB10B03921F90AF0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 7.22(e)(3) of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (regarding vessels on lakes and rivers in Grand Teton National Park).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E2E0574D9F74BF789F6770D7AB73E42"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cost recovery</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to recover all costs, in accordance with section 103104 of title 54, United States Code, associated with monitoring the use of hand-propelled vessels, including the cost of inspecting and decontaminating vessels to prevent the introduction or spread of invasive or injurious species in Yellowstone National Park, Grand Teton National Park, and the John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Parkway.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


