<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2775E0A794D468B8AC7532AB2E7DAF9" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2483 IH: Independent Contractor Tax Fairness and Simplification Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2483</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000594">Mr. Paulsen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide standards for determining employment status, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5F091F80F7C84B2EBFEA6C1CAEB0787E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H49FAC72AFCCF4F0CA77AF2498DEC673B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Independent Contractor Tax Fairness and Simplification Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HACFCB749DF1F4E448CFBBE8BB38F8FDB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H54B00C10F9934A76AFF6B9CCB3914EE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Independent contractors play a vital role in our economy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6316AA9FBE440779A4F878A44C8B231"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Independent contractors embrace the entrepreneurial spirit of our country and are free to seek economic opportunities that best fit their needs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D25A866144743C2B270934AC400D706"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Many small businesses start as an independent contractor and grow creating jobs for other individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8739C27E569E419182AA27AA1B5C1E23"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The proper classification of individuals as employees and independent contractors is a significant responsibility for businesses.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02C95879EE4241019C4941497864A4B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The rules and guidelines for determining whether an individual is an independent contractor or an employee lack clarity and consistency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A333F9770814B58B87DE3B0FEA3D846"><enum>(6)</enum><text>It is in the best interests of taxpayers, the Federal Government and the business community to have fair and objective rules for determining who is an independent contractor and who is an employee.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H401DAC15766248DFA79DF7F798D6E989"><enum>3.</enum><header>Standards for determining employment status</header> 
<subsection id="H16E396886650491493CA8B14D72933CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/25">Chapter 25</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (general provisions relating to employment taxes) is amended by adding after section 3511 the following new sections:</text> <quoted-block id="HFE8E333931784D8EAAE997F1EA313D0F" style="OLC"> <section id="H84719E0D1E154838996C2861859E4331"><enum>3512.</enum><header>Controversies involving whether individuals are employees for purposes of the employment taxes</header> <subsection id="HFEE55388E60A4C5382B44E53FBA54E80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination of certain employment tax liability</header> <paragraph id="HDBD546987653479BB3C574D0E0C6E447"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC5FFE144CBAB4CC7A64B74BBD555FF31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for purposes of employment taxes, the taxpayer did not treat an individual as an employee for any period, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD958974E55AC45178528149750B12F23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of periods after December 31, 1978, all returns (including information returns) required to be filed by the taxpayer with respect to such individual for such period are filed on a basis consistent with the taxpayer’s treatment of such individual as not being an employee,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">then, for purposes of applying such taxes for such period with respect to the taxpayer, the individual shall be deemed not to be an employee unless the taxpayer had no reasonable basis for not treating such individual as an employee.</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDAC87A951FF423FA860B45AD76F62C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statutory standards providing one method of satisfying the requirements of paragraph <enum-in-header>(1)</enum-in-header></header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), a taxpayer shall in any case be treated as having a reasonable basis for not treating an individual as an employee for a period if the taxpayer’s treatment of such individual for such period was in reasonable reliance on any of the following—</text> <subparagraph id="H71B8AAD14CED4F9EABCE3BE098B7DC43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>judicial precedent, published rulings, technical advice with respect to the taxpayer, or a letter ruling to the taxpayer,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB8C2D5C3D9AA48EC812889E9DA3509B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a past Internal Revenue Service audit of the taxpayer in which there was no assessment attributable to the treatment (for employment tax purposes) of the individuals holding positions substantially similar to the position held by this individual, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBEDE68306D0349ACA22B39DDA209BAAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>long-standing recognized practice of a significant segment of the industry in which such individual was engaged.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7D97835E884412C844EFB7D85DB0098"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consistency required in the case of prior tax treatment</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to the treatment of any individual for employment tax purposes for any period ending after December 31, 2015, if the taxpayer (or a predecessor) has treated any individual holding a substantially similar position as an employee for purposes of the employment taxes for any period beginning after December 31, 2014.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8CF5901227244F9D9E124C424DA41CD9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Refund or credit of overpayment</header><text>If refund or credit of any overpayment of an employment tax resulting from the application of paragraph (1) is not barred on the date of the enactment of this section by any law or rule of law, the period for filing a claim for refund or credit of such overpayment (to the extent attributable to the application of paragraph (1)) shall not expire before the date 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD6D84931B0ED4AE6BE313CFD56921E30"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition against regulations and rulings on employment status</header><text>Except for purposes of providing Revenue Rulings with respect to section 3513, no regulation or Revenue Ruling shall be published on or after the date of the enactment of this section by the Department of the Treasury (including the Internal Revenue Service) with respect to the employment status of any individual for purposes of the employment taxes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDEE9CED45E774BF8B5483E5B731CA1D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H79190D29E9E24C9EAF6F3F685BBAB915"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employment tax</header><text>The term <term>employment tax</term> means any tax imposed by this subtitle.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00CC2AE81DDE4C08BC3CE76499A82E67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employment status</header><text>The term <term>employment status</term> means the status of an individual, under the usual common law rules applicable in determining the employer-employee relationship, as an employee or as an independent contractor (or other individual who is not an employee).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE911FBCFD5B9409EB75DC3954375513E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>This section shall not apply in the case of an individual who, pursuant to an arrangement between the taxpayer and another person, provides services for such other person as an engineer, designer, drafter, computer programmer, systems analyst, or other similarly skilled worker engaged in a similar line of work.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H62C76D6E457C49F493AAB9DF45B057E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules for application of section</header> <paragraph id="H6FDEE112103D41FC897A513C376B115B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of availability of section</header><text>An officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service shall, before or at the commencement of any audit inquiry relating to the employment status of one or more individuals who perform services for the taxpayer, provide the taxpayer with a written notice of the provisions of this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82B83DD4E7DC4424BCF08A8239C07FC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules relating to statutory standards</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H427103AE6455478A8FDB32DDFD79DB60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a taxpayer may not rely on an audit commenced after December 31, 1996, for purposes of subparagraph (B) thereof unless such audit included an examination for employment tax purposes of whether the individual involved (or any individual holding a position substantially similar to the position held by the individual involved) should be treated as an employee of the taxpayer,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB683813E6E1747A2AB5A8316AFDD4805"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in no event shall the significant segment requirement of subparagraph (C) thereof be construed to require a reasonable showing of the practice of more than 25 percent of the industry (determined by not taking into account the taxpayer), and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19B6C2DAA13944F4AD5A0AB3924B42F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in applying the long-standing recognized practice requirement of subparagraph (C) thereof—</text> 
<clause id="H2ED825CCA6624324B6BE8DFE691FC07B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such requirement shall not be construed as requiring the practice to have continued for more than 10 years, and</text></clause> <clause id="HB96D2AC86D384D40B03C1A4DB3394581"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a practice shall not fail to be treated as long-standing merely because such practice began after 1978.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9697A45782BB439DA2E5CBBE36EBA998"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of safe harbors</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide that subsection (a) only applies where the individual involved is otherwise an employee of the taxpayer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB42C6AF9AC540A185979C21EE7F95EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header> <subparagraph id="H45DA75F9F11A4B41AA7B2C53AB5CB12A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If—</text> 
<clause id="H725EBE9147A74E77AA547C8A6065599F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a taxpayer establishes a prima facie case that it was reasonable not to treat an individual as an employee for purposes of this section, and</text></clause> <clause id="H0379636B4C4D452B85135E5FF3FA9355"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the taxpayer has fully cooperated with reasonable requests from the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">then the burden of proof with respect to such treatment shall be on the Secretary.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBA68E7092BC4831BF27313D8447DDD0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for other reasonable basis</header><text>In the case of any issue involving whether the taxpayer had a reasonable basis not to treat an individual as an employee for purposes of this section, subparagraph (A) shall only apply for purposes of determining whether the taxpayer meets the requirements of subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB612F7995CBE4FB693B7CCF2D2C8266B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Preservation of prior period safe harbor</header><text>If—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC28B51F146F0433C92C90F9FDC4573E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual would (but for the treatment referred to in subparagraph (B)) be deemed not to be an employee of the taxpayer under subsection (a) for any prior period, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67F64F3F2C6640D4975BDEB4E61E5900"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such individual is treated by the taxpayer as an employee for employment tax purposes for any subsequent period,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">then, for purposes of applying such taxes for such prior period with respect to the taxpayer, the individual shall be deemed not to be an employee.</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CB089D53F124D509291DD0C6AB1B06F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Substantially similar position</header><text>For purposes of this section, the determination as to whether an individual holds a position substantially similar to a position held by another individual shall include consideration of the relationship between the taxpayer and such individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H2C273ED5A177457BB41B863E4773E5DE"><enum>3513.</enum><header>Safe harbor standards for determining employment status</header> <subsection id="HB502A07FAAB84978B4AEDA0573026D82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>For purposes of this title, if the requirements of subsection (c) are met with respect to any service performed by any service provider, then with respect to such service—</text> 
<paragraph id="H19FD4CC9C3D148B89C344D5682EF9AA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the service provider shall not be treated as an employee,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93084BE021FD4C98926ED4F398F298E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the service recipient shall not be treated as an employer,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE64B882964844D9DB1015B9F5DC91F0F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the payor shall not be treated as an employer, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3CC217D72AF4D08B6EC68CF387F13C5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>compensation paid or received for such service shall not be treated as paid or received with respect to employment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0BDE4128E41D4EDE937B1D9D00298A81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statutory employees</header><text>Nothing in this section shall supersede the categories of employees described in section 3121(d)(3).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE737F02489374E3DB280427A2A155327"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <paragraph id="HAECA232FF4C1442D84377FCBE2973C6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirements of this subsection are met if the requirements of paragraphs (2) and (3) are met.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FE37A79A72D4E9C8A5E37CE29AAB5D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investment or income fluctuation</header><text>A service provider meets the requirements of this paragraph if the service provider—</text> <subparagraph id="H1CB34A41A6924ABDB825A3B30C66B456"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incurs significant financial responsibility for providing and maintaining the necessary equipment and facilities to perform the work outlined in their qualified agreement, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H39D0A5FD2082413C87A4A117144BA7DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>either—</text> <clause id="H056321A47EAC40199C55A1C61C345B41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>incurs unreimbursed expenses, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H65D23CCB71144CD281B8FDD55AC585C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>risks income fluctuations because the remuneration with respect to such service is directly related to sales or other output rather than solely to the number of hours actually worked or expenses incurred.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98F1697E496B41F48F5A3CB025E42C2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Control of time worked and performance of services</header><text>A service provider meets the requirements of this paragraph if the service provider—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAD4650D5D3B4494290B3DC87CD4BC48B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is compensated upon factors related to the work performed, such as a percentage of revenue or scheduled rates, and not solely on the basis of hours or time expended, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADBEB3A7320643E39D9C7E62521394DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>substantially controls the means and manner of performing the services, in conformance with regulatory requirements, the specifications of the service recipient or payor and any additional requirements specified in the qualified agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8F9269104B6F4C07A91CE161669375A8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H012E57049A9C4D44BB6CD4C3B1178023"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Service provider</header><text>The term <term>service provider</term> means any individual or entity that performs service for another company under a qualified agreement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2A576C195494D4DBF95282C9617F84C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Service recipient</header><text>The term <term>service recipient</term> means the person or entity for whom the service provider performs such service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7105B516FC148708E24383780C34739"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payor</header><text>The term <term>payor</term> means the person or entity that pays the service provider for the performance of such service in the event that the service recipients do not pay the service provider.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FCC407F7CE64D0F99660569707E86C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The terms <term>service recipient</term> and <term>payor</term> do not include any entity which is owned in whole or in part by the service provider.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CF85DAF2F944243B3BD33D4CF4363D0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified agreement</header><text>The term <term>qualified agreement</term> means a written contract between a service provider and the service recipient for whom the services are performed or the payor that provides that the service provider—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H308D545EA08D4DDC8BAB659200FF3E19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will not be treated as an employee with respect to such services for the purpose of this title, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF5A46BE2676427F89C43C6CA4AB3450"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been informed of the Federal tax obligations resulting from such treatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B9D70122F3B47E3940E3D69F5690D5A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="HAD6EA35FAC164F9B96879D631C4FC8FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 530 of the Revenue Act of 1978 is hereby repealed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3583C7939A2C44A199ADB19D3F500F8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for chapter 25 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new items:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6FDD44614A24EA385487B8168A7B886" style="OLC"> 
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HFE8E333931784D8EAAE997F1EA313D0F" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="H84719E0D1E154838996C2861859E4331" level="section">Sec. 3512. Controversies involving whether individuals are employees for purposes of the employment taxes.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2C273ED5A177457BB41B863E4773E5DE" level="section">Sec. 3513. Safe harbor standards for determining employment status.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB60BE8B14F36476FA06AE29D5D9A3216"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> 
<paragraph id="HFE1F9635224F46798FB669ECF759A9A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this Act shall take effect beginning on the first day of the first calendar year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8E092E353314262A50CF313BCFFE2A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repeal of section 530</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (b)(1) shall apply to periods in calendar years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

