<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6535C36071EB44948907DD710B37BBDD" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2519 IH: Audiology Patient Choice Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2519</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for treatment of audiologists as physicians for purposes of furnishing audiology services under the Medicare program, to improve access to the audiology services available for coverage under the Medicare program and to enable beneficiaries to have their choice of a qualified audiologist to provide such services, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE487032687CA448A946B301267B75928" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE2530C88CA9540239AEF435B4EA15603" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Audiology Patient Choice Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HABC8E0A9D17044DEBA07D6F389AC1308"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBD0EA6871CB843E6A1D684A416A496EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hearing loss is the third most common chronic disorder for Americans over 65, behind only arthritis and high blood pressure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCADD7F0963BA462899AB321ED4FF18FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Individuals with mild hearing loss are three times more likely to experience a fall and falls are the leading cause of injury and death for Americans over 65.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E2F3D4E826641ABAF42F070DC58775A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Untreated hearing and balance problems contribute to and are highly correlated with depression and social isolation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C522004D4E946EB9D30D70F3070F1A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Seniors with hearing loss run a much higher risk of cognitive problems and experience cognitive decline up to 40 percent faster than those with normal hearing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAEA30D19C10041A38E123209F328045A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Medicare beneficiaries should have access to the same level of audiologic care as is available in the Veterans’ Administration, under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, and under private insurance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B6FDCE9E2EF4A4CAFAB45B3047316BF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Medicare program needs to be updated in a comprehensive way so Medicare beneficiaries are able to have access to all of the advancements in the delivery of audiologic care.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD730278EDB8E4CDAA4E5E50DC08805CD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improved Medicare coverage of audiology services</header> 
<subsection id="H79BC1D7463F44C7FBD8EE160D8667253"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment of audiologists as physicians for purposes of furnishing audiology services</header><text>The first sentence of section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(r)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBA1BE272F246481BAD6C9216B185DDD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> before <quote>(5)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H937486B78586444584879903E8E74E43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, or (6) a qualified audiologist, but only with respect to the furnishing of audiology services described in subsection (ll)(3) for which the qualified audiologist is legally authorized to perform by the State and who is acting within the scope of the audiologist’s license (or other authorization under State law)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H271FEBD185BA49C1BAB347ABC32CF169"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improved access to audiology services available for coverage under the Medicare program and enabling Medicare beneficiaries To have their choice of qualified audiologist</header><text>Section 1861(ll)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(ll)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9142B82EB5704000A24F4398B269CA89"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>hearing and balance assessment</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H084018F02EA7465182C3774A3B9F2D02"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>, as would otherwise be covered if furnished by a physician</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD57EED35E16F4B7D87B48A940DC23643"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, without regard to any requirement that the individual receiving the audiology services be under the care of (or referred by) a physician or other health care practitioner or that such services are provided under the supervision of a physician or other health care practitioner</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA398AB40EA8A43AB9C629A6A6C8D2B31"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to items and services furnished on or after January 1 of the first year beginning more than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

