<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1ACB45F64A7B4984BFE08FBE472F624F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1587 IH: Unlocking Technology Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1587</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150324">March 24, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend section 1201 of title 17, United States Code, to require the infringement of a copyright for a violation of such section, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7D6E7540C58C4B90BC1DE90872CCCF91" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H62CCDA7817C34111A0B62AC8BF1A13C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unlocking Technology Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H09079AE58D234F36BD809EA99B841201"><enum>2.</enum><header>Infringement of a copyright required for anticircumvention prohibition</header> <subsection id="H5D1B8AB3D34E4C8B9076259A83F297B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1201(a) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6F1DC5FD06974BF895633513DF627865"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0AFD31932A264C04A2B627A7738A6C43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending the first sentence to read as follows: <quote>No person shall, in order to infringe or facilitate infringement of a copyright in a work protected under this title, circumvent a technological measure that effectively controls access to that work.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94C8531EEEC54EEDB35F2CBB352C3CA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>It shall not be a violation of this section to circumvent a technological measure in connection with a work protected under this title if the purpose of such circumvention is to engage in a use that is not an infringement of copyright under this title.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H540D4A9841A04B938D7E86DF0DDB9DFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDB2630DD68FA493C93D315032E5036DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting after <quote>for the purpose of</quote> the following: <quote>facilitating the infringement of a copyright by</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDE07A6F5C5A4F45BB60A2C2065DB2DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>circumvent</quote> and inserting <quote>facilitate the infringement of a copyright by circumventing</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2AD966F0CFEF479AB30AABB01C144324"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting after <quote>for use in</quote> the following: <quote>facilitating the infringement of a copyright by</quote>; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC35368475BC14D16BB1A078B97AC43C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82D1FC54362B4375AE11F5C023432767"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C954366C7CD4E0791FE684D28498CF3" style="USC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3A79A98044744B64945CF0B810FC734C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is not a violation of this section to use, manufacture, import, offer to the public, provide, or otherwise traffic in any technology, product, service, device, component, or part thereof that is primarily designed or produced for the purpose of facilitating noninfringing uses of works protected under this title by circumventing a technological measure that effectively controls access to that work, unless it is the intent of the person that uses, manufactures, imports, offers to the public, provides, or traffics in the technology, product, service, device, component, or part to infringe copyright or to facilitate the infringement of a copyright.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2D464961022D4A1C8D95EDD6D24805D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header> 
<paragraph id="H918EA303DF334E489A0AB461C2ABBFA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the end of the 9-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce shall submit to the committees described in paragraph (2) a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9727809900245388B3CBB7519524B96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the impact of section 1201 of title 17, United States Code, on consumer choice, competition, and free flow of information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2936CBF65B840FABECDBD2EFE30605F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether section 1201 of such title should be reformed in part, reformed entirely, or repealed; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A0A165D67434586B4AF5195367B17FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>barriers and challenges to such reform or repeal, including international trade agreements and treaties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H722F4F8DDC804F70B02D6B55B79A6612"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committees</header><text>The committees described in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HE52807F0EC3549D08A5B9A1FA462C7F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committees on the Judiciary and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D0A28A37C41407C918271F30F597C4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committees on the Judiciary and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC94CE2AB517D4714BC82776F9C6E3890"><enum>3.</enum><header>Network switching not infringement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 117 of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H57832E65B18243EFADB04DB46E221642"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD7C5B733DCF446B9B0C990194C5DE91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HBD594BAD86A64FAEB6FB828700491FA4" style="USC"> 
<subsection id="HA28CC65100154C84A79EC0411C5DC04F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Network switching</header><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of section 106, it is not an infringement to copy or adapt the software or firmware of a user-purchased mobile communications device for the sole purpose of enabling the device to connect to a wireless communications network if—</text> <paragraph id="H27CFECEC6BA8487D83A15FD70E13CEE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the copying or adapting is initiated by, or with the consent of, the owner of that device or the owner’s agent;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BB96931C9754D74A7B090D3A87F9FEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the owner of that device or the owner’s agent is in legal possession of the device; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6180953980DF42848A459DEFC1554D5C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the owner of that device has the consent of, or an agreement with, the authorized operator of such wireless communications network to make use of that wireless communications network.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H63CA26F1A82D4B9FB7CD9CBB534E7248"><enum>4.</enum><header>Harmonization of trade agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall take the necessary steps to secure modifications to applicable bilateral and multilateral trade agreements to which the United States is a party in order to ensure that such agreements are consistent with the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> <section id="H9FD82B43456940E5A050AA8E5C87646E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header> <subsection id="H6905AE4C50D14947B9FEB9E2FD806C53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply to acts carried out after the expiration of the 9-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H722FC5CFDE2E49239E0A50005625811E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Sections 2(b) and 4 shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

