<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9D001B1A9B8743158665C1B962C48C8C" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1209 IH: Improving Access to Maternity Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1209</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150303">March 3, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000622">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the designation of maternity care health professional shortage areas.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE311BC64B1A344B9AE3E0AC9533A24AA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6317F422379E40A6B04A43BE319D1E90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Access to Maternity Care Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H94CB026D615C4A7A89C0011C97088C65"><enum>2.</enum><header>Maternity care health professional shortage areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 332 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDE74AF62748468F970BB46E3826DA25" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H0F2A79E15D0742C6A5F857C259BAD2B3"><enum>(k)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB3BC6C8E8067413087559D79F860DCA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall designate maternity care health professional shortage areas in the States and at least annually thereafter review and, as necessary, revise such designations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H870B4AFE86CB4368858AB93700ECC50F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), and in applying subsection (b) pursuant to paragraph (4), the Secretary shall seek input from relevant provider organizations, including medical societies, organizations representing medical facilities, and other organizations with expertise in maternity care.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF708B2F5D01C4C42B3F182EC0330FD54" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying subsection (d), pursuant to paragraph (4), the Secretary shall collect and publish in the Federal Register data on health care professional shortage areas based on professional category of maternal health professionals providing full scope maternity health care by provider type as well as geographic region. Such data shall be presented in a manner to compare availability and need of such professionals by such professional category and geographic region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H150E2797C22B4F55A8631A2E26EDCE3A" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), and (j) (other than (j)(1)(B)) of this section shall apply to the designation of a maternity care health professional shortage area under this subsection in a similar manner and extent as such provisions apply to the designation of health professional shortage areas under subsection (a), except—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H618EBC331C8548B696B10B365219CB55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in applying subsection (b)(3), the reference in such subsection to <quote>physicians</quote> shall be deemed to be a reference to physicians and other health professionals as providing maternity care eligible for loan repayment under this part who provide full scope maternity care;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H52F7EE1D06AF45CF980D733B23C6773C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in applying subsection (d)—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="HF99AEA4A19004BCDA26BF20C805FE0CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the reference in paragraph (2) of such subsection to <quote>July 1 of 1991</quote> shall be deemed to be a reference to <quote>July 1 of 2016</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HCE14D29C6FF646DBAA429CD7A45B6295"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the descriptive list required under such paragraph, with respect to a maternity care health professional shortage area designated under paragraph (1), shall include—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H5FFA79755B5A4E06ADE282EA0A67FE8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>population groups in the area that would benefit from full scope maternity care health services; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H14C6A7A40FA541088DAA1DED1ABA7F4B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the providers and medical facilities that provide such services to such groups in such area; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3EB336031FD04CC3989DB2E74FA681F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in applying such provisions of subsections (b), (c), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), and (j), a reference to an area, population group, or facility shall be deemed to be a reference to an area or population group described in paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA301CF887C99454CAE6117E28F046B31" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H994C6EB38908444EB3CEFCBA5696C0E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term ‘maternity care health professional shortage area’ means—</text> <clause id="H36105C3CBC8A4B038434BC9BE77C4845"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an area in an urban or rural area (which need not conform to the geographic boundaries of a political subdivision and which is a rational area for the delivery of health services) which the Secretary determines has a shortage of providers of full scope maternity care health services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBCDD8E2A51E54B3BB9F0E5DDBCCC4F3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an area in an urban or rural area (which need not conform to the geographic boundaries of a political subdivision and which is a rational area for the delivery of health services) which the Secretary determines has a shortage of hospital or birth center labor and delivery units; or</text></clause> <clause id="H31BA44BEF1E24C6691EE2E9EB3925888"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a population group which the Secretary determines has such a shortage of maternal providers or facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H801B338728E64A8D842A8651A6BD3055"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>full scope maternity care health services</term> includes during labor care, birthing, prenatal care, and postpartum care.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9B9BD9856E8416C8251DC1886B35C69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>medical facility</term> has the meaning given such term in subsection (a)(2) and includes a freestanding birth center, as defined in section 1905(l)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

