<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2D7CF447B7194C81A3BA08440369564F" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1644 RH: Supporting Transparent Regulatory and Environmental Actions in Mining Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 209</calendar>
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1644</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 114–277]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20151001">October 1, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000364">Mr. Shimkus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20151001">October 1, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 26, 2015</action-instruction>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to ensure transparency in the development of environmental regulations, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HD2F6436CA9464D3797DB8031B3C26534">
<section id="HC66E63DD03034B37B4BA389498C921C3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Transparent Regulatory and Environmental Actions in Mining Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STREAM Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7CDF311A6DE34D0294AC5964582C7D5F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Publication of scientific products for rules and related environmental impact statements, environmental assessments, and economic assessments</header> <subsection id="HD47D78E657534119BF5AACFDFBD11628"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Title V of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1251">30 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H5191EC1BCC6648E9A85460CCAD174C73" style="OLC">
<section id="HD5379A03DD3149FA80E088EC8D0597D2"><enum>530.</enum><header>Publication of scientific products for rules and related environmental analyses, and economic assessments</header>
<subsection id="HBD75A14A060B4C94AC280A4E1265469C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header>
<paragraph id="HF7E3EBB895D14AE595F612CBC0053F71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall make publicly available 90 days before the publication of any draft, proposed, supplemental, final, or emergency rule under this Act, or any related environmental analysis, economic assessment, policy, or guidance, each scientific product the Secretary relied on in developing the rule, environmental analysis, economic assessment, policy, or guidance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A93AACEB8C94094ADFC9B313DABDC67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federally funded scientific products</header><text>For those scientific products receiving Federal funds in part, or in full, the Secretary shall also make publicly available the raw data used for the federally funded scientific product.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H19159B83E8C641C491846A671E06A9CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance</header>
<paragraph id="H2D713843913D4A2EB0F8E987FB150B43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Failure to make publicly available any scientific product 90 days before the publication of—</text> <subparagraph id="H3ACE2CCDF0654973BCAB09117066028A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any draft, proposed, or supplemental rule, environmental analysis, economic assessment, policy or guidance shall extend by one day the comment period for each day such scientific product is not made available; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B299ADED3E84D018671C88479EF1E9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any final or emergency rule shall delay the effective date of the final or emergency rule by 60 days plus each day the scientific product is withheld.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC3D7038DCD64FC5B91C5EF8B4266E77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay longer than 6 months</header><text>If the Secretary fails to make publicly available any scientific product for longer than 6 months, the Secretary shall withdraw the rule, environmental analysis, economic assessment, policy, or guidance. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H53074CE3879248D8A770807532A10FBF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>This subsection shall not apply if a delay in the publication of a rule will pose an imminent and severe threat to human life.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9C3574BB4E0D4CC7B8BBC11A27800C53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H051A29C72A164B73BEEA4005371A547D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Publicly available</header><text>The term <quote>publicly available</quote> means published on the Internet via a publicly accessible website under the Secretary’s control.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11984585B9B74F529F9A5E4674357F44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental analysis</header><text>The term <quote>environmental analysis</quote> means environmental impact statements and environmental assessments prepared pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCFFBDA666DB042478176E49A4A0CACD2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scientific product</header><text>The term <quote>scientific product</quote> means any product that—</text> <subparagraph id="H99A80CEE879546A286536FAF02722C6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employs the scientific method for inventorying, monitoring, experimenting, studying, researching, or modeling purposes; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H460190C4E17E44A3A82D039343432758"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is relied upon by the Secretary in the development of any rule, environmental analysis, economic assessment, policy, or guidance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA21A306BDD044A658FB91B6CBD3F7EBE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Raw data</header><text>The term <quote>raw data</quote>—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3B2726A098DC4B9F9B97560D5EDE28BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subparagraph (B), means any computational process, or quantitative or qualitative data, that is relied on in a scientific product to support a finding or observation; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68B20B92EEB342E1B8213160E886B35B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include such data or processes—</text>
<clause id="H75625144EA4446F0837499A2CB8338D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that are protected by copyright;</text></clause> <clause id="HE81A2D3C7A884E14BF5B857C0CA4FD26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that contain personally identifiable information, sensitive intellectual property, trade secrets, or business-sensitive information; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H94E1D910305140C1B29D630EBA71E9C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to the extent that such data and processes are covered by the provisions of part C of title XI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d">42 U.S.C. 1320d et seq.</external-xref>), regulations promulgated pursuant to section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note), and the provisions of subtitle D of title XIII of the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17921">42 U.S.C. 17921 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H52BAFCCB32424533825F0542292460FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in the first section of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to such title the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBF3E8AB0E49F4D6EBB864CCD71D2B266" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H5191EC1BCC6648E9A85460CCAD174C73" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="HD5379A03DD3149FA80E088EC8D0597D2" level="section">Sec. 530. Publication of scientific products for rules and related environmental analyses, and economic assessments.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="HBEFDD6359C184251B1C4EAA83437299E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study of the effectiveness of certain rule</header>
<subsection id="H3A0F4F0F71F8468AA91899AC63742203"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Title VII of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1291">30 U.S.C. 1291 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HBA2521B3A9864132BBD0266530523361" style="OLC"> <section id="HA442BF16431A47FB8AB512E4D0294AE5"><enum>722.</enum><header>Study of the effectiveness of certain rule</header> <subsection id="HB9A661230B5D4419853325C17056091F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the STREAM Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Interstate Mining Compact Commission and its State members, shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences, for execution by the Board on Earth Sciences and Resources, to conduct a comprehensive study on the regulatory effectiveness of the <quote>Surface Coal Mining and Reclamation Operations Permanent Regulatory Program; Stream Buffer Zones and Fish, Wildlife, and Related Environmental Values</quote> Final Rule published June 30, 1983 (48 Fed. Reg. 30312), and amended September 30, 1983 (48 Fed. Reg. 44777), in protecting perennial and intermittent streams through the use of stream buffer zones. If the study determines the existence of regulatory inefficiencies, then the study shall include suggestions and recommendations for increasing the effectiveness of the rule. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H07D22935099545FDA65F52CCE6AD605A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Results of the study</header><text>Not later than 2 years after execution of the arrangements under subsection (a), the Board on Earth Sciences and Resources shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, appropriate Federal agencies, and the Governor of each of the States represented on the Interstate Mining Compact Commission the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0D90D2948E394890BBF4008EB15A74A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2016 and $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2017 for the purposes of this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0E7723760EF943C6B619D0AB96241310"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on new regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall not issue any final or other regulations pertaining to the proposed rule entitled <quote>Stream Protection Rule</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 44436) or relating to stream buffer zones, until one year after the Secretary has submitted the results of the study in accordance with subsection (b). If the Secretary proposes any such regulations after such submission, the Secretary shall take into consideration the findings of the study.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBD875168BE0A4F4181F40DD5CDD25226" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in the first section of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to such title the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3CFD44553CA14C028EB35A9C519959F2" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 720. Subsidence.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 721. Research.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 722. Study of the effectiveness of certain rule.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="H8FC0BA0436FC4A3E81784F05FC974C93"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compliance with other Federal laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 702 of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1291">30 U.S.C. 1291</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6A27451B493143238C3986A7E8320E3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsection (d) and (e), respectively; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7DABACA10B6F49228B096EB2A7849986"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H77DA5C3536694275A331A9E08A1B5C1E" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H0542F3AC0ECE493D8875A889E1D517FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance with other federal laws</header><text>Nothing in this Act authorizes the Secretary to take any action by rule, regulation, notice, policy, guidance, or order that duplicates, implements, interprets, enforces, or determines any action taken under an Act referred to in subsection (a) or any regulation or rule promulgated thereunder.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
</legis-body> 
<endorsement display="yes">
<action-date date="20151001">October 1, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill> 


