<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB20F59C993DF4726B496A7B317A44362" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2015 IH: Customs Training Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2015</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150423">April 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000108">Mr. Visclosky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish educational seminars at United States ports of entry to improve the ability of U.S.
			 Customs and Border Protection personnel to classify and appraise articles
			 that are imported into the United States in accordance with the customs
			 laws of the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H32525ED97D4945F0A3018CF549BCABFA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3488A13EE10348A09A5180E14B268294" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Customs Training Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCA8F76A17DC9462D94FFC16826FBB0A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Educational seminars to improve ability of U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel to classify and appraise imported articles</header> <subsection id="HA1776E45737B4532B4A4DDD571204E8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Educational seminars</header> <paragraph id="HB3ED6B0033C94341AE30D131B8BFD540"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall establish and carry out educational seminars at United States ports of entry to improve the ability of U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel to classify and appraise articles imported into the United States in accordance with the customs laws of the United States, including to improve the ability of U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel to identify and prevent the mislabeling and transshipment of articles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H822A463E95DE462C90B793D17FD1B4DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number and exception</header><text>The Commissioner shall establish and carry out not less than 15 educational seminars each year under paragraph (1). The Commissioner may establish and carry out fewer than 15 seminars each year under paragraph (1) if the Commissioner determines and notifies Congress that it is appropriate to do so.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FDE05592C15433BAB49BBE065AB3129"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header>
 <paragraph id="H4C4FF7F7475440E4966FE3315E8189BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner and interested parties selected under subsection (d) should provide instruction and related instructional materials at each educational seminar to U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel and, as appropriate, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement personnel on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9BCC24BC60BA4D5892C3148A8DCB6811"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting a physical inspection of an article imported into the United States, including testing of samples of the article, to determine if the article is mislabeled in the manifest or other accompanying documentation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF56B00834F674539877274C7EC468A9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Reviewing the manifest and other accompanying documentation of an article imported into the United States to determine if—</text>
 <clause id="HCDBA979D96EF4D67B9883E61333F34F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the country of origin of the article listed in the manifest or other accompanying documentation is accurate; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4F96AF8574FD441C9F3A8FA24F0780EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the industry supply chain represented in the manifest or other accompanying documentation is accurate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD5ED8B0D2CE45128BE1204CC7CC1FCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other related matters as determined to be appropriate by the Commissioner.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF00ACCA960446F5ADDE0DA6F9AC1C19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval of Commissioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The instruction and related instructional materials at each educational seminar shall be subject to the approval of the Commissioner.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B836C614C224AE9B7D01EA00B019F9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Costs and expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall pay the costs to establish and carry out each educational seminar and shall pay expenses for U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement personnel, and interested parties to provide instruction in or receive training at the seminar.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7373180CD32544E186BD63D6F41E31C8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection process</header>
 <paragraph id="H86AE9462EB7A4B1597CCC02166C15B93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner shall establish a process to solicit, evaluate, and select interested parties for purposes of assisting in providing instruction in the educational seminars under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H400858403C0B4D0E8D9BF7E194F8DCA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall, in consultation with the United States International Trade Commission, evaluate and select interested parties under the process established under paragraph (1) based on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H100602ED7A214AFB9CD0B85B5EDAEE06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>availability and usefulness;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EAAA12264E54D64BDAD824EE2BCDD16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the volume, value, and incidence of mislabeling of an imported article that relates to a comparable domestic product of the interested party; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE06442A8ADE44511A74D7E1D07BB198D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other appropriate criteria established by the Commissioner.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H075CC63E7799414D93669A6C951B1DF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Commissioner shall publish in the Federal Register a detailed description of the process established under paragraph (1) and the criteria established under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0AB7DAC96B7E48168A9C62796FA5400F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0C3998CB7745416EB593F28A1333407A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner responsible for U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD67B7BB6BBD4A64AF142DAC26A8A85B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comparable domestic product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>comparable domestic product</term> means a product which is comparable in characteristics and uses with an article imported into the United States and which is covered by an educational seminar under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2A3F217ACFD7490CA57F8E2F9E4175E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Customs laws of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>customs laws of the United States</term> means any law or regulation enforced or administered by U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text> </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H671884D374B84C7F85DF557672D27289"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interested party</header><text>The term <term>interested party</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H195CF198F20F4B259E5B1DBFC487707E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler in the United States of a comparable domestic product;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBBD972DF84A4616B8D0862E4DC8AC0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a certified union or recognized union or group of workers which is representative of an industry engaged in the manufacture, production, or wholesale in the United States of a comparable domestic product;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB492D25F14814B84A98BE643535EC88D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a trade or business association a majority of whose members manufacture, produce, or wholesale a comparable domestic product in the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1935D240D56A48B4A255DE4EACA0CDE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an association, a majority of whose members is composed of interested parties described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) with respect to a comparable domestic product.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADA431147F4E4312BFA4D5CE21F455D8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States</term> means the customs territory of the United States, as defined in General Note 2 to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57DE23B17C4A4AC5B998F03E3DEA198E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel</term> means Import Specialists and other appropriate employees of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HB4CCBB154C7E41598966F16F1DDA1654"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $3,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


