<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFF095CB118AF4D29A958E0632C9E21A0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2356 IH: Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2356</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150515">May 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to provide a safe harbor related to certain
			 investment fund research reports, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HEDC4704365EA429CB4AA982E5A638813" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9187CDDB810C4AF186C7A98F9305DC0E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB2ED0686EAEE4871BFA02BAC7EB4C7F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Safe harbor for investment fund research</header> <subsection id="HC029D0B133C84B09B2C8548761810CDC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of safe harbor</header><text>Not later than the end of the 45-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall propose, and not later than the end of the 120-day period beginning on such date, the Commission shall adopt, upon such terms, conditions, or requirements as the Commission may determine necessary or appropriate in the public interest, for the protection of investors, and for the promotion of capital formation, revisions to section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide that a covered investment fund research report—</text>
 <paragraph id="H03B5BD113C6548A19C577B4EA3E16A63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be deemed, for purposes of sections 2(a)(10) and 5(c) of the Securities Act of 1933, not to constitute an offer for sale or an offer to sell a security that is the subject of an offering pursuant to a registration statement that the issuer proposes to file, or has filed, or that is effective, even if the broker or dealer is participating or will participate in the registered offering of the covered investment fund’s securities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BE2D92E6F8C49DDACC45E8B4D42D9DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be deemed to satisfy the conditions of subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2) of section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor provisions, for purposes of the Commission’s rules and regulations under the Federal securities laws and the rules of any self-regulatory organization.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20ECE42548BB4DC79570ECB965790C24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of safe harbor</header><text>In implementing the safe harbor pursuant to subsection (a), the Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="H50B0738AFFB14E5AA81DDA52947AA94F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not, in the case of a covered investment fund with a class of securities in substantially continuous distribution, condition the safe harbor on whether the broker’s or dealer’s publication or distribution of a covered investment fund research report constitutes such broker’s or dealer’s initiation or reinitiation of research coverage on such covered investment fund or its securities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE1AB4A6EE6D407CB358A4494D44A3D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not—</text> <subparagraph id="HEEEFA3CE349A4DD9AF46E5A718481413"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require the covered investment fund to have been registered as an investment company under the Investment Company Act of 1940 or subject to the reporting requirements of section 13 or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 for any period exceeding twelve months; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B8271A9BC60425299D8BBA9A310774F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose a minimum float provision exceeding that referenced in subsection (a)(1)(i)(A)(1)(i) of section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45ABD680DEA64E1A918F8E45E6B6C69B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide that a self-regulatory organization may not maintain or enforce any rule that would—</text> <subparagraph id="HDCF6B993FAA54675943BE20CD3CE58F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>condition the ability of a member to publish or distribute a covered investment fund research report on whether the member is also participating in a registered offering or other distribution of any securities of such covered investment fund;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FF28562D6A24E99B231A8B08714ABA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>condition the ability of a member to participate in a registered offering or other distribution of securities of a covered investment fund on whether the member has published or distributed a covered investment fund research report about such covered investment fund or its securities; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H831F22E8CEFE4FBDB6899ECDC17B3143"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require the filing of a covered investment fund research report with such self-regulatory organization; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99FD362093864F6E9842A28FF12154EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide that a covered investment fund research report shall not be subject to sections 24(b) or 34(b) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 or the rules and regulations thereunder.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AC424B42A4F40F38B8E6E86289012AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed as in any way limiting—</text> <paragraph id="H03F549716AE94A698FD584F6FC0D098A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the applicability of the antifraud provisions of the Federal securities laws; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B7FDDAFCB3F4DA3937EED708EC2E752"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority of any self-regulatory organization to examine or supervise a member’s practices in connection with such member’s publication or distribution of a covered investment fund research report for compliance with otherwise applicable provisions of the Federal securities laws or self-regulatory organization rules.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35A12E38D7D74095AE2AB81DC7A1F4B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interim effectiveness of safe harbor</header><text>From and after the 120-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, if the Commission has not met its obligations pursuant to subsection (a) to adopt revisions to section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, and until such time as the Commission has done so, a covered investment fund research report published or distributed by a broker or dealer after such date shall be deemed to meet the requirements of section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, and to satisfy the conditions of subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2) thereof for purposes of the Commission’s rules and regulations under the Federal securities laws and the rules of any self-regulatory organization, as if revised and implemented in accordance with subsections (a) and (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC729CBB7D49A4578B3FAA6E36A3EB74C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD059D9B91CE440F29CD1CBA93BAADB61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered investment fund research report</header><text>The term <term>covered investment fund research report</term> means a research report published or distributed by a broker or dealer about a covered investment fund or any of its securities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H892D38A2A0AA4372A921E98AD4959085"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered investment fund</header><text>The term <term>covered investment fund</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H8A5F091FD28A46DC8223A14683F6AD71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an investment company registered under, or that has filed an election to be treated as a business development company under, the Investment Company Act of 1940 and that has filed a registration statement under the Securities Act of 1933 for the public offering of a class of its securities, which registration statement has been declared effective by the Commission; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D8CB1493FCD4F1EBF69FEAF33DB035C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a trust or other person—</text> <clause id="H0E7BD91EED1F4EECB2D2BB51BA6C5C4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that has a class of securities listed for trading on a national securities exchange;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H31B0092EF95E43A5BAAB87C72DD2D8CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the assets of which consist primarily of commodities, currencies, or derivative instruments that reference commodities or currencies, or interests in the foregoing; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB6B25A62726347FE973E5D6448490C88"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that allows its securities to be purchased or redeemed, subject to conditions or limitations, for a ratable share of its assets.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FC1A9F8075F40D69ED9D6E30AB21BEC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Research report</header><text>The term <term>research report</term> has the meaning given to that term under section 2(a)(3) of the Securities Act of 1933, except that such term shall not include an oral communication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94909968EB56457EBC031D9632276DAA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Self-regulatory organization</header><text>The term <term>self-regulatory organization</term> has the meaning given to that term under section 3(a)(26) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

