<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4139D8493BA143B285BDE02C9DDF41AF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3328 IH: Small Business Regulatory Sunset Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3328</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require Federal agencies to review certain rules and regulations, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4EA2770B7C59414C9B96BDE790A4E60D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEFE9B495CB6F4A09B0F1B5854F0C5AE5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Regulatory Sunset Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB8DD585E11354E3E876FAFF0303639F5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7EF3095498CE4477BD589E4AA33F11ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA931946E02F742A4A505D578EB85ACC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered rule</term> means any rule or group of rules—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3D1A1781A28247069D2EE08201818784"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for which an agency is required to prepare a regulatory flexibility analysis under section 603 or 604 of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5DEC2F18BF74545BFF4D1114FAFE8DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is a major rule;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36AAA5F5080743148A4D4CB28641A663"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>major rule</term> has the meaning given the term in section 804 of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87AF92C020B4448F88004840FE2A9794"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the terms <term>rule</term> and <term>small entity</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 601 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HE00457DACA8A4DD0B7012C1EC802AD8F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Periodic review of preexisting small business regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 610 of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H838A4DBCE3A44DD9AE0AB375DBF03D50" style="USC">
				<section id="H5E1442D8916B4D11B4F99AF668770DC1"><enum>610.</enum><header>Periodic review of rules</header>
					<subsection id="H7C15397D768B4036BA62F17EB95275BC"><enum>(a)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC62FB78506A44D329364539A7505FA56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Small Business Regulatory Sunset Act of 2015</short-title>, each agency shall establish a plan for the periodic review of—</text> <subparagraph id="H3B6DC4F8A2C94AFF95547027DF2AEAE6" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each rule issued by the agency that the head of the agency determines has a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, without regard to whether the agency performed an analysis under section 604 with respect to the rule; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68FA4C36076D4D959187B15122A996A7" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any small entity compliance guide required to be published by the agency under section 212 of the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H241AFE074D994CF0A29FCC79A764849D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In reviewing rules and small entity compliance guides under paragraph (1), the agency shall determine whether the rules and guides should—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD46FBFB2F4D14D05A50064F9599DAB98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be amended or rescinded, consistent with the stated objectives of applicable statutes, to minimize any significant adverse economic impacts on a substantial number of small entities (including an estimate of any adverse impacts on job creation and employment by small entities); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53B4B2D6ADAD4332BEF7D4EF00B4388B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continue in effect without change.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79478B8D467742F99F420EC7B9AAC65D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Each agency shall publish the plan established under paragraph (1) in the Federal Register and on the Web site of the agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EA7F71FE326409892BFC9E3ED9E3965" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An agency may amend the plan established under paragraph (1) at any time by publishing the amendment in the Federal Register and on the Web site of the agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA13287C179E941E594EB886D0F2FB0CA"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Each plan established under subsection (a) shall provide for—</text> <paragraph id="HEAD97183178E4B92A741C918C7578053"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the review of each rule and small entity compliance guide described in subsection (a)(1) in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Small Business Regulatory Sunset Act of 2015</short-title>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2F1FB298980C41F19733DF8F05E0FBB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 9 years after the date of publication of the plan in the Federal Register; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AD8B4A3E3534ACB998ABC6C51869701"><enum>(B)</enum><text>every 9 years thereafter; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10FDAEFE80FA41B28ACD890016CA79DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the review of each rule adopted and small entity compliance guide described in subsection (a)(1) that is published after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Small Business Regulatory Sunset Act of 2015</short-title>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F411B70C2614AA69FF1DAD8ED7A0611"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 9 years after the date of publication of the final rule in the Federal Register; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EB8CE1BDB3F4F8B980DF78B96E278B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>every 9 years thereafter.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0154C90F8004E79A17132BE891A90B9"><enum>(c)</enum><text>In reviewing rules under the plan required under subsection (a), the agency shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="H47DE077F9C0A4045975138D71F62ED5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the continued need for the rule;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE641D87FA0D456EA721DC05DDAC908C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nature of complaints received by the agency from small entities concerning the rule;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2C3AE82AE514AE698B3856F4E7515D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>comments by the Regulatory Enforcement Ombudsman and the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD02557976C4526A42768348579F2CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the complexity of the rule;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H35FA823D1B4A4E5E82C9715ADF4E4D45"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the extent to which the rule overlaps, duplicates, or conflicts with other Federal rules and, unless the head of the agency determines it to be infeasible, State and local rules;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18D80F5209D943BB8F99640C0EA16C17"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the contribution of the rule to the cumulative economic impact of all Federal rules on the class of small entities affected by the rule, unless the head of the agency determines that such a calculation cannot be made;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81D63B7123624B8D87206B85FBC0191A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the length of time since the rule has been evaluated, or the degree to which technology, economic conditions, or other factors have changed in the area affected by the rule; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB947AD7F55B443C8B8AE494AA00C9751"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the economic impact of the rule, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H649803B427C8460A803BC25D0F27533F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimated number of small entities to which the rule will apply;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BDB18B7A8F54406AC171BEC232CC534"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the estimated number of small entity jobs that will be lost or created due to the rule; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DB9A66CCDB840BCA0DE79807299CB6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the projected reporting, recordkeeping, and other compliance requirements of the proposed rule, including—</text>
 <clause id="HA67844F2352A4078B199641201BC7909"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an estimate of the classes of small entities that will be subject to the requirement; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCFAF2704E65148A48ED0F3973B9F9045"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the type of professional skills necessary for preparation of the report or record.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA31B9B725F6C49DBB1B15BBEAEC053B1"><enum>(d)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA3F8E568E16C4C679952F8695A68406F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each agency shall submit an annual report regarding the results of the review required under subsection (a) to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H98A5A780AA7D4BCDAA930EDA412A42D4" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Congress; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22153B732B3F499CA4F71C50B77A4AE8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an agency that is not an independent regulatory agency (as defined in section 3502(5) of title 44), the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95F23B7D0701426081F3540038D7B724" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include a description of any rule or small entity compliance guide with respect to which the agency made a determination of infeasibility under paragraph (5) or (6) of subsection (c), together with a detailed explanation of the reasons for the determination.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FF0FF34A5D14664B600CC8301712FFD"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Each agency shall publish in the Federal Register and on the Web site of the agency a list of the rules and small entity compliance guides to be reviewed under the plan required under subsection (a) that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H78D46E9FEC694973A64BCD028E944350"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a brief description of each rule or guide;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD24791BC316E4155920B629DE20E3C77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each rule, the reason why the head of the agency determined that the rule has a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities (without regard to whether the agency had prepared a final regulatory flexibility analysis for the rule); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E05EC9ACDF744F795FBD288E2AF757D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a request for comments from the public, the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration, and the Regulatory Enforcement Ombudsman concerning the enforcement of the rules or publication of the guides.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88B09A2441BA464D8EC4FA1A81251DD4"><enum>(f)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2CE1D99BDACB41759D36C74EBCAB0201"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 6 months after each date described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b), the Inspector General for each agency shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H16350435FA0944EB88FD42DF2662FC5A" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine whether the agency has conducted the review required under subsection (b) appropriately; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E73BF0C7C8445128BDD8C40117F494E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the head of the agency of—</text> <clause id="HE8B1ADA82BBD44D9A325085DBCECB1FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the results of the determination under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H83BD79E481FB4CD1A0587D38C9DA3889"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any issues preventing the Inspector General from determining that the agency has conducted the review required under subsection (b) appropriately.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A3D46EACA424CDAA01D83B5253587C6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5D61CFAE11DB47028A255B82689CDE43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 6 months after the date on which the head of an agency receives a notice under paragraph (1)(B) that the agency has not conducted the review required under subsection (b) appropriately, the agency shall address the issues identified in the notice.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H825538E6C71143BDAF130E9CF9C88019" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the last day of the 6-month period described in subparagraph (A), the Inspector General for an agency that receives a notice described in subparagraph (A) shall—</text>
 <clause id="HB5A19E00E26A41B2AD826F71A6260ACC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine whether the agency has addressed the issues identified in the notice; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4272D190CA6542699E4DD7EAB9E32C81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify Congress if the Inspector General determines that the agency has not addressed the issues identified in the notice.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD498C13215AA42319D5380BF9C50BEC6" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Inspector General for an agency transmits a notice under subparagraph (B)(ii), an amount equal to 1 percent of the amount appropriated for the fiscal year to the appropriations account of the agency that is used to pay salaries shall be rescinded.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BCACEE51C3A455792D26AFB48963E2D" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prevent Congress from acting to prevent a rescission under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H4B87C561E3934C7EB2A590CC167753A4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sunset of new small business regulations</header>
 <subsection id="H0B6220F625654169B76E0B7FD11AD829"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b) and beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, each covered rule promulgated by an agency shall cease to have effect on the date that is 7 years after the date on which the final version of the covered rule is published.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCB6604A7A96548E5A2FE68DA72CE2B32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension of rule</header>
 <paragraph id="HCCD0F58B9CC0467EB67A1BA9580341C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before the end of the 7-year period described in subsection (a), an agency may take action to renew a covered rule in accordance with the process described in paragraph (2) and if such action is taken, the covered rule shall remain in effect until modified or repealed by the agency action or statute.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H89188AAEC212491C94CD29AB6D20F571"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewal process</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA049E2856FF144DB806574CB66ACBC67"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agency may renew a covered rule by using the notice and comment rulemaking process.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H086EAA3479A3497B8FBB09FF052D31FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting a rulemaking to renew a covered rule under subparagraph (A), an agency shall—</text>
 <clause id="H93877CD98D174851856DBC3D49B134E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>solicit and respond to public comment from entities affected by the covered rule;</text> </clause><clause id="H53E6FB36EE6345609A8DBCCF71450845"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>compare the projected costs of the covered rule to the actual costs realized by implementation of the covered rule and determine whether modifications can be made to the covered rule to lower the cost of the covered rule;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC20FDAA9DA9A44DE8A8782E978E1F1E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>consider whether any regulatory alternatives exist that would accomplish the same regulatory objective as the covered rule with less of an impact on affected small entities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF74056DB12D40AAB2167754380F55A1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>make modifications to the covered rule, if necessary, to reflect—</text> <subclause id="HE4C0E5C270F3444282D6BF70EB2BC5C8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>comments solicited under clause (i);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H873AC7774B674362A6E2255C9090BAB2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>modifications described in clause (ii); and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H46E6D0B2CCD74475BF6AB459CD2D1612"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any regulatory alternatives described in clause (iii).</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


