<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H66C35EB2DBAE46AC83A8A33451D74FE9" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 273 IH: Minority Small Business Enhancement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 273</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150112">January 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Small Business Act to enhance services to small business concerns that are
			 disadvantaged, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCCA0EC8540FD4D0B97A8AFCB7134D84E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6FD072A59F6440B5BA2C1FEDCB614441" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Minority Small Business Enhancement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H05DAAD7693AA459CAFBD341E4D2F972F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhancement of services to small businesses that are disadvantaged</header> <subsection id="HDD1DCBED1B6C42C08495A1915AC3EB4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Net worth</header><text>Section 8(a)(6)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(a)(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>disadvantaged individual.</quote> the following: <quote>For purposes of eligibility for admission as a Program Participant and for continued eligibility after admission, the net worth of such individual may be any amount less than $1,500,000.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H55841D80A9CD4FDC89F2E9F8404AB409"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Time limit on participation</header><text>Section 7(j)(15) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(j)(15)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1C527B4DE3414D70906703B078E708FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33A7F5CC294D427DA6D9C3CFB96551CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(A)</quote> after <quote>(15)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H72E6E3EA7CB843BE84F557755D6BE4DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H221667C86B2641199F853B6EE797EE29" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H022DBD286F8F4AB69FDAB0D1565CBF69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>No time limitation relating to the period that a small business concern may receive developmental assistance under the Program and contracts under section 8(a) shall apply to a small business concern that has not completed a contract under section 8(a).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3A1BFF4F3C77492B9F95884387CFDF91"><enum>3.</enum><header>Bundled contracts</header>
 <subsection id="H05C91480D6FF4E4B8233DBC137BA2B89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 3(o) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(o)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HDCC2F150D04249DD93CBB7511E534FE9" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H5641F8D6D6724A50AB676791B8F03D4F"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Definitions of bundling of contract requirements and related terms</header><text>For purposes of this Act:</text>
						<paragraph id="H65856D5D2E0E43C580B30B6A2D0CB9B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bundled contract</header>
 <subparagraph id="H74AD1E6C19CD4FE59AC81F3E9A370571"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>bundled contract</term> means a contract or order that is entered into to meet procurement requirements that are consolidated in a bundling of contract requirements, without regard to its designation by the procuring agency or whether a study of the effects of the solicitation on civilian or military personnel has been made.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD4E4398CF5A480FB324082DEF5A4E25"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The term does not include—</text> <clause id="H878B6BFE7F5742B0A6F8D5C29CC4EBB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a contract or order with an aggregate dollar value below the dollar threshold specified in paragraph (5); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF2A6B405BE943719BBEADA7DBB3F637"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a contract or order that is entered into to meet procurement requirements, all of which are exempted requirements under paragraph (6).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B737805AD854370A86E621E04A08DC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bundling of contract requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC9BF45CB30894B919C8F197A129E87E3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>bundling of contract requirements</term> means the use of any bundling methodology to satisfy 2 or more procurement requirements for goods or services previously supplied or performed under separate smaller contracts or orders, or to satisfy 2 or more procurement requirements for construction services of a type historically performed under separate smaller contracts or orders, that is likely to be unsuitable for award to a small business concern due to—</text>
 <clause id="H93447472A2E14E589A341A3DC08C8BE1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the diversity, size, or specialized nature of the elements of the performance specified;</text> </clause><clause id="H3CD930887557415392064AF5ED521A9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate dollar value of the anticipated award;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2BE1C3604AB74CBDB0B18FEDE6DA786A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the geographical dispersion of the contract or order performance sites; or</text> </clause><clause id="H334DA1D37D5D4B63B1AD1B73A0E91D62"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any combination of the factors described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C7640A04FB34B23B82701321759A517"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of new features or functions</header><text>A combination of contract requirements that would meet the definition of a bundling of contract requirements but for the addition of a procurement requirement with at least one new good or service shall be considered to be a bundling of contract requirements unless the new features or functions substantially transform the goods or services and will provide measurably substantial benefits to the government in terms of quality, performance, or price.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99F5F85E4F0E40F8B7DFA19B5A241777"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The term does not include—</text> <clause id="HD5D8A12017B44CCDB5A3D4F2831E827C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of a bundling methodology for an anticipated award with an aggregate dollar value below the dollar threshold specified in paragraph (5); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB6C9B0EB916643329C872E278CE03A00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of a bundling methodology to meet procurement requirements, all of which are exempted requirements under paragraph (6).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A2219AC2A6046489A81B17E32CAD620"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Bundling methodology</header><text>The term <term>bundling methodology</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0BE505E6E79846CDBA888A569719EA10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a solicitation to obtain offers for a single contract or order, or a multiple award contract or order; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8229EB1D4A9D4726A1A668DC47456C21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a solicitation of offers for the issuance of a task or a delivery order under an existing single or multiple award contract or order.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28DF5A016EB14A5E971225861114EC5C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Separate smaller contract</header><text>The term <term>separate smaller contract</term>, with respect to bundling of contract requirements, means a contract or order that has been performed by 1 or more small business concerns or was suitable for award to 1 or more small business concerns.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC34E9DA445941019EB5BC730A7C91BE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dollar threshold</header><text>The term <term>dollar threshold</term> means $65,000,000, if solely for construction services, and $5,000,000 with respect to all other circumstances.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DEE941926CB46329DFAC144BDBFC34A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exempted requirements</header><text>The term <term>exempted requirement</term> means a procurement requirement solely for items that are not commercial items (as the term <term>commercial item</term> is defined in section 4(12) of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/403">41 U.S.C. 403(12)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8790CDF8BFF47219147F5A67F725A3B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Procurement requirement</header><text>The term <term>procurement requirement</term> means a determination by an agency that a specified good or service is needed to satisfy the mission of the agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCD9809950E2D4B41B4792311652A7C5A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proposed procurement requirements</header><text>Section 15(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H39AB70AEB79847D69037718795895610"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>necessary and justified.</quote> and inserting <quote>necessary and justified, as well as identifying information on the incumbent contract holders, a description of the industries which might be interested in bidding on the contract requirements, and the number of small businesses listed in the industry categories that could be excluded from future bidding if the contract is combined or packaged.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92BB6B673CF843D899E1FA836C86B61E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the sentence beginning <quote>Whenever the Administration and the contracting procurement agency fail to agree,</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>Whenever the Administration and the contracting procurement agency fail to agree, the Administrator may review the proposed procurement, may delay the solicitation process for not more than 10 days to make recommendations, and the matter shall be submitted to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to mediate the disagreement.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0173B6115A53428F8FF91A07F79D9E08"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal contracting goals</header>
 <subsection id="H1D1352E38D5348C793C480B0AC522409"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase in certain goals</header><text>Section 15(g)(1) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H31E8499AEE594AD3BE9B2E88427D4B32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not less than 23 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than 25 percent</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7459CB107D6042BD81B5A2A18D0EA206"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not less than 5 percent</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>not less than 10 percent</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89C063328DE54A95BC23B7955BE47E8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on number of categories for which a business may qualify</header><text>Section 15(g) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H1D82E5D01A624ACC918ADAA4487AA951" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB46EC1386CF9477A9B3A5484B79F2A32"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection and subsection (h), with respect to each procurement contract a small business concern may not qualify as more than 2 specified categories, regardless of whether such small business concern satisfies the definition of more than 2 specified categories. The specified categories are small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, qualified HUBZone small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, and small business concerns owned and controlled by women.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H330AFD5112FE43BFBEE3CCF25D131A58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Government accountability office study</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2016, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct and submit to Congress a report describing the results of a study on disparities in the awarding of Federal contracts to procure goods or services with respect to small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, small business concerns, and other business concerns.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


