<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0FD764051E884B0784E6FEBFA9915421" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2544 IH: Excess Uranium Transparency and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2544</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the USEC Privatization Act to require the Secretary of Energy to issue a long-term Federal
			 excess uranium inventory management plan, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7938F891985B4926BE03BEFA2C6F56D8" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDF183D58FDEB40B2A3D9710D97093CEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Excess Uranium Transparency and Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0B4A4DDADD534A95A42FDC01A604426A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Uranium transfers and sales</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3112 of the USEC Privatization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2297h-10">42 U.S.C. 2297h–10</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6743D3673674422F98B286A9C291E600"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (b) through (f) as subsections (d) through (h), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3B42A90B66C4FF8B912D38FE5EAD843"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE369BFF7C1348D2AFDC2B4FFB844B59" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H031567C181FA4C62B009DB2A4DCB92A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H439916C2375643C5918A39BF37F650B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Depleted uranium</header><text>The term <term>depleted uranium</term> means uranium having an assay less than the assay for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H801FDC43960D431787348B9F7ABA0F62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>natural uranium; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA63BB20E0F054C5DB45A05BA214369EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>0.711 percent of the uranium-235 isotope.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A03D20F21CE4630A72B6E03850E32B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Highly enriched uranium</header><text>The term <term>highly enriched uranium</term> means uranium having an assay of 20 percent or greater of the uranium-235 isotope.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EAA7EC86A854DAA9A1AD2E4A9F23B47"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Low-enriched uranium</header><text>The term <term>low-enriched uranium</term> means uranium having an assay greater than 0.711 percent but less than 20 percent of the uranium-235 isotope.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAEA5994BD104972BD4A88300E6EFD68"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Metric ton of uranium</header><text>The term <term>metric ton of uranium</term> means 1,000 kilograms of uranium.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7ADFDD025B74331B2179D6A9074397E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Natural uranium</header><text>The term <term>natural uranium</term> means uranium having an assay of 0.711 percent of the uranium-235 isotope.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB842A0DA994B458D836C36E74A502B17"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Off-spec uranium</header><text>The term <term>off-spec uranium</term> means uranium in any form, including depleted uranium, highly enriched uranium, low-enriched uranium, natural uranium, UF6, and any byproduct of uranium processing, that does not meet the specification for commercial material (as defined by the standards of the American Society for Testing and Materials).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60844568BAED42C98B334C7431EEFACC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Uranium</header><text>Other than in subsection (c), the term <term>uranium</term> includes natural uranium, uranium hexafluoride, highly enriched uranium, low-enriched uranium, depleted uranium, and any byproduct of uranium processing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7FF1C7C77A434E299E2124C1FF02B15A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Uranium hexafluoride; UF6</header><text>The terms <term>uranium hexafluoride</term> and <term>UF6</term> mean uranium that has been combined with fluorine, to form a compound that, dependent on temperature and pressure, can be a solid, liquid, or gas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E0C75DBE56F4DCDBB6308557CCADEAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers and sales by the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall not provide enrichment services, or transfer, sell or otherwise provide any uranium to any person except in accordance with this section.</text>
					</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC5E46DAFDB44D93B49C935F215E7519"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development of Federal excess uranium management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H1CF63FBC3DC2421AB24BD76127C8AFB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on January 1, 2017, and not less frequently than once every 10 years thereafter, the Secretary shall issue a long-term Federal excess uranium inventory management plan (referred to in this section as the <quote>plan</quote>) that details the management of the excess uranium inventories of the Department of Energy and covers a period of not fewer than 10 years.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HEF655D0918C34B48AE69BF981CE9C051"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header>
 <subparagraph id="H326253795389496FBB4F67F1FD14F843"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The plan shall cover all forms of uranium within the excess uranium inventory of the Department of Energy, including depleted uranium, highly enriched uranium, low-enriched uranium, natural uranium, off-spec uranium, and UF6.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03CEDB0689D54F8D9B4FC7EB403C6BA9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reducing impact on domestic industry</header><text>The plan shall outline steps the Secretary will take to minimize the impact of transferring, selling, or otherwise providing uranium on the domestic uranium mining, conversion, and enrichment industries, including any actions for which the Secretary would require new authority.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0019A74B46CD449EB3366B0B8EFABDAE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Maximizing benefits to the Federal Government</header><text>The plan shall outline steps the Secretary shall take to ensure that the Federal Government maximizes the potential value of uranium for the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57A30784FE054CE1B48A17C80D6AA0AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Proposed plan</header><text>Before issuing the final plan, the Secretary shall publish a proposed plan in the Federal Register pursuant to a rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07F9E04ECF324B82AA4DC71A739796DD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadlines for submission</header><text>The Secretary shall issue—</text> <subparagraph id="H90BCFC1D6A0F4F1CA126F39A436A4F64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a proposed plan for public comment under paragraph (3) not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58904410B32A47FCB3B302B4C8803BAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a final plan not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BE38BB6EFEA4D55BCB87F14ED12B862"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d) (as redesignated by paragraph (1))—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC38F0A0026064CD19718A6BE1B5C7B22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the sixth sentence of paragraph (3), by striking <quote>subsections (b)(5), (b)(6) and (b)(7) of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (5), (6), and (7)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83662281258F4EACA229C1E08893B968"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>(b)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EDD19A8882C4A5EA06E190FECAF6178"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1) (as redesignated by paragraph (1)), by striking <quote>subsection (c)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (2)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H363FB1ACD03B4D7E9792F4E8E78745A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f) (as redesignated by paragraph (1))—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D0E24AE11A64E829A5244CC7C468A54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB267CEFFC1E47B2902F29C163818471" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD13A6B3A675A4FC68FC9B9C17CBCA820"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the transfers authorized under subsections (e) and (g), the Secretary may transfer, sell, or otherwise provide any uranium from the stockpile of the Department of Energy, subject to the following limitations:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6ECCDD8737914E14992C4A717604D8EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Effective for the period of calendar years 2016 through 2023, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not transfer, sell, or otherwise provide more than 2100 metric tons of natural uranium equivalent annually in any form, including depleted uranium, highly enriched uranium, low-enriched uranium, natural uranium, off-spec uranium, and UF6.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01ABBB8B34CA4C9CB57EF17975111E02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Effective beginning on January 1, 2024, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not transfer, sell, or otherwise provide more than 2700 metric tons of natural uranium equivalent annually in any form, including depleted uranium, highly enriched uranium, low-enriched uranium, natural uranium, off-spec uranium, and UF6.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78BF849B592E4F76BAC5EA3923E7313D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>(2) Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (e)</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C41C299FD8A44F5B19C70B428130DF0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H00B2FD6CEE964B549DC67484B7CEFD76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text>Except as provided in subsections (d), (e), and (g), and subject to paragraph (3)</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77C85631BD9D47458273FCD661A22A00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCA3DAA58CCA4B59A51DDDFDE1AEA64A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD5C831C52160417DA649F6DFA5C39567"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for determinations</header> <subparagraph id="HFF23228216D641BABE4B2CC74BF8A26F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Proposed determination</header><text>Before making a determination under paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary shall publish a proposed determination in the Federal Register pursuant to a rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7667D702A5F741F8BB1002F24A74B6B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Quality of market analysis</header><text>Any market analysis that is prepared by the Department of Energy, or that the Department of Energy commissions for the Secretary as part of the determination process under paragraph (2)(B), shall be subject to a peer review process consistent with the guidelines of the Office of Management and Budget published at 67 Fed. Reg. 8452–8460 (February 22, 2002) (or successor guidelines), to ensure and maximize the quality, objectivity, utility, and integrity of information disseminated by Federal agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA8170892FD6448AA81AF5A5A46C1CC1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waiver of secretarial determination</header><text>Beginning on January 1, 2021, the requirement for a determination by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B) shall be waived for transferring, selling, or otherwise providing uranium by the Secretary if the uranium has been identified in the updated long-term Federal excess uranium inventory management plan under subsection (c)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF480D6E221F94B0EBB358FBBE2E87940"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (g) (as redesignated by paragraph (1)), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>(d)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>(f)(2)</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


