<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9FDDE78B3EDF4E08938666A34EA66E44" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 164 IH: Ensuring the Full Faith and Credit of the United States and Protecting America's Soldiers and Seniors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 164</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require that the United States Government prioritize all obligations on the debt held by the
			 public, Social Security benefits, and military pay in the event that the
			 debt limit is reached, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H52E1379FACC14D40A6E87FCC9E06988C" style="OLC">
		<section id="H7C3B5FEDBB714326BA23F58854E1AE7D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring the Full Faith and Credit of the United States and Protecting America's Soldiers and
			 Seniors Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H29464C95B9F241B78C9E90B1DB0EA637"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC882DDD31174F5783B4C665DEC87352"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury is legally required to carry out the obligations set forth in Public
			 Law 104–121.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32D00926D3984D8CB017B82DE3B7E6DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The debt obligations held by the Social Security trust fund may only be redeemed in order to pay
			 Social Security benefits and necessary administrative expenses.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3A1BDD69ED84284BD1AC0C557B5A974"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">So long as there is a positive balance of assets in the Social Security trust fund, an appropriate
			 amount of obligations may be converted into an equal amount of publicly
			 held debt in order to finance the full and timely payment of all Social
			 Security obligations without exceeding the debt ceiling.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HFC65244409D9475AA3D7946A91EA74EF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prioritize obligations on the debt held by the public, Social Security benefits, and military pay</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the event that the debt of the United States Government reaches the statutory limit as defined
			 in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3101">section 3101</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, the following shall take
			 equal priority over all other obligations incurred by the Government of
			 the United States:</text>
			<paragraph id="H89792E4229E84F3692747D1D9DD1B41D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the Department of the Treasury contained in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3123">section 3123</external-xref> of title 31, United
			 States Code, to pay with legal tender the principal and interest on debt
			 held by the public.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H4884AB9E5DDC4B9EA9AE6BBD45A6F27A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The authority of the Commissioner of Social Security to pay monthly old-age, survivors’ and
			 disability insurance benefits under title II of the Social Security Act.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HFD92D733727F45D183B9D62F8573DCFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The payment of pay and allowances for members of the Armed Forces on active duty.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


