<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6FC56CC51D004984873DC63C1E30A5A9" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1850 IH: FPS Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1850</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To protect Federal employees and visitors, improve the security of Federal facilities, authorize
			 and modernize the Federal Protective Service, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HE2613215123C4B8783DEB41E2D9DDDA6" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB731D4D945D14206B6E34E2FBB69ACEA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FPS Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" id="HE5C559C7DBC34B44A29E45104081D7C8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the terms <term>appropriate congressional committees</term>, <term>Federal facility</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, <term>Director</term>, <term>facility security level</term>, <term>Federal Protective Service law enforcement officer</term>, and <term>protective security officer</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1331 of title 40, United States Code (as added by this Act).</text>
		</section><section id="H175E2A533AD541F7B619103BB94DF700"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal protective service</header>
 <subsection id="HD30D508D28F74E97A8834977D971A8A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/13">Chapter 13</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD560858AD5DC4CD78C8D85F15832FBA0" style="USC"> <subchapter id="HA95BBC54028F414491ECCA23924FD34A"><enum>II</enum><header>Federal Protective Services</header> <section id="HB64EBF0EEE354EF189BCB8846F99D445"><enum>1331.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC4944FFBB03C4BCEBE3CC1D92B43AEE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE0CE9B7E753043A88CEDC3CA10ADE15F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE205A36B1A134688ABC538A842304618"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC7400FC53BCA43BEAE22E9A46206CFD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H87974E79560E40CC81C45E84A5864391"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3F2BCE62AE9A4FA8A6A7EBD5B6D4CBD7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Federal Protective Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF0828708C81A451292C0CDF2D2512297"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal facility</header><text>The term <term>Federal facility</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEDC5420A822645EDB37CFDBCF28BA8AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any building and grounds and all property located in or on that building and grounds, that are owned, occupied or secured by the Federal Government, including any agency, instrumentality or wholly owned or mixed-ownership corporation of the Federal Government; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8DC2D5C7658A42288854DD248A89920B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H678C5B0266FE436191788B4ABF2BC167"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any building, grounds, or property used for military activities; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H539D4E0DBF334BE38066EB28EFCE882C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any facility used for activities covered under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2011">42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC85ED542154B4D53AFBE2E18F0B4853B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal Protective Service law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>Federal Protective Service law enforcement officer</term> means a law enforcement officer or agent designated under section 1332.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D0C559923B94EA0BF05320D4A0F0962"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Facility Security Committee</header><text>The term <term>Facility Security Committee</term> means an agency or an internal agency component responsible for security policy at a specific Federal facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H601BDFFE70F94AC4B5338F6276154E9C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Facility security level</header><text>The term <term>facility security level</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H17DBD8FAAA7C402BBBC9F40A2525C550"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a rating of each Federal facility based on the analysis of several facility factors including factors that provide a basis for that facility’s attractiveness as a target and potential effects or consequences of an attack, which then serves as a basis for the implementation of certain levels of security protection by the Interagency Security Committee; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC3CC7C086EC14461B54903C0C91681C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is determined by the Federal Protective Service, the United States Marshals Service under section 566 of title 28, or another agency authorized to provide all protective services for a facility and is guided by Interagency Security Committee standards.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8DF01C3754AB4CD2BFF4DA0228F49D3B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>In-service field staff</header><text>The term <term>in-service field staff</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9F32C260A1794A67B5EBF7B91FECD51D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal Protective Service law enforcement officer; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H77C7E700E4EB4904BAC30BF5B89E1F6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a police officer, inspector, area commander or special agent, or such other equivalent positions as designated by the Secretary who, while working, is directly engaged on a daily basis in protecting and enforcing law at Federal facilities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H79BDF78B7BEB424683F5DA26BFB283DF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Protective security officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>protective security officer</term> means an employee of a Federal Protective Service contractor or subcontractor engaged in the protection of a building, grounds, or property that is owned, occupied, or secured by the Federal Government (including any agency, instrumentality, or wholly owned or mixed-ownership corporation thereof) and the persons on the property.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3AD80C93B0F740FFBC0BC304DFF9BA62"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security acting through the Director.</text> </paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4704FE2903EB428AB1B35022482CC902"><enum>1332.</enum><header>Law enforcement authority of Secretary of Homeland Security for protection of public property</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H121DFF6BE0374ABCA79F20C4EEA9FCBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>To the extent provided for by transfers made pursuant to the Homeland Security Act of 2002, the Secretary shall protect the buildings, grounds, and property that are owned, occupied, or secured by the Federal Government (including any agency, instrumentality, or wholly owned or mixed-ownership corporation thereof) and the persons on the property.</text>
							</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0777E510DEFF4EB1B029C0C3B032AEBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Officers and Agents</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H419ED01D33624EB79348E0984370FD11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Secretary may designate employees of the Department of Homeland Security, including employees transferred to the Department from the Office of the Federal Protective Service of the General Services Administration pursuant to the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as officers and agents for duty in connection with the protection of property owned or occupied by the Federal Government and persons on the property, including duty in areas outside the property to the extent necessary to protect the property and persons on the property.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1E6D830E40D1423798F9D1D16725E544"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers</header><text>While engaged in the performance of official duties, an officer or agent designated under this subsection may—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2C5DA50BD3EA4F26AD7FE55CD96E376C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enforce Federal laws and regulations for the protection of persons and property;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2E6777D2F9E64A22B2B8044BB28CF0FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make arrests without a warrant for any offense against the United States committed in the presence of the officer or agent or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if the officer or agent has reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing a felony;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF2D4807AD8404DBCA32646A970FFB3AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>serve warrants and subpoenas issued under the authority of the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H84730FAC85824FF8BDF7F79C5D92B00B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conduct investigations, on and off the property in question, of offenses that may have been committed against property owned or occupied by the Federal Government or persons on the property; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCB057519AD524974BDFB1F1ED63EFEC8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>carry out such other activities for the promotion of homeland security as the Secretary may prescribe.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4756BEAE5FBF430981C09384D918CC39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional power</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An officer or agent designated under this subsection may carry a firearm on or off duty.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H06DCACDCEFB547608922FFD664FC14C4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the minimum level of training or certification for—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A089E64E7634EB59702E1F4A5DF260E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employees of the Federal Protective Service including Federal Protective Service law enforcement officers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3A9D7F8CB7FD4451AD5DEE6CD835AF5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protective security officers; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5047D967E10945528BCE44B308CC5189"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a reliable system will be developed to track the compliance of protective security officers with the certifications deemed necessary by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC4F1F08BF11F4E45BAC9BA9BDF4B7BAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inspections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall inspect Federal facilities protected by the Federal Protective Service for the purpose of determining compliance with Federal security standards, as determined by the Interagency Security Committee, and making appropriate risk mitigation recommendations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7398DE6D322B4DA386AD371471173375"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Security countermeasures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, shall ensure and supervise the effective design, procurement, installation, and operation of security countermeasures, including armed contract guards, electronic physical security systems, and weapons and explosives screening devices, for a Federal facility protected by the Federal Protective Service.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H2D96D77AD6C34689A1290BBE70782BEB"><enum>1333.</enum><header>Full-time equivalent employee requirements</header>
 <subsection id="H0B7EEE1AF907471186A6DFB5F8B3E188"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the Federal Protective Service shall maintain at any time not fewer than 1,870 full-time equivalent employees, including not fewer than 1,318 in-service field staff.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9BEB1934AB674359A4E20F8ED99B5116"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>In any fiscal year after fiscal year 2015 in which the number of full-time equivalent employees of the Federal Protective Service is fewer than the number of full-time equivalent employees of the Federal Protective Service in the previous fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that provides—</text>
 <paragraph id="H17043904AC83422F96F0EAB824488E5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an explanation of the decrease in full-time equivalent employees; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H406C1EEF9AA649F5A3863BD78DDA1CA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a revised model of the number of full-time equivalent employees projected for future fiscal years.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFD2E4C4000BC422BBBED6F8EA65A5592"><enum>1334.</enum><header>Protective security officers</header>
							<subsection id="HBB3FF2B7998D4FED8F89D943F303F4EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorities for protective security officers</header>
 <paragraph id="H65FF6C1E3C7F41829872510174058274"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Carrying of firearms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may authorize protective security officers engaged in the protection of buildings and grounds that are owned, occupied, or secured by the General Services Administration Public Building Service as the Secretary considers necessary in the interests of the common defense and security to carry firearms to carry out their official duties.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H931D1992671149ECA40BECDF77298B50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Detention without a warrant</header><text>A person authorized to carry firearms under this subsection may, while in the performance of, and in connection with, official duties, detain an individual without a warrant for any offense against the United States committed in that person’s presence or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if that person has reasonable ground to believe that the individual to be detained has committed or is committing such felony. The detention authority conferred by this paragraph is in addition to any detention authority under other laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF22C875C45CA4B32A78E45B26407AD88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following limitations apply:</text> <paragraph id="HD3BF6F0A49B54E1984AA2CBEBF0E4BE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A protective security officer authorized to carry firearms under this section may detain an individual only when the individual to be detained is within, or in direct flight from, the area of such offense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H027FD65926704B71ABB70F92F3002A9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A person granted authority to detain an individual by this section may exercise that authority only in the enforcement of laws regarding any building and grounds and all property located in or on that building and grounds that are owned, occupied, or secured by the General Services Administration Public Building Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE18E9C690878403C8FBE4BA8308AD3C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary, with the approval of the Attorney General, shall issue guidelines to implement this section.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H9D8EFFEF1DFB41D1AFDE85FD1C8C0E96"><enum>1335.</enum><header>Compliance of Federal facilities with Federal security standards</header>
 <subsection id="H070D34A78C894596AB1B40ECA7958647"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may assess security charges to an agency that is the owner or the tenant of a Federal facility protected by the Federal Protective Service in addition to any security charge assessed for the costs of necessary security countermeasures if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H526B96B489E14B42AE3AFA8FCF972BD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary, in coordination with the Interagency Security Committee, determines a Federal facility to be in noncompliance with Federal security standards established by the Interagency Security Committee or a final determination regarding countermeasures made by the appeals board established under section 1336(h); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1DD4483EFF647CA9F01712032004D01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Interagency Security Committee or the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B4BA6FD147D4F2892C31D354F0A253B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provided notice to that agency and the Facility Security Committee of—</text>
 <clause id="HE52A676CA3184D4D9C3541B88FE014D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the noncompliance;</text> </clause><clause id="H020840CFE6BA486FADBFE45D0C33FC37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the actions necessary to be in compliance; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H74E3385F5C854B3BB0A4611BD9CBF811"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the latest date on which such actions need to be taken; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AB23166D5D04A6A8B8AF0EA8E70FC98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the agency is not in compliance by that date.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A66FA26079D4EDD86B5BAC6AE51EF73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on noncompliant facilities</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees, in a classified manner if necessary, of any facility determined to be in noncompliance with standards established by the Interagency Security Committee.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H50F0ABAC3227451F9239B428E86F965E"><enum>1336.</enum><header>Interagency security committee</header>
 <subsection id="HCA9A960841274A868935E9A09EC14694"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the executive branch the Interagency Security Committee (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) responsible for the development of safety and security standards and best practices to mitigate the effects of natural and manmade hazards in Federal facilities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D5B614E1C2E477F9D924E6CF180D696"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Committee shall be chaired by the Secretary or a designee of the Secretary. The chairpersons shall be responsible for the daily operations of the Committee and appeals board, final approval and enforcement of Committee standards, and the promulgation of regulations related to Federal facility security prescribed by the Committee.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H440727A55B7D4A18811F25C49936D6D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="H33AB1BC3D5734E0C8CCBA746B4E72AFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voting members</header><text>The Committee shall consist of the following voting members:</text> <subparagraph id="H3B711C7F69844FE7AF3FAAE5DBFFCE5A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Agency representatives</header><text>Representatives from the following agencies, appointed by the agency heads:</text>
 <clause id="H3779B40A7F01488190A950F15114921A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Department of Homeland Security.</text> </clause><clause id="HE96E98958664489CBB539E8DB6CEB5C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Department of State.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE8CCFA7ABCDC4F0E8F3223FF18F06C64"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Department of the Treasury.</text> </clause><clause id="H253BC987A4B342798F09E80652EAD385"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Department of Defense.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H57A4C1776D6E44C082573A8132F5FA7E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Department of Justice.</text> </clause><clause id="HCA24B4BB010B452BBDAA54F28525164E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Department of the Interior.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB742CFE6E215468398776BD6FA7F705A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Department of Agriculture.</text> </clause><clause id="H8451F2204C274D609E8F2DE33CDC3D18"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Department of Commerce.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H886EABF6F4CB4AD886F4991B88ABC8BA"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Department of Labor.</text> </clause><clause id="H6405635E1F47478CA15FB21E26D63228"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCD3C92D73B0F4DE690E22730A427262E"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text> </clause><clause id="H9D05BF6402354A59BA0C7CBD3F6EAAA7"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Department of Transportation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF64413AEA7F4A1AB476396456A4464B"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>Department of Energy.</text> </clause><clause id="HE963BC34F8994C9A8606CEB14AA49FF9"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>Department of Education.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF1BA0690F9D340A7B2769CE8A9CAB462"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>Department of Veterans Affairs.</text> </clause><clause id="H4CCD06D002F847F2B6A1B679B6154913"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB5334C3EDFB743B4AB058BAD710677B7"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>Central Intelligence Agency.</text> </clause><clause id="HFD2344F5221E403EAD192DC33A633E8D"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H547B07CA5B5344CA913CE52CC6C3CA6F"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>General Services Administration.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E72E34E4388409B8CBF738DDE84CEC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other officers</header><text>The following Federal officers or the designees of those officers:</text>
 <clause id="H8E003BA68DB2405D96FE6CF0F9506466"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Director of the United States Marshals Service.</text> </clause><clause id="H6C754A2BFCCD485B8E30144872BABDEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1DB5EEF930F413EB9B5A2D3072701F8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Judicial branch representatives</header><text>A representative from the judicial branch appointed by the Chief Justice of the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69CD5B8FD58B4BEEBB6B21FD823383DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Associate members</header><text>The Committee shall include, as associate members who shall be nonvoting members, representatives from the following agencies, appointed by the agency heads:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFBC612AF46F34B1F94F3AE4C78DEC804"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal Aviation Administration.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56CBAA102DDD4B40A4F77B3DB101428F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67D631FCFF3D49D6BF09F8DF0C343555"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3B6F3B8D7384023810615429987AE65"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B79F7A02C394DF2A3876255261E7A48"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Federal Reserve Board.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC93033EB01E4EEAA9913BE1F083F35B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Internal Revenue Service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FEE1069952949DF86FC2DC801ECD247"><enum>(G)</enum><text>National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2B5609D8A4F4CFC9DF128AD4BED4931"><enum>(H)</enum><text>National Capital Planning Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16852FC542664E7AA6003A3EE7A339E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>National Institute of Standards &amp; Technology.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3243190300614694A57E20698E1A11BE"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5BD08B5B837441F926873BFA0853E75"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Office of Personnel Management.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2F84606890E4B2FAAAF557E3FF4A92E"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Securities and Exchange Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H284AAE202F6840FA9251DF3C1EFA5525"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Social Security Administration.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDCF3BA0E6EB43C1B5D6823339737A8D"><enum>(N)</enum><text>United States Coast Guard.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A97E152999E47EFAD5E96D89DB74EAC"><enum>(O)</enum><text>United States Postal Service.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AE32A004EF2472C97D783D1682E61FA"><enum>(P)</enum><text>United States Army Corps of Engineers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC8C622A4A2C48529673E242F717BB89"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6854F55D0E6E41EEA922F54FB5401728"><enum>(R)</enum><text>Any other Federal officers as the President shall appoint.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H219C625F8516485CA5B07F43719BC3D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Working groups</header><text>The Committee may establish interagency working groups to perform such tasks as may be directed by the Committee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H694665B1CC6048269647CFD391E0FAF8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Committee shall consult with other parties, including the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, to perform its responsibilities. At the discretion of the Chairperson of the Committee, such other parties may participate in the working groups.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H23872AD107064275BEA22AFBAE9BE261"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Committee shall, at a minimum, meet quarterly.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H66CB4B08D6DC4E2DB44F1AD6CA094AE2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Committee shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3CCD7FB064A244AA899A2F60EE967DC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>FPS Improvement Act of 2015</short-title>, propose regulations to the Secretary for promulgation under section 1332(c)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA7AACC5264746B19B99D7C33E946437"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for determining facility security levels, unless the Committee determines that similar regulations are issued by the Secretary before the end of that 1-year period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DBBD78D63D14D388518762E3D7CB3AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to establish risk-based performance standards for the security of Federal facilities, unless the Committee determines that similar regulations are issued by the Secretary before the end of that 1-year period;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55D88F55F8254810BD51F02D8145F1E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish protocols for the testing of the compliance of Federal facilities with Federal security standards, including a mechanism for the initial and recurrent testing of Federal facilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AF3CAF74700424889EFDCB6FBF67376"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prescribe regulations to determine minimum levels of training and certification of contract guards;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H043F88A5BD2542F1B40840BD7E80D7FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prescribe regulations to establish a list of prohibited items for entry into Federal facilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE95912B4DA4D2C963235C238293455"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish minimum requirements and a process for providing security training for members of Facility Security Committees (as described in section 1337);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FB41A2DBD4A4EE286E9C1352D317669"><enum>(6)</enum><text>take such actions as may be necessary to enhance the quality and effectiveness of security and protection of Federal facilities, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H17909EECFA924349B1A438F27687EA1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encouraging agencies with security responsibilities to share security-related intelligence in a timely and cooperative manner;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA97E982AFFFA446B9AA93BDDFDDBA9C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessing technology and information systems as a means of providing cost-effective improvements to security in Federal facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DE7E53D729D4E778DD727614704FFFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing construction standards for those locations with threat levels or missions that require blast resistant structures or other specialized security requirements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2EACDBC99B6490C97C901AECE5C4F34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>evaluating standards for the location of, and special security related to, day care centers in Federal facilities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A27994C025640768C6E70A3F5E360F8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assisting the Secretary in developing and maintaining a secure centralized security database of all Federal facilities; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB934A2B6C67444BE92E17909B31ACFDA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>carry out such other duties as assigned by the President.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9166E90F2CD4F6288A63E77DC065C2F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Appeals board</header> <paragraph id="H139C36328F374EF791729F945D32BB74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Committee shall establish an appeals board to consider appeals from any Facility Security Committee, or the Secretary, of a—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8D04AB23B0F74761B7F8AF2BDBD1D700"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facility security level determination;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6088B89997E6485ABCA724391D40DDA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Facility Security Committee decision to overturn a determination of necessary countermeasures or physical security improvements if the Secretary considered such a decision a grave risk to the facility or its occupants; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8A44A7805CB4C5BB6ADA43FC1DA71BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determination of noncompliance with Federal facility security standards.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H993FE764AEF6455AB4D1F81662D19984"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final appeal</header><text>A decision of the appeals board is final and shall not be subject to administrative or judicial review.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H907713A4AE1943FF9B19AF3C26EDFD05"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Agency support and cooperation</header>
 <paragraph id="H95B18EF9D80244D78A61AA8EC9756D49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent permitted by law and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall provide the Committee such administrative services, funds, facilities, staff, and other support services as may be necessary for the performance of the functions of the Committee under this subtitle.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HEACB7FF69EF745F398045D4AF8D337A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cooperation and compliance</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2250E12995184D61B9B4338FA62E009A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each agency shall cooperate and comply with the policies, standards, and determinations of the Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25D072E8487E4E89BAD2D138DCAF17CD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Support</header><text>To the extent permitted by law and subject to the availability of appropriations, agencies shall provide such support as may be necessary to enable the Committee to perform the duties and responsibilities of the Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83D1A26D36DD43449F4603F9B49825CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>The Secretary shall be responsible for monitoring agency compliance with the policies and determinations of the Committee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H393C49CC1C2C450F8D397C1A6D5753B8"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department such sums as necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H03D342724D704B7D8FB9EAB3D204FB63"><enum>1337.</enum><header>Facility security committees</header>
 <subsection id="H11D15B0929A946B683EA54E5CE25BE70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Maintenance of facility security committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agencies that are tenants at each Federal facility shall maintain a Facility Security Committee for that Federal facility. Each agency that is a tenant at a Federal facility shall provide 1 employee to serve as a member of the Facility Security Committee.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HF6A2136D30914814BF198B1D539C1B83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chairperson</header>
 <paragraph id="H456211D912D94809B672548537BA6204"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Facility Security Committee shall be headed by a chairperson, elected by a majority of the members of the Facility Security Committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3CD33F0E84B4A619C0C878A534187DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The chairperson shall be responsible for—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FA268A5CB4D4944BFCC80C2F88DE340"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintaining accurate contact information for agency tenants and providing that information, including any updates, to the Federal Protective Service;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19DDF3E684334A6ABE84BC16007AE96A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>setting the agenda for Facility Security Committee meetings;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78DBB617F99A43C99590540D1B964B14"><enum>(C)</enum><text>referring Facility Security Committee member questions to Federal Protective Service for response;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D8F2FF05FEF49CBBB3B3DD9E55DF8EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reviewing a security assessment completed by the Federal Protective Service or designated security organization representatives and, if requested by the Federal Protective Service, accompanying the representatives during on-site facility security assessments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H345930544FBB4C1086553A2B453AD6A1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>maintaining an official record of each meeting;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF38CBE682F39400BBD041FE2AF1320C3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>acknowledging receipt of the facility security assessment from Federal Protective Service;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40C23EC3656D47F3BFFA6607C338ED67"><enum>(G)</enum><text>maintaining records of training of or waivers for members of the Facility Security Committee; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD67756E886014D03B5CA811B1CE9E161"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other duties as determined by the Interagency Security Committee.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01D406DBF6BD4D809D12D90C7ACF1544"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training for members</header>
 <paragraph id="HD1C29313D64F4532A9C77A8E3D444162"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraphs (3) and (4), before serving as a member of a Facility Security Committee, an employee shall successfully complete a training course that meets a minimum standard of training as established by the Interagency Security Committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80F57F7400F64C028DF600A388884F92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training</header><text>Training under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HDB9772B9686C4F66B5924F4D0FBE4504"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be provided by the Federal Protective Service in accordance with standards established by the Interagency Security Committee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AF241454BC345D8A972F71BA835D5DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be commensurate with the facility security level; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF3AF96A2F8946F2AB73796B4CC9A1AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include training relating to—</text>
 <clause id="H753011895A9749A39090DD082992618D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>familiarity with published standards of the Interagency Security Committee;</text> </clause><clause id="H593E10CE4D754A5BB67740DC5580485E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>physical security criteria for Federal facilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD55EAF5589C44E1195F654958721F96A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>use of physical security performance measures;</text> </clause><clause id="HEF12D182C8E842ECB279F82C0428AE63"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>facility security levels determinations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0758B48DAB8F4419A64B961AE4517E0A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>best practices for safe mail handling;</text> </clause><clause id="H527C36B346BC4978BEB7EE977D2DC877"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>knowledge of an occupant emergency plan, the facility security assessment process, and the facility countermeasures plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEF2AD44332DF497B88A3D0CFC85FAB75"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the role of the Federal Protective Service and the General Services Administration; and</text> </clause><clause id="H56BCE5D4E97F4BA09E74758CBE8B7367"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>financing of countermeasures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F73D645B0EF4F21B253E07E98E39F56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The training requirement under this subsection may be waived by the Secretary, the head of a Facility Security Committee, or the Chairperson of the Interagency Security Committee if the Secretary, the head of a Facility Security Committee, or the Chairperson determines that an employee has related experience in physical security, law enforcement, or infrastructure security disciplines.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H7DF0BD7A92324733938F2C0413104042"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Incumbent members</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFFC79E0B49684F60A8CCDF52B8C5E886"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This subsection shall apply to any Facility Security Committee established before, on, or after the date of enactment of <short-title>FPS Improvement Act of 2015</short-title>, except that any member of a Facility Security Committee serving on that date shall, during the 1-year period following that date—</text>
 <clause id="HC2ED9115357D4FC1AF63DAF59ADB2EF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>successfully complete a training course as required under paragraph (1); or</text> </clause><clause id="H0181329AE3314C28A7575BC41ECDEA60"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>obtain a waiver under paragraph (3).</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4F2897C10DD4AB0A58C590E0A95303D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings and quorum</header>
 <paragraph id="H9A2A7BF2823B4CCDAC0090177845B1B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Each Facility Security Committee shall meet on a quarterly basis, or more frequently if determined appropriate by the chairperson.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H148C7A6DAEFC475C9E6950895FAD2F82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of a Facility Security Committee shall be present for a quorum to conduct business.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5AB9B5842074CCA999726B5C662352E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appeal</header>
 <paragraph id="H6BBF1EEE3BB54475902A24318B8F64C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a Facility Security Committee disagrees with a determination of a facility security level or a determination of noncompliance with Federal security standards, the Chairperson of a Facility Security Committee may file an appeal of the determination with the Interagency Security Committee appeals board.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D483D8965AC47728F33108D7EA8CDAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Decision to appeal</header><text>The decision to file an appeal shall be agreed to by a majority of the members of a Facility Security Committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BE5EFC35DC2455B82B4D550A9F47F5E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matters subject to appeal</header><text>A determination of the Federal Protective Service may be appealed under this subsection, including any determination relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D6010F0E62C460BAC11A464F3F2C02E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>countermeasure improvements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E3627468C4842368A20A3333490A5ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facility security assessment findings; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2A989A701F745999A5D7FE0335533E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facility security levels.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H4ADC4EFC8AC54A8899A8DE25D0635E55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="H13DA738E0CA24AFEBC21A87BA6A65C71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Section 1315 of title 40, United States Code, is repealed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28C9B3EE21F242758E8B0ABF18149243"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H777249A21FE541F689D5603A05DC2ED4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting before the item relating to section 1301 the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2CFB7A4243F4B0C9A1254575123E503" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter I—General Authorities</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">and</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40235FBB008343ADBDC0D246D0B7A7C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 1315 and adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02B2EF9AC10A41ABBC81427B76E803A7" style="USC"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HD560858AD5DC4CD78C8D85F15832FBA0" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="HA95BBC54028F414491ECCA23924FD34A" level="subchapter">Subchapter II—Federal Protective Services</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HB64EBF0EEE354EF189BCB8846F99D445" level="section">Sec.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HB64EBF0EEE354EF189BCB8846F99D445" level="section">1331. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4704FE2903EB428AB1B35022482CC902" level="section">1332. Law enforcement authority of Secretary of Homeland Security for protection of public property.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2D96D77AD6C34689A1290BBE70782BEB" level="section">1333. Full-time equivalent employee requirements.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HFD2E4C4000BC422BBBED6F8EA65A5592" level="section">1334. Protective security officers.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H9D8EFFEF1DFB41D1AFDE85FD1C8C0E96" level="section">1335. Compliance of Federal facilities with Federal security standards.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H50F0ABAC3227451F9239B428E86F965E" level="section">1336. Interagency security committee.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H03D342724D704B7D8FB9EAB3D204FB63" level="section">1337. Facility security committees.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66C3ED47463845B88A0D35517621DC2D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subchapter I of chapter 13</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/13">Chapter 13</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, is amended by inserting before section 1301 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H374593CC503F4B8CBD23317CC261A274" style="USC">
						<subchapter id="HDD4A52900E4F444190BD5D51C8B4DB2F"><enum>I</enum><header>General Authorities</header></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03404C0A84A14A369B66C0AA8A914CA3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Carrying concealed firearms</header><text>Section 926B(f) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>a Federal Protective Service law enforcement officer,</quote> after <quote>Federal Reserve,</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDE8C006A3BE41638624C12FCD5C4398"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 877(a) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/457">6 U.S.C. 457(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>1706(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>1332(b) of title 40, United States Code</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCF87A58F2B34664B0967FA791CF095E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Central Intelligence Agency Act amendment</header><text>Section 15 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3515">50 U.S.C. 3515</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H617A2F4C135541B49C03A5DB567F2838"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1) by striking <quote>1315(b)(2) of title 40</quote> and inserting <quote>1332(b)(2) of title 40</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H136118FE7D8040B6B3700063E64130FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b) by striking <quote>1315(c)(2) of title 40</quote> and inserting <quote>1332(c)(2) of title 40</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F1E115DD89D4A3EB5BDF8DBF2BF0475"><enum>(7)</enum><header>National Security Agency Act amendment</header><text>Section 11 of the National Security Agency Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3609">50 U.S.C. 3609</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H395318A7C4634A0185DDDF3FB42977DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1) by striking <quote>1315(b)(2) of title 40</quote> and inserting <quote>1332(b)(2) of title 40</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD217D5DEB8C3456F8C6E300A8C2232BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b) by striking <quote>1315(c)(2) of title 40</quote> and inserting <quote>1332(c)(2) of title 40</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8D527BBE6D9B483D9B17A1FC9255CEBA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on Federal Protective Service personnel needs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the personnel needs of the Federal Protective Service that includes recommendations on the numbers of Federal Protective Service law enforcement officers and the workforce composition of the Federal Protective Service needed to carry out the mission of the Federal Protective Service during the 10-fiscal year period beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section><section id="H2000BBA312214A2C9C83CE04C32C9BAF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on the feasibility of federalizing the protective security officer workforce</header>
 <subsection id="HE35729FE424E442593EFB12B54D23E04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the feasibility of federalizing the protective security officer workforce.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC582B3C7BA1475291431ECFFBDEE676"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and comment</header><text>The Secretary shall provide the report prepared under this section to a qualified consultant for review and comment before submitting the report to the appropriate congressional committees. The Secretary shall provide the comments of the qualified consultant to the appropriate congressional committee with the report.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H89126A1C52C44C928214A66C7E003E16"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under this section shall include an evaluation of—</text> <paragraph id="H0D7BF79F2D94431890AEBB7DCD56A01A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">converting in its entirety, or in part, the protective security officer workforce into full-time Federal employees;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3AA19C886B342E2971DCEF2E60A4AFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the option of posting a full-time equivalent Federal Protective Service law enforcement officer at each level 3 or 4 Federal facility, as determined by the Interagency Security Committee, that on the date of enactment of this Act has a protective security officer stationed at the facility;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79BBF62B7FDE40AC89993207DAD692F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential increase in security of any option evaluated under paragraph (1) and (2);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H678504806B684499BB05E43D1D637D2A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the immediate and projected costs of any option evaluated under paragraph (1) and (2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FF5C1E6CFC44221A71A159957D39091"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the immediate and projected costs of maintaining the current level of protective security officers and full-time Federal Protective Service law enforcement officers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F4FCC36E8A64FBAB2033B2AE9EA9D8F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a comparison of similar conversions of large groups of contracted workers and potential benefits and challenges.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1B665D2FA65E40A599D2A07C00B56CA1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report on agency funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the method of funding for the Federal Protective Service, which shall include recommendations regarding whether the Federal Protective Service should—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDC6D795C5FD84C3A9BDB3716D0975201"><enum>(1)</enum><text>continue to be funded by a collection of fees and security charges;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F8F3CD93495492081C597CC2EE66788"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be funded by appropriations; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9901D2909C054178BB313233B2FC049F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be funded by a combination of fees, security charges, and appropriations.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H1A426511DCE44D25A7AC628B7A556E69"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on preventing explosives from entering Federal facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the feasibility, effectiveness, safety and privacy implications of the use or potential use of available methods to detect or prevent explosives from entering Federal facilities, including the use of additional canine teams, advanced imaging technology, or other technology or methods for detecting explosives.</text>
 </section><section id="H2CB569E386E34F10B79C12387B36F1A6"><enum>8.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, including the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to affect—</text> <paragraph id="H21977B7A12CB4C6981AF98FB49C30BD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the authorities under section 566 of title 28, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC691E7990124237A3585F307A5F3FAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority of any Federal law enforcement agency other than the Federal Protective Service; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H882F8349E1254AC08409FAE4D9374367"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any authority of the Federal Protective Service not specifically enumerated by this Act that is in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


