<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3A67E67EC136445BAA0DD88793336A7C" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 450 IH: Protect Democracy From Criminal Corporations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 450</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150121">January 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit criminal corporations from making disbursements of funds in connection with a campaign for election for Federal, State, or local office.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7A6594FB20EB49CBBC0B6DE24816795B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9B5EF5984757488781DC0F86FF0A7DC1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Democracy From Criminal Corporations Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H99B38736536047EE97C2DA316D77A631"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting political spending by criminal corporations</header> <subsection id="H701EB5C1EE8D4A148FE665863051E194"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H20627365C4F349BDB675254A2B01BA17" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H4E97DBAEB85847B3A777F7F5333DB407"><enum>325.</enum><header>Prohibiting political spending by criminal corporations</header> 
<subsection id="H9B53CEFC65DB4449A73B930074B971A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> 
<paragraph id="H223D2AE956A644ABAA898173CFEB3741"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent that corporations are permitted under law to make a disbursement of funds in connection with a campaign for election for Federal, State, or local office, including a disbursement consisting of a contribution or donation of money or other thing of value, an independent expenditure, or a disbursement for an electioneering communication (as defined in section 304(f)(3)), it shall be unlawful for a corporation which is a criminal corporation, or for any separate segregated fund established under section 316(b)(2)(C) by a criminal corporation, to make such a disbursement during the applicable period described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CA7744E3CC14D539FCE15FDA4FA0EB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable period described</header><text>In paragraph (1), the <quote>applicable period</quote> with respect to a criminal corporation is the 6-year period which begins—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0FC6BC4B58CF4B90A26BA98DD1E7E908"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a criminal corporation described in paragraph (1) of subsection (b), on the date on which the corporation is finally convicted of the offense described in such paragraph; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A07C3BFBEFD43798B0D54E946C65C5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a criminal corporation described in paragraph (2) of subsection (b), on the date on which the corporation enters into an agreement described in such paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEE4704E5D743423F8D6966C0DD3665BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criminal Corporation Defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>criminal corporation</term> means a corporation—</text> <paragraph id="HEA8F621FD3A843799FCA65FAFB294DED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>which has been convicted of violating section 371 of title 18, United States Code (relating to conspiracy to commit offense or to defraud the United States), or any other felony involving dishonesty or a breach of trust; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DEE525AF5CC4D8FA5866C9B8ECC1D3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which has been charged with violating section 371 of such title or with another felony involving dishonesty or a breach of trust and has entered into a nonprosecution agreement, a deferred prosecution agreement, or any other agreement with the Attorney General to resolve the charge, if the terms and conditions of the agreement include a requirement that the corporation make a payment equal to or greater than $1,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC4E54C9A0DAC458782F93536944ED9DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to a corporation which is convicted of the offense described in paragraph (1) of section 325(b) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (as added by subsection (a)), or which enters into an agreement described in paragraph (2) of such section, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

