<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6A84DBE3B8C4407B9378BB5D569C9F8E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1646 IH: Homeland Security Drone Assessment and Analysis Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1646</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to research how small and medium sized unmanned
			 aerial systems could be used in an attack, how to prevent or mitigate the
			 effects of such an attack, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H09BB9624710843FAB894E284F886F0B6" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBC7FF1DBAE2944A7A0D3C33C32E4E9E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeland Security Drone Assessment and Analysis Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF15EB3231EE1437FA9B7B6998345714F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Drone assessment and analysis</header> <subsection id="H784E94A1E7374306BBE2EF0BB5CFAAE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall research how commercially available small and medium sized unmanned aerial systems could be used to perpetuate an attack and, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Secretary of Energy, develop Federal policies, guidance, and protocols to prevent such an attack or mitigate the effects of such an attack.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCF38538682BB4D51A7540F903E58B803"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dissemination to State and local officials</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall disseminate information to State, local, and tribal law enforcement officials regarding how such officials may bolster preparedness for and responses to attacks perpetrated by commercially available small and medium sized unmanned aerial systems.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5B189C04AC3847AB8DDFFE0A8CA22B59"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate an assessment of the security threat associated with the commercial availability of small and medium sized unmanned aerial systems. Such assessment shall be informed by research conducted in accordance with subsection (a) and may be developed in coordination with the Centers of Excellence of the Department of Homeland Security and other academic institutions.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


