<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD4D9EBD1E2434582BD7F5EA13717F25C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1607 RH: Ruth Moore Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 156</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1607</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 114–207]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150325">March 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000613">Mr. Dold</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000570">Mr. Guinta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150716">July 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>
			</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>July 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 25, 2015</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the disability compensation evaluation procedure
			 of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for veterans with mental health
			 conditions related to military sexual trauma, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDDC7BD979ED34E879C2BA43C43E0F42B" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6F2E9C5F79E5444594D49647A40C9C89" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ruth Moore Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAD447BA4E77A46A69004CE011841CA60" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports on claims for disabilities incurred or aggravated by military sexual trauma</header> <subsection id="HE7406330BDC3480DBE10B5B309B27A41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual reports</header> <paragraph id="H1524531D0A24437FA4DB11488AFB0019"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter VI of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90977EE9CA6B440CA2509B766E76DE2D" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
						<section id="H144321F9EDFB485D9521DE84DEDE7D36"><enum>1164.</enum><header>Reports on claims for disabilities incurred or aggravated by military sexual trauma</header>
 <subsection id="HAA8F4C6EEBA4498CB2C7DFBB37ED47C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 1, 2015, and each year thereafter through 2019, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on covered claims submitted during the previous fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE91FF57A775411E9FC176B7FE07F2F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA3DBEC84FD8E439AB90610821344FF25"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of covered claims submitted to or considered by the Secretary during the fiscal year covered by the report.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC169EF68D1F45D09341CA39FF6FC630"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Of the covered claims listed under paragraph (1), the number and percentage of such claims—</text> <subparagraph id="HAF4AECF8C30B400BBC610A0A1337FED1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submitted by each sex;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H178ABE4308AD4DFC903BFB6AEBF7ED9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that were approved, including the number and percentage of such approved claims submitted by each sex; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53D928F09828456799063A6EA044DB5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that were denied, including the number and percentage of such denied claims submitted by each sex.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8D44B208FDC453BA6B5B9E0560521FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the covered claims listed under paragraph (1) that were approved, the number and percentage, listed by each sex, of claims assigned to each rating percentage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC048B508987F4B8E91F32BF8065C8793"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Of the covered claims listed under paragraph (1) that were denied—</text> <subparagraph id="H743A550C515F4F7C89F1224E984B345C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the three most common reasons given by the Secretary under section 5104(b)(1) of this title for such denials; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9614CCAD170342419DF0ABDF68515DEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of denials that were based on the failure of a veteran to report for a medical examination.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H994A66C04FFF4DE4BAFF1CA890CA8C1D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of covered claims that, as of the end of the fiscal year covered by the report, are pending and, separately, the number of such claims on appeal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C4CFBC19227449AA07C518201E24F27"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For the fiscal year covered by the report, the average number of days that covered claims take to complete beginning on the date on which the claim is submitted.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABA52383918D4E179F1BFD584EA13B04"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of the training that the Secretary provides to employees of the Veterans Benefits Administration specifically with respect to covered claims, including the frequency, length, and content of such training.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0E4324293B642A9A94EC9B8D8CBCC54"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C95989CDCBF43008F5C2B7572465EF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered claims</term> means claims for disability compensation submitted to the Secretary based on a covered mental health condition alleged to have been incurred or aggravated by military sexual trauma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7B12350462E241978827ED68D192651A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered mental health condition</term> means post-traumatic stress disorder, anxiety, depression, or other mental health diagnosis described in the current version of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders published by the American Psychiatric Association that the Secretary determines to be related to military sexual trauma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCF77658D079849B08DD30CA75A1605C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>military sexual trauma</term> means, with respect to a veteran, psychological trauma, which in the judgment of a mental health professional, resulted from a physical assault of a sexual nature, battery of a sexual nature, or sexual harassment which occurred during active military, naval, or air service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF64DE36B25C948C59E8F7B74A2F14E1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8243C8C6F5B4E949C9672C2BE3F7A1D" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
						<toc changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
							<toc-entry level="section">1164. Reports on claims for disabilities incurred or aggravated by military sexual trauma.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9290EDD2706D48B8B9A6C6E8C2F986B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress an initial report described in section 1164 of title 38, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1), by not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act. Such initial report shall be in addition to the annual reports required under such section beginning in December 2015.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAFA935B2EF44FCB919A1FB531729DA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should update and improve the regulations of the Department of Veterans Affairs with respect to military sexual trauma by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCCE4C2F5C393405A80B50512311D5C31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensuring that military sexual trauma is specified as an in-service stressor in determining the service-connection of post-traumatic stress disorder by including military sexual trauma as a stressor described in section 3.304(f)(3) of title 38, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCC0A8BEB7604FA3BFB43A53036FDED7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizing the full range of physical and mental disabilities (including depression, anxiety, and other disabilities as indicated in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders published by the American Psychiatric Association) that can result from military sexual trauma.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FC4B52D2CB347D8983EECF14505D2C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on the date that is 15 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the Secretary updates and improves regulations as described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB435979794304410B72C23E6FF944F7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to each veteran who has submitted a covered claim or been treated for military sexual trauma at a medical facility of the Department with a copy of the report under subsection (a)(3) or section 1164 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), that has most recently been submitted to Congress;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38623697384F46E181ADF7C6F9C576E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide on a monthly basis to each veteran who has submitted any claim for disability compensation or been treated at a medical facility of the Department information that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB54CC910D3BA4A46AB74D8AC2A1448B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that the Secretary plans to complete such updates and improvements to such regulations;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0597C1459ED04E89A724BB18DA424EC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of covered claims that have been granted or denied during the month covered by such information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A32546742C44B4A01EE3BA6A5AB2D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a comparison to such rate of grants and denials with the rate for other claims regarding post-traumatic stress disorder;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08013B74D4DC4FF0BAB222EAEF5AD321"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the three most common reasons for such denials;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFC84774100A46689CDEBDC21015A3F0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the average time for completion of covered claims;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82904A35232F482487C1F68F2A9E4B54"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the average time for processing covered claims at each regional office; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C17F8D9A7DF4AA6B221B23832A59B11"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any information the Secretary determines relevant with respect to submitting a covered claim;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DF99E464E2943DBB83A207DE7CB6974"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in addition to providing to veterans the information described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall make available on a monthly basis such information on a conspicuous location of the Internet website of the Department; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA2CD4C22B8C403C837908DE7098D4B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress on a monthly basis a report that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HE9BD5F35246E48029415D0B53D64B5DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of all adjudicated covered claims, including ancillary claims, during the month covered by the report;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03000BE1C7264E0192ABE43F0F7FCB1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the outcome with respect to each medical condition included in the claim; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE53BCFA9A274A0CB0504548357AA694"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the reason given for any denial of such a claim.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C288F64BF8C46F0B192D5E6032A1402"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Military sexual trauma defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2F65FC93D41D430FAD9E5DD4DD91A89A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered claim</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1164(c)(1) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78AA893004364A3E99EA3C133AA4471A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>military sexual trauma</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1164(c)(3) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD9BF035D43C24858B82F4239B4FB340A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on awards and bonuses paid to senior executive employees of Department of Veterans
 Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 705 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/703">38 U.S.C. 703</external-xref> note) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>, of which, during fiscal years 2016 through 2018, not more than an aggregate amount of $2,000,000 in each such fiscal year may be paid to employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs who are members of the Senior Executive Service.</quote>.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>July 16, 2015</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


