<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6FA3F0E2379841499F2CCDC4E009B67F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1465 IH: Medical Evaluation Parity for Servicemembers Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1465</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150319">March 19, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide an individual with a mental health screening before the individual enlists in the Armed Forces or is commissioned as an officer in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HFBF7576C49FE48188A8A54BCA361A5C2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H20E8CE1B85014354B438FEA127F4543A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Evaluation Parity for Servicemembers Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4491C88885194E1E9F465B3CB9D8F4F2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preliminary mental health screenings for individuals becoming members of the Armed Forces<editorial></editorial></header> <subsection id="H3845CAA3650A4756BD573DE5C78BFF7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/31">Chapter 31</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE22FDBCDEB46413FAF83843FD544165F" style="USC">
<section id="HC41DD44202C4470C888B3479A07324F1"><enum>520d.</enum><header>Preliminary mental health screenings<editorial></editorial></header>
<subsection id="H3CFA45B3477B4723A31E317273C187FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of mental health screening</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before any individual enlists in an armed force or is commissioned as an officer in an armed force, the Secretary concerned shall provide the individual with a mental health screening.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H20538CC5BB564A54B6358705C9558D33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of screening</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5EF7BC161CAD4516ABDCC55FABC5CA6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall use the results of a mental screening conducted under subsection (a) as a baseline for any subsequent mental health examinations of the individual, including such examinations provided under sections 1074f and 1074m of this title.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE71648F269FD4C67AFB512A579421DDC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not consider the results of a mental health screening conducted under subsection (a) in determining the promotion of a member of the armed forces.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF9A941A722244D5B8A061A8D59C33B4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of privacy laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to applicable laws and regulations relating to the privacy of information, the Secretary shall treat a mental health screening conducted under subsection (a) in the same manner as the medical records of a member of the armed forces.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H5856F4CA20CF44959DCC310770359D15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding after the item relating to section 520c the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B7625ABF224413393988D67F45E8E3C" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">520d. Preliminary mental health screenings.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF5C6B650824F4173B8021F93F66DF650"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="HC728B94C416D4A57ADE5B52DBE0C4BC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header> <subparagraph id="H281F467607FD463691BEC307A7660F7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the National Institute of Mental Health of the National Institutes of Health shall submit to Congress and the Secretary of Defense a report on preliminary mental health screenings of members of the Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB488E34B9EC947EAA85BAFCBF635541D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>The report under subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="H975665A1E8ED41CA908C6F1C38CABCFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations with respect to establishing a preliminary mental health screening of members of the Armed Forces to bring mental health screenings to parity with physical screenings of members.</text></clause>
<clause id="HCEF18955C1D54866AA1F35C05082BC6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations with respect to the composition of the mental health screening, evidenced-based best practices, and how to track changes in mental health screenings relating to traumatic brain injuries, post-traumatic stress disorder, and other conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H230686FEB8E844C4B3E970FCFB54F34A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Institute of Mental Health shall carry out subparagraph (A) in coordination with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the surgeons general of the military departments, and other relevant experts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0CD4E27C3A364893BF6B1DD0C647F4D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports on efficacy of screenings</header>
<subparagraph id="H63132CE198D2487DB36634103B1E28F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Secretary of Defense</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which the Secretary of Defense begins providing preliminary mental health screenings under section 520d(a) of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the efficacy of such preliminary mental health screenings.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64CDCDCACA5C42A8BE951EFB9DBCEF43"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Comptroller General</header><text>Not later than one year after the submittal of the report under subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the efficacy of the preliminary mental health screenings described in such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H24C0C33F534541E099762D9852359E67"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>The reports required by subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="H7DB2865AD955444B9589DBD549DA9E54"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An evaluation of the evidence-based best practices used by the Secretary in composing and conducting preliminary mental health screenings of members of the Armed Forces under such section 520d(a).</text></clause>
<clause id="H7107CB4792464B168F9E99F15A511B81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An evaluation of the evidence-based best practices used by the Secretary in tracking changes in mental health screenings relating to traumatic brain injuries, post-traumatic stress disorder, and other conditions among members of the Armed Forces.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB40B170B461D41AAB284C50517E525DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation of preliminary mental health screening</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may not provide a preliminary mental health screening under section 520d(a) of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), until the Secretary receives and evaluates the initial report required by subsection (c)(1).</text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE1E8DCFAAA640D3B12EE7990F33F2BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on efficacy of physical examinations for certain members of the Armed Forces upon separation from active duty</header>
<subsection id="H2410C15D56864538993CF121EFC04091"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the efficacy of the mental health components of the physical examinations provided under paragraph (5) of section 1145(a) of title 10, United States Code, to members of the Armed Forces who are separated from active duty as described in paragraph (2) of such section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB7C6A074BA194D74853837AB9B509F95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation of effectiveness</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include an evaluation of the effectiveness of the physical examinations described in such subsection in—</text>
<paragraph id="HF6CBD1C935EE4EAAA9CE905AEA9C946B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying members of the Armed Forces with traumatic brain injury, post-traumatic stress disorder, and other mental health conditions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DAACFF859CD46748F3B3A9588AE8F9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring that health care is provided for such members.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


