<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6DFD3C5FFF08433EB619ED0D3500BD3D" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 720 EH: Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 720</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To improve intergovernmental planning for and communication during security incidents at domestic airports, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB218DD4DDF1F493CA82738345A6F3C1F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5E5C34DADD4848ED8C0DE51CE50ADA19" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HFEA4BF3428434B57A2815C7022E1E752"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0A40E66C87DA4E368C24A14A2822C76E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security) of the Department of Homeland Security.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB84319964DBA4203A169011EA5414D23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <term>Administration</term> means the Transportation Security Administration.</text> </paragraph></section>
<section id="HB79D91A1A65A478BAE8DF4DD54DD6307"><enum>3.</enum><header>Security incident response at airports</header> 
<subsection id="H66479672DBE045F985274BEA4DCFCE43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, conduct outreach to all airports in the United States at which the Administration performs, or oversees the implementation and performance of, security measures, and provide technical assistance as necessary, to verify such airports have in place individualized working plans for responding to security incidents inside the perimeter of the airport, including active shooters, acts of terrorism, and incidents that target passenger-screening checkpoints.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H45F92086E9754F329A6E1018EE614C6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Types of plans</header><text>Such plans may include, but may not be limited to, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8592837FF7684161B0311F67F3D76136"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A strategy for evacuating and providing care to persons inside the perimeter of the airport, with consideration given to the needs of persons with disabilities.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA096F79780C84BA59E2FF53D081A28E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for establishing a unified command, including identification of staging areas for non-airport-specific law enforcement and fire response.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC186BD4F402E4C13A29408B336C570D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A schedule for regular testing of communications equipment used to receive emergency calls.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA52ED56303D41029D3CA8743327BE6B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An evaluation of how emergency calls placed by persons inside the perimeter of the airport will reach airport police in an expeditious manner.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA0F135BD7D774D4BA9A0A1B4E05F940D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A practiced method and plan to communicate with travelers and all other persons inside the perimeter of the airport.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD3AEC7D3D9E42EEAC4CBAD7095BC36D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To the extent practicable, a projected maximum timeframe for law enforcement response.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H799FF9E80F0E4234A15B1A80F17B4A33"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A schedule of joint exercises and training to be conducted by the airport, the Administration, other stakeholders such as airport and airline tenants, and any relevant law enforcement, airport police, fire, and medical personnel.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8784C687207E4322A0064268EB5306CE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A schedule for producing after-action joint exercise reports to identify and determine how to improve security incident response capabilities.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9A083BD78E2C4E73B7ACF7F32421C95C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the findings from its outreach to airports under subsection (a), including an analysis of the level of preparedness such airports have to respond to security incidents, including active shooters, acts of terrorism, and incidents that target passenger-screening checkpoints.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H694327BF0DD944898776383E00B44960"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disseminating information on best practices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9B2D459953E14344BF8ED348F4F44C3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify best practices that exist across airports for security incident planning, management, and training; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3F272D3178D42F0A1048C2D898A7C5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a mechanism through which to share such best practices with other airport operators nationwide.</text> </paragraph></section>
<section id="H558A61053059415CB87A7C3E9BB60EFB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Assistant Secretary shall certify in writing to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate that all screening personnel have participated in practical training exercises for active shooter scenarios.</text> </section> <section id="HE3C831CAF87D420C85943E023D69DF88"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reimbursable agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate an analysis of how the Administration can use cost savings achieved through efficiencies to increase over the next 5 fiscal years the funding available for checkpoint screening law enforcement support reimbursable agreements.</text> </section>
<section id="HAC2F4BE755C44E1B83139244A8805FBB"><enum>7.</enum><header>No additional authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act, and this Act shall be carried out using amounts otherwise available for such purpose.</text> </section> <section id="H67674EB4C9444BA7B36BD2678755196F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Interoperability review</header> <subsection id="H51A6981AE7EA48DF81527E6126FA7ED0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary of the Office of Cybersecurity and Communications, conduct a review of the interoperable communications capabilities of the law enforcement, fire, and medical personnel responsible for responding to a security incident, including active shooter events, acts of terrorism, and incidents that target passenger-screening checkpoints, at all airports in the United States at which the Administration performs, or oversees the implementation and performance of, security measures.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H0CC02EE4D73447FDA61077BC05F8E864"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the completion of the review, the Assistant Secretary shall report the findings of the review to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20150210" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives February 10, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

