<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEBAA20B8E69141669D9326E00B446E53" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 439 IH: Illegal Entry Accountability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 439</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150121">January 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001102">Mr. Clawson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To suspend foreign assistance to certain countries related to unlawful migration.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H81E747C369B441F3A99BF7EE7B46239A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9480123F68BF4A869A87049CF0D545A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Illegal Entry Accountability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFF08FB1C895F434B96F1F6E74A539A0F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HEB1905400EA44180A88181E1C30B6448"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The border between the United States and Mexico is not secure on either side, thereby allowing hundreds of thousands of individuals annually to enter the United States illegally.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B7E1C6AD1FA4223838178D6C764B3A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The majority of the individuals illegally crossing the United States-Mexico border are from Mexico, Honduras, Guatemala, and El Salvador.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF33040D95D8C4A02AE3A530ADFD6A921"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Today, tens of thousands of unaccompanied alien children are crossing the United States-Mexico border sparking a humanitarian crisis and endangering thousands of children.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9487EDB8CA9540B398E98D4A6E62F91F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security is spending millions of Americans’ tax dollars to process and provide housing and healthcare services to unaccompanied alien children.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7B34D5A67CC444418B6CA73A4927D5BA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The countries previously listed have failed to secure their borders and have failed to adopt and enforce policies that discourage illegal immigration into the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3A7F010689274256B0B6498773AF65DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Suspension of foreign assistance</header> <subsection id="HE239F8E7410D482BBA7BEFC93D01BAA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall immediately suspend all United States foreign assistance to the countries of Mexico, Honduras, Guatemala, and El Salvador. Such assistance may be reinstated only if Congress determines that Mexico, Honduras, Guatemala, and El Salvador have taken sufficient action to mitigate unlawful United States-Mexico border crossings by their respective citizens.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD4EEA17E8CEC4FDA954D39EA71819616"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary of State shall annually submit to Congress a report documenting the measures taken by Mexico, Honduras, Guatemala and El Salvador to mitigate unlawful entry into the United States by its citizens.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEC4EED7058CC408FB76AEC85C98AACB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Foreign assistance distributed under the International Narcotic Control Law Enforcement program shall not be considered under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


