<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9A0D05BF36104B6E8799154FCA172F2E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2081 IH: To extend the deadline for commencement of construction of a hydroelectric project involving the Gibson Dam.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2081</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To extend the deadline for commencement of construction of a hydroelectric project involving the Gibson Dam.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H00F20FBC64184B66AE1CCBC5C491BEA7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC9AC3DAC9A944D7AB4D5DD2DDA8E02CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Extension of time for Federal Energy Regulatory Commission project involving Gibson Dam</header>
<subsection id="H18DFE7C7948140718F410444EF9C1E67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) that would otherwise apply to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission project numbered 12478–003, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (referred to in this section as the <quote>Commission</quote>) may, at the request of the licensee for the project, and after reasonable notice and in accordance with the procedures of the Commission under that section, extend the time period during which the licensee is required to commence construction of the project for a 6-year period that begins on the date described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1127BA2D8EAF47109F3CC787A49DCBBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Date described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date described in this subsection is the date of the expiration of the extension of the period required for commencement of construction for the project described in subsection (a) that was issued by the Commission prior to the date of enactment of this Act under section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


