<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD6F7DC50F0B24A058F2C47120E662C09" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2225 IH: PRIMED Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2225</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150501">May 1, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a temporary dividends received deduction for repatriated foreign earnings, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H390481C5BE834FD694B93540A16112B0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1968914FD9C2461F9294C60502852CED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prioritizing Reinvestment in Infrastructure and Military while Eliminating Debt Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>PRIMED Act</quote> . </text></section> <section id="H5F0042420C424CE891B97EA8EBF3D27B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dividends received deduction for repatriated foreign earnings</header> <subsection id="H8F4D2F7E0FAC4CBF8A52E76BFCB3D55F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Period for repatriation</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/965">section 965(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Only cash dividends received during the period beginning after the date of the enactment of the Prioritizing Reinvestment in Infrastructure and Military while Eliminating Debt Act of 2015, and ending on December 31, 2016, shall be taken into account under subsection (a).</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA8414CBFAF0A4BC58A882A73EA620580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (f) of section 965 of such Code is amended to read as follows: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09C3E1087AF74347AE0380F28606CA16"> <subsection id="H8F3E1E731A604804B2E4F56D3762C8A6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The taxpayer may elect to apply this section to any taxable year that includes the period described in subsection (a)(1). Such election may be made only for one taxable year that includes such period and only if made on or before the due date (including extensions) for filing the return of tax for such taxable year.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD3567E26E404F3DB8903A030FDCA111"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H69E8205A431B40718818D457BEADC6E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Threshold period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 965 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>June 30, 2003</quote> each place it occurs and inserting <quote>June 30, 2014</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H357C2FD1B7EB4E23884A3FC45F0B03F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indebtedness determination date</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 965(b)(3) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>October 3, 2004</quote> and inserting <quote>May 1, 2015</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A7503A8D5CC4D6881A4F08938C35F06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HEB70F3F8E8694975AEAF5DE1B923D07C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Debt reduction</header> <subsection id="H5B32F101F1C54FF09BBB73E2BDCAB773"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxes which—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE13C1A2047DE41AE8604953C53B7C41F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are received in the Treasury during a fiscal year for which there is not Federal budget deficit, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E2394DC42B746548FA38FDC1F977300"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are attributable to eligible 965 dividends received by corporations which are United States shareholders,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">an amount equal to <fraction>1/3</fraction> of such taxes, reduced by <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the amount of the foreign tax credit allowed under section 901 which is attributable to the non-deductible portion of such eligible 965 dividends, shall be used to reduce the Federal debt (in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury considers appropriate).</continuation-text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7585B3F47EB843DEA9F77B3FFAD4958A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the terms <quote>eligible 965 dividend</quote> and <quote>non-deductible portion</quote> shall have the respective meanings given such terms in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(b)(7)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1F4680989F79443F9461AE25E5C6EB97"><enum>4.</enum><header>Highway Trust Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">Section 9503(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF370A801FCB8420FBBD1AB1FDE26AA85"> 
<paragraph id="H0C549C4F038E4C4BB3DC4B9078F19FF8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Other transfers to Highway Trust Fund</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8A903BE16D0A41C5BE884EF1FAA84A6B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to the Highway Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the excess of—</text> <clause id="HA424BF79A8084B44A627281F50DC2B64"><enum>(i)</enum><text><fraction>1/3</fraction> of the taxes received in the Treasury which are attributable to eligible 965 dividends received by corporations which are United States shareholders, over</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD8C811EA056E45EB9A04CDFE6388BC51"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><fraction>1/3</fraction> of the amount of the foreign tax credit allowed under section 901 which is attributable to the non-deductible portion of such eligible 965 dividends.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D04B9E57DAF47EF8ED32197BE169977" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<clause id="H7C6BC8CB487C46BABA3410204762D044"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Eligible 965 dividend</header><text>The term <term>eligible 965 dividend</term> means any amount received from a controlled foreign corporation for which a deduction is allowed under section 965, as determined based on estimates made by the Secretary.</text></clause> <clause id="HC4F0266932C447FDBD561620BE15BEA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Non-deductible portion</header><text>The term <term>non-deductible portion</term> means the excess of the amount of any eligible 965 dividend over the deductible portion (as defined in section 965(d)(3)) of such amount.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HAE931AA438164F69AA9DF7C60454D76E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Adjustment to defense discretionary spending limitations</header> 
<subsection id="HB0D1F286939347B38B0F223CF5B12C2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and on February 1 of each of calendar years 2016 through 2020, the revised security category in section 251(c) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 for fiscal year 2016 and the fiscal year beginning on September 1st of such applicable calendar year, respectively, shall be adjusted by the amount described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9123F365D27746349C2D42978A63B503"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment amount</header><text>The adjustment provided in subsection (a) is equal to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8065AACC2BBC4BDE93562E6DDAE5E3F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text><fraction>1/3</fraction> of the taxes received in the Treasury during the most recently ended calendar year which are attributable to eligible 965 dividends received by corporations which are United States shareholders, over</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04ACF8A7C4CC4DF8A3483D59A2C63AD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><fraction>1/3</fraction> of the amount of the foreign tax credit allowed during the most recently ended calendar year under section 901 which is attributable to the non-deductible portion of such eligible 965 dividends.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4879593056AB4FF4869E7B70C20FBDB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b), the terms <quote>eligible 965 dividend</quote> and <quote>non-deductible portion</quote> shall have the respective meanings given such terms in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(b)(7)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

