<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA855710690BE4440AE1AFE2203329C78" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2210 IH: Coach-Only Airfare for Capitol Hill Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2210</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150501">May 1, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit the use of funds provided for the official travel expenses of Members of Congress and other officers and employees of the legislative branch for airline accommodations which are not coach-class accommodations, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD8609F34A4BA4AEB8EBAF87F94FA46DD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA36945BA6D9F4BEE8D71CAEBF257CBC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coach-Only Airfare for Capitol Hill Act of 2015</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HE97A45E576D94333AAE735BA694C70A1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of funds for official travel expenses of Members of Congress and legislative branch employees for airline accommodations other than coach-class</header> <subsection id="H8E5A75AC63FE41EB84378B60652210A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), no funds appropriated or otherwise made available for the official travel expenses of a Member of Congress or other officer or employee of any office in the legislative branch may be used for airline accommodations which are not coach-class accommodations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD00D332D5B844BB2B032FF65B6FF8B76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Funds described in subsection (a) may be used for airline accommodations which are not coach-class accommodations for an individual described in subsection (a) if the use of the funds for such accommodations would be permitted under sections 301–10.121 through 301–10.125 of title 41 of the Code of Federal Regulations if the individual were an employee of an agency which is subject to chapter 301 of such title.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1485FB4EA38246639D22AF6BCAB36A38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to affect any officer or employee of an office of the legislative branch which, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, is subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 41 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEB532B0A70D4467291FEA807FA044B5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<paragraph id="H096D36C6CB9B4ABEB0143CB0C96D52A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coach-class accommodations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>coach-class accommodations</term> means the basic class of accommodation by airlines that is normally the lowest fare offered regardless of airline terminology used, and (as referred to by airlines) may include tourist class or economy class, as well as single class when the airline offers only one class of accommodations to all travelers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD99DA00EF9F4FDC80F217B5D41388AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBD64E674B33F4103B25D18A24282D2A8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2016 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

