<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H06E24AFA1721436F944510683BF4A7F8" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1742 IH: Child and Elderly Missing Alert Program Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1742</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150413">April 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize the Attorney General to provide a grant to assist Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies in the rapid recovery of missing individuals.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA43EE5A0901F4699AA63D22230AD5D9A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAA4A3176CF6840FF87A0047EBDBAC594" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Child and Elderly Missing Alert Program Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H785241EE1D2F4BBFA7973362CAEE4FD9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program to assist Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies in the rapid recovery of missing children, the elderly, and disabled individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1701 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3796dd">42 U.S.C. 3796dd</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H15CD31C3405C498E9D6D205CCE1328C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9D3232328C04F3AA42D3A2CFD551F61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (16), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1C6AC612C810444AADF6620308D7783C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (17), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8F91072CF3E4534A6554B7AAE8EAC67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CFC1DB949164CF099CB49DFFAF1EAA7" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H9EE3881848A04721B85DA3BBBAC013C6"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to permit eligible nonprofit organizations to assist Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies in the rapid recovery of missing children, elderly individuals, and disabled individuals through the use of a rapid telephone and cellular alert call system, in accordance with subsection (l).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9455D4D481244F1809C1BDBB86A17A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C78F0D5D9394BDB9DB1E20063F0A104" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H2D64B9AD879243A09F9625CEEC8FB6B7"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Child and Elderly Missing Alerts</header>
<paragraph id="H80BF761C0DD54BAC8B8DDEE0D8FB210E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to award grants to eligible nonprofit organizations to assist Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies in the rapid recovery of missing children, elderly individuals, and disabled individuals through the use of a rapid telephone and cellular alert call system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H125AA13A83B64837BF6BC351FAEB04E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The grants awarded under this subsection shall be used to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HACA1FAB41F2846A6A271AE222DC8EE4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide services to Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies, in response to a request from such agencies, to promote the rapid recovery of a missing child, an elderly individual, or a disabled individual by utilizing rapid telephone and cellular alert calls;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A8A013841F647D68161D72A444931FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain and expand technologies and techniques to ensure the highest level of performance of such services;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0F44CBF722274948863F60D631E1EA95"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide both centralized and on-site training and distribute information to Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agency officials about missing children, elderly individuals, and disabled individuals and use of a rapid telephone and cellular alert call system;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA08A56293114CD4B88FF49417124D93"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide services to Federal, State, tribal, and local Child Abduction Response Teams;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD14ABEFB36D4495DB4131DD009264EEC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assist Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies to combat human trafficking through the use of rapid telephone and cellular alert calls;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFCFEEB96F46C4D90AFF05EE16FFFA93C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>share appropriate information on cases with the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, the AMBER Alert, Silver Alert, and Blue Alert programs, and appropriate Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC5387D47858A4ED29146995A8F1DB817"><enum>(G)</enum><text>assist appropriate organizations, including Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies, with education and prevention programs related to missing children, elderly individuals, and disabled individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EED3659B0E64907BA0C12010EBBBDD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be an eligible nonprofit organization for purposes of a grant under this subsection, a nonprofit organization shall have experience providing rapid telephone and cellular alert calls on behalf of Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies to find missing children and elderly adults.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB822F62BBBAD44AA8D581EE6542452BC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grant period and renewal</header><text>The Attorney General shall determine an appropriate grant period for grants awarded under this subsection. Such grants may be renewed at the discretion of the Attorney General.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8617CB12DE0444C6BD89064289888CCA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall require each grantee under this subsection to annually submit the results of the monitoring and evaluations required under subsections (a) and (b) of section 1705, and shall publish an annual report regarding such results and the effectiveness of the activities carried out under each such grant.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD355A2A01E1A426485D18568391528BB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Inapplicable provisions</header><text>The following provisions of this part shall not apply to grants awarded under this subsection:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD14163FA3200452E9A6CFEEBB968EF54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subsection (j) of this section (relating to grants to Indian tribes).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE20CC310CE0146A18ED0E9272C27ABFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1703 (relating to renewal of grants).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE00480914854A65B748C22B4519B0DA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text>
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30D7BF68C2BA4CCEB069534C18FDB9BC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual under 21 years of age.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H691B41EDA7E94DD49B08ABC24206B3C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disabled individual</header><text>The term <term>disabled individual</term> means—</text>
<clause id="HB0DAB2E095DE41A48DA184960D0E20FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual with 1 or more disabilities (as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)); or</text></clause> <clause id="H6E17A714867745828AC62A9658BF397D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who has been diagnosed by a physician or other qualified medical professional with Alzheimer’s disease or a related dementia.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H99D62425D13A48DF9F835010714D9E2E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Elderly individual</header><text>The term <term>elderly individual</term> means an individual who is 60 years of age or older.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0CAE43D8B3F45E6A16BCC6D3C01C0D3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Missing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>missing</term>, with respect to a child, an elderly individual, or a disabled individual, means such a child or individual who has been reported to law enforcement as missing and whose whereabouts are unknown to Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H48F383871512485BA291FCEAF1FF5FB2"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rapid telephone and cellular alert call system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rapid telephone and cellular alert call system</term> means an automated system with the ability to place at least 1,000 telephone and cellular calls in 60 seconds to a specific geographic area determined by law enforcement—</text> <clause id="H331E27471DFA4E018693D3552835E221"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based on the last known whereabouts of a missing individual; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HEE1184A3F2F04B2EAFB0EF91507EAF58"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based on other evidence and determined by such law enforcement agency to be necessary to the search for the missing individual.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

