<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H318879AC45B34FE4AE3C90F55AB9F6D9" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 125 IH: FHA In-Person Servicing Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 125</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize a pilot program to improve asset recovery levels, asset management, and homeownership
			 retention with respect to delinquent single-family mortgages insured under
			 the FHA mortgage insurance programs by providing for in-person contact
			 outreach activities with mortgagors under such mortgages, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H36843C46661A4AEA9436335C54A2E6E9" style="OLC">
		<section id="H59FE9D9A6AE74EFEAD372BDB3C8EFC28" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FHA In-Person Servicing Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HAFC506745B16476194F0FA90D18FC7AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program</header>
			<subsection id="H75B4E7C1B8E94A0DBA17560048FAE524"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall carry out a pilot program under this section
			 to use the authority under section 204(a)(2) of the National Housing Act
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1710">12 U.S.C. 1710(a)(2)</external-xref>) to make payments to a qualified entity or entities
			 to compensate for their costs of making in-person contact with mortgagors
			 whose payments under covered mortgages are more than 60 days past due, for
			 the purpose of—</text>
				<paragraph id="H60D1215D44F54F71A447950CA30EC21F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying mortgagors eligible for loan modifications or refinances and providing packages to the
			 mortgagee for such purposes;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H57696E95A68D498D93CEFCCA5B432D84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying mortgagers not eligible for a loan modification or refinance but willing to engage in
			 pre-foreclosure sales or deeds in lieu of foreclosure, and providing
			 information to the mortgagee in order to facilitate such actions;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H1E71E300EB4F41BBA111D61814CE355C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying whether a home’s current occupant is the mortgagor or a renter, and if not occupied,
			 taking steps to locate and make contact with the mortgagor;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H83D692DCC9754DB7926A728E42ED2469"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing information to the Secretary and the mortgagee regarding the condition of the home, in
			 order to facilitate any actions needed to prevent the deterioration and
			 loss of value of the home and assist the Department more generally in its
			 asset management responsibilities; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H965FF8F3118345308B52637EB6968C4E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing all relevant information on mortgagors and homes to the mortgagee on the loan and the
			 Secretary in a format, approved by the Secretary, which helps improve
			 asset management and maximize asset recovery of these delinquent loans.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EDF8D40F75546D7B11BA491CC981F89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified entities</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified entity</quote> means a single entity or a consortia or partnership of entities that—</text>
				<paragraph id="HFE4F94E0230C473DB990027BDB9EE77B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have experience in carrying out the activities identified in subsection (a);</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H24F6CB8A03EB4C6388D73D61093721AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are not affiliated with the mortgagor under any of the covered mortgages for which it is authorized
			 to carry out actions under the pilot program under this section; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD2A339B615194963933F997E5DEB9303"><enum>(3)</enum><text>comply with all relevant State and Federal laws.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0673E8BAD79345CA8E9EF7DAFFB703D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of a qualified entity or entities</header>
				<paragraph id="HAD2FA995E97045CDB3B2EF80E24C8C9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The Secretary shall have the discretion to select qualified entities to participate in the pilot
			 program under this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HF90DFEDA1A3B447F86D10E70796CA2AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>Such selection shall be based on the qualifications and experience of the entity or entities to
			 carry out the specific activities identified in subsection (a), including
			 the level of infrastructure capability in reporting detailed information
			 on the mortgage loan, underlying property, and the mortgagor.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HC400F76292D0482E8921A48513C9BADF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participating loans</header><text>The Secretary shall make available not less than 50,000 and not more than 100,000 loans that meet
			 the delinquency criteria of subsection (a) for this pilot program.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBC9AE8D621394109A55F101789DD0CC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall select the qualified entity and entities and make available loans under the
			 pilot for their performance within 90 days of the enactment of the Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7A2E4C379B54B53BE9C8FFCC3C15F89"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payments</header><text>Payments to the entity or entities selected to carry out the pilot program under this section may
			 be based on—</text>
				<paragraph id="H6BC56438004449558068606A8473AAA3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a flat amount per covered mortgage;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H39FCBF97133D4A2D8837CC84B12859B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a performance success basis based on—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H004BC54E710F4932B5C86BD83800ED1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>completed packages; or</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD96E7431108C472E9E08275F2D21D8DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>completed loan modifications, pre-foreclosure sales, and deeds in lieu of foreclosure; or</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0294AB3F41BD413D9C55CC8940118CCC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a combination of the methods under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD04B2D063E7549A498B8E707073D8464"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Entities selected to participate in the pilot program under this section may not charge any fees or
			 require any payments, directly or indirectly, from the mortgagor or the
			 mortgagee of a covered mortgage in connection any activities under the
			 program.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HED694CA0636640D29AD35CF21226512F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>HUD review and reporting</header><text>The Secretary shall publish periodic updates on the status of the pilot program under this section,
			 commencing not later than 30 days after the completion of actions under
			 subsection (c)(1) and (c)(3), and thereafter not less often than every 90
			 days
			 until termination of the pilot program under subsection (h). Not later
			 than 60 days after termination of the pilot program, the Secretary shall
			 submit to the Congress and make publicly available a final report on the
			 pilot program, including information and analysis of performance
			 characteristics, which may include comparisons of estimated asset recovery
			 levels under the pilot program compared to comparable loans not included
			 in the pilot and loans that have gone through loan sales.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HFA79194F14944EADB52ECC37D7FEF454"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text>
				<paragraph id="HCC0B6C0EC8704EB28D6865106C973842"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered mortgage</header><text>The term <quote>covered mortgage</quote> means a mortgage on a 1- to 4-family residence insured under subsection (b) or (k) of section 203,
			 section 234(c), or 251 of the National Housing Act (12 U.S.C. 1709 (b) or
			 (k), 1715y(c), 1715z–16).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0B6B254128524FB9AFF6911C91C17069"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F0B511C03B44D3BA094937640B2ADE1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not make any payments under the pilot program under this section to any qualified
			 entity for any in-person contact with a mortgagor that occurs after the
			 expiration of the 24-month period beginning upon the completion of the
			 actions under subsection (c)(1) and (c)(3).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


