<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3AC980BB0E784F16B9E4BC1AE9B6885D" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3270 IH: To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to exempt Indian tribes from compensatory mitigation requirements in connection with certain discharges of dredged or fill material, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3270</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to exempt Indian tribes from compensatory mitigation requirements in connection with certain discharges of dredged or fill material, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9CD1F0DEBD0C447F951E775AC6BB15DD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE83F7D1BCA9841E487B66091238D1263" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exemption from compensatory mitigation requirements</header> 
<subsection id="H1266CDC7D9F9476C86205F50654B4DDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6DD94FA8CB11447FBED9A3FC1003D6CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H14DE4620A1514DD7B8A5F3A40C892E88"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Indian tribes</header> <paragraph id="H161939DA21BC465CB7F1F5B2D4C474C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exemption from compensatory mitigation requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an Indian tribe that applies for a permit for a permitted activity to be conducted on Indian land shall not be required to provide any form of compensatory mitigation as a condition of the permit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5749F3267C34EDE8AD10924E9580766"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation of Indian tribe permit application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In evaluating a permit application submitted by an Indian tribe to carry a permitted activity to be conducted on Indian land, the Secretary may not take into account the nonavailability of compensatory mitigation pursuant to the exemption provided by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33FAF4439C5E46348A41080FC21CE6A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Situations in which Indian tribe ceases to maintain permitted activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an Indian tribe described in paragraph (1) ceases to maintain the permitted activity on Indian land, or seeks to abandon such an activity without a good faith transfer, the Indian tribe shall obtain a permit modification from the Secretary, which may require restoration and rehabilitation of the area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49C7E4CCBE3B4F0FACE8AF2008F564BB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on statutory construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exemption from compensatory mitigation requirements provided by paragraph (1) may not be construed to affect the applicability of any other requirement under this Act to an Indian tribe or Indian land, including requirements to avoid and minimize adverse impacts to wetlands, streams, and other aquatic resources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB03D7264C944456BBEE498C3C9B27E40"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC8D9EB8DEBBA47CBB648C1F1CC2C6679"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Indian land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Indian land</quote> means land owned by, operated by, or otherwise belonging to an Indian tribe.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H357D839DB2B449178032DD2DE5D90D73"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Indian tribe</quote> means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEEA0FA33699C4C35B2D9D121B76703FC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Permitted activity</header><text>The term <quote>permitted activity</quote> means a discharge of dredged or fill material for which a permit is issued under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H171192F808F14A30A74F62D64164B389"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to permits issued under section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

