<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H714B0B0836D74DD09631C2DA0AF11358" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1961 IH: Climate Change Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1961</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to establish a Climate Change Education Program.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HDC4796580CE44237A6FF463070742B48" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H927551FC98304638A424BF44DEDED857" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Change Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4BA7AC8A6A0449E5B8F934C509D4E7BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H730DDF234D5E420F8EFBF1F2F65290DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the evidence for human-induced climate change is overwhelming and undeniable;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19293AFA262D450E8F1F5484767CB8F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States is the second highest emitter of carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases in the world;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D1CE38D15D94FACAD65B84FB4B21125"><enum>(3)</enum><text>atmospheric carbon can be significantly reduced through conservation, by shifting to renewable energy sources such as solar, wind, tidal, and geothermal, and by increasing the efficiency of buildings, including domiciles, and transportation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E7EF20D27694BC38C750EB05A696C0C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing clear information about climate change, in a variety of forms, can remove the fear and the sense of helplessness, and encourage individuals and communities to take action;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37A22AB526874CDDB7608EA736486CFB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>implementation of measures that promote energy efficiency, conservation, and renewable energy will greatly reduce human impact on the environment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D1A9722AADD4E939C86B12125472291"><enum>(6)</enum><text>informing people of new technologies and programs as they become available will ensure maximum understanding and maximum impact of those measures.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC77BB4CA840E459AB4008112C5FFA0E4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>climate change education</quote> means informal and formal interdisciplinary learning at all age levels about climate change and its effects on environmental, energy, social, and economic systems.</text></section> <section id="HE3CFD4394F1649189697D1C890EA0FC7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Climate Change Education Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall establish a Climate Change Education Program to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5B86FCC842D04789BE1E01B80E63F6FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>broaden the understanding of human induced climate change, possible long-term and short-term consequences, and potential solutions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82B8F6CCF1554C55BE2E9F6350E1CDED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>apply the latest scientific and technological discoveries to provide formal and informal learning opportunities to people of all ages, including those of diverse cultural and linguistic backgrounds;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD30AF774A34B470E81B40F11E515C9D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>emphasize actionable information to help people understand and to promote implementation of new technologies, programs, and incentives related to energy conservation, renewable energy, and greenhouse gas reduction; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE892E99A27EF4FEAAA1648C8DB4CFD1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform the public of impacts to human health and safety as a result of climate change.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFDC614E86F6E4617BC84D1E7631C8D44"><enum>5.</enum><header>Program elements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Climate Change Education Program shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H8074279F676149D38EF3598574DFBAC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a national information campaign to disseminate information on and promote implementation of the new technologies, programs, and incentives described in section 4(3); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H593DC3CCEFB345908BD723FF31220F5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the grant program described in section 6.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3C88DA1035BF413E898858E9A96DA566"><enum>6.</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall establish a program to make grants—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFC6452301B854497A219928D5E500360"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support national public education, outreach, and communication programs to engage substantial numbers of the public in understanding climate change while developing educated and empowered consumers, investors, and citizens;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBADBAF840D374C1CBBB5CF2D239AE1D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to encourage and support statewide plans and programs for climate change education, including relevant teacher training and professional development, STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) education, and multidisciplinary studies to ensure that students graduate from high school climate literate, with a particular focus on programs that advance widespread State and local educational agency adoption of climate change education, including funding for State education agencies to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC5C775331284454E95813050ACCA3055"><enum>(A)</enum><text>integrate key principles of climate change education into existing K–12 State academic content standards, student academic achievement standards, or State curriculum frameworks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC73357AA38CF4C769A34FAE1B50B70C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create model State climate change curricula; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4C5B1B3D1FA45F3BDEB64EC13F72AA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>create State green school building standards or policies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71D596FAA11F4C3096A806AE9FD2C5C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to improve the quality of and access to higher education in green collar industries and green economy-related fields such as green business, technology, engineering, policy studies, and sustainability science, with a particular focus on programs that address restructuring institutional incentives and reducing institutional barriers to widespread faculty adoption of interdisciplinary teaching of climate change education;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48348483F3A643768ACDC16C2F19BCB0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for institutions of higher education to engage teams of faculty and students to develop applied climate research and deliver to local communities direct services on climate mitigation and adaptation issues impacting such communities, with a priority on distressed communities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3536F4AEF784EEEA3E4A1410050909B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for projects that build capacity for climate adaptation at the State and national level including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4D76A5B7CE6947048D445BEBF8181F0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>career education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63BEE14D91D249BDA9EB51CD1AD56243"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expanding green collar workforce training;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H830FF3995A9E4A58A1DD06C20E8E1E6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>secondary school preparation or work-based experiences in green collar fields; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3275B2B3107E41808BA75DB3BAE8CAE2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>continuing education needed for practicing professionals for green economy-related fields.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H6C6E7ECF3E7545DBACD9CFFCC63C161E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall transmit to Congress a report that evaluates the scientific merits, educational effectiveness, and broader impacts of activities under this Act.</text></section> <section id="HF93B08FB4D314E4489155A1EEDE1AF7E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020 for carrying out this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

