<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H176E0D02B2A444389D07574498674804" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 251 IH: Homes for Heroes Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 251</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150109">January 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To transfer the position of Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs in the Department of Housing and
			 Urban Development to the Office of the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7A3748E231B042BCA8D01271FEF65FD3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD0471F7B9171458488EC00E5A6C0F942" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homes for Heroes Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC534C021824C4F438054C67A4BDE143A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special assistant for Veterans Affairs in the Department of Housing and Urban Development</header> <subsection id="H1FA4C3262AFA422CB76910922C673FA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of position to Office of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3533">42 U.S.C. 3533</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FFDA47FDF374131B0F34BB3EDF312F7" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HE312902D9468451B9148C78D48855D56"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Special assistant for veterans affairs</header>
 <paragraph id="H3518BAE14F3246958E8F8688BC617D3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Position</header><text>There shall be in the Office of the Secretary a Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs, who shall report directly to the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1B26F0303504911B9213A7585BF977A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs shall be appointed based solely on merit and shall be covered under the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7932CD412E0B43F1ADDA813CD3EAB79E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs shall be responsible for—</text> <subparagraph id="H77EF9B5A89F14796A2A3401CD09006B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensuring veterans have fair access to housing and homeless assistance under each program of the Department providing either such assistance;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89E4CF59D82B43D1918853C6E3CAF061"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinating all programs and activities of the Department relating to veterans;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E768262FE8641288F6AC76A3494A9C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>serving as a liaison for the Department with the Department of Veterans Affairs, including establishing and maintaining relationships with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5CE376E024C4EACA5B1BE8E2494CE3C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>serving as a liaison for the Department, and establishing and maintaining relationships with the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness and officials of State, local, regional, and nongovernmental organizations concerned with veterans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H976276FCB05D4FBD8A0A4DF6BBF3AD98"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing information and advice regarding—</text> <clause id="HB40FEC93BAA64E518130A4273AD0CEA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sponsoring housing projects for veterans assisted under programs administered by the Department; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC69E7E45B9324084950E3C5F5FA82172"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assisting veterans in obtaining housing or homeless assistance under programs administered by the Department;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EDF47189D5F4C269BAF4D87A134F564"><enum>(F)</enum><text>coordinating with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in carrying out section 3 of the Homes for Heroes Act of 2015; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F937D0DBC2046478D81ADA17470EF8F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>carrying out such other duties as may be assigned to the Special Assistant by the Secretary or by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2C6B9861CB7347CDA10B1493E39A9FE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of position in Office of Deputy Assistant Secretary for Special Needs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that the initial Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs is appointed pursuant to section 4(h)(2) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act, as added by subsection (a) of this section, the position of Special Assistant for Veterans Programs in the Office of the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Special Needs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall be terminated.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H091DFA0B8EFA4FD797F92BEF83C0BAA3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual supplemental report on veterans homelessness</header>
 <subsection id="HAB836D6D5BAA4E33800CD23EEC3C33CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in coordination with the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness, shall submit annually to the Committees of the Congress specified in subsection (b), together with the annual reports required by such Secretaries under section 203(c)(1) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11313">42 U.S.C. 11313(c)(1)</external-xref>), a supplemental report that includes the following information with respect to the preceding year:</text>
 <paragraph id="H40E860BAB271471D81D3E98288BDC77C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The same information, for such preceding year, that was included with respect to 2010 in the report by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs entitled <quote>Veterans Homelessness: A Supplemental Report to the 2010 Annual Homeless Assessment Report to Congress</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H74EF8D8CC637439480B0BE43A0275605"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information regarding the activities of the Department of Housing and Urban Development relating to veterans during such preceding year, as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H006A214092B643DEBA622D7BD4FD83E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of veterans provided assistance under the housing choice voucher program for Veterans Affairs supported housing (VASH) under section 8(o)(19) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(19)</external-xref>), the socioeconomic characteristics of such homeless veterans, and the number, types, and locations of entities contracted under such section to administer the vouchers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04EC0860ED4A4D19B81CEF6FBA31675C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A summary description of the special considerations made for veterans under public housing agency plans submitted pursuant to section 5A of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437c-1">42 U.S.C. 1437c–1</external-xref>) and under comprehensive housing affordability strategies submitted pursuant to section 105 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12705">42 U.S.C. 12705</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5DDFCBE973E4D1BAED27C8B90A95484"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the activities of the Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CEA13F3C74244D49C3211857AC251A3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the efforts of the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the other members of the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness to coordinate the delivery of housing and services to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF36A682823D44D0B45DA498B5519B07"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The cost to the Department of Housing and Urban Development of administering the programs and activities relating to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA2AC30D1BB04C558C714FEC633BF6FE"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other information that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs consider relevant in assessing the programs and activities of the Department of Housing and Urban Development relating to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C76829403744A7BA0AAB1B7FBC5CB64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Committees</header><text>The Committees of the Congress specified in this subsection are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HB5B9AE22FD134E00B774D6F4978536D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B412448ABC34955BD13DFDA0326A810"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BD2292980AD4294A8AB088DE8D421A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0F11497A0DA488080AD4D5F8C44040D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B7D7A3C60A2457AB6A6D81772CFF5D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61ABC9C2587E4A159EEFF99D0683F108"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

