<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2BFABEFEF7E44FB5BAB1334BF630B60E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1526 IH: Medicare Audit Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1526</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150323">March 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modify policies relating to payment under the
			 Medicare program for durable medical equipment, orthotics and prosthetics,
			 and prosthetic devices, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4515265671184343B45A7ABCAB4F779B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBD4C6E83163441FD93F92CF6A126EEF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Audit Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H487424E7533B41B5944BA97613BFA09A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicare payment for durable medical equipment, orthotics and prosthetics, and prosthetic devices</header> <subsection id="HB93260FB62214E39B5B5A38C5FDF24CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of prosthetist and orthotist notes for determinations of medical necessity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1834(h)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(h)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H282FD53C1364438AB0D502CC1D571F90" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HA4950924835D45AD9DFEB196B700DE8B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Use of prosthetist and orthotist notes for determinations of medical necessity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining under section 1862(a)(1) whether an orthotic or prosthetic or prosthetic device furnished to an individual on or after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph is reasonable and necessary, any records or documentation of an orthotist or prosthetist who furnished such orthotic or prosthetic or prosthetic device to such individual shall be considered part of the medical record of the individual.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBFA9CB56256A40D48D0AF2797E11D389"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorizing MAC and RAC review for supplier license or accreditation for durable medical equipment
			 and orthotics and prosthetics</header>
 <paragraph id="H1B4D7230D13A4CBAADB73E92D288C720"><enum>(1)</enum><header>MAC review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1874A(a)(4)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395kk-1">42 U.S.C. 1395kk–1(a)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including determining that payment shall not be made to a supplier of durable medical equipment, or of orthotics and prosthetics, for which a claim for payment is made on or after the date of the enactment of the Medicare Audit Improvement Act of 2015 on account of the application of section 1834(h)(1)(F) (relating to supplier licensing or accreditation by a National Board)</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB61B5F519C2429F8AD6046F630E9E5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>RAC review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1893(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ddd">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4EB299E4CDC4E129F28BE68B29B65EE" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H4675FDDD41D24FD687B9E973966B8ED0"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Review of supplier license or accreditation for durable medical equipment and orthotics and
 prosthetics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), with respect to durable medical equipment and orthotics and prosthetics for which a claim for payment was made by a supplier in 2011 or a subsequent year, a payment that should not have been made to such supplier for such durable medical equipment or such orthotics and prosthetics on account of the application of section 1834(h)(1)(F) (relating to supplier licensing or accreditation by a National Board) shall be considered an overpayment under this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BF131F7B9CE4B66913FFE077BFB66AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exempting services that receive prior authorization from RAC review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1893(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ddd">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(h)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b)(2), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFFFEACE3375A406DBD57675D21F60B45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>subject to paragraph (11),</quote> after <quote>Program,</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F5170FAE4744FF7AA358A6BE49A0947"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E67DBECC4BA40DAB8273319C2B357A1" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HEC2C8F5A06C9401CB4007EDAEED696AD"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Services that receive prior authorization exempted from review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recovery audit contractors may not conduct reviews with respect to payments under this title for durable medical equipment, orthotics or prosthetics, or prosthetic devices for which audits under this subsection have not been initiated before the date of the enactment of this paragraph and to which prior authorization under this title applies.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8498311B9A8D4244B529AA8CC19DEB9A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report on overturned MAC and RAC denials</header><text>Section 1874A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395kk-1">42 U.S.C. 1395kk–1</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66A23CA1D6F44F76A11C6252500FF108" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H8C248490B3DE4235AC2E80FA024A2CED"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual report on overturned MAC and RAC denials</header>
 <paragraph id="H58F9C2B17DC34F4E9679B23E82CE437E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than March 1 of 2016, and of each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes the information described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CDE12A24AA745A3BEDE262B85EC27A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information described in this paragraph, with respect to determinations by medicare administrative contractors that payment cannot be made, and by recovery audit contractors that payment should not have been made, under this title for items and services, is the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5FAF57D435B4453189A6A536894A6353"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of such determinations that, in the prior year, were determined on appeal to have been incorrect.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BF31DAB5B6743FCB114A769155D256C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The HCPCS codes that, in the prior year, accounted for—</text> <clause id="H466A0B003BBB4AAFBCB158830B9F693D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the greatest number of such determinations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD6FAE6F44F084208BC7C7F0085BAE39B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the greatest total amount payment being at issue in such determinations.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD947AE3D132D4E7EBAABA8A43A1AB9A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of such determinations that, in the prior year, were based upon a determination—</text>
 <clause id="H79E152EC38594AA6A05275F19E61DF6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the items and services were furnished to an individual as an inpatient rather than as an outpatient;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H208618722146431AA9563D23E9059D26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regarding the application of the medical review activities described in the notice entitled <quote>Selecting Hospital Claims for Patient Status Reviews: Admissions On or After October 1, 2013</quote>, posted on the Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (commonly known as the <quote>two-midnights rule</quote>);</text> </clause><clause id="H006A17C1433143EB9AC65EEDB63221DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that applied to a provider of outpatient services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC293CBFE49334DC1ACFF16EFADFADD3D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regarding a claim for payment for orthotics or prosthetics or prosthetic devices.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H7650C20880D247BCBA00E0828251BACD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treating orthotics and prosthetics separately from medical equipment and supplies</header> <paragraph id="HCDEA54CAED8A4054849FA545F9502C09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1834 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H61D23EDC5DAF49AB97EDC36A7732F39A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(5)—</text> <clause id="H3D5A0D4DE68F41C3A2EE788E833659CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2A85C747853442FF8D2DEC2B253618F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (D) through (F) as subparagraphs (C) through (E), respectively;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AAB5CAC0BA142769077774F54EE8593"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H354393E7D9CF48DC98E246EEF52B3EA5" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="H52EBAE5703884D798F02E6B52156255A"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Requirements for orthotists and prosthetists</header>
								<paragraph id="H8866F5DE73EA464EB2C805FCA4DA87EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuance and renewal of supplier number</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF93FC79C3ADA402CAE0072C23AC02729"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No payment may be made under this part for orthotics and prosthetics (as described in section 1861(s)(9)) furnished by a supplier of orthotics and prosthetics unless such supplier obtains (and renews at such intervals as the Secretary may require) a supplier number.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC609464BB26485988C3EB66EA997E87"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Standards for possessing a supplier number</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A supplier of orthotics and prosthetics may not obtain a supplier number unless the supplier—</text> <clause id="H8A98FFE7B9274DEFADF47252B86DCE13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complies with all applicable State and Federal licensure and regulatory requirements;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA9965A17FD304F3AAA9E156B87012FE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquires accreditation from the American Board for Certification in Orthotics, Prosthetics and Pedorthics, Inc., the Board of Certification/Accreditation, International, or such other accreditation entity that the Secretary determines to have accreditation standards that are equivalent to the accreditation standards of such boards;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4490EF7EB7C74F92A485149D59777D26"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>maintains a physical facility on an appropriate site;</text> </clause><clause id="H644B92D563D748619B4265A874E8E1F5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has proof of appropriate liability insurance; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF27E8D0092944ABBC01DFB0EA3C7B11"><enum>(v)</enum><text>meets such other requirements as the Secretary may specify.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H720AC00DC3DC4370AF5530A59785F156"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition against multiple supplier numbers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not issue more than one supplier number to any supplier of orthotics and prosthetics unless the issuance of more than one number is appropriate to identify other entities under the supplier’s ownership or control.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H610C1BD5726D4CFBBD6A1AA81D15E2D1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Prohibition against delegation of supplier determinations</header><text>The Secretary may not delegate (other than by contract under section 1842) the responsibility to determine whether suppliers meet the standards necessary to obtain a supplier number.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC824BC05441746DE8B2AC412261C34D3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Construction relating to previously issued and renewed supplier numbers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supplier numbers obtained under subsection (j)(1) prior to the enactment of this subsection by suppliers of orthotics and prosthetics that meet the standards described in subparagraph (B) shall be considered to have obtained a supplier number for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8F5E95C6A694BF181200044A787E77C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certificates of medical necessity</header>
									<subparagraph id="H3BA618E3890D437D942B5C73D83364EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Information provided by suppliers of orthotics and prosthetics on certificates of medical necessity</header>
 <clause id="HB7D2BCEC187C4A10B0CCE2A77AF0E7F3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A supplier of orthotics and prosthetics may distribute to physicians, or to individuals entitled to benefits under this part, a certificate of medical necessity for commercial purposes if the certificate contains the following information:</text>
 <subclause id="H166AED4EBE8D41C0A732D45527ABC989"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the supplier and the beneficiary to whom such orthotics and prosthetics are furnished.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H11E9ABA8C17F4F868A61C6D712ADBECC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the treating physician, including the name, Medicare provider number, address, and telephone number of such physician.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H22B0D39DCF6F42C19DF346E203692C9A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A description of such orthotics and prosthetics.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEA11324BA235425DB402EDE49A20F16D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any billing code identifying such orthotics and prosthetics, including the HCPCS codes, and summary descriptors of the items and services being recommended.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA572C1B2EE894CE08170F6F0876042BB"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The codes used under this title for payment for such orthotics and prosthetics, a description of the medical and functional condition of the beneficiary, and information about the need of the beneficiary for the orthotics or prosthetics.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H57DA9F68C90A48ADBDFB2CA13A5A3ECF"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Any other administrative information identified by the Secretary.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H8AEB7C2607E54412981B258B81EA2A29"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Information on payment amount and charges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a supplier distributes a certificate of medical necessity for orthotics and prosthetics, the supplier shall also list on the certificate of medical necessity the fee schedule amount and the supplier’s charge for the orthotics and prosthetics being furnished prior to distribution of such certificate to the physician.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H32E920BFA5074405BC87F3DAF3CC47B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any supplier of orthotics and prosthetics who knowingly and willfully distributes a certificate of medical necessity in violation of clause (i) or fails to provide the information required under clause (ii) or (iii) is subject to a civil money penalty in an amount not to exceed $1,000 for each such certificate of medical necessity so distributed. The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to civil money penalties under this subparagraph in the same manner as they apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87FF558450DD4939AE59819231D5F0B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Signature of treating physician required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require that, in order for a certificate of medical necessity submitted to the Secretary to be treated as showing that orthotics and prosthetics are reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of an illness or injury or to improve the functioning of a malformed body member, the certificate of medical necessity be signed by the treating physician.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB80D37F6F7BE49C781404511D4C3DAAD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>certificate of medical necessity</quote> means a form or other document, including a detailed written order, containing information required by the Secretary to be submitted to show that orthotics and prosthetics are reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury or to improve the functioning of a malformed body member.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F37863CABD7411AA9531C8B98336126"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coverage and review criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually review the coverage and utilization of orthotics and prosthetics to determine whether such orthotics and prosthetics should be made subject to coverage and utilization review criteria, and if appropriate, shall develop and apply such criteria to such items.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HDE895BECDCE64997AA58E438266D9050"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on patient liability</header>
 <subparagraph id="H401914C574BC411197A06A4A8444344B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), if a supplier of orthotics and prosthetics furnishes orthotics and prosthetics to an individual for which no payment may be made under this part (including, subject to section 1879, because the orthotics and prosthetics are not reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury or to improve the functioning of a malformed body member, as required under section 1862(a)(1)), any expenses incurred for such orthotics and prosthetics furnished to an individual by such a supplier not on an assigned basis shall be the responsibility of such supplier. The individual shall have no financial responsibility for such expenses and the supplier shall refund on a timely basis to the individual (and shall be liable to the individual for) any amounts collected from the individual for such items or services. The provisions of subsection (a)(18) shall apply to refunds required under the previous sentence in the same manner as such provisions apply to refunds under such subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBDFC16CCDC944A79C0A19A1702243E6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a supplier of orthotics and prosthetics furnishes orthotics and prosthetics to an individual for which payment is denied in advance under subsection (a)(15), expenses incurred for such orthotics and prosthetics shall be the responsibility of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H005997D208AB41109E2D89AACE6DED76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1865(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395bb">42 U.S.C. 1395bb(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or section 1834(r), as applicable,</quote> after <quote>section 1834(j)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC773C31D84F4718B54E039867E58E77"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation of competitive acquisition for off-the-Shelf orthotics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1847(a)(7)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3(a)(7)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0B84B144FD8F45AFB877F36F269AB118"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE460499F62A5417C84085D16EAEF7667"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ii) as clause (iii); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84F918F11C6845C99FADFF4268B74A05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (i) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H996E8B3390024F89A0231EC62268CDB4" style="OLC"> <clause id="HE556007FBB124E6FB1F18150926FAEC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by an orthotist or prosthetist described in subclause (II) or (III) of section 1834(h)(1)(F)(iii) to the patients of the orthotist or prosthetist as part of the professional service of the orthotist or prosthetist; or</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC46864F73387440194C6930113F711BD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limiting recoupment from Medicare appellants until completion of ALJ appeals process</header><text>Section 1869 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0CD311EB9EF44E6A5A78BE230AB6553" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H50B632645B8B47C799D3D1CA5C9E8C84"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Limitation on recoupment prior to completion of ALJ appeals process</header>
 <paragraph id="HCB80B39ED3E5484DBD4F16C08DB33DDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary may not recoup more than half of the amount of any payments made to a qualifying provider or supplier with respect to a claim for items or services that is subject to a determination, reconsideration, or hearing under this subsection, before—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE5773ACA3C6D4C49A1DF91514E26FB0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which a decision has been rendered under subsection (d)(1) with respect to such claim; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5C548FCB71F46438C7F7A663101B0FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a determination or reconsideration for such claim which is not eligible for a hearing under subsection (d)(1), the date on which the appeals process for such claim under this section (other than subsection (h)) is treated as exhausted.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48809A6FA8C14BC79192D4403731E6B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying provider or supplier defined</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>qualifying provider or supplier</quote> means a provider of services or supplier that—</text> <subparagraph id="H3468F797292B4F0099F64ADC05DD6B95"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has maintained a Medicare provider number for six years or longer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56D14388751647C7933966436EB152A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not under investigation for any potential violations of applicable Federal and State laws and regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D37BA6AE43E4752B5C5C504531D489E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a good record of submitting proper claims for items or services under this title, as determined by the Secretary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB1FE2DEB62F4F629A67389D2875E4D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>furnished the items or services described in paragraph (1) to an individual in person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE76A901B013D4647AD9249777B40E663"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Eligibility for payment for suppliers and providers based on qualifications</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H032838FC9F24490A9129143C5EC2D714"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title XVIII of the Social Security Act is amended by inserting after section 1863 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395z">42 U.S.C. 1395z</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE57C7CA571F2481C9E8D23C43DB05CF6" style="OLC">
						<section commented="no" id="HD76880606E3A4C01A5BD5CF4050D7C7A"><enum>1863A.</enum><header>Eligibility for payment for suppliers and providers based on qualifications</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HB18AFEE310EB4DCD877D79417803BBEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No payment may be made under this title for an item or service that is furnished—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB6AA75060D4D40A48F8B26AD64694868"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in a State that requires a provider or supplier to be licensed in order to furnish such item or service, unless the provider or supplier furnishing such item or service possesses all applicable licensure from the State; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE18233CA6BFD4E10834CDC630A8C8DFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a State that does not require a provider or supplier to be licensed in order to furnish such item or service, unless the provider or supplier meets all applicable qualifications, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAE04131DA0EF457D9D2111BBA09E6866"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable qualifications defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), the term <quote>applicable qualifications</quote> means, with respect to a provider or supplier, all applicable accreditations, certifications, and credentials required of such provider or supplier under this title in order for such provider and supplier to receive payment under this title for items or services furnished by such provider or supplier, including the requirements described in the special payment rules for certain prosthetics and custom-fabricated orthotics under section 1834(h)(1)(F).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9BFDF2DC8E544456A1F5C3968042C1AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to items and services furnished on or after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


