<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4CB452DCFB884D23A0F1B6F0029DAEBC" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 349 IH: Great Lakes and Fresh Water Algal Bloom Information Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 349</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150114">January 14, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001150">Mrs. Miller of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to create an
			 electronic database of research and information on the causes of, and
			 corrective actions being taken with regard to, algal blooms in the Great
			 Lakes, their tributaries, and other surface fresh waters, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H67CAF02F78DD4FB0B3BF8281F2D1163C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9ABDE591638046B7A9308E14EA374786" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Great Lakes and Fresh Water Algal Bloom Information Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HED75DEE924A94D25B0EF66D5031F52E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Great Lakes algal blooms information database</header> <subsection id="H797A74A42B2245779869D1CDF1AA6CD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall create an electronic database of research and information on the causes and corrective actions being taken with regard to algal blooms in the Great Lakes, their tributaries, and other surface fresh waters.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H95EDED775C2A4ED79D8373196388DC56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Administrator shall include in the database relevant chemical, physical, and biological data that have been collected by an accredited university, association or organization, research group, Federal agency, State, or local government in the United States or Canada.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H785027157905498284A910E1AF45C398"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>In creating and making information available through the database, the Administrator shall protect confidentiality of information in accordance with all applicable United States laws and regulations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD15686C4BC9C4CF5BDF5D4D31E8DBF38"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report and availability of information</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H143FE07B2D3F4936A79C9298DF79233E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report to the Congress each year comprehensive findings on information that was included in the database in the year covered by the report, including information regarding corrective actions being taken; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B6439F3ABA442AEA4E5E297010E705D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make information in the database electronically available to the public.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F46629C4C3B43C2A7C68C2643B105F1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No new authority</header><text>This section shall not be construed to grant any authority to the Administrator, including any authority to require submission of data.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


