<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H90B4E8D32A134FC899D0D7643ADEAD4D" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2467 IH: Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks National Monument Correction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2467</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000182">Mr. Neugebauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000456">Mr. Fleming</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To clarify that the Secretary of Homeland Security may undertake law enforcement and border security activities within the Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks National Monument, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6149A0E49ED245089CD71DACC1C599B4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7BB12F760D834448B62CA30C59446F63" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks National Monument Correction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" id="HDA20160123394FA98A98BD53B9C3FE0A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purpose of this Act, the term <term>National Monument</term> means the area designated as the <quote>Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks National Monument</quote> in Presidential Proclamation 9131, dated May 21, 2014.</text></section>
<section id="H27F3F2E02C454899B427F5E44C08D4B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Border security and law enforcement</header>
<subsection id="HF34CEB6501F64ECAB55286354FE51221"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Neither the National Monument designation nor any management plan in furtherance of the National Monument shall be interpreted or construed to—</text> <paragraph id="HAAEA61EA6E144211BC39882E4A50080D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevent the Secretary of Homeland Security from undertaking law enforcement and border security activities within the areas designated as a National Monument, including the ability to use motorized vehicles within the National Monument;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6DD9CB2C518B45ECA7E401B93096C94A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limit the 2006 Memorandum of Understanding among the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Agriculture regarding cooperative national security and counterterrorism efforts on Federal land along the borders of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H752AD8E15E1848ED828052B7E39C6C4F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prevent the Secretary of Homeland Security from conducting any low-level overflights over the National Monument that may be necessary for law enforcement and border security purposes; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE2E6BDBB75C84859A191E8821DF5D9BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prevent the Secretary of the Interior from allowing within the National Monument the installation and maintenance of communication or surveillance infrastructure necessary for law enforcement or border security activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H495749A4825147678D0FFB5B713D973A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative access</header><text>The route excluded from the Potrillo Mountains identified as <quote>Restricted—Administrative Access</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Potrillo Mountains Complex</quote> and dated December 10, 2013, shall be available for administrative and law enforcement uses, including border security activities.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD6F401202AF24B7A9D650B3C6EEDFD88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Law enforcement activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or any land management plan issued in furtherance of this Act or Presidential Proclamation 9139, dated May 21, 2014, shall prevent Federal, State, or local law enforcement personnel from having unfettered access to the National Monument, including the use of specialized equipment and motorized vehicles outside of existing roads and trails.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HAE95245D0F4148F98D12B245DB065CA4"><enum>4.</enum><header>National Defense</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in the national monument designation or any management plan in furtherance of the national monument shall restrict or preclude—</text>
<paragraph id="H8C1DE53B402749AD87C44992A5D8B88D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft over the National Monument, including military overflights that can be seen or heard within the National Monument;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CE5D725B3A545528ADB3C40881E4B33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the designation of new units of special airspace over the National Monument; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F83BA37AA1F46B29279DB0D630D35BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or establishment of military flight training routes over the National Monument.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

