<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H93ABACDE0599482CB7EEAA2F3F23EF12" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2522 IH: To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to award grants for the provision of furniture, household items, and other assistance to homeless veterans to facilitate their transition into permanent housing, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2522</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to award grants for the provision of furniture, household items, and other assistance to homeless veterans to facilitate their transition into permanent housing, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7821D13F32A94C55BFE2DF0EA9F877ED" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8831874725494B20A635C908DF77BA30" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Pilot program on provision of furniture, household items, and other assistance to homeless veterans moving into permanent housing</header> 
<subsection id="HD6046FB78CE64BF7986FDEAC54EB3EF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program required</header> 
<paragraph id="H95CDD5A4E8734B3CBF179DE601CC4E50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall commence a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of awarding grants to eligible entities to provide furniture, household items, and other assistance to covered veterans moving into permanent housing to facilitate the settlement of such covered veterans in such housing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6E427B3D53A485B877417A427D4C8D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>For purposes of the pilot program, an eligible entity is any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA5914FE1775649C1B308DC8994A99C3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A veterans service agency.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39B0854659594438A3FFCFDD2B5F62B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A veterans service organization.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0F3CC22B16E42AFB71398CB3E892BFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A nongovernmental organization that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D1637647B724E6B8E00DBBD09581552"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is described in paragraph (3), (4), or (19) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such code; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C95C345CDB54A9BB8F64B518DCFA44F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has an established history of providing assistance to veterans or the homeless.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54B2231EB39C4820BB9F2235F990EF6D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered veterans</header><text>For purposes of the pilot program, a covered veteran is any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H028FE96621514AEEB6367ACDA3E21818"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A formerly homeless veteran who is receiving housing, clinical services, and case management assistance under section 8(o)(19) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(19)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0ADED82C0F004837940236725D0EAD8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A veteran who is receiving—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H396471CB6D824E76846A3A3C2D91A9A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assistance from, or is the beneficiary of a service furnished by, a program that is in receipt of a grant under section 2011 of title 38, United States Code; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HEB6164D3E79A40638BDA6C4A3A01E5D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>services for which per diem payment is received under section 2012 of such title.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA71EC4EB90F64A8488B0AEA1804CA133"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A veteran who is—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H8A9B3A6AFC11475DAF4F693CFB0F3D3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a beneficiary of the outreach program carried out under section 2022(e) of such title; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30B3F4AF18EA4632938AD4AC06AB774D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in receipt of referral or counseling services from the program carried out under section 2023 of such title.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H33E4D517807D4418B1E6B47C06507501"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A veteran who is receiving a service or assistance under section 2031 of such title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA5D78F554B474CD1AB5A496E00250960"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A veteran who is residing in therapeutic housing operated under section 2032 of such title.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H88A1913F077243CA91ECAC0402BF7858"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A veteran who is receiving domiciliary services under section 2043 of such title or domiciliary care under section 1710(b) of such title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H82EFF409BF9F469096BC78D0A12BEBD4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A veteran who is receiving supportive services under section 2044 of such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H281CCF0343D14AD78EDA18E298AE4F5C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program during the three-year period beginning on the date of the commencement of the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDBA0A2958C634A01AED4285BF46F3357"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header> 
<paragraph id="H21192B21EF344FFF8F80037D33421A9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program through the award of grants to eligible entities for the provision of furniture and other household items as described in subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72DB1BEC5F714E10BC7ED9DD83B95D28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The amount of a grant awarded under the pilot program shall not exceed $500,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H425BBA570CB049BCA2FE804E783243F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15009E4976BE4485B942DA5A5650AD86"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity seeking a grant under the pilot program shall submit to the Secretary an application therefor in such form and in such manner as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05A9481C6C7B43D19BF711EB79551874"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection priority</header> <subparagraph id="HA87E38A3A248482AAC036D4E262B5BF5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Communities with greatest need</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), in accordance with regulations the Secretary shall prescribe, the Secretary shall give priority in the awarding of grants under the pilot program to eligible entities who serve communities which the Secretary determines have the greatest need of homeless services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H041179469D344532BC8365E8667479B7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text>The Secretary may give priority in the awarding of grants under the pilot program to achieve a fair distribution, as determined by the Secretary, among eligible entities serving covered veterans in different geographic regions, including in rural communities and tribal lands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4422969C139E439C84BDFC130598C0A1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header> <paragraph id="HF7C4B383397042188EE9758A3D9354AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), each eligible entity receiving a grant under the pilot program shall use the grant—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H38D77E43BAF44E26A80804F0D5227BEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to coordinate with the Secretary to facilitate distribution of furniture and other household items to covered veterans moving into permanent housing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F2DCE460FE341E598F08B8092097328"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to purchase, or otherwise obtain via donation, furniture and household items for use by such covered veterans;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H516599342891491980129167F3648D55"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to distribute such furniture and household items to such covered veterans; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53332D9F9BB743BF9B123C1AAC94DFFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to pay for background checks, provide security deposits, provide funds for utilities, and provide moving expenses for such covered veterans that are necessary for the settlement of such covered veterans in such housing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB53432CFB49F4E3BA3F5DF4B864E0F6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount of assistance</header><text>A recipient of a grant awarded under the pilot program may not expend more than $2,500 of the amount of the grant awarded for the provision to a single covered veteran of assistance under the pilot program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1E26CB8B72740EDB8D96ADB3AED4C3A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Memorandums of understanding</header><text>In the case of an eligible entity receiving a grant under the pilot program that entered into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary before the date of the enactment of this Act that provides for the provision of furniture and other household items to covered veterans as described in subsection (a) without Federal compensation, the eligible entity may use the grant in accordance with the provisions of such memorandum of understanding in lieu of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0DAE3F15037C4C4AB9D488386B468DDD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Full use of funds</header> 
<subparagraph id="H525C2AA00B6A4DD7B6FE4AC364C6CD87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A recipient of a grant awarded under the pilot program shall use the full amount of the grant by not later than one year after the date on which the Secretary awards such grant.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F56CEF15A264385AC8016ACA56DD051"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recovery</header><text>The Secretary may recover from a recipient of a grant awarded under this section all of the unused amounts of the grant if all of the amounts of the grant are not used—</text> 
<clause id="H42DC3DA4221A457BB9A4D8BD83440208"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pursuant to paragraph (1) and subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; or</text></clause> <clause id="HC7B29FE69F8F46628F31D79AA72C5989"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a case described in paragraph (3), pursuant to an applicable memorandum of understanding.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H257099B05F374A22A1F04D5C093A5546"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct outreach, including under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, to inform covered veterans about their eligibility to receive household items, furniture, and other assistance under the pilot program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HABEC8687FE364127BE89795218FEFD63"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA6F4DE39566D4613B913EA350B23EBB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluating an application by an eligible entity for a grant under the pilot program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7ECD77073AA4A22BEA269DDDDA15BAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>otherwise administering the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H772861DA0B024143AC9F3155F588D9A5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HD1B6C0F80DC44B76B222DE9B32271680"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the date that is 90 days after the last day of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the pilot program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H220B791ED8C84E70847DD971AD7775CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8957F33724F24C81A2EFCD0EF3BFBC45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the pilot program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H845BB370AD4945708CBC5EB2DC4A2777"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The findings of the Secretary with respect to the feasibility and advisability of awarding grants to eligible entities as described in subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H762BC99B1F2A48CA86AD44688FA6835E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such recommendations as the Secretary may have for legislative or administrative action to facilitate the settlement of covered veterans into permanent housing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBE51E88B25764A2DA6888956CF06028F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each year of the pilot program.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H23D3A6E218024352888F405972EBEA8A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0F58A0244D5B4D3E9989041AF28CC46F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>The term <term>outreach</term> has the meaning given such term in section 6301(b)(1) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H569C2D216BBA4A63B000F77C0F906E51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Veterans service agency</header><text>The term <term>veterans service agency</term> means a unit of a State government, or a political subdivision thereof, that has primary responsibility for programs and activities of such government or subdivision related to veterans benefits.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H171BD3093C5E4F59A548963773291DC9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Veterans service organization</header><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


