<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H62C93FDDEF184143887FADF0463ED53C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1831 IH: Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1831</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000570">Mr. Ryan of Wisconsin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish the Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H16BE14FBDE4A4411A818A1DDDC5EA9DB" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAB8AF299415B4693BD5732FE20BDA9CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H40676B08E1AE4BD0B189AAD59FFCD0F6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established in the executive branch a commission to be known as the <quote>Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text>
		</section><section id="H4B74292C2ECF40A3852E0C6587CF543F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Members of the Commission</header>
 <subsection id="H849D181E10134F84846E820B258261AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text>The Commission shall be comprised of 15 members as follows:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9869CFF059E746DB95E639D3EB50A3DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three shall be appointed by the President, of whom—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEB1781209367438B872DDC11CF71C78E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 shall be an academic researcher, data expert, or have experience in administering programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB756C9ED9C24BE39DC8A9D032D7D870"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 shall have expertise in database management, confidentiality, and privacy matters; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BCF7372DCF94488819831B70D81FE2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 shall be the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (or the Director’s designee).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H12B2B3E86A0D458FBC74A9F3BC52D1D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, of whom—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE41DEE1DDA044CCBB68988E0D411EE50"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 shall be academic researchers, data experts, or have experience in administering programs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF3205C7B175D4E9F8B63FC8845FC5EDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 shall have expertise in database management, confidentiality, and privacy matters.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3599FCC98689446F9F06DCB2F0327E07"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, of whom—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H542C08D6F5BB4D39B6A667E8C309D968"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 shall be academic researchers, data experts, or have experience in administering programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD9EF4BC7459469D8C0CADB8CC065715"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 shall have expertise in database management, confidentiality, and privacy matters.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8C0B1A1981AC43CAA220170C72EDDF81"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate, of whom—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEDCB0CBFFA24416784A6807A78626402"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 shall be academic researchers, data experts, or have experience in administering programs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDA17DFEA9991432CB56A7A733F3E3111"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 shall have expertise in database management, confidentiality, and privacy matters.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBA4834194F1B469A9646672891F862CC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate, of whom—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAA1904BC225444E3BD68F630EF6D3D87"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 shall be academic researchers, data experts, or have experience in administering programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H60307706E23141798D35119736EA6F37"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 shall have expertise in database management, confidentiality, and privacy matters.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CBF24EDFAC14D2FB30FAD6388785FB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expertise</header><text>In making appointments under this section, consideration should be given to individuals with expertise in economics, statistics, program evaluation, data security, confidentiality, or database management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2CB0CF73D5AD4261BB16143BAF730AF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson and Co-Chairperson</header><text>The President shall select the chairperson of the Commission and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall select the co-chairperson.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD0AAC8D4F30249B9A1BF9D2CB8CA74FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing of appointments</header><text>Appointments to the Commission shall be made not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H05B35C1616C642E9984C7A52B722C6A0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms; vacancies</header><text>Each member shall be appointed for the duration of the Commission. Any vacancy in the Commission shall not affect its powers, and shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H90B83F6B08BF4646843652268C22C354"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of the Commission shall serve without pay.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8572780FE2204CB09D4B392331C83C38"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8C66738335A842EFBF6DED457EFF00DF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of the Commission</header>
 <subsection id="HA77B9C4EAC3642CB94731F15B3D7D6AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall conduct a comprehensive study of the data inventory, data infrastructure, and statistical protocols related to Federal policymaking and the statistical and programmatic agencies responsible for maintaining that data to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9BD5541C3D204F72AF28D8B4E2F87E4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine the optimal arrangement for which administrative data on Federal programs and tax expenditures and related data series may be integrated and made available to facilitate program evaluation, continuous improvement, policy-relevant research, and cost-benefit analyses by qualified researchers and institutions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5B2A98986A64A218F4F10230C0E86A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make recommendations on how data infrastructure and protocols should be modified to best fulfill the objectives identified in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D8D9DF44CE34E81A90DDF94EDD12560"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations on how best to incorporate outcomes measurement, institutionalize randomized controlled trials, and rigorous impact analysis into program design.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1B7F1F6BDF75445387E873F03FB48F56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In undertaking the study required by subsection (a), the Commission shall consider if and how to create a clearinghouse for program and survey data, which shall include evaluation of—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC8A496C7BA62406E9C39B0C6945D24F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>what administrative data that are relevant for program evaluation and Federal policy-making should be included in a potential clearinghouse;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE60087FAF9934AE49F7E3BAD74984381"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which survey data the administrative data identified in paragraph (1) may be linked to, in addition to linkages across administrative data series;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D561E37A8854EFDA177B0FB610D8F3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">what are the legal and administrative barriers to including or linking these data series;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3FAFDF0B96A44F9C834F755220B76AD8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>what data-sharing infrastructure should be used to facilitate data merging and access for research purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD985739425DA46559CCA9BEE615BFEDA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>how a clearinghouse could be self-funded;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6D456A5C2A4A44E7A833474C3089F981"><enum>(6)</enum><text>which types of qualified researchers, officials, and institutions should have access to data;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6993BC67C5444CC1A263448D408206C7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>what limitations should be placed on the use of data provided;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC0E28C0545754454ABF056DA602064D9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>how to protect information and ensure individual privacy and confidentiality;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAED86A4D60804A8D98F3C3DA7586D835"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the data and results of research can be used to inform program administrators and policymakers to improve program design; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA205CA86C6045C89BAF0AED32ED2DF1"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">what incentives may facilitate interagency sharing of information to improve programmatic effectiveness and enhance data accuracy and comprehensiveness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F76B0BE081F4414AD251DAA66147E03"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Upon the affirmative vote of at least three-quarters of the members of the Commission, the Commission shall submit to the President and Congress a detailed statement of its findings and conclusions as a result of the study required by subsection (a), together with its recommendations for such legislation or administrative actions as the Commission considers appropriate in light of the results of the study.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C0D7860126E4BBCBA1484F6894E08DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The report under subsection (c) shall be submitted not later than the date that is 15 months after the date a majority of the members of the Commission are appointed pursuant to section 3.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H41C82F7F5C944360A76ACD32D0958629"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>administrative data</quote> means data—</text> <paragraph id="H444F01F4988345009C89F1BB8E2E598B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">held by an agency or a contractor or grantee of an agency (including a State or unit of local government); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E27FA0D2D624A1CA8450C9A16D1D3FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collected for other than statistical purposes.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF6A0621F6A574192AE7C293FA270BB37"><enum>5.</enum><header>Operation and powers of the Commission</header> <subsection id="HDF86982079B347A3A012B89EACD56EE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administrative assistance</header><text>The heads of the following agencies shall advise and consult with the Commission on matters within their respective areas of responsibility:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD3D9DE8E20E444F0B8843F392AF36D5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of the Census.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DC8134794D9481189047B760F6C6106"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Internal Revenue Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7486CBBC2B7476FA53AFE074D1B0DAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H82E8509686DC4CE481785C707EA8B649"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB082595650E443139328575EC9B99E74"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEE385B3AA544CB19DEC7308D6CAFFFB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Social Security Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD66AE96ED0384C66BCE208A991F301E6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of Education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H008C14B79E514CC3A8D352CA878FC391"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D265013F9624DD79ACFAC3BE8BD6268"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Office of Management and Budget.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H326CA73E4F5D43B5BB56055A42D2B33C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Bureau of Economic Analysis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08361E87E5E148288E15D71CC430E2D0"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA42BCF40A68840C690F4030C96363580"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Any other agency, as determined by the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H693E263517204BD0BDC3F1A79C8005CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet not later than 30 days after the date upon which a majority of its members have been appointed and at such times thereafter as the chairperson or co-chairperson shall determine.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2BAC6EDC030B4EFC879F0AE697101908"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of procedure</header><text>The chairperson and co-chairperson shall, with the approval of a majority of the members of the Commission, establish written rules of procedure for the Commission, which shall include a quorum requirement to conduct the business of the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB151C49F22D84EAFBAD506944CB00831"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Commission considers appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H69043769E2444ACE99646AE3022204A4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text>The Commission may contract with and compensate government and private agencies or persons for any purpose necessary to enable it to carry out this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB55ED334C94D4652A14FAB6E6B748D34"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Mails</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other agencies of the Federal Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA9AC47D42E9544748E95A01E69EA2152"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Gifts</header><text>The Commission may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property.</text> </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HDB0FB04EB135450AA7EB15990E8B89A5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC70F0B2D06D7489C8909480DFEDC6A37"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the request of the Director of the Census, the agencies identified as <quote>Principal Statistical Agencies</quote> in the report, published by the Office of Management and Budget, entitled <quote>Statistical Programs of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2015</quote> shall provide funds, in a total amount not to exceed $3,000,000, to the Director for purposes of carrying out the activities of the Commission as provided in this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02EE616B1E924DF59EB541C5403E8921"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Bureau of the Census shall provide administrative support to the Commission, which may include providing physical space at, and access to, the headquarters of the Bureau of the Census, located in Suitland, Maryland.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H8EF1B120B5AB4A2AB131A5B5B9D73048"><enum>7.</enum><header>Personnel</header>
 <subsection id="H6FD211B363664017922B190F58D4ED76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Commission shall have a Director who shall be appointed by the chairperson with the concurrence of the co-chairperson. The Director shall be paid at a rate of pay established by the chairperson and co-chairperson, not to exceed the annual rate of basic pay payable for level V of the Executive Schedule (section 5316 of title 5, United States Code).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC990F535682F46E4A15CC4610F33036B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Director may appoint and fix the pay of additional staff as the Director considers appropriate.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H11DEF924BA7942F9A8D91968DBFC97BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Experts and Consultants</header><text>The Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals which do not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay for a comparable position paid under the General Schedule.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HF31367F90DC44FE8BCA9643C4C8B4E24"><enum>8.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

