<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H860D77A263484D1C9A686716308E258B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3253 IH: Expedited Consideration of Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3253</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish procedures for the expedited consideration by Congress of the recommendations set
			 forth in the Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings report prepared by the
			 Office of Management and Budget.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFCC379695E1843DB9F1219ACB31670A1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H78B07594C7D648B99DC0D2E0393DE0CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expedited Consideration of Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H58D1DB91BA5F47DCA485D6F8BEB5068E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited consideration of Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings prepared by the Office of Management and Budget</header> <subsection id="HBA749CD679D84656A3EF5F059AD9C087"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Part B of title X of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/681">2 U.S.C. 681 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF71BB2A579AB433E9B9F2F418DABACAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 1013 through 1017 as sections 1014 through 1018, respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H340867E4B482464A8BE9348F1E35EC1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 1012 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H5AC41E144F8D401887A7CD64A77BEF51" style="OLC">
						<section id="HC69DB679D6BA46A080FBC3B04B178E40"><enum>1013.</enum><header>Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings report prepared by the Office of Management and Budget</header>
 <subsection id="H17AE7373C726475E8C74F01F8AC4F9FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HED1CD4FDBA5C4097B4CC7F559D243BD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>continuous session</term> relating to a House does not include a period during which that House has adjourned sine die or during which that House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a date certain; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H391EF7AB41B84C079F2E4A7E4B0AE12D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered bill</term> means a bill or joint resolution—</text> <subparagraph id="H8F0A6EBC20ED47A7AC951900A812CCEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transmitted under subsection (b)(2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7195D38A06F4AD28C81A9E7EC83699D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>introduced under subsection (c).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B472B92BBE245CFB290F7A9950DC2C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special message</header> <paragraph id="H891D2EC20F8743799291149EA36859DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the publication of any Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings report prepared by the Office of Management and Budget, or any successor thereto, the President may transmit to Congress a special message to carry out all or part of the recommendations contained in the report.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H560C9BA9F502463F901A59D70A4B706E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposed legislation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With a special message transmitted under paragraph (1), the President shall include a draft bill or joint resolution that would carry out the recommendations of the President.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA445C27518AD406784368A244924916D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Introduction</header>
 <paragraph id="H3353E88CF53643D6BF60245ADEC3C3CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The majority leader or the minority leader of the Senate and the majority leader or the minority leader of the House of Representatives shall introduce (by request) a bill or joint resolution transmitted to Congress under subsection (b)(2) not later than the end of the second day of continuous session of the Senate or the House of Representatives, respectively, after the date on which the President transmits the bill or joint resolution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04CAA0AF85F2449DBA028608A5659654"><enum>(2)</enum><header>By other Members</header><text>On and after the third day of continuous session of the Senate or the House of Representatives after the date on which a bill or joint resolution is transmitted to Congress under subsection (b)(2), and if the bill or joint resolution has not been introduced under paragraph (1) in that House, it shall be in order for a Member of the Senate or the House of Representatives to introduce the bill or joint resolution.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AA1AD3FB92C4D5E8BDBDAC3D96424E9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Referral</header>
 <paragraph id="HC03C766FD4CE4C2A9BD27BE100285451"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the Senate and the House of Representatives, a covered bill shall be referred to the committee or committees of the House with subject matter jurisdiction over that measure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36C9AA4B82D04BFE85505D9E3B7E2858"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>A committee to which a covered bill is referred—</text> <subparagraph id="H74A46754F8014EF8A26284B8ACD8EC39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall report the covered bill without substantive revision;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H641A8AB7AB2C4767AC75E47B413322DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may report the covered bill with or without recommendation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD599A822456A4A6593B493E2AC49120C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall report the covered bill not later than the seventh day of continuous session of that House after the date of receipt of the special message that the covered bill accompanied.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F525364C7864DA89F09D4A2C0E4F75F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Discharge</header><text>If a committee fails to report a covered bill within the period specified in paragraph (2)(C), the committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the covered bill and the covered bill shall be referred to the appropriate calendar of the House.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H673B2BC9343343EC8FB6E7C52E46ED26"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expedited consideration in the House of Representatives</header>
								<paragraph id="HA087E36103324F8E8B510435A2B14525"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC43301413AF04363B74905CF40EE0DC3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After each committee authorized to consider a covered bill reports it to the House of Representatives or has been discharged from its consideration, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the covered bill in the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48FEA31C169849498C6CB73F3454FD14"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Motion</header><text>For a motion to proceed to a covered bill—</text> <clause id="H6C7B723B86FA46DD9C080BA2473A4841"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the motion shall be highly privileged and shall not be debatable;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBEB096BF1F6F4546A91A63DAC05376EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all points of order against the motion are waived;</text> </clause><clause id="H940254051873439CAA4A1BFB908C6309"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA12D06EEBAAC40A3A51E3040269CF10E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an amendment to the motion shall not be in order; and</text> </clause><clause id="H234FEA547B784CECAFF1CEBB5855EAE4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>it shall not be in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H053D05130B714C48BEAA4EFF316D6033"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>If the House of Representatives proceeds to consideration of a covered bill—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H767D18F410434D8EA2440B8519A72067"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered bill shall be considered as read;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H595D8F32CC5742C59D04584A2936D0D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all points of order against the covered bill and against its consideration are waived;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H119240A40CDB4937B5CBC4950E3F5FE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the covered bill to its passage without intervening motion except 4 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2D09A6A27034DDF8D91C4654BEF157A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a motion further to limit debate is in order and shall not be debatable;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC4B62B0D71D49DC846C202E1205DC78"><enum>(E)</enum><text>no amendment to the covered bill shall be in order; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BDB92ED3B9847248AE725274FF37F74"><enum>(F)</enum><text>it shall not be in order to move to recommit the covered bill or to move to reconsider the vote by which the covered bill is agreed to or disagreed to.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H885B287F31C54C6FBF0729F0F6854F45"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Vote on passage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The vote on passage of a covered bill shall occur—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H654EF1A8ADDD4A39970EBAC099DD6A06"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediately following the conclusion of the debate on the covered bill; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78D4AF9F61924C429EBDD9AC4F2A0754"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than the tenth day of continuous session of the House of Representatives after the date on which the covered bill is introduced.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B53F48C1917442B9D1909D7F85C09D8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4FA41BC95DA24C2B997470BF33246443"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Appeals from decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the House of Representatives to the procedure relating to a covered bill shall be decided without debate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7FFC71A163E459CB5544C92A320A5AD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other rules relating to consideration</header><text>Except to the extent specifically provided in this subsection, consideration of a covered bill shall be governed by the Rules of the House of Representatives.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD47BD214373D4FB8A592E2EF32A73AFB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expedited consideration in the Senate</header>
								<paragraph commented="no" id="H4A9526E99A2349268DCBDF354CA87E31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCC5E5B9C48A64721B156AFD20283DD0B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after each committee authorized to consider a covered bill reports it to the Senate or has been discharged from its consideration to move to proceed to the consideration of the covered bill.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9EAC9AC52F094390951DFD8CFCC8E1B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Motion</header><text>For a motion to proceed to a covered bill—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HF85573C1F68A4B809501BEC9F9259568"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all points of order against the covered bill (and against consideration of the covered bill) are waived;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HED6F3336E05943198F5738DFA16D024A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the motion is not debatable;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H3428F9D97E474323ADC1132416290E2B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the motion is not subject to a motion to postpone;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H0752EFC5E7E64E0BB7ABEAFF52730DDD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFB5DAE70824F49CD839EACC1D779A7BE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an amendment to the motion shall not be in order; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H07F231827A164473ACE69F5E55D6EB61"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>if the motion is agreed to, the covered bill shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6058A08A8F054EDCB613EF5A2C394FCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>If the Senate proceeds to consideration of a covered bill—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H71F63662E3C24C5DA7678341EB23562E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consideration of the covered bill, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between the majority and minority leaders or their designees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF791483971BB4B94802943786B495557"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a motion further to limit debate is in order and not debatable;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1341803315AC49F68AF70EAC8E78ADF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an amendment to, a motion to postpone, or a motion to recommit the covered bill is not in order;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF246458003CE4DE2A9B73DD04135065C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business is not in order;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3A9B4B2725134242A0A9F46B79B23722"><enum>(E)</enum><text>debate on any debatable motion or appeal in connection with a covered bill shall be limited to not more than 1 hour, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the mover and the manager of the covered bill, except that in the event the manager of the covered bill is in favor of any such motion or appeal, the time in opposition thereto, shall be controlled by the minority leader or a designee; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF29EFC030DDB4EB9BC1D73FF01581D15"><enum>(F)</enum><text>it shall not be in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the covered bill is agreed to or disagreed to.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H32C9B6EDED2445C79524F6B78C7C0FB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>The vote on passage of a covered bill shall occur—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0A1B88E2C1C94EB18F5838B913FDC68A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>immediately following the conclusion of the debate on the covered bill, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H059B03B29C814DDF8848634BDEE13593"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than the tenth day of continuous session of the Senate after the date on which the covered bill is introduced.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE2EAA3BE4EDA48C7BAD87FD3C9E7DFBE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate to the procedure relating to a covered bill shall be decided without debate.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H103F72B2BC984041B325061FE54FC504"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rules relating to Senate and House of Representatives</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H566D84FA20314C31BD1BDD7EF7229A45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coordination with action by other house</header><text>If, before the passage by one House of a covered bill of that House, that House receives from the other House a covered bill—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3B579BA6842F4377B985ECB07441F3BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered bill of the other House shall not be referred to a committee; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC3DCB08F74484AB7A826AEBFB887FEC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the covered bill of the House receiving the resolution—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H6780C3220A4946509557EF3EDB5A205D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the procedure in that House shall be the same as if no covered bill had been received from the other House; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA086437BB2B04DA0B7A46DC00EEB6E96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the vote on passage shall be on the covered bill of the other House.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE01D0EA4DA8243E18B90AD3082CEB235"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Engrossing</header><text>If a covered bill is agreed to by the Senate or the House of Representatives, the Secretary of the Senate or the Clerk of the House of Representatives, respectively, shall cause the covered bill to be engrossed, certified, and transmitted to the other House of Congress on the same calendar day on which the covered bill is agreed to.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EAC7D59C75B4E4182B50B0CE6907531"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Suspension of procedures</header><text>In the Senate and the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H504C1091EEF044D995A9584C46DBB338"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a motion to suspend the application of this section shall not be in order; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5E9BB5E3E9645EAB9A089770781A2C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>it shall not be in order to suspend the application of this section by unanimous consent.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CC6626B84424B1292D4D1BEFD7CFD2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exercise of Rulemaking Powers</header><text>Section 904 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/621">2 U.S.C. 621</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H224A19F9039C448B85B63C3FE5E3A8E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>and 1017</quote> and inserting <quote>1013, and 1018</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EC3BD69F5B8409BB6F8F5BB4ED697C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>section 101</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 1013 and 1018</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4806B52576EE4C67B2B8FE80DC26526B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming Amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HEFE239C3324C472DBE2457D8193B0139"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 1011 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/682">2 U.S.C. 682</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF838683C755499DBF304DFFFF964A9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>1013</quote> and inserting <quote>1014</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0C26B9D150E4A0593BAD138F1FD9221"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text> <clause id="H1304FF0DC93F4EF1B5E46F3FDBD2DBA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1016</quote> and inserting <quote>1017</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7F4BDA35570945BEB22C77140C5DD5AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1017(b)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>1018(b)(1)</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H770B47E7ED2E4690A8F6BDDDD88E5286"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1015 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/685">2 U.S.C. 685</external-xref>) (as redesignated by subsection (a)) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H79C07F3E9BE247D7925ED7FD4560D310"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1012 or 1013</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>1012, 1013, or 1014</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9EAFBCC090744689F128A4CD1E786F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <clause id="HD3DBCA7988A6439AA771B0AE4B217FDB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>1012 and 1013</quote> and inserting <quote>1012, 1013, and 1014</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HF07FBE93BFEA484D8485B297CF0705C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>1012</quote> and inserting <quote>1012 or 1013</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H080FF37D3C66440D9BB561BA563936F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>1013</quote> and inserting <quote>1014</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00EE06C61983431E88A2292CCCED7433"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1)—</text>
 <clause id="H4371030E8D2549868BCF1D71E8D0DE4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="H59A9CD7167914CE6864C5EE234DD23C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H945199A35664456597CCC073FEC650BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>1013</quote> and inserting <quote>1014</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD52410C66C264D09AA361F51D9A50D8D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block id="H83508246C8E342A6B69725A4A37A615E" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HF8083A362B4F48778661BFDDB125428E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>he has transmitted a special message under section 1013 with respect to a Cuts, Consolidations, and Savings report; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F601E01DEE14FBD820D8AA690626F48"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical Amendments</header><text>The table of sections for subpart B of title X of such Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HAEEA5D48AACB497891B2E3AA9B999DDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the items relating to sections 1013 through 1017 as items relating to sections 1014 through 1018; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB97C860BC9D44340AE0E20C8789D9724"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 1012 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H5994BF2F9DDF4CB3A968A2B8B429152E" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1013. Expedited consideration of certain proposed rescissions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0495C9C2D49B494199EBFFA5F746F3A0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority provided by section 1013 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (as added by section 2) shall terminate effective on the date of the sine die adjournment of Congress during 2018.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


