<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H10194284CAE64712A1BCFA79805A943D" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 920 IH: Smarter Sentencing Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 920</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To focus limited Federal resources on the most serious offenders.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2DBF096FF4654286B5AA0A2E5EDC3F2A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0723BE2A85FF43789B7D3BD120C6F790" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Smarter Sentencing Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H11859AD85A734E89999001859810B9E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Applicability of statutory minimums</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3553(f)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>defendant</quote> and all that follows through <quote>point</quote> and inserting <quote>criminal history category for the defendant is not higher than category 2</quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HA42C7487B34040478A2703E20E42785B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of applicability of the Fair Sentencing Act</header>
<subsection id="H679D35A1642C4004A150CA6B7F28CB68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of covered offense</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered offense</term> means a violation of a Federal criminal statute, the statutory penalties for which were modified by section 2 or 3 of the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/220">Public Law 111–220</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 2372), that was committed before August 3, 2010.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCFEFB86DB91D499697252F33C16AA0A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Defendants previously sentenced</header><text>A court that imposed a sentence for a covered offense, may, on motion of the defendant, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, the attorney for the Government, or the court, impose a reduced sentence as if sections 2 and 3 of the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/220">Public Law 111–220</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 2372) were in effect at the time the covered offense was committed.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8F59946EA9E94F49B9E5045C34479E1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>No court shall entertain a motion made under this section to reduce a sentence if the sentence was previously imposed or previously reduced in accordance with the amendments made by sections 2 and 3 of the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/220">Public Law 111–220</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 2372) or if a motion made under this section to reduce the sentence was previously denied. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a court to reduce any sentence pursuant to this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8757BD35275D4400878005C764FF70A5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sentencing modifications for certain drug offenses</header> <subsection id="HEB625C819613482F89537F7FD25F669B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Act</header><text>The Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H7C27F7835574464C9ABD85C5CF8DE009"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 102 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA54C5CFEC0774929A4D5A98908E2FE5E" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HF3E9470CF2EF4AD58F67AB5A102E639E"><enum>(57)</enum><text>The term <term>courier</term> means a defendant whose role in the offense was limited to transporting or storing drugs or money.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFBEEA8A2110B42689FA737A3B4F778C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 401(b)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(b)(1)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H21C9CAB99744426C9CCE6B9ED15EFE31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the flush text following clause (viii)—</text>
<clause id="H0E5B1CA067CC4BCA8773C6C337A23F10"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>10 years or more</quote> and inserting <quote>5 years or more</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H367858585D4A45D587D9E37B43024125"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment which may not be less than 20 years and</quote> and inserting <quote>such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 10 years and</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1EB0C953CBA5466AB8FC6C4A85DF1C62"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>mandatory term of life imprisonment without release</quote> and inserting <quote>term of imprisonment of not less than 20 years</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27F7E441A64343CFB9BCD9DB8ABF6F9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the flush text following clause (viii)—</text>
<clause id="H7099EBED6BFE4942BF60F104A8D3B7B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>5 years</quote> and inserting <quote>2 years</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC39476361D1F4D7787209D71BA86AFE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not be less than 10 years</quote> and inserting <quote>not be less than 5 years</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7A8DAC6DE29C44B09E6FEE3233416651"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Import and Export Act</header><text>Section 1010(b) of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960">21 U.S.C. 960(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7D2E7F0CF92F491F866F7ADC0F81364A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the flush text following subparagraph (H)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD493D8FD03044751BA6DECFF2239FFD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, other than a person who is a courier,</quote> after <quote>such violation</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H715643D6A941488D8565B2A800715D2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>person commits</quote> and inserting <quote>person, other than a courier, commits</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6E019056D29D4582B58E5C13210410A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>If a person who is a courier commits such a violation, the person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 5 years and not more than life. If a person who is a courier commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a felony drug offense has become final, the person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 10 years and not more than life.</quote> before <quote>Notwithstanding section 3583</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07D386CA67EB4FCE96D341EAF6025671"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the flush text following subparagraph (H)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H048E90573354448791CB043B881174C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, other than a person who is a courier,</quote> after <quote>such violation</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H941ECAB7F07442B58C860B1D85876A2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>person commits</quote> and inserting <quote>person, other than a courier, commits</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71F71DEEE8D0498782C2E87BAADC9B2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>If a person who is a courier commits such a violation, the person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 2 years and not more than life. If a person who is a courier commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a felony drug offense has become final, the person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 5 years and not more than life.</quote> before <quote>Notwithstanding section 3583</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HAAB9BFFF23644EC08C4C6F0E3A3F7228"><enum>5.</enum><header>Directive to the Sentencing Commission</header> <subsection id="H87AEB490A77646E7ADC427F690F8B975"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Directive to Sentencing Commission</header><text>Pursuant to its authority under section 994(p) of title 28, United States Code, and in accordance with this section, the United States Sentencing Commission shall review and amend, if appropriate, its guidelines and its policy statements applicable to persons convicted of an offense under section 401 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841</external-xref>) or section 1010 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960">21 U.S.C. 960</external-xref>) to ensure that the guidelines and policy statements are consistent with the amendments made by sections 2 and 4 of this Act and reflect the intent of Congress that such penalties be decreased in accordance with the amendments made by section 4 of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HBEC68DB0867E42398B7A55FD4A92F8CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out this section, the United States Sentencing Commission shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="HB1172339C03D4EC3A2B47ECF58A8E41C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the mandate of the United States Sentencing Commission, under section 994(g) of title 28, United States Code, to formulate the sentencing guidelines in such a way as to <quote>minimize the likelihood that the Federal prison population will exceed the capacity of the Federal prisons</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3D7BADC400F24FABB62237BD46083291"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions of the United States Sentencing Commission in its October 2011 report to Congress entitled, Mandatory Minimum Penalties in the Federal Criminal Justice System;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H233A84D00522453BB94AAE447DAFE2AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the fiscal implications of any amendments or revisions to the sentencing guidelines or policy statements made by the United States Sentencing Commission;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2A5EBDE286EE4C249787090E22849C23"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the relevant public safety concerns involved in the considerations before the United States Sentencing Commission;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC26143FEB4BE4035A638A5FE250CD230"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the intent of Congress that penalties for violent, repeat, and serious drug traffickers who present public safety risks remain appropriately severe; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H8B40DDC07A3C44C1A8B27429E14EDEEA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the need to reduce and prevent racial disparities in Federal sentencing.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H71576ECE1840417283572F16285851F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Emergency authority</header><text>The United States Sentencing Commission shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H1122517609A94D5BA2ADA117BEC0792D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promulgate the guidelines, policy statements, or amendments provided for in this Act as soon as practicable, and in any event not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, in accordance with the procedure set forth in section 21(a) of the Sentencing Act of 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/994">28 U.S.C. 994</external-xref> note), as though the authority under that Act had not expired; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7768A5C9D57D4CA69955D000D5912772"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pursuant to the emergency authority provided under paragraph (1), make such conforming amendments to the Federal sentencing guidelines as the Commission determines necessary to achieve consistency with other guideline provisions and applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H47109D3D38D84EA69D6DD46B34019AF8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report by Attorney General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report outlining how the reduced expenditures on Federal corrections and the cost savings resulting from this Act will be used to help reduce overcrowding in the Federal Bureau of Prisons, help increase proper investment in law enforcement and crime prevention, and help reduce criminal recidivism, thereby increasing the effectiveness of Federal criminal justice spending.</text></section> <section id="H64BA31214B96425AAFA8493FF12AF3BB"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on Federal criminal offenses</header> <subsection id="H7B4BED0D6F96481D89DEC4F6CA566D44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text>
<paragraph id="H4F14396DE2954390953F091EC055EA22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal regulatory offense</term> means a Federal regulation that is enforceable by a criminal penalty; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H804D5D623DB949D38720A6D2A1699B37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal statutory offense</term> means a criminal offense under a Federal statute.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE62A62DDF0054CA6AB153705FD93A356"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on criminal statutory offenses</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report, which shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H9F52A87A19C44BE6A33B8833158BDD09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all criminal statutory offenses, including a list of the elements for each criminal statutory offense; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1FC7B8A282BE4C6E9CC12ADCE9E54053"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each criminal statutory offense listed under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H83C263AA8D864F309954FCB76FC8D4B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the potential criminal penalty for the criminal statutory offense;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0C51F328CE584185A5642C2F3E8F921B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of prosecutions for the criminal statutory offense brought by the Department of Justice each year for the 15-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E49229882794FF9B0C27A230D4E9081"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the mens rea requirement for the criminal statutory offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC4A522ED2D494E7AB25EA40CB5CBA5A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on criminal regulatory offenses</header>
<paragraph id="H1E74CA777D0441E7875B614B66D84DC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency described in paragraph (2) shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HF403CE18F3BB43EAB7650C3437FC0421"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of all criminal regulatory offenses enforceable by the agency; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H149D3D2750B94174B4B460D58BED910C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each criminal regulatory offense listed under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H3CA22CCFC21342C8B5FBA395841E4048"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the potential criminal penalty for a violation of the criminal regulatory offense;</text></clause>
<clause id="HE2FD5C4EA86C42D69C4C22B0F8D2F764"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of violations of the criminal regulatory offense referred to the Department of Justice for prosecution in each of the years during the 15-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H57F885A857D3497D9B2D823A4CD29E8A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the mens rea requirement for the criminal regulatory offense.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC6445117B4494C2A9C8A089882681D4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agencies described</header><text>The Federal agencies described in this paragraph are the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Education, the Department of Energy, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Labor, the Department of Transportation, the Department of the Treasury, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the Farm Credit Administration, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Election Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Federal Maritime Commission, the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, the National Labor Relations Board, the National Transportation Safety Board, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission, the Office of Compliance, the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Securities Investor Protection Corporation, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Small Business Administration, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Office of Government Ethics.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H33266DE11E9443F6A4FF41675D9FF773"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Index</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
<paragraph id="H0EB3F5736569457E97CC68ED44EAE9DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Attorney General shall establish a publically accessible index of each criminal statutory offense listed in the report required under subsection (b) and make the index available and freely accessible on the website of the Department of Justice; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9248EE014BF6457F85F7100E8B94EE1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the head of each agency described in subsection (c)(2) shall establish a publically accessible index of each criminal regulatory offense listed in the report required under subsection (c)(1) and make the index available and freely accessible on the website of the agency.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H74B8E16A02034510BDACF6E0732A1DD0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require or authorize appropriations.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

