<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD1D65410141E4F55B38734B16F5FCF9A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 508 IH: Super Pollutant Emissions Reduction Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 508</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a task force to review policies and measures to promote, and to develop best practices
			 for, reduction of short-lived climate pollutants, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB1C46CA27DE0413D817A26485FEBE47A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H56CDC0E5F6CB437BA0C536B7CA13AB71" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Super Pollutant Emissions Reduction Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SUPER Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H925D7F86E6B64264991D8445976EFDAA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H093141695E1240C0BC026C409DF8C919"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2EC57EBA1463458E9CFD5A1302EA675A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Carbon dioxide is estimated to account for 55 to 60 percent of anthropogenic radiative forcing (or manmade global warming), while the remainder is driven by non-carbon dioxide climate pollutants, primarily short-lived climate pollutants. These short-lived climate pollutants, or <term>super pollutants</term>, have shorter atmospheric lifespans than carbon dioxide but cause much more warming per molecule, and in many cases the emissions are growing much faster than carbon dioxide.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F2C5D805A240FE80284D11C02AF84E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Several of the short-lived climate pollutants are also potent air pollutants that harm human health and reduce crop yields. Reducing these pollutants can save thousands of lives every year in the United States and millions globally, while also increasing agricultural production.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C8655ADAD064D99A4F680126D53922F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">International efforts to address short-lived climate pollutants are underway, including the Climate and Clean Air Coalition to Reduce Short-Lived Climate Pollutants, led by the Department of State and the United Nations Environment Programme, the Global Methane Initiative, and the negotiation of amendments to the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAB9E4B1A63B44CE94936F4B4E885F12"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Many of the technologies to reduce short-lived climate pollutants already exist, but adoption of such technologies has been slow.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H635B1780F1294C98AE1DF14D9E09C4F5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Government has a number of programs and initiatives some of which aim to, or the outcomes of which, reduce emissions of short-lived climate pollutants, but these programs are scattered across multiple agencies and there is insufficient coordination to maximize reductions of these pollutants. In February 2012, the Government Accountability Office published an annual report, <term>Opportunities to Reduce Duplication, Overlap and Fragmentation, Achieve Savings, and Enhance Revenue</term>, which examined the efficiency and efficacy of government programs, including those that address diesel emissions that contain black carbon, a short-lived climate pollutant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61156A383C5E413EA87B1CD6AF48C70A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Executive Order 13514 requires Federal agencies to develop plans for reducing hy­dro­fluo­ro­car­bons and methane, but few agencies have focused on these compounds in their annual Strategic Sustainability Performance Plans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCA2726A7B45848D5971CDB966E5ED115"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Because of their short atmospheric lifetimes, reducing global emissions of short-lived climate pollutants can quickly cut the rate of global temperature rise in half, by 2050, and help stabilize global temperatures below 2 °C above pre-industrial temperatures by 2100, when combined with reductions of global emissions of carbon dioxide. Cutting short-lived climate pollutants along with carbon dioxide can also reduce the rate of projected global sea-level rise by half and total sea-level rise by a third. Steps to reduce short-lived climate pollutants are likely to have air quality and public health benefits as well.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4041729ED8574A02A8CF82E6A4B6E30B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to—</text> <paragraph id="H9048EE433E7F43FB964336C1DBA147DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate and optimize the Federal Government’s existing efforts to address short-lived climate pollutants;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A580E8589A24B0498F175F64F010FCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce overlap and duplication of such efforts; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD748A94A8F8A4B0C9DF682B06E4FF2DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage Federal operations, programs, policies, and initiatives to reduce short-lived climate pollutants by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H263CBF21C2DB4A88ACEF36F2C3BFA69A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that the coordinated Federal programs are effective and forward-looking in their efforts to control short-lived climate pollutants;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD47B103AEE044D7BBA1D9D620F9706D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring coordination of such Federal operations, programs, policies, and initiatives with State, local, regional, tribal, and industry efforts; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H264025A3617C4BABA19908E2C11C761D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting such State, local, regional, tribal, and industry efforts.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF586AB45CEA7480988611849402C2770"><enum>3.</enum><header>Task force on super pollutants</header> <subsection id="H1DC38F9E77114483A37221A8F8AE3243"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall establish the <term>Task Force on Super Pollutants</term> (referred to in this section as the <term>Task Force</term>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAB9CF47193EE4BD8899D0990CD72E822"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H968FD0410B8544449A9E0E7DE5CE8C83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review existing and potential policies and measures that promote reduction of short-lived climate pollutants, in part by identifying and evaluating programs and activities of the Federal government that contribute, or could contribute, to such reduction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC42A68C9986B48C6A866E481EEA8F500"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify and recommend specific existing Federal programs and activities evaluated under paragraph (1) that are unnecessarily duplicative and can be consolidated to achieve greater efficiency and effectiveness;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC37BB386C9424F28BBA67F5D51A7EF9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify gaps where programs do not exist, and recommend focused programs and activities to fill these gaps to achieve reductions of short-lived climate pollutants, with an emphasis on industry standards and public-private partnerships where possible;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53B7CB8101334FB08A2F2FB1FFBDC3A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify, compile, evaluate, and develop best practices for reductions of short-lived climate pollutants, including by—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA815AA8DABA4B9FBB4BE42EFDCF43D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying and evaluating both domestic and international best practices and standards practiced and set by governments, industry in each sector listed in subsection (c)(5), standards bodies, and other relevant institutions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE2A2433015F4E9A98BD7F7CCCF22049"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying and evaluating cost-effective mitigation projects, strategies, and policies at the State, local, and tribal level, with the greatest potential for reduction of short-lived climate pollutants; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC51F33E90C8B49289A05E63B0BAC88E2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress a report on the findings and recommendations developed under paragraphs (1) through (4).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BCCE339D96648D5A60CBA4387DFD998"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The task force established under subsection (a) shall include representatives of—</text> <paragraph id="H5D21659B48A54C15A4D43DEF62839EE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all relevant Federal agencies, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H025DD940B2324FA0AB7E638C2F001E37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H679B3E630DC74BEB973B3B9D7BF7BA07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H968B1ABDDCF043BE84EBC0B225A1802E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BDE1BB0EA9E41E99BFAD1FE678C6F43"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary of Transportation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD862CBCF7374549825C8E58DEAC213A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27FD21F61AB64EDA94D989765A4276EC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Secretary of State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD79FC40348C14619B038D1B4013BEF50"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Secretary of Commerce; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59039FAB24A64F71B0A62F8446AA7AFB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA1ABD60F29A45A4A45B0A2A0E8CA09A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant offices and councils within the Executive Office of the President, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2D07C149B1E420899AD10529BF58ED9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of Management and Budget;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H956F5BD59D9F45FFBBD524F779AF379D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of Science and Technology Policy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68C83F6CA5A942ED9C57C43954052CD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Quality;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA2C8AD5B7524E5D9557D4E3B4AD9BB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State, local, and tribal governments or associations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H22811819B2F5403CABDAA7A0436C6931"><enum>(4)</enum><text>academic and non-governmental organizations with expertise in short-lived climate pollutants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35C75B85401444CE809C12D3C2326D97"><enum>(5)</enum><text>relevant industry organizations, representing at least the following sectors:</text> <subparagraph id="HAAE66DA5A55F42A1B94D8D6284E763EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Energy supply and transmission, including fossil fuels.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB12B1B06F89C45DCBAA0C59BE504E1F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Solid waste.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDDA401D0C5C466B8F318BAAB41B5FF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Transportation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0924A337AD441F1BDA43A4DEB20D64C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Chemical manufacturing and user industries.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4496DD186654153AC1982DB72C20F2F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Agriculture.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FA508EA617A4926990D279E97EC8EDC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Wastewater.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD5332476347434ABB176172C409DC1F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Buildings.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAF7CB2B541EE4D16801D4ECA6CBE53B1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Other sectors as determined appropriate by the President.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD1E76EC93F8848CDB8508075448E5F6D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>short-lived climate pollutant</term> means any of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8FB1CDBF33174DD8AE127F7DCA9C623A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Black carbon.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6630127ED3994BBA93249CE4ACD58610"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Methane.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11550D859635403EAB3FEF0FCAC14DCE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Hydrofluorocarbons.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D4C844DB3AD4807B1FF5500598BF17F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Tropospheric ozone and its precursors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF64A07565EEE4F41996A73582452F33F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Emissions from banks of ozone-depleting substances.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

