<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H48B047B94A1F4A0CAEE0F05D2A134688" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4291 IH: SAFER Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4291</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for additional security requirements for Syrian and Iraqi refugees, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6C4D2C7AD1E7463482DF70F5BF750174" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5694D5B51BB444C9A0EC3D1BF93EAA94" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure Accountability for Emigres and Refugees Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SAFER Act of 2015</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H107577B29A644CB7B7B351A04379FC15"><enum>2.</enum><header>Security requirements for Syrian and Iraqi refugees</header> <subsection id="H4B75CACAFF8F45B9A9A78DD456DBC9D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to admitting to the United States as a refugee under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) a covered alien, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Director of National Intelligence, shall ensure that the covered alien—</text>
 <paragraph id="H267560A230D14DF8A8FCFCB620F93FCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has taken and passed a lie detector test, as determined by the Secretary;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB88C848D363C4946A4ED731CA7F2A60A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has submitted to the Secretary biometric identification information, including DNA, which the Secretary has compared against all relevant databases and determined that the covered alien has no known history of engaging in terrorist activity (as such term is defined in section 212(a)(3)(B)(iv) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(iv)</external-xref>)); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9139909EDBD241779A751C5C8F9086AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not pose a threat to the national security of the United States based on a background check that the Secretary conducts, which includes a review of the covered alien’s interactions on and posting of material to the Internet (including social media services), and for purposes of which, the alien has submitted to the Secretary such information as the Secretary determines necessary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5A5AD2B223848509621D922943F7077"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered alien</header><text>The term <term>covered alien</term> means an alien applying for admission to the United States as a refugee who—</text> <paragraph id="HF0A4F27D7FA146F6B3B4E8C447597A87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a national of Iraq or Syria;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16F12F01BFBB4BAE955D5AA23EB78450"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has no nationality and whose last habitual residence was in Iraq or Syria; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FEF90699ADC4457A2DEA154BCC0BD74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has been present in Iraq or Syria at any time on or after March 1, 2011.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CEEDAE2693E432DBFC587A24C9856A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This Act shall cease to have effect on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


