<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE092118C0A0C4D3FB7181DAD9F6773C2" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 524 IH: Local Control of Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 524</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150126">January 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000186">Mr. Nunnelee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001102">Mr. Clawson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000458">Mr. Fincher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000566">Mr. Gowdy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000570">Mr. Guinta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000602">Mr. Pompeo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit the Federal Government from mandating, incentivizing, or coercing States to adopt the
			 Common Core State Standards or any other specific academic standards,
			 instructional content, curricula, assessments, or programs of instruction.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H97323294447A456BA492F66CDD56F1BE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1D1B2BD8DD424160955F9BF65D8EBE4F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Control of Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4F17BD493E2446EA927A937CA534C15C"><enum>2.</enum><header>General ESEA prohibition</header> <subsection id="HD000E2605AA6470CAF6D88A2C8FF9B53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9527 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7907">20 U.S.C. 7907</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H160945E9D0864A95A8F50AA91FDFDA5B" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H6407CE1FD6434D178EDC4A19621FC558"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition of Federal government mandating common standards, programs of instruction, curricula,
 assessments, or academic standards</header><text>An officer or employee of the Federal Government shall not directly or indirectly, through grants, contracts, or other cooperative agreements under this Act (including waivers under section 9401)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9B9E2F67A7504734A910DE76A68F7A4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mandate, direct, or control a State, local educational agency, or school's specific instructional content or any specific academic standard, assessment, curriculum, or program of instruction, including through any requirement, direction, condition, or mandate to adopt—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFFF9FD0806DB4CAEA1056177622F7604"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Common Core State Standards developed under the Common Core State Standards Initiative, any other academic standards common to a number of States, or any specific statewide or nationally recognized content standards; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD96BCE31D7C2481FB2A10F2F6B73FAA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any assessment, instructional content, or curriculum aligned to, or based on, specific academic standards, including any of the standards described in subparagraph (A);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03A5EF4CCDF942AEA6418B1617D5FADB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incentivize a State, local educational agency, or school to adopt any specific instructional content, academic standard, assessment, curriculum, commonality of standards or assessments, or program of instruction described in paragraph (1), which shall include providing any priority, preference, or special consideration during the application process based on any specific content, standard, assessment, curriculum, commonality, or program; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53EB223F138A4D09B1A1FC3726FA7A66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make financial support available in a manner that is conditioned upon a State, local educational agency, or school's adoption of any specific instructional content, academic standard, assessment, curriculum, commonality of standards or assessments, or program of instruction described in paragraph (1), even if such requirements are specified in section 14006 or 14007 of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 281) or any other Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83C382EEA2E64102837A881783DA0DE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 9527(a) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7907">20 U.S.C. 7907(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>curriculum, program of instruction, or</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HAF962DF4B5D04425866FCB6BC0EE4F93"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on requiring adoption of common standards with respect to waivers</header>
 <subsection id="H6E39F5C90EDC4C9191277C2CC6039C2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9401 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7861">20 U.S.C. 7861</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E4D66312E1C4C09921795B2ACF0F683" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H0C1FCA16CAFE422085CC422CD82F70BC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition on requiring certain standards for waivers</header>
 <paragraph id="HA20693BB56B246F8929A13CF12AB801A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall not require that a State, local educational agency, Indian tribe, or school adopt, as a prerequisite or condition for any waiver under this section, any specific instructional content, academic standard, assessment, curriculum, or program of instruction, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB709157B5AEB4FA0A179A0B38A2BAEE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Common Core State Standards developed under the Common Core State Standards Initiative, any other academic standards common to a number of States, or any specific statewide or nationally recognized content standards; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF91DA1DFB0B40C2AD98CC30FF5D7CE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any assessment, instructional content, or curriculum aligned to, or based on, any specific academic standards, including any of the standards described in subparagraph (A).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83EC10CB21D748A5B035315E6D4E9D45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect on previously issued waivers</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0F2BC0BBAAC443F2854C19B569CEC1BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any requirement described in paragraph (1) that was required for a waiver provided to a State, local educational agency, Indian tribe, or school under this section before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Local Control of Education Act</short-title> shall be void and have no force of law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98CE897950264B4E998E03A9868988A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibited actions</header><text>The Secretary shall not—</text> <clause id="H32CA9CCC01AA464AAA6BC5806AC390D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enforce any requirement that is void pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDD5E28B3BF634504B641546BD8CB3705"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require the State, local educational agency, Indian tribe, or school to reapply for a waiver, or to agree to any other conditions to replace any requirements that is void pursuant to subparagraph (A), until the end of the period of time specified under the waiver.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC33AF73705EE4FA3B8764697990B56F3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No effect on other provisions</header><text>Any other provisions or requirements of a waiver provided under this section before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Local Control of Education Act</short-title> that are not affected by subparagraph (A) shall remain in effect for the period of time specified under the waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HB62E586389E04B2BB274421D562DAD79"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition in Race to the Top Funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XIV of Division A of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 14007 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF62C1CCB2BA747A097EDBE455F6E6F84" style="OLC">
 <section id="H73A17D2D46FE458E9E8CB72FA270185C"><enum>14007A.</enum><header>Prohibition on requiring or preferring common standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The prohibitions of section 9527(e) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 shall apply to each grant awarded under section 14006 or 14007 in the same manner as such prohibitions apply to a grant awarded under such Act.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


