<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5678DE6CEA204C4EBB3F10F0FBD6FB10" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2304 IH: SPEAK FREE Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2304</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150513">May 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 28, United States Code, to create a special motion to dismiss strategic lawsuits against public participation (SLAPP suits).</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC7EFEB1DB6A44A9D8AF2E4573B688D13" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H10DBB7FF0F8649B1A1F1AACA86FFE7B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Participation, Engagement, and Knowledge Freedom by Reducing Egregious Efforts Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SPEAK FREE Act of 2015</quote>. </text></section> <section id="HDD09F39E37344CFEA55D987170715F7B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special motion to dismiss strategic lawsuits against public participation</header> <subsection id="H13EBEFAC72FD4737BE3AA54400FC4550"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part VI of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding after chapter 181 the following new chapter:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H5AE4B610F1F647A592345CDDB6BC49AF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<chapter id="HFEE5A84920F44DCA9EBFE518479B2CB1"><enum>182</enum><header>Special motion to dismiss strategic lawsuits against public participation </header> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4201. Strategic lawsuit against public participation defined.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4202. Motion to dismiss strategic lawsuit against public participation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4203. Discovery.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4204. Interlocutory appeal.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4205. Motion to quash.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4206. Removal.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4207. Fees, costs, and sanctions. </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4208. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc> 
<section id="HF9BEDF94C48748C481DDEDB94F9A2202"><enum>4201.</enum><header>Strategic lawsuit against public participation defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter, the term <quote>strategic lawsuit against public participation</quote> or <quote>SLAPP suit</quote> means a claim that arises from an oral or written statement or other expression, or conduct in furtherance of such expression, by the person against whom the claim is asserted that was made in connection with an official proceeding or about a matter of public concern. </text></section> <section id="H0557A6F96C2D4988984E2D421CC0A2AB"><enum>4202.</enum><header>Special motion to dismiss strategic lawsuit against public participation</header> <subsection id="H0B2F9D0CFEBC4EA08621D91E22867C42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), a person against whom a SLAPP suit is asserted may file a special motion to dismiss. If the party filing a special motion to dismiss a SLAPP suit makes a prima facie showing that the claim at issue arises from an oral or written statement or other expression by the defendant that was made in connection with an official proceeding or about a matter of public concern, then the motion shall be granted and the claim dismissed with prejudice, unless the responding party demonstrates that the claim is likely to succeed on the merits, in which case the motion shall be denied. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA2EA36FBDF334B748373E9344F01FA9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<paragraph id="HDCA0D7654F39406FA7C94493DA1131A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement actions</header><text>The court shall not grant a special motion to dismiss under this section if the claim is an enforcement action brought by an agency or entity of the Federal Government or a State or local government. </text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C9E9548F9A547B8B45AA6334D748B1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commercial speech</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), the court shall not grant a special motion to dismiss under this section if the claim is brought against a person primarily engaged in the business of selling or leasing goods or services where such claim arises from the statement or conduct of such person and such statement or conduct—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H04B3F9FC3E9343D9AF58DAC6EA75461C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consists of representations of fact about such person’s or a business competitor’s goods or services, that is made for the purpose of obtaining approval for, promoting, or securing sales or leases of, or commercial transactions in, the person’s goods or services, or the statement or conduct was made in the course of delivering the person’s goods or services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9A453F879214155A60FD81BFA52291B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">arises out of the sale or lease of goods, services, or an insurance product, insurance services, or a commercial transaction in which the intended audience is an actual or potential buyer or customer.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAA24B9C60B840B294C2AD9DE5A63C7E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), the court shall not grant a special motion to dismiss under this section if the claim is a public interest claim. </text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H8BBACA8C92814D8DB3C8DC5838638B3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations on exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (b) shall not apply as to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8FF6C5A033A943438EE10A1A3750FB4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any claim against a person or entity engaged in the dissemination of ideas or expression in any book or academic journal, while engaged in the gathering, receiving, or processing of information for communication to the public;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0926F92D3634DB2868EB5FB1F88FE95"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any claim against any person or entity based upon statements or conduct concerning the creation, dissemination, exhibition, advertisement, or other similar promotion of journalistic, consumer commentary, dramatic, literary, musical, political, or artistic works, including motion pictures, television programs, or articles published online or in a newspaper or magazine of general circulation; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B51DE848FB744EF9A04C93B52AD980E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any claim against a nonprofit organization that receives more than 50 percent of annual revenue grants or awards from, programs of, or reimbursements for services rendered to the Federal, State, or local government.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCC41E9B0426D4825BCD20244E4E9D068"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Time Limit</header><text>Unless the court grants an extension, a motion to dismiss a SLAPP suit shall be filed—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7C08AB24A82441D88AAB330B318E521C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 45 days after the date of service of the claim, if the claim is filed in a Federal court; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22CC25AFE1F9455086AA5A314242F522"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of removal, if the claim is removed to Federal court under section 4206.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H065DC0C82CF045C99C25C2838E830D29" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Hearing</header> 
<paragraph id="HA6E6252B72EC4CAFB713011B79E2DD63" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the court shall set a hearing on a special motion to dismiss a SLAPP suit on a date not later than 30 days after the date of service of the special motion to dismiss a SLAPP suit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA2ECFB895944656BCAB2C32899E9717" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hearing postponed</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the court may postpone the hearing for up to 60 days, but shall set the hearing on a date that is not later than 90 days after the date of service of the special motion to dismiss a SLAPP suit, if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H69AAE6FAAA6146EA99E2E40784919574" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the docket conditions of the court require a later hearing; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60F04A50A45240A49CE653A9227CF4C3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there is a showing of good cause; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C09AA7DCEFD41ECA22422927CD120A4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the parties agree to postpone the hearing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA189FBBAD68F455A8733B34FAB60E2EC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension for discovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court allows specified discovery under subsection (a) of section 4203, the court may extend the hearing date to allow specified discovery under that subsection, but the court shall set the hearing on a date not later than 120 days after the date of service of the special motion to dismiss a SLAPP suit.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H551BB9389EF54BDD8B68B2D502BAC20C" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Ruling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court must rule on a special motion to dismiss a SLAPP suit not later than 30 days after the date on which the final paper is required to be filed or the date argument is heard, whichever is later.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H603FE74684584C1A88F836AE231426D7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evidence</header> <paragraph id="H6DB600C4F73F42ECA73992670D629863"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether a legal action should be dismissed under this chapter, the court shall consider the pleadings and affidavits stating the facts on which the liability or defense is based.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE562B03A72FF4862805BF41C6BB923F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court has ordered specified discovery pursuant to section 4203, the court may consider such discovery.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8A81D3C7169B4D2DB71F055C664183AE"><enum>4203.</enum><header>Stay of discovery</header> <subsection id="H3DB44A5E39D64F9389753740D410B47B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), upon the filing of a special motion to dismiss under section 4202, discovery proceedings in the action shall be stayed until a final and unappealable order is entered on such motion unless good cause is shown for specified discovery. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB103593572FE40A9AF67FF1A16B31BA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A stay issued under subsection (a) based on the filing of a special motion to dismiss under section 4202, that only seeks dismissal of a third-party claim or a cross claim asserted by a defendant shall only apply to discovery that is requested by the party asserting the third-party claim or cross claim or discovery that relates solely to the third-party claim or cross claim.</text> </subsection> </section> <section id="HDAB5851E755240ED9413BC48F18B4364"><enum>4204.</enum><header>Interlocutory appeal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An aggrieved party may take an immediate interlocutory appeal from an order granting or denying in whole or in part a special motion to dismiss under section 4202.</text></section> 
<section id="H403A7612E8D545BBA2ED4A69FFBDC42F" commented="no"><enum>4205.</enum><header>Motion to quash</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A person whose personally identifying information is sought in connection with a claim subject to the procedure described in section 4202(a) may at any time file a motion to quash the order to produce the information. If the party filing a motion to quash makes a prima facie showing that the order is for personally identifying information, then the motion shall be granted and the order to produce the personally identifying information shall be quashed, unless the responding party demonstrates with an evidentiary showing that the claim is likely to succeed on the merits of each and every element of the claim, in which case the motion to quash shall be denied. No determinations made in deciding a motion to quash under this section shall impede or otherwise diminish the availability of the procedures described in section 4202(a).</text> </section> <section id="H3A6E2C9050AE469FB6B2A6967D98AA92"><enum>4206.</enum><header>Removal</header> <subsection id="H0ADDDCE88C7D4CDEA6524BB5300FA278"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Special motion To dismiss SLAPP suit</header> <paragraph id="H1620106CEF454D58AF37F7D3ACD936EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a civil action in a State court that raises a claim described in section 4202(a) may be removed to the district court of the United States for the judicial district and division embracing the place where the civil action is pending. The grounds for removal provided in this section need not appear on the face of the complaint but may be shown in the petition for removal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCAC0E486ACC41C287702CB56FC8D8D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Removal may not be requested under paragraph (1) on the basis of a third-party claim or a cross claim asserted by a defendant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84D3B8D8FB8F4F1E99EFD09244050417"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Remand</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a civil action is removed under paragraph (1) and an order denying in its entirety a motion to dismiss filed under section 4202 is not appealed within the time permitted by law or all potential appellate proceedings have been exhausted, the court shall remand the remaining claims to the State court from which the civil action was removed. The remaining claims shall not be remanded to State court if the order granted a motion to dismiss in part and such order is not appealed within the time permitted by law or all potential appellate proceedings have been exhausted. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE825E6F8B8494E8498A2D3C8D6E5DE8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Motion To Quash</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proceeding in a State court in which a request or order that reasonably appears to be a request or order described in section 4205 is sought or issued may be removed to the district court of the United States for the judicial district and division embracing the place where the civil action is pending by any person that seeks to file a motion to quash under section 4205 and asserts a defense based on the First Amendment to the Constitution or laws of the United States.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HAC3113A99FA24AAFA2E6C7515BB6DE5C"><enum>4207.</enum><header>Fees, costs, and sanctions</header> <subsection id="H3DA6FDC387E64868AB429AA4178B9B48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Attorneys fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), a court shall award a person that files and prevails on a motion to dismiss under section 4202 or a motion to quash under section 4205, litigation costs, expert witness fees, and reasonable attorneys fees. A party shall be a prevailing party as to a special motion to dismiss or to quash if a claim or discovery request is voluntarily dismissed or withdrawn after the filing of a special motion to dismiss.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7FB843FDA1D04839B75EACA75B6E8BA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Frivolous motions to dismiss</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), if a court finds that a motion to dismiss under section 4202, a motion to quash under section 4205, or a notice of removal under section 4206 is frivolous or is solely intended to cause unnecessary delay, the court shall award litigation costs, expert witness fees, and reasonable attorneys fees to the party that responded to the motion or notice.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF1A9B3A6CC87453AA8E04DA01EFAAA97"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government and the government of a State, or political subdivision thereof, may not recover litigation costs, expert witness fees, or attorneys fees under this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6BE5063E337A405FB8444D9F3EAB857A"><enum>4208.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter:</text> <paragraph id="HAD5E47E08A904E2DBE8176F1AA5902D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Matter of public concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>matter of public concern</quote> means an issue related to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H75D08DAF54554EA1A20725329FDD087F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health or safety;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A26C42B72F042E4B43069A216A3E3AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>environmental, economic, or community well-being;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9919B86CF9247F6AADBA43B9270ECE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H753CBB2560A84427AB003124FA1C286E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a public official or public figure; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H826E1EAD087D492C9ABC0276830B9A0F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a good, product, or service in the marketplace. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53C0398BF3BC4F099E6CA7BC5AFC6CB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>nonprofit organization</quote> means any organization that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09E1D6907F0348A3AABF2CFE58C3F7B3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public interest claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public interest claim</quote> means a claim—</text> <subparagraph id="HA71B1D860DDF490F9D16048B9F2A92AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is brought solely on behalf of the general public;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H404FC009A68F4174A65A78004EF5B92F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">where private enforcement is necessary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAFACAEBD5DCD40E58ECEB5F19D4A0FC6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that places a disproportionate financial burden on the plaintiff in relation to the plaintiff’s stake in the matter;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD67FAB53012946ADBCA86E047C811B6F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, if successful, enforces an important right affecting the public interest and confers a significant benefit on the general public; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60D7E6C84AF14301A56F78AE27186332" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding attorneys fees, costs, or penalties, would provide relief only for the general public or a class of which the plaintiff is a member.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8F7013B83094DA8BA7D3EE1115FE72D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian tribe.</text></paragraph> </section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1D016277A073446CBF3961821391D457"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and Conforming Amendments</header> <paragraph id="HC62966DCCC984DF7B86F8D26C7BEAE67" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Table of chapters</header><text>The table of chapters for part VI of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 181 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HCF82143FB6A64AC5BBC991EA61AF7647" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<multi-column-toc-entry level="chapter" bold="on"><toc-enum>182.</toc-enum><level-header level="chapter" bold="on">Special Motion to dismiss strategic lawsuits against public participation</level-header><target>4201</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DA8A44FA99747C9A54B414008932A95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interlocutory decisions</header><text>Section 1292(a) of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H758C1341A96F4123B2D38945946720F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting a period;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0C5EA7D846945329CDD36FCA81456B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6DBA7590B37457B809999127977551C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HE48ED9D7C9D44BDE88A73D417E224620" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H74143830B33F4A308754714249A7A932"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interlocutory orders granting or denying in whole or in part special motions to dismiss under section 4202. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84C70FE13F9D4A5DA62D1CB24FB2D72F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions to discharge</header><text>Section 523(a) of title 11, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9518003EE7444B79ACA2E6204ACE3323"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (18), by striking <quote>; or</quote> at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB282268D70734E48BDB2CCD07CACE576"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (19), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDA9693DEB8142DEB710CA4584E03EE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (19) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H45C821B41A63422DAA1B13A38207809A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H6EF6195112C843B99EB545D81CCE9AE6"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for litigation costs, expert witness fees, or reasonable attorney’s fees awarded by a court under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/182">chapter 182</external-xref> of title 28 or under comparable State laws.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA499458492164C579B6657A4729E1FB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to other laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall preempt or supersede any Federal or State statutory, constitutional, case, or common law that provides the equivalent or greater protection for persons engaging in activities protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H16777F380E5B4A54822CBCC9808F21B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed broadly to effectuate the purpose and intent of this Act. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


