<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H010DE86585EA496EAAB66B14AF9378B0" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2235 IH: National Mitigation Fisheries Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2235</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150505">May 5, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To ensure the continuation of successful fisheries mitigation programs, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6B430F5C1BA24458AE2D1C86F841731A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBD72BF9887CB461D8DB1CE1F8EE77788" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Mitigation Fisheries Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H175FD3082E544E1D96CFF887F01FC8C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H99E082BB47A44EB6B37E4FD7794A41BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The operation of dams and other water diversion projects are for the benefit of the American public. They provide inexpensive energy, flood control, water storage for municipal and agricultural purposes, and opportunities for recreational boating and enjoyment. The construction and operation of these Federal water resources development projects have had impacts on many water systems, habitats, and their respective fish populations, resulting in the need to build and operate fish hatcheries to mitigate for aquatic resources affected by these projects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6862D75CCE084B4B884FE1B28DAD220C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In accordance with the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/742a">16 U.S.C. 742a et seq.</external-xref>), the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/661">16 U.S.C. 661 et seq.</external-xref>), the Watershed Protection and Flood Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1001">16 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), the United States Fish and Wildlife Service has established policy (501 FW 2) to seek to mitigate for fish, wildlife, and their habitats, and uses thereof, from the effects of land and water developments.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDBFDA4C277AE498F97668BAA0A6DB01C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Service currently operates fish hatcheries that are involved in mitigation fishery activities related to construction and operation of Federal water resources development projects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAD5637FBC994422B1C292DBFFB35A04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Inconsistency in authorities to construct and operate Federal water resources development projects has led to a myriad of mechanisms for funding and conducting Federal mitigation fishery activities. In most cases, Federal water project development agencies fund mitigation fishery costs. In some cases, the Service expends its appropriations to offset or completely pay for mitigation fishery costs.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF74EC13E4AC24ECCBAF27B493E8FBA8F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The water development agency should bear the financial responsibility for mitigation fishery costs incurred by the Service.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD7F04A9E14AD459AB57DD3C3202567B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mitigation fishery activities</header> <subsection id="H0FC025C894A04DA889021F969230EBAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of charges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Service shall impose a charge for conducting mitigation fishery activities.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD94A9C39687B4637AC4B1489C59DF607"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fishery mitigation plans</header>
<paragraph id="H7D695A400168428E85F60EBFD7217802"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development</header><text>A charge imposed by the Service under subsection (a) shall be paid by a water development agency in accordance with a fishery mitigation plan developed and approved by the Director and the head of the agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C4AA5AB736A412C85751114C2661FDF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A fishery mitigation plan developed under this subsection shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF50C191C7CDE46388BB4496A06B33FE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the long-term goals and annual targets under which the Service will conduct mitigation fishery activities in connection with projects carried out by a water development agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0265C864B4F5434E9192B091DCD208DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish charges to be imposed by the Service on the agency for conducting the mitigation fishery activities; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2B29A53518B44A1789B8179363A8B30E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include the terms under which the agency will make payments on the charges to the Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE2EFF54EAED043E4A83A410C01FAF4D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participation of States and Indian tribes</header><text>A fishery mitigation plan under this section shall be developed in cooperation and coordination with affected States and Indian tribes.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H030AD5550A474F35BCEBE2E926005F88"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Renegotiation</header><text>The Director of the Service and the head of a water development agency shall renegotiate a fishery mitigation plan under this subsection every 3 years to adjust for changing mitigation fishery costs covered by the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF1E0D964EE5943DDA774C17A04816F1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of charges</header><text>Charges imposed by the Service for conducting mitigation fishery activities shall be reasonably related to the mitigation fishery costs associated with the activities.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF33FE595D4064EF39DE7CDB90E6B2AEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payment of charges</header>
<paragraph id="HEEBF292C13A74DBE93D9647479CD603A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On or before the first day of each fiscal year beginning after September 30, 2015, a water development agency shall make a payment to the Service for that fiscal year as required under a fishery mitigation plan developed by the Service and the agency under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H103F3F6E18D24B949ADBE46F178026DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Crediting of payments; availability of amounts</header><text>Funds paid to the Service under this subsection shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1B5B4EF42EA2437EA6A4015A67A2CE0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be credited to the appropriation of the Service initially charged for providing the service for which the payment is being made;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68429CB5F96C4C8293DB5AB02A703601"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be available to the Service for expenditure in amounts specified in appropriations Acts; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H432AB767E41E456BBE6C4D88E3D57050"><enum>(C)</enum><text>remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC3EC5DCF7074DD59BC7309134EDA988"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Projects without fishery mitigation plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the absence of a fishery mitigation plan, the Service may conduct mitigation fishery activities and receive funding from a water development agency for the activities based on the terms and conditions that applied with respect to the activities in the prior fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H833B9C6D13DD4B138B8834BB1F91D5E7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HDC6AD86AF0D7469BBB4379F08CA81F40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mitigation fishery activities</header><text>The term <quote>mitigation fishery activities</quote> means rearing and stocking of native and nonnative fish to replace or maintain fishery resources or harvest levels (or both) lost as a result of a Federal water resources development project, and includes project planning, population assessment and evaluation, genetic monitoring, broodstock development, and fish health sampling.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC9A59E0A36A84CBEA1022642AB38E748"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mitigation fishery costs</header><text>The term <quote>mitigation fishery costs</quote> means the expenditures necessary to operate, maintain, and rehabilitate mitigation fishery facilities and to conduct mitigation fishery activities, and includes personnel, transportation, utilities, contractual services, fish feed, supplies, equipment, routine maintenance, deferred maintenance, fish eggs, technical support, fish health, management and administration, planning, outreach and education, and hatchery product evaluations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45CB206AA56A4E27BC250725F216B81C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mitigation fishery facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>mitigation fishery facility</quote> means a facility described in subsection (g) that is owned and operated by the Service through the National Fish Hatchery System for the purpose, either wholly or substantially in part, of conducting mitigation fishery activities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFA4134C5C30C4566A16FDDBBB052AAB3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Service</header><text>The term <quote>Service</quote> means the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0237A169E3A46BBA09D68C84498B7FA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Water development agency</header><text>The term <quote>water development agency</quote> means the Army Corps of Engineers, the Bureau of Reclamation, or the Tennessee Valley Authority.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1FDA73E218740A18B54C940D117E944"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Listing of mitigation fishery facilities</header><text>The mitigation fishery facilities referred to in subsection (f) are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HA44ED31CC37F46F784CEADB715C5B2DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In Arkansas—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF78CE67AE9734E5D91FEE5DC641801A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Greers Ferry National Fish Hatchery; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H574EDA0D6F084BCF8FC1965DE59E9FAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Norfork National Fish Hatchery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2886D5207914A98A2798FC751E720C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In Georgia—</text> <subparagraph id="HB9A1AB4845B3453D9CC3C1DF5CF2510C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Chattahoochee Forest National Fish Hatchery; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBF06CADC3ECF400A9A7925D7E5207BFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Warm Springs Fish Health Center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2F12AC85271461D8D786F8DEAD6432A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In Kentucky, Wolf Creek National Fish Hatchery.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB7360191F94B4A809F85FFE28393311F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In Missouri, Neosho National Fish Hatchery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8456562A5EB434AAC1008F945EC3265"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In Montana—</text>
<subparagraph id="H66611746EDBC4B36BC8B619E948196D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Ennis National Fish Hatchery; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFC8992980354D45AE828AE750E043D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Bozeman Fish Health Center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H04D10768936C471894497773EF192BCD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In North Dakota—</text> <subparagraph id="H917E59D8FF844D5CAE9E2258DD35F964"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Garrison Dam National Fish Hatchery; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H331409092FF44F07955D26A4CAE98191"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Valley City National Fish Hatchery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B88B734B4C64DF59C12445790DBD984"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In Pennsylvania, Lamar Fish Health Center.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEE3DEE210EAF4ECE81E6F16F31F60743"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In South Dakota, Gavins Point National Fish Hatchery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76922ED10B5642D6801F5CFDBD6BDEB9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In Tennessee—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB52BD4E855734FCBB0788EE5D6A7CACE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Dale Hollow National Fish Hatchery; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H358BD4782930413FB736EAD4570B8FCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Erwin National Fish Hatchery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B8F7E76DFDC4E169BDDC132D6A442F4"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In Utah, Jones Hole National Fish Hatchery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C57287E7BB54B589C8A9D065485B375"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In West Virginia, White Sulphur Springs National Fish Hatchery.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED31D82A291B44EEBF3D4F7DC19E925B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In Wisconsin, LaCrosse Fish Health Center.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AE2A00D1A77407F973128F474E3D2B4"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In Wyoming, Saratoga National Fish Hatchery.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


