<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23C63FBFEFB840D9B23AD54C3F8BF235" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3954 IH: Camp Lejeune Reservist Parity Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3954</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for access to hospital care and medical services
			 furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs for certain members of the
			 reserve components who received training at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5032B0D0CB7B4DC3B0073771DAB2C748" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8F2A99B4914748859C27A1CFEA9B8BB2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Camp Lejeune Reservist Parity Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBA61C2442BC0417982D5D66627AE025C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Eligibility of certain members of reserve components who received training at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, for hospital care and medical services furnished by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1710(e)(1)(F) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H73F8D1CE44D246D6878895B1AAB540B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>active duty in the Armed Forces</quote> the following: <quote>or a member or former member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces who participated in training</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45061E75CA114F1EBAD6DF1A85C3C297"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>30 days</quote> and inserting <quote>a total of 30 cumulative days</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HF4BFF94E881C44D5927A840E291D720B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comptroller General study on access to hospital care and medical services under Honoring America’s Veterans and Caring for Camp Lejeune Families Act of 2012</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of the access to hospital care and medical services for veterans and family members stationed at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, as provided under section 1710(e)(1)(F) and section 1787 of title 38, United States Code. Such study shall include each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H420BD224786F49B28B088213EF61D507"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The five most common reasons why access to such care and services is denied by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF619C7A8E443456B9940C3F7D5CD8A01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total number and percentage of veterans who seek access to such care and services who are denied such access.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD54F84FC675446D387A5817F5E6E7B4F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The average number of days required for processing an application for such care and services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H965EC1309B50417AA1D0E395383FF25C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The percentage of such applications that are processed accurately by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EFF5F5707BC4A789463F1E7762F8040"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The total number and percentage of veterans who submit such an application who appeal the decision of the Department regarding the application.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E4059AEAE7E43FEBE2BF3503B0A7596"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The average number of days between the date of the submittal of such an application and the date on which a decision is made regarding the application.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


