<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA8BF75726284597AA9317F3329F35F8" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2474 IH: Wall Street Accountability through Sustainable Funding Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2474</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to impose fees and assessments to recover the cost of appropriations to the Commission.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5574C35459554A39900DE31FD11291E3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H34FE9DC3635D4DDABB02E0545066C56E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wall Street Accountability through Sustainable Funding Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H32BA05D2782C4E3B939EC4F8A461D00C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement that the Commodity Futures Trading Commission impose fees and assessments to recover the cost of appropriations to the Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12 of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/16">7 U.S.C. 16</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H561BA87582824D668881724EE1D4C0EF" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H7D198E694CF54AA0AFC10B248268AD99"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Recovery of costs of annual appropriations</header> 
<paragraph id="H294E8722617E48A08053D3689FC09EE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Imposition of fees</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD6971ECEDEBC447DA3B3A740F71AA368"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the Commission shall, by order, impose a fee on each agreement, contract, or transaction that is a contract of sale of a commodity for future delivery, an option, or a swap, including an agreement, contract, or transaction transacted through the use of a foreign terminal, so that the total of the fees so imposed during each fiscal year is sufficient to recover the costs to the Government of the annual appropriation to the Commission by Congress for the fiscal year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68D1ED44EC72438DA3C9978DB3BFB0E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Foreign terminal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subparagraph (A), the term <term>foreign terminal</term> means a technology, software, or device, which is located in the United States and used to execute an agreement, contract, or transaction on a foreign board of trade, or which is located outside of the United States and used to execute an agreement, contract, or transaction within the United States on a domestic board of trade.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H425788029432481B8E36422B5968767F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission, by rule, may exempt any such agreement, contract, or transaction from any fee imposed under this paragraph, if the Commission finds that the exemption is consistent with—</text> <clause id="HC49D26186CA84EE8A20314962BA6EB4D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the public interest;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDFF3CC1BCC0A4BECADCF79112727816F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the equal treatment of contract markets, derivatives clearing organizations, and market participants; and</text></clause> <clause id="H71DD7AF7D0D142D79359398C127971D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the operation of a nationwide market system.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD073A473FD8A4BA3932550986B4D68FE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fees imposed under this paragraph on all transactions of the same kind shall be determined in a uniform manner.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85345EEF33494916A3EB7819566DC523"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Mid-year adjustment</header> <clause id="H61AB2DD726F448E99FE53B4F385354EE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By March 1 of each fiscal year, the Commission shall determine whether, based on the fees collected under this subsection during the first 5 months of the fiscal year, the total of the amounts collected and to be collected under this subsection for the fiscal year is reasonably likely to be 10 percent (or more) greater or less than the costs described in subparagraph (A) for the fiscal year. If the Commission so determines, the Commission shall by order, no later than March 1 of the fiscal year, adjust the fee rates otherwise applicable under this paragraph for the fiscal year so that the total of the amounts so collected and to be collected is reasonably likely to equal to the costs so described.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H549FD7258A924605B64650C2930A3597"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2)(C) and (4), an adjusted rate prescribed under clause (i) of this subparagraph in a fiscal year shall take effect on the later of—</text> <subclause id="H5EE6E86B419A43B0BE05BA82B9B6FF53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the 1st day of the fiscal year to which the rate applies; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC86B2E878A364ECB9976CC237B9B1BFE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>60 days after the date on which a regular appropriation to the Commission for the fiscal year is enacted.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H015B7C9A19A34CB7916BDF82F67E0D5C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall publish in the Federal Register notices of the fee rates applicable under this paragraph for a fiscal year not later than 30 days after the date on which a regular appropriation to the Commission for the fiscal year is enacted, together with any estimates or projections on which the fee rates are based.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE180C52DCF8B4375AA8080B03EC21A2E"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Inapplicability of rulemaking requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In exercising its authority under this paragraph, the Commission shall not be required to comply with section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC91C2D65518B4C79B9E2D2391D03CD2E"><enum>(H)</enum><header>No judicial review</header><text>A fee rate prescribed under this paragraph and published in accordance with subparagraph (F) shall not be subject to judicial review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72ED03C2DD4D433D98F396038D43A4EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment and collection of fees</header> 
<subparagraph id="H337A194E3D744E5599949D74EB976200"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Cleared transactions; uncleared swaps reported to swap data repositories</header> 
<clause id="H0B53D6B184B84245A6D5F39AE27F31D5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Payment of fees</header> 
<subclause id="H6EF00BACF8CF47A184AC8366923D2D70"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Cleared transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a contract of sale of a commodity for future delivery, an option, or a swap that is cleared by a derivatives clearing organization registered or exempt from registration under this Act, each party to the agreement, contract, or transaction shall pay the fee determined under paragraph (1) to the derivatives clearing organization.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB741E64B97C243688FAB3CDB86FFC61D"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Uncleared swaps reported to swap data repositories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a swap that is not cleared by a derivatives clearing organization registered or exempt from registration under this Act and that is accepted by a swap data repository registered under section 21, each party to the swap shall pay the transaction fee determined under paragraph (1) to the swap data repository.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H7B1A1CDB8B144D19A4E65FD40C4FB5AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Collection of fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall collect the fees paid in accordance with clause (i) in such manner and within such time as the Commission deems appropriate, except that if the Commission has not collected a fee paid in accordance with clause (i) within 30 days after receipt by the derivatives clearing organization or swap data repository, as the case may be, the organization or repository, as the case may be, shall transmit the fee to the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H186CA9287D764E38A3D9E5101E6ED2BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Uncleared swaps reported to commission</header><text>In the case of a swap that is not cleared by a derivatives clearing organization registered or exempt from registration under this Act and that is reported to the Commission pursuant to section 4r, each party to the swap shall pay the fee determined under paragraph (1) to the Commission in a manner and within such time as the Commission deems appropriate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4BB68D3CDA3942E1B6CE8A769C0943BE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Subject to appropriations</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (4), a fee shall not be collected under this subsection for a fiscal year, except to the extent provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBED9A4B6F55C4BD1A798A6A271920587"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deposit of fees</header> <subparagraph id="H3FF83E132AA143B1A27882CEBE6FA292"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Offsetting collections</header><text>A fee collected under paragraph (2) for a fiscal year shall be deposited and credited as offsetting collections to the account providing appropriations to the Commission.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17F5FBF765DC4878B321AF3263241086"><enum>(B)</enum><header>General revenues prohibited</header><text>A fee collected under paragraph (2) for a fiscal year shall not be deposited and credited as general revenue of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6A6760CBCA34727A7003A0D1D477885"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Lapse of appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If on the first day of a fiscal year a regular appropriation to the Commission has not been enacted, the Commission shall continue to collect (as offsetting collections) the fees imposed under paragraph (1) at the rate in effect during the preceding fiscal year, until 60 days after the date such a regular appropriation is enacted.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F722877F5604D5CA8E1D4FA4DFF7B7B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Commodity Futures Trading Commission reserve fund</header> 
<paragraph id="H53D105DBAE644B42B1DFFDC80007E644"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a separate fund, to be known as the <quote>Commodity Futures Trading Commission Reserve Fund</quote> (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Reserve Fund</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB99614B2718D4602AED7E23DFAA45454"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Imposition of fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall impose and collect an additional fee, as provided in subsection (i), except that the total amount of the fees imposed and collected in each fiscal year shall not exceed an amount equal to the amount (if any) by which $50,000,000 exceeds the balance in the Reserve Fund as of the end of the preceding fiscal year, and paragraphs (2)(C) and (4) of subsection (i) shall not apply with respect to this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8362990193CA40D08847DEF8131054D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deposits into reserve fund</header> 
<subparagraph id="H011665DAEAFE42948D1DF3B968698C14"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this paragraph, all fees collected under this paragraph shall be deposited into the Reserve Fund.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H635683716323456285FC7015C42C1754"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The balance in the Reserve Fund shall not exceed $50,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42AE4EE6E1AA4A10A2AB2258638F2117"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The Commission may obligate amounts in the Reserve Fund, not to exceed a total of $50,000,000 in any 1 fiscal year, as the Commission determines is necessary to make long-term investments in information technology for use by the Commission and to cover unexpected expenses of the Commission (as determined by the Commission). Not later than 10 days after the date on which the Commission obligates amounts under this paragraph, the Commission shall notify the Congress of the date, amount, and purpose of the obligation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE773D022BAE6493CAC8271E4387A61AC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Reserve Fund shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF63F12DD55A417188D31FA6D742F606"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Amounts in the Reserve Fund shall not be construed to be Government funds or appropriated monies and shall not be subject to apportionment for the purpose of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/15">chapter 15</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, or under any other authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

