<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3B028E824E41479280AA94421A09CC63" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3202 IH: LEAP Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3202</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001102">Mr. Clawson of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001045">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend section 42 of title 18, United States Code, popularly known as the Lacey Act, to add
			 certain species of lionfish to the list of injurious species that are
			 prohibited from being imported or shipped.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA60BE833931148BCAC5A0B26F282714C" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CD0BF27B38C4201AEA233C8220813A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lionfish Elimination and Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or as the <quote>LEAP Act of 2015</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H78E52495732547A4BC9161E81AD05FE9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Addition of species of lionfish to the list of injurious species that are prohibited from being imported or shipped</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 42(a)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <quote>Dreissena polymorpha;</quote> the following: <quote>of the red lionfish of the species Pterois volitans; of the devil lionfish of the species Pterois miles; of the Hawaiian turkeyfish of the species Pterois sphex; of the soldier lionfish of the species Pterois russelii; of the clearfin lionfish of the species Pterois radiata; of the species Pterois paucispinula; of the frillfin turkeyfish of the species Pterois mombasae; of the luna lionfish of the species Pterois lunalata; of the mandritsa of the species Pterois brevipectoralis; of the spotfin lionfish of the species Pterois antennata; of the scorpionfish of the species Pterois andover;</quote>.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


