<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9ED209E52076402EA37B794C7289B28F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3825 IH: Intelligent Technologies Initiative Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3825</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151023">October 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve transportation safety, efficiency, and system performance through innovative technology
			 deployment and operations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H722724ECE799403ABD5FDADAD1D6215F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8BA3E3A38039457F85453587F03758EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Intelligent Technologies Initiative Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0855E022DEB04D7B9B226EEE84ECAB0C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBEB1DE17225A4A83B446526035B3F539"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a State or local government, including a territory of the United States, tribal government, transit agency, port authority, metropolitan planning organization, or other political subdivision of a State or local government or a multi-State or multi-jurisdictional group applying through a single lead applicant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8ACAF84515FD47CEAC11AD835ED9C7AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ITS</header><text>The term <quote>ITS</quote> means intelligent transportation systems.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H12D1077A97DD4B8BB02906EA038B2626"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multi-jurisdictional group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>multi-jurisdictional group</quote> means a combination of State governments, locals governments, metropolitan planning agencies, transit agencies, or other political subdivisions of a State that have signed a written agreement to implement the Intelligent Technology Initiative across jurisdictional boundaries. Each member of the group, including the lead applicant, must be an eligible entity to receive a grant under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3874623E3ABD4ADF93715485AEA6B7CF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text> </paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EBC137783074E2EB5FBF90D0FC2B06C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Intelligent technology initiative</header> <subsection id="H0584F49B990747778BDBB3AF0E6EB3EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish an Intelligent Technology Initiative to provide grants to eligible entities to establish deployment sites for large scale installation and operation of ITS to improve safety, efficiency, system performance, and return on investment. The Secretary shall develop criteria for selection of an eligible entity to receive a grant, including how the deployment of technology will enable the recipient—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF1A0C113F09C4D99A1B373BF33DB8FD0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to reduce costs and improve return on investments, including through the enhanced utilization of existing transportation capacity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66C234A31AB048EEA7BC62DB1693A8A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to deliver environmental benefits and reduce energy consumption by alleviating congestion and streamlining traffic flow;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EA879D1E6604D729D581165B9C081BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to measure and improve the operational performance of its transportation network;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6418D61DAFF4060B0DE0E988A45B755"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce the number and severity of traffic collisions and increase driver, passenger, and pedestrian safety;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1DE42339A164A07B0013244BB73B33A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collect, disseminate, and utilize real-time traffic, transit, parking, and other transportation-related information to improve mobility, reduce congestion, and provide for more efficient and accessible transportation alternatives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A5303E4B95B46979DAA3781F8816133"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to monitor transportation assets to improve infrastructure management, reduce maintenance costs, prioritize investment decisions, and ensure a state of good repair; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE940018A465944BBB1597B73394506C7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to deliver economic benefits by reducing delays, improving system performance, and providing for the efficient and reliable movement of goods and services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H844B2E8CAF3E444D949F4F276D54DCBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Request for applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall request applications in accordance with section 4 for participation in the Intelligent Technology Initiative.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H87F21C3D5DEE4969B103C28F356338A0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant program</header>
 <subsection id="H5561216A73C749A9AA024427227C054A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be considered for a grant under this Act, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary that includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8539D90255F647C2A9A3E135F8082097"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deployment plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to deploy and provide for the long-term operation and maintenance of intelligent transportation systems to improve safety, efficiency, system performance, and return on investment, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8EC475E044484E58B5814E88D326093C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>real-time integrated traffic, transit, and multimodal transportation information;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DAFB17785694A70BF57F4DA98F2A005"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advanced traffic, freight, parking, and incident management systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6F3A0F7333E45D1963811164EF26C26"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collision avoidance systems;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39F985E4E7CC451DA3B594267FD306C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>advanced technologies to improve transit and commercial vehicle operations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55DEB941675443B0BCC19F08C5EAC95A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>synchronized, adaptive, and transit preferential traffic signals;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58E0B5DF98E145F6B48B9BB7C9CE0F2A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>advanced infrastructure condition assessment technologies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1919BC950704AF8BEA9F32C817E23FD"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other technologies to improve system operations, including ITS applications necessary for multimodal systems integration and for achieving performance goals.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF972A6505FE1493487E9D0F6EA04C183"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Quantifiable system performance improvements, including reducing traffic-related crashes, congestion, and costs, optimizing system efficiency, and improving access to transportation services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3029731F6C7643438D02A1E832842699"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Results</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Quantifiable safety, mobility, and environmental benefit projections including data driven estimates of how the project will improve the region’s transportation system efficiency and reduce traffic congestion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81620D11041E441FBC0B83E921551B6A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for partnering with the private sector, public agencies including multimodal and multi-jurisdictional entities, research institutions, organizations representing transportation and technology leaders, and other transportation stakeholders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE117692AFF04AFC9A1879A029A82F03"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Leveraging</header><text>A plan to leverage and optimize existing local and regional ITS investments.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H70C3B693393D45398583E42AECCC5940"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Interoperability</header><text>A plan to ensure interoperability of deployed technologies with other tolling, traffic management, and intelligent transportation systems.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75515703DDA447E08BA1FE2E51A187E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant selection</header>
 <paragraph id="H717E76696FE9449AB5410847DF7AD466"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant awards</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall award a grant to not more than 6 eligible entities with funds available for up to 5 fiscal years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H836A7D16207D44FAA3BA7CC22CCB3665"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geographic diversity</header><text>In awarding a grant under this section, the Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that grant recipients represent diverse geographic areas of the United States, including urban, suburban, and rural areas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5F71A12C2BF149FBB6F892A03EF9A087"><enum>5.</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A grant recipient may use funds authorized in this Act to deploy, operate, and maintain ITS and ITS-enabled operational strategies, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD540C84F16494392B3A4F6AAE0048551"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advanced traveler information systems;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE3E71F295D9490D85C753174CD97A35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advanced transportation management technologies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55A8139C08944D8192461DD3F8F62DCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>infrastructure maintenance, monitoring, and condition assessment;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H35D7A6BFF3EE4359BC4CC4982C288496"><enum>(4)</enum><text>advanced public transportation systems;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03092FA70EC64385AF4B3FFAEB346A76"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transportation system performance data collection, analysis, and dissemination systems;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0671C15AAB83408784ED9DF0F07DAC95"><enum>(6)</enum><text>advanced safety systems, including vehicle-to-vehicle and vehicle-to-infrastructure communications and other collision avoidance technologies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADE6BBC08307416DA519101D2671F731"><enum>(7)</enum><text>integration of intelligent transportation systems with the Smart Grid and other energy distribution and charging systems;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD347BB88EBED4FC1AC685AC0B0B8A867"><enum>(8)</enum><text>electronic pricing and tolling systems; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD588967A5B23455BB0E64A1F6FB02356"><enum>(9)</enum><text>advanced mobility and access technologies, such as dynamic ridesharing and information systems to support human services for elderly and disabled Americans.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H1703F99A63EB4BB8A9A3A57ABA935233"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subsection id="H643DF1210D0241CC93062A08A2C35FD6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after an eligible entity receives a grant award under this Act and each year thereafter, each grant recipient shall submit a report to the Secretary that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3E34044155A147C7A96E9DC3FCB832A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deployment and operational cost compared to the benefits and savings from the pilot program and compared to other alternative approaches; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDB62E0A00DE43D08D8D90FD24304CF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how the project has met the original expectation as projected in the deployment plan submitted with the application, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC99B0D55300471F82275270EA1C582D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data on how the program has helped reduce traffic crashes, congestion, costs, and other benefits of the deployed systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D261B2578E4452DAB91D1DA1CC4EA5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>data on the effect of measuring and improving transportation system performance through the deployment of advanced technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6A8271E8D994487B51DD7156CFB45D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of providing real-time integrated traffic, transit, and multimodal transportation information to the public to make informed travel decisions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6427F58101948A495F629FB811D3B21"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lessons learned and recommendations for future deployment strategies to optimize transportation efficiency and multimodal system performance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC001FCBA52645F9846B7468756AD3E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after grants have been allocated and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that describes the effectiveness of grant recipients in meeting their projected deployment plan, including data on how the program has—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0783318B844C44A6B154F724F7504F90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduced traffic-related fatalities and injuries;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE2D7F40DDBB4BCF8CDB5FA9B5A773AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduced traffic congestion and improved travel time reliability;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43FC3063A5FA455780BC2F977A0AD540"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reduced transportation-related emissions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7540F39D61094DEBAE66D6D9F40ECCB3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>optimized multimodal system performance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1313016E8504E9DAABBA2A40D079373"><enum>(5)</enum><text>improved access to transportation alternatives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H254DDFC9065E4F74AB68A615EEA99C48"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provided the public with access to real-time integrated traffic, transit, and multimodal transportation information to make informed travel decisions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C148F4B49054A7EA098CE8A2F211C81"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provided cost savings to transportation agencies, businesses, and the traveling public; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0612EE39BC640C3A19D80A30E04AC63"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provided other benefits to transportation users and the general public.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F9E55685AE1411DB2A8A6CD6EA9A203"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional grants</header><text>If the Secretary determines from a grant recipient’s reports that the recipient is not carrying out the requirements of the grant, the Secretary may cease to provide any additional grant funds to the recipient. The Secretary shall have the authority to redistribute remaining funds to select additional eligible entities for a program under this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9588A7BED140441F89D961959D70600C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
			<subsection id="H889BAA6544F04980B372CFBC7AF42662"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="H09CB701C0F90473B9C091515C37424D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated out of the Highway Trust Fund to carry out this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="HA33270F2E5FB43CEA32DE3125C6DC106"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2015;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED0BCCF1F7B94898BE67522C2678ED9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2016;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B7FFDE673454A808CED45C5A7549EA0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2017;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD86E33057BB9429AACB89482A8B862B5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6997028B92B480DA2D69EFBC5B43E72"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2019; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H696C3A6C55B54D7BA02B58F9CEA26D39"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2020.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29BF264E8585422CA04DCA49B5C8EE39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contract authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds authorized under this subsection shall be available for obligation in the same manner as if the funds were apportioned under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, except that such funds shall not be transferable, the obligation limitations shall not apply to such funds, and shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C0FAD26291D4266A24DA78946A141B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant limitation</header><text>The Secretary may not award more than 25 percent of the amount appropriated under this Act to a single grant recipient.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4A90C0ADBC044A35A0877CCFB3DCB840"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenses for grant recipients</header><text>A grant recipient under this Act may use not more than 5 percent of the grant award each fiscal year to carry out planning and reporting requirements.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H630099FEABBE431A95519F513A2F47EF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expenses for Secretary</header><text>Before awarding grant funds under this Act, the Secretary may set aside $3,000,000 each fiscal year for program reporting, evaluation, and administrative costs.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


