<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H738F299F5F6A440B856C228EF578B96C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 318 IH: Stop the Revolving Door in Washington Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 318</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to extend the post-employment restrictions on lobbying by
			 Members of Congress and officers and employees of the legislative branch.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF9A0C9C7560C4BE9943D796A12DAC121" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC02B3241BC874FD69F7558BC2BC35843" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop the Revolving Door in Washington Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H48F078AC50A14D7F9407890EE1E6CFCA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of post-employment restrictions</header> <subsection id="HB24753C2B7444015820A5DCE78BF06BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of restrictions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 207(e) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H71C1336F74A5485FA551D70AD1E41182"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5332B687DB64D2F80F07F03438F8DCA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA4D99BE31C6346A689606F035F01EEBE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Members of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is a Senator or a Member of the House of Representatives and who, within 5 years after that person leaves office, knowingly makes, with the intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before any Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress or any employee of any other legislative office of the Congress, on behalf of any other person (except the United States) in connection with any matter on which such former Senator or Member seeks action by a Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress, in his or her official capacity, shall be punished as provided in section 216 of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72D7B4A098BA4B7CB47644532B72B526"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9C4F366FE6C4A90B042A66DCAC41D67" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB9DF6BFA0B6F49FEAFB87BB0B3ED2148"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Officers of the Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is an elected officer of the Senate or of the House of Representatives and who, within 2 years after that person leaves office, knowingly makes, with the intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before any Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress or any employee of any other legislative office of the Congress, on behalf of any other person (except the United States) in connection with any matter on which such former elected officer seeks action by a Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress, in his or her official capacity, shall be punished as provided in section 216 of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CC029687053414D83C653483263B731"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employees of the Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is an employee of the Senate, or an employee of the House of Representatives, to whom paragraph (5)(A) applies and who, within 2 years after the termination of that employment, knowingly makes, with the intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before any Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress or any employee of any other legislative office of the Congress, on behalf of any other person (except the United States) in connection with any matter on which such former employee seeks action by a Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress, in his or her official capacity, shall be punished as provided in section 216 of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2036F49234A456EA536DAB95B9C923C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employees of other legislative offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is an employee of any other legislative office of the Congress to whom paragraph (5)(B) applies and who, within 2 years after the termination of that employment, knowingly makes, with the intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before any Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress or any employee of any other legislative office of the Congress, on behalf of any other person (except the United States) in connection with any matter on which such former employee seeks action by a Member, officer, or employee of either House of Congress, in his or her official capacity, shall be punished as provided in section 216 of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65AB0A2F67264C3E8FD2406E3F709048"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (7), (8), and (9), as paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H06A4F39BD003442592F801B62B6B74D7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), as redesignated—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD753E0EB4E5E4CFB8FCF657A8C3197DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (3)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DD5370DDEF14A6EAE1CB63AC58DB6CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (4)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2A787ABA182443996D7E2E5BF6B655A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(G), as redesignated, by striking <quote>(3), (4), or (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>or (3)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA006B0D7E585400FA702A71935A63A39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 103(a) of the Honest Leadership and Open Government Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4702">2 U.S.C. 4702(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (2), (3), (4), or (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (3)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50A845A7DEEA4C08834E999F1F4DA26D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by section 2 shall apply to individuals who leave office or employment to which such amendments apply on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


