<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1860E5018DF04DD291B984F497BF00DA" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 821 IH: Wi-Fi Innovation Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 821</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To promote unlicensed spectrum use in the 5 GHz band, to maximize the use of the band for shared
			 purposes in order to bolster innovation and economic development, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H859273B8D2BF43338A7640EFC0B22ACF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H419B91EA9A0240B1862A2C60DC7DCBD4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wi-Fi Innovation Act </short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF5AB90675FB1455B9922BB1B6DEEF40A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Promoting unlicensed spectrum</header> <subsection id="HA2DE240BC51541E4BB27EC5F4FCD4931"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H881FD79694854433983EB3C7A0DF0228"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H10803E4539B447F891D8653811D9F488"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dedicated Short-Range Communications Services</header><text>The term <term>Dedicated Short-Range Communications Services</term> has the meaning given the term in section 90.7 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDF8429E02CF45FC992F7A6D0AE93BB3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Dynamic Frequency Selection</header><text>The term <term>Dynamic Frequency Selection</term> has the meaning given the term in section 15.403 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FBC0502A98B41F5A42A4CEEE0279365"><enum>(4)</enum><header><enum-in-header>5850–5925</enum-in-header> MHz band</header><text>The term <term>5850–5925 MHz band</term> has the meaning given the term in section 6406(c) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1453">47 U.S.C. 1453(c)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB3C64CA50E5473EA6D067AD9BA0E219"><enum>(5)</enum><header>NTIA</header><text>The term <term>NTIA</term> means the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAC94C6E010F4DDE984B2BEEFC3B2895"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Technical rules suitable for the widespread commercial development of unlicensed operations</header><text>The term <term>technical rules suitable for the widespread commercial development of unlicensed operations</term> means technical rules that, to the maximum extent feasible—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H47C1C8477531432E9B7679B96ECF15E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>permit outdoor unlicensed operations;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55E8813B9DA24C34BDCD1411A03C1F2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>permit unlicensed operations at a maximum conducted transmitter output power limit of not less than 1 watt; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E6177844B9B4B89A623D748539C50EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>do not require unlicensed devices to employ Dynamic Frequency Selection.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEEFE095AF5074F2F84550D2591663011"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of Regulations To Promote Unlicensed Use in the 5 GHz Band</header> <paragraph id="HCED133A6A8054CF5BEDCEAEC699744B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H06B7950F86E0492AA9FC69625D9A88EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Provision of additional unlicensed spectrum</header><text>The Commission shall modify title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide additional unlicensed spectrum in the 5850–5925 MHz band under technical rules suitable for the widespread commercial development of unlicensed operations in the band, as specified under paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0231647E52C463AA5A8EEC863A28738"><enum>(B)</enum><header>NTIA cooperation</header><text>The NTIA shall facilitate the modification described in subparagraph (A) by cooperating with the Commission to identify the spectrum management actions necessary to accommodate the regulatory changes specified under paragraph (2).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6AF2A5B12934F81934C8D22366D6238"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required actions and modifications</header>
					<subparagraph id="HED8A774BB2C04DB7A5F56C3A31E6DCE0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <clause id="HFBD0CC99888B47E49559C40B5F1308DC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Office of Engineering and Technology public notice</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Office of Engineering and Technology of the Commission shall issue a public notice seeking comment on proposals for—</text>
 <subclause id="HD6783C9D26A14C6EA950C2623EF4E187"><enum>(I)</enum><text>interference-mitigation techniques and technologies, and potential rechannelization, that would accommodate both incumbent licensees, including Dedicated Short Range Communications Services licensees, and widespread commercial unlicensed operations in the 5850–5925 MHz band; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H21145F5153AC42F1A7E7B92E1FBA055E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>deployment timelines for the technologies described in subclause (I).</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HE556E3672FAE4346AAC2F0798CBB964D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>NTIA response</header><text>The NTIA, in response to the public notice issued under clause (i), shall publicly submit to the Office of Engineering and Technology a description of any current and anticipated further Federal uses of the 5850–5925 MHz band.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A3297B2F3B547D3B5B2C6034913EC72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Test plan</header>
 <clause id="H71D458254B7A483BA52B29C95192A4BE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall, in consultation with the Department of Transportation and the NTIA, develop and publish a test plan, including a timeline, for the use of unlicensed devices in the 5850–5925 MHz band.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H700902D9C4DF4C7294BFCE8D74C82121"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The test plan developed and published under clause (i) shall be designed to allow the Commission to evaluate technologies for allowing unlicensed devices to utilize the 5850–5925 MHz band without causing harmful interference to incumbent licensees, including Dedicated Short Range Communications Services licensees.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCE6EE2010C244738B61CA03EF37E1DF7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Testing multiple methods</header><text>The Commission may choose to test multiple methods of sharing the 5850–5925 MHz band.</text> </clause><clause id="HB7E3757C060A4E6B803BBE78C71168C5"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing the test plan under clause (i), the Commission shall consider—</text>
 <subclause id="H818A4D0DC03D4F788D2AE76E68F89A0C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the comments filed in response to the public notice issued under subparagraph (A)(i);</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2B3C5CAEC8AA4FC6AB37F54ABB83FB8F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the comments filed in response to ET Docket No. 13–49;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H20706F9B18204A09A8C681599AF7850F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the functions currently authorized under exclusive allocation that could be performed by unlicensed or shared spectrum;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8D8900274C704D968AD54F5C93148DF6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>whether a system of priority access could substitute for exclusive licensing and, if so, whether the system of priority access should be confined to—</text>
 <item id="H793BC3BD7ABE4AFD8B7FCE57F8DA76FB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>particular portions of the 5850–5925 MHz band; and</text> </item><item id="H530C5BE90D4D4FF1880F19CDA278FE33"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>functions critical for dedicated short-range communications crash avoidance;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HE53DC27A31394A348E35F97F770E824B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>whether non-exclusive licensing or other forms of shared spectrum access could substitute for exclusive licensing;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC2A3F516E6EE4F3BA39C2A5403F17819"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>whether the Commission could promulgate rules to migrate existing licensees to an alternative band;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H949745888A85477A83F44601A4A7426C"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>whether, to protect critical public safety communications, the Commission could allow sharing in only a portion of the 5850–5925 MHz spectrum; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H113EDD9AAAA74504ADB657AA67CD4428"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>whether shared use or a system of priority access—</text> <item id="HE67CEB86E00D46038B4319A2390991C0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>causes harmful interference to incumbent licensees; or</text>
 </item><item id="H2B8454E6867A4CE9B59853CB788D6217"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>compromises safety-of-life uses by incumbent licensees that are necessary for advancing motor vehicle safety.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37D42CD00423446DBC06114A33DD4340"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Testing; results</header><text>Not later than 15 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, in consultation with the Department of Transportation and the NTIA, shall—</text>
 <clause id="H039F648F6E274A9C8C006324FF3AE0AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct testing in accordance with the test plan developed under subparagraph (B);</text> </clause><clause id="HA1275CD02D1243C3891AAEDADEFB4343"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publish a summary of the results of the testing to the docket relating to the 5850–5925 MHz band; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H507EDB3F92C64AE6BEC86E05939C7571"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reference the results of the testing and the comments filed under subparagraph (A) in determining unlicensed device use of the 5850–5925 MHz band.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H312C1435E9824925AE4A3B4B3DD97DE4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <clause id="H375FD5D1530E42EC92686C387A8DCE4D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <subclause id="H2830B24D69974847AE6E1946BE8E922E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the Commission determines that a mitigation technology, rechannelization, or other approach would allow unlicensed operations in the 5850–5925 MHz band that will not cause harmful interference to existing licensees of that band, the Commission shall modify part 15 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, to adopt technical rules suitable for the widespread commercial deployment of unlicensed operations for the 5850–5925 MHz band; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA427AF44EE724E868F6E476DC9252741"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the Commission determines that no mitigation technology, rechannelization, or other sharing approach would prevent unlicensed operations in the 5850–5925 MHz band from causing harmful interference to existing licensees of that band, the Commission—</text>
 <item id="H90FB63F5E37E480BA264A20C3731E146"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>shall provide notification of the determination to—</text> <subitem id="HB97CC62ED19F41BBA063E4BA30B5D2BD"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>Congress;</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HE60CD8C911F342E9BEC6993E5FD12F53"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation; and</text> </subitem><subitem id="HB82CB114714F48E7B1ECEC102977EC7A"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the NTIA; and</text>
 </subitem></item><item id="H92AB73D77C0D424F8FD37E43345F7D49"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>may not modify part 15 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, to adopt technical rules suitable for the widespread commercial deployment of unlicensed operations for the 5850–5925 MHz band until the Commission can ensure that such operations will not cause harmful interference to existing licensees of that band.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HA72265B8B4AE4B69917922A9F6990EC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Intelligent transportation systems</header><text>The Commission shall modify subpart M of part 90 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to the Intelligent Transportation Systems radio service), and subpart L of part 95 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to dedicated short-range communications service on-board units), if the Commission determines that such a modification would maximize the utility of the 5850–5925 MHz band while protecting existing licensees from harmful interference.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1F513E99C0E0469EBE2D8451765DDE6A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assessing unlicensed spectrum and wi-fi use in low-income neighborhoods</header>
			<subsection id="H188BB41C0F014C1B807658F96FD8DEDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header>
 <paragraph id="HA0604D9A3179488D8BD8473919936E6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Communications Commission (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall conduct a study to evaluate the availability of broadband Internet access using unlicensed spectrum and wireless networks in low-income neighborhoods.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF3636381E04C6D875FD58995096D22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting the study under paragraph (1), the Commission shall consider and evaluate—</text> <subparagraph id="HD8BB97CB3F844AD699FD573E31B5FD1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any barriers preventing or limiting the deployment and use of wireless networks in low-income neighborhoods;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7F4076808B4491996CC935390A88786"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how to overcome the barriers described in subparagraph (A) through incentives, policies, or requirements that would increase the availability of unlicensed spectrum and related technologies in low-income neighborhoods to increase broadband adoption by elementary and secondary school-age children in schools and at home in these communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H785EB022C8BC4BF68A41FA6514A4A879"><enum>(C)</enum><text>proposals that would encourage the home broadband adoption by not less than 50 percent of households with elementary and secondary school-age children that are in low-income neighborhoods; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA869AAFFD3604A4CA25104BC8982744F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the availability of wireless Internet hot spots and access to unlicensed spectrum for children described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74AD28C6A6384119BE53718CB229E7AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H656C3A085D224788986173DCFF75CD12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H71585F4177BF4FBA81013904F48275A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>makes recommendations with respect to the potential incentives, policies, and requirements described in subsection (a)(2)(B).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


