<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H31234A10355F4036B98210E2BAEF7BDB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 786 IH: Vaccine Access, Certainty, and Innovation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 786</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150205">February 5, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To improve access, certainty, and innovation with respect to vaccines.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H1B6353337D4E48B896FC64C146A2C8A1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE3E5F0011DBA4413B1B5DC2CEA732219" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vaccine Access, Certainty, and Innovation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H12E992F3B1E04B569CC880D2D096795B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HE3E5F0011DBA4413B1B5DC2CEA732219" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H12E992F3B1E04B569CC880D2D096795B" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC613B178E86C498D9AA079D6795327F6" level="title">Title I—Development, Licensure, and Recommendations</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H14336FED14524E3D89BD302FEDED4EEB" level="section">Sec. 101. Review of transparency and consistency of ACIP recommendation process.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE9DC5A173DAD404782BD9E3A2D26630E" level="section">Sec. 102. Guidance on vaccine development.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC9EF978891DA49A88C420914EBA5A9B5" level="section">Sec. 103. Meetings between CDC and vaccine developers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB6C8654DC8624182B1EBA075F0E510A2" level="section">Sec. 104. Modifications to priority review voucher program for tropical diseases.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HBFA6AA13F1EA4DCBA61A2DD14A2A7605" level="section">Sec. 105. Guidance on changes to an approved application for biological products.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H260C358DD47A41DD9A144016D9B3EA0A" level="section">Sec. 106. Expediting the process for export certifications for vaccines.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H954946A7971D4DFFA7C9EE0568108A41" level="section">Sec. 107. NIH vaccine research.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC329DC8410DB4B5D91A453B89FDFA86F" level="title">Title II—Medicare, Medicaid, and other provisions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8C47DCB12244451FAEAE235719219BC5" level="section">Sec. 201. Requiring prompt updates to Medicare program upon issuance of ACIP recommendations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H951AF95E0F3D484E86B2A77AF9C185C6" level="section">Sec. 202. GAO study and report on Medicare and Medicaid beneficiary access for vaccines.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H38AB9F5B37054E8887540F7B5A220437" level="section">Sec. 203. Encouraging health plans to establish programs to increase adult immunization.</toc-entry> </toc> </section> 
<title id="HC613B178E86C498D9AA079D6795327F6"><enum>I</enum><header>Development, Licensure, and Recommendations</header> 
<section id="H14336FED14524E3D89BD302FEDED4EEB"><enum>101.</enum><header>Review of transparency and consistency of ACIP recommendation process</header> 
<subsection id="H72BCE5EDB544400696584FC9C6CCC9C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall conduct a review of the transparency and consistency of the process used by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices in formulating and issuing recommendations pertaining to vaccines.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5C9B4521948748A1BFD252B78672253D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The review under subsection (a) shall include assessment of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA2F4DA340E3440B0A559062FC26F798E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the criteria used to evaluate new and existing vaccines;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46270AF794934203970E87EB6CD1E5E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) approach to the review and analysis of scientific and economic data, including the scientific basis for such approach; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF17ED9581BA45CDA7FB0E9F0BACD60B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which the processes used by the working groups of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices are transparent and consistent.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H812B6118D4BC4FF6A930A92FDBA09439"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stakeholders</header><text>In carrying out the review under subsection (a), the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall solicit input from vaccine stakeholders.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H787C5C2B4B2A4D85872778DFD3B6DE1B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall submit to the appropriate committees of the Congress and make publicly available a report on the results of the review under subsection (a), including recommendations on improving the transparency and consistency of the process described in such subsection.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEF09EA8B1C984305A437C5184C065601"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices</term> means the advisory committee on immunization practices established by the Secretary of Health and Human Services pursuant to section 222 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/217a">42 U.S.C. 217a</external-xref>), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE9DC5A173DAD404782BD9E3A2D26630E"><enum>102.</enum><header>Guidance on vaccine development</header> 
<subsection id="H36301F57A36D42DCB19531E2D0D5F54E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue final guidance to facilitate the use of accelerated and expedited pathways for the development and licensure of vaccines to prevent—</text> <paragraph id="H28FE59F42681496F8BAB55C9666CD0E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>emerging, re-emerging, or rare infectious diseases with respect to which the low prevalence or nature of the disease may render the existence or collection of clinical outcome data unlikely or impractical; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38966B25D6914BF88308AF314FF690F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>infectious diseases with respect to which currently available vaccines are not addressing the full scope of public health needs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H318D39346F7443D9AEEF84E0F140A9DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the guidance required by this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consider issues relating to clinical development strategies for diseases described in subsection (a), including the development and acceptability of novel clinical and surrogate endpoints, the use of novel or accelerated study designs, the use of observational real-world data, the use of novel adjuvants, the use of new technologies or approaches to collecting and monitoring patient-level data, and the demonstration of efficacy through studies in healthy volunteers for the purpose of licensure.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC9EF978891DA49A88C420914EBA5A9B5"><enum>103.</enum><header>Meetings between CDC and vaccine developers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 310 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/242o">42 U.S.C. 242o</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H2ED23E7623624534A6C7990D160D5FA1" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H2BAFA375C78F4E4E8F358B6272CB4ED6"><enum>(c)</enum> <paragraph id="H621A867F91934F6C8103D53128503FC4" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>vaccine developer</term> means a nongovernmental entity engaged in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCFDC86A12487444799DDA106F73B4561" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development or production of a vaccine; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B9AE2AC374F455AA4E529E46BF46507" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>vaccine research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75078019E4114F14AC55D381075AAFF4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HBD1EE4CD8A2743EB87FE7BB52C2240F4" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the submission of a written request by a vaccine developer, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall convene a meeting of representatives of the vaccine developer and experts in immunization programs, epidemiology, and other relevant areas, including such experts from the Food and Drug Administration and the National Vaccine Program, at which the Director (or the Director’s designee), for the purpose of informing the vaccine developer’s understanding of public health needs and priorities, shall provide the perspectives of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and other relevant Federal agencies regarding—</text> <clause id="H2AEDD5C72E4046E5835F6F0C720AB95D" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>public health needs, epidemiology, and implementation considerations with regard to a vaccine developer’s potential vaccine profile; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEF4ED739EE4D4F67AC9BCDA08F3E6AEF" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>potential implications of such perspectives for the vaccine developer’s vaccine research and development planning.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7D4EC7161B947D1B82A1A57613DA00E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (or the Director’s designee) shall convene a meeting requested under subparagraph (A) not later than 90 business days after receipt of the request for the meeting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10BCB0C855FA4C94B06B0D0DA460828F" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="H5DE713C56374495CA7A01F04EE8CBD3E" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the submission of a written request by a vaccine developer, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall provide to the vaccine developer any age-based disease epidemiological analyses or data that—</text> <clause id="HAE67633F927F45B49F516CCEBFA5CD57" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are specified in the request;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA1D7DCE5A152459BB99AA230A2C4F737" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have been published;</text></clause> <clause id="HB8DDC3C3F32E49F0B2525AA0D0B3A62D" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have been performed by or are in the possession of the Centers; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFFFD2CCA9CF743298245982B5AD1F30F" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are not a trade secret or otherwise confidential information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code, or section 1905 of title 18, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03A2617BC3F94261A72A004AE7C905F6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide analyses requested by a vaccine manufacturer under subparagraph (A) not later than 90 business days after receipt of the request for the analyses. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB482CB6998DD4096A5A40A63CCE5DC53" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall promptly notify a vaccine developer if—</text> <subparagraph id="H84C200F8766B40B5BAAB7B4387861C44"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary becomes aware of any change to information that was—</text> 
<clause id="HFAE21489D5F841EF9A7975375173B4F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shared by the Secretary with the vaccine developer during a meeting under paragraph (2); or</text></clause> <clause id="HF828E88647774D28B8147726439F4C13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provided by the Secretary to the vaccine developer in one or more analyses under paragraph (3); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FFAB44100CD41F5B180031AC3B718E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the change may have implications for the vaccine developer’s vaccine research and development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HB6C8654DC8624182B1EBA075F0E510A2"><enum>104.</enum><header>Modifications to priority review voucher program for tropical diseases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 524 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360n">21 U.S.C. 360n</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFC1F9369EB1945639058262777BAB824"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA0A6270DA46F48328B9C3E94512A7D88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<clause id="H446FA8F5DBDC42D4A6D453318FD99367"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter before subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>This term</quote> and inserting <quote>In this section, this term</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDBD0E749D9CF4EBDB368D851911840CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (R), by striking <quote>designated by order of the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>designated by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (4)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H045C65C5C0BC4E309E3A3175CD9A0F55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9ACC378FE6564FE69F7443DC91636907"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1D32406958454CB29A0B07DF31903C48" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HA132186E91DD43EF8204489C018390E3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Designation of other infectious diseases as tropical diseases</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1096B0330182411A897079410D0B6178"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process under which the Secretary—</text> <clause id="HFE391DDBA3624668A22AF61E37028AF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>using a methodology that is made available to the public on the Internet site of the Food and Drug Administration, designates infectious diseases other than the diseases specified in subparagraphs (A) through (Q) of paragraph (3) to be tropical diseases for purposes of this section; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H29BE9453AE51464B8628E564D4579FCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publishes on such Internet site a complete, updated list of the diseases that are tropical diseases for purposes of this section. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1071983F8F844CB98BE0E696B65D0E0E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In designating an infectious disease as a tropical disease under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<clause id="H2C0D28B81BC2432EAA0123AEAC863C5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consider the potential impact of the disease on the public health due to—</text> <subclause id="HC5627D43D417439D9BD179ED22D5FD4E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the potential rate of spread of the disease; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H048F3C325083442084DA87ABE07A3234"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the potential severity of the disease in terms of human morbidity and mortality; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H02D99D7EF18F4BCCB9BA5219D6AB0DD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consult with experts in tropical infectious diseases, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Food and Drug Administration, medical professionals, the clinical research community, and the World Health Organization.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3E3554B6DF5491689400D44A77E7416"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Every 5 years, or more frequently as determined necessary by the Secretary, the Secretary shall review, provide modifications to, and re-publish the list published under subparagraph (A) and any revisions made to the methodology for designation of diseases under such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9ABB3CA4AE644CA1B1A6A9DE7E45DFDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE2D69560606747C0844299F5C141453D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>The sponsor of a tropical disease</quote> and inserting:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H628AD9B29C3B4C8D81F2C67D2874FD9E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HD42188610D794D34A997AADC93DB5570"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sponsor of a tropical disease</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88D50645B6CF44DF8517E05366B0453E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after such paragraph (2)(A) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H32C044157A344B5E9437C0007DC37747" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HCE7B1E1B40374AD299D71AAFCE81ADEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification of transfer</header><text>Each person to whom a priority review voucher is transferred shall notify the Secretary of such change in ownership of the voucher not later than 30 business days after such transfer.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05FB329C67F1464E9D05587206DD5DDF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>The sponsor of a human drug application</quote> and inserting:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H94FAA587066E4A34978D74F46C003E98" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H2445178CA9D14103B6BFDCF37FAC85ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sponsor of a human drug application</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C6A950252EE4F7FAF68AFE891BE78E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4)(A), as designated by subparagraph (D), the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HBC9439218DB1483E95142F1633CA8A3F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HF4848F89E7AF47ED89239E25146C7951"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transfer after notice</header><text>The sponsor of a human drug application that provides notification of intent under subparagraph (A) may transfer the voucher after such notification is provided, if such sponsor has not yet submitted the human drug application described in the notification. Upon such a transfer, notwithstanding subparagraph (A), such sponsor shall not remain legally committed to pay a user fee because of the sponsor’s notification of intent under such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65536FB6D72B4AB6B504D283AA70BE46" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5BC1395C47974519AF57ABD9401B76FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H7EA8568443F24306BD58643FCF4CE4CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fee amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the priority review user fee shall be determined each fiscal year by the Secretary based on the difference between—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD3823B9A28BE4973A0DD31601ECAE444"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average cost incurred by the agency in the review of a human drug application subject to priority review in the previous fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H969CEC466DDA4A6090A580A8F510EDBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average cost incurred by the Food and Drug Administration in the review of a human drug application that is not subject to priority review in the previous fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBFA6AA13F1EA4DCBA61A2DD14A2A7605"><enum>105.</enum><header>Guidance on changes to an approved application for biological products</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue final guidance that—</text> <paragraph id="H2796031145E447778F10539D3C69CA9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>addresses changes in a licensed biological product or the labeling, production process, quality controls, equipment, facilities, or responsible personnel for such a product established in the application for the product that was approved under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2761C555428A471283CC65E56F8CDBE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not address such changes for specified biotechnology or specified synthetic biological products listed in section 601.2(c) of title 21 of the Code of Federal Regulation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FB8EF1DA2CE4B78932BF492A19BED50"><enum>(3)</enum><text>updates and supersedes the guidance entitled <quote>Changes to an Approved Application: Biological Products,</quote> that was issued by the Food and Drug Administration in July, 1997.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H260C358DD47A41DD9A144016D9B3EA0A"><enum>106.</enum><header>Expediting the process for export certifications for vaccines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 801(e)(4) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/381">21 U.S.C. 381(e)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4F63D1DEE71F4241AFA1F403259DE4C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter following clause (ii) in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>within 20 days of the receipt of a request for such certification</quote> and inserting <quote>within 20 business days of the receipt of a request for such certification, except that in the case of a vaccine the Secretary shall issue such certification within 10 business days of the receipt of a request for such certification</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B96B69B20C848E6AB77B7E8B81A8361"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>within the 20 days prescribed by subparagraph (A)</quote> and inserting <quote>within the period prescribed by subparagraph (A)</quote>. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="H954946A7971D4DFFA7C9EE0568108A41"><enum>107.</enum><header>NIH vaccine research</header> <subsection id="H256AB19EC99A47DCBC6E25A1BB196F2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart 6 of part C of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285f">42 U.S.C. 285f et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE483640EFB564D898C608CCDEA448C63" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H493856FC659A4FCA92FF6216B5D88678"><enum>447D.</enum><header>Advancement of vaccine development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out the general purpose described in section 446, the Director of the Institute shall conduct or support translational science, research, and research training to advance the development of vaccines for the prevention of diseases, including the advancement of vaccine development programs into clinical trials. </text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H133B060288AC4ACD8458C56C4D47A8B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of NIH vaccine research</header> <paragraph id="H38050B72C77C4EC7B0365E82F11AFFA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE01DEE9BE43E4445AE0BFF69EDFFE504"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a review on vaccine research being conducted or supported by the Institutes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6421F20F4DD840098024EA07FE9713AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish a report on the results of such review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA4D14F24CAD4E1FBADA09F135FBA229"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>At a minimum, the report under paragraph (1)(B) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H79E982C7392E4C56B051DDB1689C4983"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe intramural and extramural vaccine research and development programs that are being conducted or supported by the National Institutes of Health, including those that are translational or clinical phase studies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36B198A4E11A452F91B9C80AFE8A9802"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide a summary of funding allocations made to conduct or support the matters described in section 447D of the Public Health Service Act, as added by subsection (a), and identify projected funding needs with regard to future research or support with regard to these matters; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D55A29D2C854C279B6F6F8F0F781DD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify funding and collaborations with the private sector through—</text> 
<clause id="H70B2C023E16C4960B4861B58F0E2A2E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Small Business Innovation Research and Small Business Technology Transfer programs; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCD9E86700812497B80C63372B729D7C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cooperative research and development agreements.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </title> 
<title id="HC329DC8410DB4B5D91A453B89FDFA86F"><enum>II</enum><header>Medicare, Medicaid, and other provisions</header> 
<section id="H8C47DCB12244451FAEAE235719219BC5"><enum>201.</enum><header>Requiring prompt updates to Medicare program upon issuance of ACIP recommendations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case that the advisory committee on immunization practices established by the Secretary of Health and Human Services pursuant to section 222 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/217a">42 U.S.C. 217a</external-xref>) issues a recommendation for a vaccine or an update to a recommendation for a vaccine that the Secretary is using under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to coverage of vaccines or immunizations under such title, the Secretary shall determine whether or not to update policies under such title with respect to such coverage on a date that is not later than 60 business days after the date on which such advisory committee issues such recommendation or update.</text></section> <section id="H951AF95E0F3D484E86B2A77AF9C185C6"><enum>202.</enum><header>GAO study and report on Medicare and Medicaid beneficiary access for vaccines</header> <subsection id="H2C74233066B8494191A2FEB2CAABF3C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (in this section referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study on the impact of reimbursement rates under the Medicare program under parts B, C, and D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act and under the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act on access by targeted individuals to vaccines recommended by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Such study shall include an analysis and determination of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H497467AD792745D58950E04308F6AA8E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the reimbursement rates for vaccines under such parts of the Medicare program and under the Medicaid program, including those rates paid by a PDP sponsor under part D of title XVIII of such Act, Medicare Advantage organizations under part C of such title, and Medicaid managed care organizations (as defined in section 1903(m)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(m)(1)(A)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC028B9D67534B08A8F616E5E6CEAD81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of targeted individuals during the 3-year period prior to the study who were eligible for a vaccination recommended by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H977602A7FE094AC2BB6B227F6CA0E6E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of such targeted individuals who actually received a vaccination described in paragraph (2), with a particular breakdown of adults, the elderly, and populations located in rural or underserved communities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61A46CE590AC4C9583B132B6A16A2990"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the extent to which the reimbursement rates under such parts of the Medicare program and under the Medicaid program for vaccinations described in paragraph (2) affect their use by physicians or access for such targeted individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H052194FC52C143E3B9B8B3A9EF9FAD1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Targeted individuals</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the term <quote>targeted individual</quote> means and individual who is—</text> <paragraph id="HC9FDCF5DB266462F85ED952D9BB980DF"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph id="HE05A48546E3A4F1F8EA06C4F2ACCE7F6" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entitled to benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act or enrolled in part B of such Act; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8AC8343794C40CCAE4FCD6F0B68485A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eligible for medical assistance under title XIX of such Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29A76389B0C64176AD781AD7EECDBA17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>within a vulnerable population.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B69552A89954C1BB03D4A25940CA42D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate committees of the Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under subsection (a), including—</text> <paragraph id="HBA992535799F4230A0D27EDB7AF1653E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the findings of the study; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8442BFD945C241E9923A9A779408D57A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations based on the results of the study, including recommendations for such legislative and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H38AB9F5B37054E8887540F7B5A220437"><enum>203.</enum><header>Encouraging health plans to establish programs to increase adult immunization</header> <subsection id="H9DE2ECB7145E4CBE97EF17051B62A6F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Private health plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2718 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-18">42 U.S.C. 300gg–18</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4E4B5C84B4484CC7AEEDE62340AA39FB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H16988D18F76C4FDD9B631D224325BCED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Programs to increase adult immunization</header> 
<paragraph id="H0BEBA51E1D5C4F66BD1550226DC6C128"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, for plan years beginning on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Vaccine Access, Certainty, and Innovation Act of 2015</short-title>, activities that improve health care quality described in subsection (a)(2) shall include programs to increase adult immunization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBA45EA88A9545A7AC675FFCD99D1956"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2016, the Secretary shall establish standardized methodologies, including definitions, for which activities, and in what regard such activities, constitute programs to increase adult immunization in accordance with this subsection. The Secretary shall consult with relevant stakeholders in establishing such methodologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDBC672CA6BF44DDC862EB1A828EF7597"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medicare Advantage and part D plans</header><text>Section 1857(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H86DAB9BC01374B489B2A9123804A286C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HE3212814D749427A820D95F6A240633F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inclusion of expenditures on programs to increase adult immunization in minimum medical loss ratio calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of calculating the minimum medical loss ratio under paragraph (4), for plan years beginning at least 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the numerator shall include any expenditures on programs to increase adult immunization.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


