<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC832BE5039524A41AE1DD9315A911ADB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2123 IH: Enhancing Veterans’ Access to Treatment Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2123</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000613">Mr. Dold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000591">Mr. Tom Price of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish non-formulary drugs and medicines to veterans diagnosed with mental health disorders, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA3682B38A6424BD996338DC494310AB9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2D6F2411450C4CA5A6AE6F5FA65A0E56" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header> 
<subsection id="HC5B7065EA24A484BB73C13F96D08AAF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Veterans’ Access to Treatment Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H6698E400271C4A419A88FF27A7B5A337"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs furnishing of non-formulary drugs and medicines to veterans with mental health disorders</header> <subsection id="H851AC34CDA764EDDAA65D94603FA9E54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Availability of non-Formulary drugs and medicines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of a veteran who is enrolled in the patient enrollment system under section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, who a duly licensed physician, including a Department of Defense physician, has determined is taking or has taken during the 90-day period preceding the date of such determination, a prescribed drug or medicine that has been effective in treating a mental health disorder with which the veteran has been diagnosed, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall take such steps as may be necessary to furnish such drug or medicine to such veteran if the prescription is ordered by a duly licensed physician, regardless of whether such drug or medicine is available under the formulary in use by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0803602BF1224FAEADC57795EEDD2CFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>VA capacity To dispense certain non-Formulary drugs and medicines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall revise the prescription medication formulary of the Department of Veterans Affairs to ensure that all medications within the classes of antipsychotics and antidepressants that are prescribed by Department of Defense physicians, including such medications prescribed for the treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, schizophrenia, depression, and bipolar disorder, are available at all Department of Veterans Affairs pharmacies.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

