<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFFE0972CA4ED4417B9545DC85F00B38A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3786 IH: Student Loan Fair Prepayment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3786</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151021">October 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 and the Truth in Lending Act to clarify the application
			 of prepayment amounts on student loans.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5BDBCB5BE0104A4DA640B3B508A86349" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9C4266B95C884CD4AB009E44DBFE0FC8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Loan Fair Prepayment Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF286D9E5447E4343BE8BDE556F9CFDD1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of prepayment amounts for FFEL and Direct Loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(d) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8E4A92977BF423CB4F7E9D63A1E9E60" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H8B11DA2C3FB643578C659A7BBBB130DF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Application of prepayment amounts</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBB44B5592148402293FD72F015C57CFC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection or any other provision of law—</text> <clause id="HCB92084FF04B49678A790D05B55D4576"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to loans made to an eligible borrower under this part or part B, which are held by the same holder and which have different applicable rates of interest, the holder of such loans shall, unless otherwise requested by the borrower in writing, apply the borrower’s prepayment amount (within the meaning of section 682.209(b) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation) for one or more of such loans, first toward the outstanding balance of principal due on the loan with the highest applicable rate of interest among such loans; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H84E3EF6E6ED043D794DE597C0895B47A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>except as provided in clause (i), with respect to loans made to an eligible borrower under this part or part B, which are held by the same holder and which have the same applicable rates of interest, the holder of such loans shall, unless otherwise requested by the borrower in writing, apply the borrower’s prepayment amount (within the meaning of section 682.209(b) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation) for one or more of such loans, first toward the outstanding balance of principal due on the loan with the highest principal balance among such loans.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA425BA30D4E74C799EA5724FC9432006"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible borrower</header>
 <clause id="H3A633FD5957844DDA9569739A180A3AE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>eligible borrower</term> means a borrower with no outstanding balance of fees, including collection costs and authorized late charges, due on any loan made under this part or part B.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H43204DD109124D5AA1CAB34C15BE511E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prepayment amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A prepayment amount (as described in subparagraph (A)) made by a borrower who is not an eligible borrower to a holder shall be applied first toward the borrower’s outstanding balance of fees, including collection costs and authorized late charges, due on any loan made under this part or part B held by such holder.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCAA5B1E900B44DDA989DBA0FBFBCE57C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This paragraph shall not apply to an income-based repayment plan under section 493C or an income contingent repayment plan under section 455(d)(1)(D), such as a Pay As You Earn repayment plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H401E68BF9EC94438BBE19974E2A4B2D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Application of prepayment amounts for Perkins Loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 464(c)(1)(C) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087dd">20 U.S.C. 1087dd(c)(1)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3787165534BC42F8BEA4D51903EA8F5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (i);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99C3FA04F53F428AB3C1DFAF8D5D9080"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD05E0E17863643FFB27FFF5446AFE76A" style="traditional"> <clause id="H75E6FBE669A743F299A6AFD5C5CEF0B3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide that the institution shall, in the case of a borrower with no outstanding balance of fees (including collection costs and authorized late charges) due on the loans held by the institution and who repays more than the amount due for a repayment period—</text>
 <subclause id="HFEEECFCBE2B942598C13EB743ED6514C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to loans held by the same institution and which have different applicable rates of interest, use the excess to prepay (within the meaning of section 674.31(b)(4)(iv) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation) the principal due on the loan with the highest applicable rate of interest among such loans, unless otherwise requested by the borrower in writing; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HED82C93A30D84D38905A0E905D311569"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subclause (I), with respect to loans held by the same institution and which have the same applicable rates of interest, use the excess to prepay (within the meaning of section 674.31(b)(4)(iv) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation) the principal due on the loan with the highest principal balance among such loans, unless otherwise requested by the borrower in writing; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE14A1392BB4742A897B62CC6485A5C0F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide that the institution shall, in the case of a borrower with an outstanding balance of fees (such as collection costs and authorized late charges) due on the loans held by the institution and who repays more than the amount due for a repayment period, first apply such excess toward such outstanding balance of fees;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H7F8E6B7F6DF3441C96AD80FA40FA3F61"><enum>4.</enum><header>Application of prepayment amounts for private education loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 128(e) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38F6449C344642EB9281016F3C137AD5" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H6602E2DE1A5048188DD56A8FFF581E30"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Application of prepayment amounts</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7E3393A38FD145C1A276F8D936C08554"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text> <clause id="H0856C22C8692402DB78BA492693FE7CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to a borrower with more than one private education loan which are held by the same holder and which have different applicable rates of interest, the holder of such loans shall, unless otherwise requested by the borrower in writing, apply the borrower’s prepayment amount (within the meaning of section 682.209(b) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation) for one or more of such loans, first toward the outstanding balance of principal due on the loan with the highest applicable rate of interest among such loans; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H2348F476D13946B19B63B7FAFF000AD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in clause (i), with respect to a borrower with more than one private education loan which are held by the same holder and which have the same applicable rates of interest, the holder of such loans shall, unless otherwise requested by the borrower in writing, apply the borrower’s prepayment amount (within the meaning of section 682.209(b) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation) for one or more of such loans, first toward the outstanding balance of principal due on the loan with the highest principal balance among such loans.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A8DF7A3A7A649F8A428845D27F87310"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header>
 <clause id="HB3DC4E785E7D460AAE16B5021ECBB007"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any prepayment amount made by a borrower to a holder if the borrower has an outstanding balance of fees, including collection costs and authorized late charges, due on any private education loan held by such holder.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H980F229FB55446768C98B656622BA4B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prepayment amounts</header><text>A prepayment amount (as described in subparagraph (A)) made by a borrower described in subparagraph (B) to a holder shall be applied first toward the borrower’s outstanding balance of fees, including collection costs and authorized late charges, due on any private education loan held by such holder.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


