<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H26CD13E484594375B8C364A0422E5223" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1307 IH: Global Free Internet Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1307</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To combat trade barriers that threaten the maintenance of an open Internet, that mandate unique technology standards as a condition of market access and related measures, and to promote online free expression and the free flow of information.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6AA14B0628B245979297628D618F27AF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6DEF8FFBC758414EAAE13F82970BF250" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Free Internet Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD4C2162F824D4E21BA9B7D1F4E76AB63"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H730C4F4235A84703BF2BE9CB23B541E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A single, open, global Internet is a vital tool for facilitating the free and secure flow of information and products without regard to distances or national boundaries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1366F36A0C46423BAEE2712A13508275"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The goal of a single, open, global Internet is best supported by policies that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFAE00BFF8E1C442EA9B9E2FF0385C55F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage utilization on a global basis of technology standards set by international standards-setting organizations, including industry-led and other voluntary bodies, and selected by the market;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H499AF7B696FF4AE495253798EE693626"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">respect the security of information, privacy, and speech of Internet users;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB697C08AD2264F628319D7369CA4EF7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote investment in Internet-related innovation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D3B518C70D74059AA32D6CCC423DE99"><enum>(D)</enum><text>refrain from compelling Internet service providers and other intermediaries to restrict the free flow of information on the Internet; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H62F7E71F80954D14AF0F97FF6A1E2908"><enum>(E)</enum><text>allow trade in Internet-related goods, services, information, and content.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51A5737C9DD94104AA646FC253B29ACA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Certain governments and international bodies are adopting or considering policies contrary to the goal of a free, open Internet, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB3A9E68F9440416BB4AD689587CEF4E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mandating unique technology standards favoring domestic producers as a condition of market access or pursuing related policies regarding standard-setting that are discriminatory and subvert the open, global nature of the Internet;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3566601A510441B980605921F933BF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sponsoring or tolerating the use of Internet-related tools to gain unauthorized access to public-sector and private-sector networks in the United States to disrupt their operation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4EA2BDA193994163ABEDADD3886AAC8C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>blocking, filtering, or otherwise restricting Internet communications in a manner that discriminates against Internet-based services and content originating in other countries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B95EA58BB1F4EEAB689AD4D8507684B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>monitoring Internet use and communications in a manner that restricts individual privacy and freedom; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8186C67E33634E3FB163E07557A6C2A3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>imposing market access requirements or liabilities that discriminate against or otherwise impede Internet-related goods, services and content from other countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBDD912C6F0248CCA1C998603DD25753"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such actions threaten the interests of the United States by—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3A84CA9CCAD046FE84B6B7FC33DFFC14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitating attempts by foreign governments to restrict or disrupt the free flow of information on the Internet;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7C89C533FB3A44C7831E5ADB3B6404AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoting <quote>national Internets</quote> in conflict with the underlying rationale and architecture of the Internet as originally envisioned and constructed, thereby compromising the Internet’s full functionality and promise;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H04470615BAA74A74901A3BCA3D870473"><enum>(C)</enum><text>harming United States workers and businesses, undermining a strong United States industrial base, and putting foreign competitors at an advantage; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2F446BD4FCA4751A42A8A0EFBFDCAB2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>putting at risk the utility of the Internet as a tool of open communication, assembly, and commerce, and the individuals who seek to use it for such purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="H593EAC20E9DD46CCA83CD2D60A8EA7F8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Task force on the Global Internet</header>
<subsection id="H26366D358BD2499681B3B38C5052903A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
<paragraph id="HE386AADEE2DF4D188C67D55F3C5B385A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the executive branch a Task Force on the Global Internet (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Task Force</quote>), hosted by the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4EDF26785134E37839CE2204E18EAAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The President shall select from among the members of the Task Force under subsection (b)(1) to serve as Chairperson.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3ADF0DE08D994203AC42D711C8A77037"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Task Force shall consist of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2DAD22E4139A4F109FE9AF1521101A63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Four United States persons with substantial expertise in Internet policy who are not employees or officers of Federal, State, local, or tribal governments and who—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCB238ED914C54EB18A5B0C13A0631D52"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are nominated by the public through a process managed by the Department of Commerce that solicits public recommendations through the Internet and are appointed by the President, acting through the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27265C168B58488ABFE10E9755A5B711"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall serve on the Task Force for renewable terms not to exceed 3 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D1DB077805F44A8B2E7ED1070474423"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The leader of the majority party in the Senate and the leader of the minority party in the Senate shall each appoint one United States person with substantial expertise in Internet policy to serve on the Task Force for renewable terms not to exceed 3 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77E1C6614B744E488D9A210153AC97D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the leader of the minority party in the House of Representatives shall each appoint one United States person with substantial expertise in Internet policy to serve on the Task Force for renewable terms not to exceed 3 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1CCE2FE3BB67480A8AEF86DBAC8E73C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the Chair of the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies as determined to be appropriate by the President, acting through their respective designees.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H5CAFAFB8482D48E2AF7F6264E4337164"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Staff of Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request of the Task Force, the head of any Federal department or agency or other Federal official described in subsection (b)(4) may detail, with or without reimbursement, any of the personnel or services of the relevant Federal department or agency to the Task Force to assist it in carrying out its functions.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFBE1DE15A30A4FAC8DA9273917944EE5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>In addition to such other responsibilities the President may assign, the Task Force shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2C3CAFE491BE40438DC0CAECD4CF9825"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement strategies in response to foreign and domestic government policies that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE613915A11C3471A84661816D92C3FE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>unjustifiably or unreasonably burden or restrict international trade in Internet-related goods, services, and content;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73FBF9ABC70A4F14823FB3478B8A4A90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mandate or otherwise preference Internet-related technology standards and related measures;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H518356CC02554DD1A31BD78D76BE49E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impede the free flow of information on the Internet; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D7E139548B54D879617567F0ACD9F17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>otherwise threaten the open, global nature of the Internet, the interests of Internet users and the United States in Internet-related international trade and discourse;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29C283D4FED94960A5C5F53FDA219402"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult and share timely information with the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD752D7524E24069B09865A9196C3170"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult and share timely information with civil society groups with expertise in Internet policy;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5FB9E1B3D2024DFE8B9831D0D38935ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinate the activity of all Federal departments and agencies as necessary to implement the strategies developed in accordance with paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D8C6E7C9D0B4B26921B4505AE7379C9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>prepare a report and action plan in accordance with section 4;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F1A1AF530C8485EB11A106C73065EC8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>hold public hearings and solicit public comment through the Federal Register and the website for the Task Force as appropriate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H160D03DF153B463FA7C2ACD1B45F7A94"><enum>(7)</enum><text>appoint a Task Force member, responsible for serving as a point of contact for correspondence and inquiries related to the activities of the Task Force.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H86FDB28FC9C14DCCB036346D3954E84B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report and action plan to the President and Congress</header>
<subsection id="H2B3CDA9626A742C6B637DA20F54C6919"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Task Force shall transmit to the President and the appropriate congressional committees a report and action plan that—</text> <paragraph id="HC7AAF2C9F67A44EC984F52709E195049"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies acts, policies, or practices of the United States, foreign governments, or international bodies, and related measures that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H73FAE235ED0C453FA74A67CCCC94A4D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deny fair and equitable market access to or otherwise unjustifiably or unreasonably burden or restrict discourse or trade in Internet-related goods, services, and content;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD597745CCDC74296B4072BEBFF0857BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mandate, give preference to, or promote Internet-related technology standards that diverge from widely adopted international standards, or otherwise lead to the adoption of discriminatory or trade-restrictive technology standards or conformity assessment procedures; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC849C097628A46778BDD927B9077DD5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise threaten the interests of the United States in the technical operation, security, and free flow of global Internet communications;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04EA1A401EE9458A95F5FE4039B62DF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>estimates the trade-distorting impact or extent of suppression of free expression of measures identified under paragraph (1) on United States commerce, the interests of Internet users, and the functioning of the Internet;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB2C89AEB8EAA4220B3773D498DBBB622"><enum>(3)</enum><text>designates which measures identified under paragraph (1) are priority concerns;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2DD43B1CC484914AA42038408B7FE80"><enum>(4)</enum><text>sets forth a strategy and actions to be taken by Federal departments and agencies in response to measures identified under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF1548523EAD14DB5A5FBD4DC385651AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provides information with respect to any action taken (or the reasons if no action is taken) in response to any such measures identified in prior years’ reports, including such actions as are required under section 5.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3E63B3A140CD487F98DADE80E9996BDE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of reports</header><text>The reports and action plans required under subsection (a) may contain a classified annex if the Task Force determines that such is appropriate.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1CC8DF18C63D4537B1F8C97516C321C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination and notice</header><text>In preparing each annual report and action plan required under subsection (a), the Task Force shall—</text> <paragraph id="H56C76E144E87497EA84A930C8DC57145"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek public participation by—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0BAEBD72407B4A2C90A49590B415D39D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publishing a notice in the Federal Register that includes instructions on how the public may submit comments on the report and plan;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46B8F56FAA664317937E95ED9C08F051"><enum>(B)</enum><text>holding at least one public hearing; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFC0751DAD8E94F3CB53996FE915006A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing a website for the Task Force that publishes timely information regarding the Task Force’s activities and provides an opportunity for the public to submit comments to the Task Force;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD7BF7DB883944DF8DA500C507110185"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult and coordinate with all relevant executive branch departments and agencies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H864502BA324945BDA3E46C23501AF755"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult and share timely information with civil society groups with expertise in Internet policy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC1A66F8F8594F3ABA56D9276252BF80"><enum>(4)</enum><text>take into account information from such sources as may be available to the United States Trade Representative and such information as may be submitted to the Trade Representative by interested persons, including information contained in reports submitted under section 181(b) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2241">19 U.S.C. 2241(b)</external-xref>) and petitions submitted under section 302 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2412">19 U.S.C. 2412</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9244E2292A6D49A3AD1A0B3B9D417DFA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Task Force shall publish in the Federal Register the report and action plan transmitted to Congress under subsection (a), but shall omit information transmitted to Congress under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFB6576907CD74768B72AE1FE816ADA2B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
<paragraph id="H45871D91EABF4D16B95802A828370659"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H334752CFAC084F85AA7AC370F9C7A5C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HB0DAB598ED4B4C75B0BF0A36FF36BD57"><enum>5.</enum><header>Section 301 investigation and potential sanctions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the transmission of each annual report and action plan required under section 4, the United States Trade Representative shall, in accordance with the requirements of sections 301 through 304 of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2411 through 2414), initiate an investigation, make any determinations required, and take any actions specified under such sections with respect to any acts, policies, or practices of a foreign government or international body that are identified in each such annual report and action plan as priority concerns, including restrictions on sale in the United States of products developed and manufactured in countries implementing such acts, policies, or practices.</text></section> <section id="H65F0902B4E35411FAB10770A81DF1867"><enum>6.</enum><header>Review and investigation by Federal Trade Commission and Department of Justice</header> <subsection id="H288AC280293244D9B9230D503F6080D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review and investigation</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission and the Attorney General shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H2C3997973E334A62A0A681D58D342BB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review each act, policy, or practice described in paragraph (1) of section 4(a) that is contained in a report or an action plan transmitted under such section to Congress; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81DA1159DBA3434BBFCEE0B04D877043"><enum>(2)</enum><text>investigate whether such act, policy, or practice (or any related action by a nongovernmental entity) violates the antitrust laws of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8657D565AC9643FE9397A4D3A6C10824"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>antitrust laws</term> has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12(a)</external-xref>), except that such term includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H73FB4DA8CF214AA495A007ECAD9FAF59"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report to President and Congress on international trade agreements</header> <subsection id="H19DC09FC73574C9BA21F6D0E3E0975EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Task Force shall submit to the President and the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text>
<paragraph id="H43E04B2797FB409589402C2D6291A961"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses the sufficiency of existing multilateral and bilateral trade agreements in—</text> <subparagraph id="H82785B1A038941319C8059C056F465FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promoting international trade in Internet-related goods, services, and content;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4ECED23DA81C4B6B86ABA681B1153FF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encouraging the utilization on a global basis of technology standards set by international standard-setting organizations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5AAFDD6624554F49A11B29ABF46B3D62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protecting the security and functioning of the Internet;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA12CDB7F51224448A4A26D5AFC2FCE09"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitating the free flow of information on the Internet; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59F1E31E8E354D3A82AE0AF19F5F2F44"><enum>(E)</enum><text>protecting the interests of Internet users; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB27B4F855A9E4E6580AD7058D8F27694"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommends, as appropriate, modifications of existing agreements or the negotiation of new agreements to advance the objectives identified in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2A325AC3539E4599AB5AA6FF27251CB8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the negotiating objectives of the United States for future bilateral and multilateral trade agreements should include the goals specified in subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H220926556BC940AABC851FAC0BAF16DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of reports</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) may contain a classified annex if the Task Force determines that such is appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H81C5F8A9B64A4BECBB8FD310FF6FAFF6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination and notice</header><text>In preparing each report required under subsection (a), the Task Force shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HC5ECA1C15ACD457C8B215A13C5CA1260"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek public participation by—</text> <subparagraph id="H5F33B553F3224412A76FB612CE10F1E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publishing a notice in the Federal Register that includes instructions on how the public may submit comments on the report and plan;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B8264A777CF4F0E8233662392A5C562"><enum>(B)</enum><text>holding at least one public hearing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC91A8D069BB4400E9C3B34EB42DE39AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing a website for the Task Force that publishes timely information regarding the Task Force’s activities and provides an opportunity for the public to submit comments to the Task Force;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9FF48E8AD7E64B0B88CEB18D31B55433"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult and coordinate with all relevant Federal departments and agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H096F005846A645E18490478305C7C11E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult and share timely information with civil society groups with expertise in Internet policy; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEBD27110963C440F90A0B6A6C1078537"><enum>(4)</enum><text>take into account information from such sources as may be available to the United States Trade Representative and such information as may be submitted to the Trade Representative by interested persons, including information contained in reports submitted under section 181(b) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2241">19 U.S.C. 2241(b)</external-xref>) and petitions submitted under section 302 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2412">19 U.S.C. 2412</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFF16B1167EDC4242BDECAAD7F4E505A8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Task Force shall publish in the Federal Register the report transmitted to Congress under subsection (a), but shall omit information transmitted to Congress under subsection (c).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H704A2B1ADCE94589B4F27D761974EF0A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H88216AA333984BD1A161B0276953568F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC76802CF54FA4C3EA34CF06EEAAA3C93"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Finance, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA7CCA9D67A5248C1BF6A7D0891D010F1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Standards-related training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Task Force shall coordinate with intergovernmental, national government, and private sector entities, including the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Patent and Trademark Office, the Trade and Development Agency, the United States Telecommunications Training Institute, the United States Agency for International Development, the Federal Trade Commission, and any other appropriate entities, for the purpose of organizing training of foreign and domestic government officials and national standard-setting and conformity assessment bodies with respect to best practices, including coordination with nongovernmental international and domestic standards bodies, in accordance with the annual report and action plan required under section 4.</text></section>
<section id="H48530480F5AD473EA41A6000D575D23F"><enum>9.</enum><header>Outside consultation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Task Force shall establish a regularized process to receive and respond to timely input from businesses, organizations, experts, and other interested parties regarding the fulfillment of its functions.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

