<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7C6AA67ECB494C91AB1F172301B962A7" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3812 IH: Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3812</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151022">October 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the identification of corporate tax haven
			 countries and increased penalties for tax evasion practices in haven
			 countries that ship United States jobs overseas, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H87838DAF398C41EDA7D520D52581A5C4" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFB25571C72D34F098DD8214165C4C359" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1EC482409C8C4E2496B04B19029B49C9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identifying corporate tax haven countries and increasing penalties for tax evasion practices in haven countries that ship United States jobs overseas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall develop and publish a list of countries the Secretary determines to be corporate tax haven countries. In developing such list, the Secretary may consider the following criteria:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1D7FBAA4F07245C4BCD722375E310BE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Tax rate in the country.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HABDF6EDDE18349F3BDB19614D6ACCC9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Lack of effective exchange of information between governments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A67A380A3C84480A99681ADF781DF2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lack of transparency in financial services sector.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB95340CA67D34F55B0C84B8AAC4C7B6B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Lack of requirements of substantial economic activity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E7B153999314525A848AB93338B0A04"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Incentives which may encourage a United States corporation to invest abroad rather than domestically.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41F73A6EE85D472CAE8A80A3FB310070"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Other factors deemed relevant by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="section">The Secretary shall review and update such list every 3 years.</continuation-text></section><section id="H0FFB2BB245EF4731BFBD7DCB56A9D39C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increase in penalties for corporate tax evasion practices concerning returns, documents, and activities relating to tax haven countries</header> <subsection id="H9923F45847294F859D72535E9299B95E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Accuracy-Related penalty on underpayments</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6662">Section 6662</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3E5E369C59D4A5D88AC4C38167A10DD" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H0E2F81304DD240B7A331BE0061E5DF9A"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Increase in penalty in case of tax haven countries</header>
 <paragraph id="H9119D4A78832446AA354231FC398E2F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any portion of an underpayment by a corporation for a taxable year which involves an undisclosed foreign financial asset located in a tax haven country at any time during such taxable year, subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to such portion by substituting <quote>60 percent</quote> for <quote>20 percent</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE91FE59B0BAC45E9884BA17D4BB55CEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tax haven country</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>tax haven country</term> means a country on the list published under section 2(a) of the <short-title>Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2015</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HF1EE455EEEF34F56AFA862F1EBCED1B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Understatements with respect to reportable transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6662A of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CBC266E6A644718BFEBD31742636AD8" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HDB98CF1DC8884A9096BE935E7B391A14"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Increase in penalty in case of tax haven countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any portion of a reportable transaction understatement by a corporation for a taxable year which involves a transaction that originates, terminates, or otherwise occurs in a tax haven country (as defined in section 6662(l)(2)), subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to such portion by substituting <quote>40 percent</quote> for <quote>20 percent</quote>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H67F3080460334000A014CA01775802D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fraud penalty</header><text>Section 6663 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE4661E53ADB47CF8530826C9605575E" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H5979C6F57C61440CA4B1EBA14FF3CFF5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Increase in penalty in case of tax haven countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any fraud by a corporation involving an activity occurring in a tax haven country (as defined in section 6662(l)(2)), subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>100 percent</quote> for <quote>75 percent</quote>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD40A5CBEF4C84800B6B57C2770057332"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Erroneous claim for credit or refund</header><text>Section 6676 of such Code is amended by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e) and by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF17C9D899A34C9EACF5F038F6FA80A6" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H25402E688C8C4EBE8CC1C497A9924234"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Increase in penalty in case of tax haven countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of claim or credit by a corporation for any excessive amount due for credits or refunds involving funds held or invested in a tax haven country (as defined in section 6662(l)(2)), subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>40 percent</quote> for <quote>20 percent</quote>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59EE98F48316499F937FE104B2B729C4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Willful attempt To evade or defeat tax</header><text>Section 7201 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In the case of an attempt by a corporation which involves a tax haven country (as defined in section 6662(l)(2)), the preceding sentence shall be applied by substituting <quote>$1,000,000</quote> for <quote>$500,000</quote>.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4EEEBC6A74B44E01848A21D03C9BE395"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Fraud and false statements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7206 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In the case of an offense by a corporation described in the preceding sentence which involves a tax haven country (as defined in section 6662(l)(2)), the preceding sentence shall be applied by substituting <quote>$1,000,000</quote> for <quote>$500,000</quote>.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H64F7FFFA07EF4B13893B09BDF6AC04F0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Fraudulent returns, statements, or other documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7207 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In the case of an offense by a corporation described in either of the two preceding sentences which involves a tax haven country (as defined in section 6662(l)(2)), the appropriate sentence shall be applied by substituting <quote>$150,000</quote> for <quote>$50,000</quote>.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC4D65765A9824B4C8CB1246AA081AF53"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="HA76673BD5B134EAA8718009CAB93525F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply to underpayments attributable to transactions entered into after the date on which the list developed under section 2 is first published.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC42F33DF1217475DA011C11964C3B2C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (c) shall apply to returns the due date for which (determined without regard to extensions) is after the date on which the list developed under section 2 is first published.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43D09F18408149A4B0EADBAC0C51F986"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (d) shall apply to refunds and credits attributable to transactions entered into after the date on which the list developed under section 2 is first published.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9ADD7A0A7D88414EA189F84E74642E40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The amendment made by subsections (e), (f), and (g) shall apply to offenses committed after the date on which the list developed under section 2 is first published.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD857CBEFEAC34C6CAD9D91DE75DC0828" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preferences in Government contracts</header>
 <subsection id="HCFB7C6412CAB47AA8334AF356AF5ECC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal department or agency may give a preference in the award of a contract for the procurement of goods or services in a fiscal year to any potential contractor that has not engaged in outsourcing during the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year in which the contract is awarded.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H41C94AA03D88423991DD1082936A2850"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To request outsourcing information from potential contractors</header>
 <paragraph id="H4E713A62592E42C6AF50B04AD0E8D6CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any solicitation for offers for a contract issued by a Federal department or agency in a fiscal year, the department or agency shall request each offeror for the contract to provide information regarding whether the offeror engaged in outsourcing during the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year in which the contract is to be awarded.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AA37766554F4AEAB5DED181F26DE837"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty and debarment</header><text>Any offeror found to be in violation of paragraph (1), including making a false statement regarding the offeror’s engagement in outsourcing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8BBB36D544E54CFBB73330881D015C40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall, notwithstanding section 1001 of title 18, United States Code, be liable to the United States for a civil penalty in an amount not more than the value of the contract the offeror is seeking; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED730081A6A5410EAF3BC5C85D3FA9E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be debarred, by the head of the department or agency soliciting the offer, from contracting with the Federal Government for a period of two years starting on the date on which the offeror is found to be in violation of paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3197BA57FAF64DC18E21DF8B3F711688"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply to solicitations for contracts issued on and after the date occurring one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F970735712144D1874BCC85999CFB1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Outsourcing defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>outsourcing</term> means the laying off of a United States worker from a job, and the hiring or contracting for the same job to be performed in a foreign country.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H829DAF0456D0485D95DD9C17ED7A9C1D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Deficit reduction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Amounts which the Secretary of the Treasury estimates are received in the Treasury by reason of this Act are hereby set aside for the reduction of the public debt.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


