<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9AC4E50DD71F41179C9DF0DD775AA9D7" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3352 IH: State Health Care Options Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3352</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to
			 provide greater flexibility with respect to waivers granted to States, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1D1281A0CBCE4541B6CF2B5AAFF0D076" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9C1C86042FD74FB19827550F67F7A870" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Health Care Options Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3286D46702B2476F97650E7C4A0C4CFE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increasing State flexibility through provision of health-flex and exchange waivers</header> <subsection id="H6470D0ACBAD842CF9072A61E06DA58ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State options</header> <paragraph id="HC3E677E296BE4A30AFE1969A535DB386"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act is amended by inserting after section 1332 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18052">42 U.S.C. 18052</external-xref>) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A5958D8BF54476782BF5D8FB9DB99C5" style="OLC">
						<section id="H140C9F7A59FD4450BB6149975A7BCCD8"><enum>1332A.</enum><header>Options for State flexibility</header>
							<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8D5A7E83F8C4C0F90346E575D823EA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State options</header>
 <paragraph id="H20AD9AAD64B341E8B2F00C7E483F2A09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State provides to the Secretary a notice (in this section referred to as a <quote>waiver notice</quote>) of intent to implement a health-flex waiver (described in subsection (b)(1)), an exchange waiver (described in subsection (b)(2)), or both, and such notice complies with paragraph (2), the waiver shall be deemed to be approved and effective, except as provided in paragraphs (5) and (6).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4768108A5D714712A0790376DFBA6C1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of a waiver notice</header><text>A waiver notice with respect to a State shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2EEB034575D34EEEB716C70836396E67"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The years for which the waiver shall be effective (which may be indefinite).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00D0C99735A84BFD98F99B79B6945C6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assurance that the State will comply with annual reporting requirements established by the Secretary relating to the activities of the State under the waiver, which reporting requirements shall include information on affordability, access, and transparency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E33A103C29649FC83CC1DD2669617E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a health-flex waiver—</text> <clause id="H407E4352FE40421FA20219E1C9D50473"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the requirements to be waived;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H646F8AEB60F04A2D88294346AB98CD10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that there will be available throughout the State one or more health plans that provide the catastrophic level of coverage described in subsection (c)(1)(B)(i) for which an enrollee's required contribution (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A(e)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, determined on an annual basis) does not exceed 6.5 percent of the median household income (as defined in section 36B(d)(2)(A) of such Code) of residents of the State for the most recent taxable year for which information on such median household income is available to the Secretary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4DD9C61E4083459890EFF3EAD9DE0725"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an assurance that the certifying entity (as defined in subsection (c)(2)) has a process to certify health plans as permissible health plans consistent with subsection (c).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC459F6044D24BE7B7B20C091F3D51E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In the case of an exchange waiver, assurances that the State—</text> <clause id="H0FF2759A72EF4FF4981B210470C736A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>will be responsible for functions that are necessary to carry out the waiver that would otherwise be performed by an Exchange;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H275E43012CBC49F09CDFA3D393851C19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>will comply with subsection (d);</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HEC64CFF0FC7D4DE8A0ED11239C2DF1CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the capability to receive from the Secretary subsidy eligibility information; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE634295F586C42248D011E8D0E426EB9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has and is applying standards for privacy, security, and data encryption for subsidy eligibility information that are determined to be satisfactory by the Secretary.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H27580FB49960422CAAC92EDA7907BC7B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effectiveness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A waiver under this section shall be effective for the years described in the waiver notice under paragraph (2)(A), except that no waiver under this section shall be effective for a year unless the waiver notice for such waiver was submitted before November 1 of the previous year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E19697E27794D32B82CC541A673909D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Modification or termination</header><text>A State may modify or terminate a waiver for the State under this section by submitting to the Secretary a subsequent waiver notice with respect to such waiver.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C4A63DE847B45F2B453B1C3C776AC33"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disapproval authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a waiver notice fails to comply with paragraph (2) and notifies the State of the reason for such determination not later than 30 days after the date on which the State submits the waiver notice, such waiver notice shall not be effective.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA30934A10FB342A397402499B25A4BE0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a State is in violation of an assurance submitted under paragraph (2) and notifies the State of the reason for such determination, the Secretary may revoke the waiver. Such revocation shall be effective on the first day of the first year that begins after the 60-day period that begins on the date on which notification of the revocation occurs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7CEE47AF5A2E4DB6B8FAFF7772039D30"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring a State to enact a law in order to carry out the provisions of this section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AC61D55EF5A456D844716F21D63BBCB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waivers</header>
 <paragraph id="H2F91909A01CC40799013CE4DC4D9D993"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Health-flex waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A waiver under this paragraph (in this section referred to as a <quote>health-flex waiver</quote>), with respect to a State, is a waiver of any of the requirements in sections 1301 through 1303.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE651D268972C45CE8064ED64E31B6EA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exchange waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A waiver under this paragraph (in this section referred to as an <quote>exchange waiver</quote>) permits a State to elect to be responsible for certain Exchange functions, including serving as the certifying entity for the purposes of subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5F8E1448B6040BCA0A850B4B2BB465B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No waiver of adult child coverage and preexisting conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to permit a State to waive the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H1724BF4E45794F669B84E977E61CA89B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition of preexisting condition exclusion</header><text>Section 2704 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-3">42 U.S.C. 300gg–3</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H988ECF354097476D80BBAD963A5612E3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension of coverage for adult children</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2714 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-14">42 U.S.C. 300gg–14</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4E320E4CE5147ACA4F91599505414AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certifying permissible health plans</header> <paragraph id="H5CF2DA17D4B949DE8ABD13BDBA34E95A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permissible health plan defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, the term <term>permissible health plan</term> means, with respect to a State, a health plan that is offered for sale in the individual or small group market in the State and that is certified by a certifying entity to meet the following requirements:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9FEA78F99B6143A5B1B2FAA2A19E07C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Benefits</header><text>The plan provides benefits for items and services within each of the following categories:</text> <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC750F8DD75BB44CA822899DF80679479"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Ambulatory patient services.</text>
 </clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EA5C0B0360B4400AD7BAB9A21FFFACB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Emergency services.</text> </clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B247DF3E9414E3B9C7C5D8A19F57346"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Hospitalization.</text>
 </clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0392F82B35A424294011E4A05FAA607"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Physician services.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDF9A491702364FFB8CC970C381A7334F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Levels of coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan provides a level of coverage that complies with one of the following levels of coverage (as established by the State):</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H877318CB9DD44EE9A9B4FD29BF70AEDC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Catastrophic.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HAAD927DCEBD54616955A95BC238BA162"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Standard.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H58B44F0A614E42519E75F6A55A931002"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>High.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H321D9D9E33244774981A7949C264CFBB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Transparency justifying premiums</header><text>The issuer of the plan makes available to the public information about the demographics of the population enrolled under the plan, the utilization of health care items and services by such population under the plan, and other factors that serve as a justification for the premium levels (including any premium increases) under the plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9806990C465D484090E480710122C467"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Information requirement</header><text>The issuer of the plan submits information as required under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(g)(3)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H194C5E2E8C864FB38D3F671873E0E989"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certifying entity defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>certifying entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H63B238E308C74463A6F23FCA005F66F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a health plan that is offered through an Exchange established by a State, such Exchange; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA24742EDCAD544CE90151E3BBC737BEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a health plan that is not so offered, the State in which such plan is offered.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF4D9657E1C34DC4B13904EF3596F7D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of certifying permissible health plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to eligibility for premium assistance tax credits and reduced cost-sharing for individuals enrolled in permissible health plans, see <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and section 1402(f)(4) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071</external-xref>), respectively.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE02E013B93E54B108FD82052907CAE12"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determining subsidy eligibility</header>
 <paragraph id="H45F4F20DAEDA41B6929AC9C45A415F0F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a State that has in effect an exchange waiver, the State shall determine the eligibility of individuals residing in the State for the assistance described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H085B203B03D54464AB3C99E11B74F9A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure of Federal information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State that has in effect an exchange waiver, the Secretary or the Secretary of the Treasury, as appropriate, shall make subsidy eligibility information available to the State, but only the minimum amount of information necessary to enable the State to determine the amount of the assistance described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (3) for which the individual enrolled in a permissible health plan is eligible.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HACABC93F84BA466D95DD349FAD176499"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsidy eligibility information defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>subsidy eligibility information</term> means information concerning the eligibility of an enrollee or a prospective enrollee in a health plan for—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H40698D9AD58046048241EB90CA339132"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a premium assistance credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D4A59AC807840B78FD5C4E7E08DB1F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduced cost-sharing under section 1402.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9DBD1977DF1945998A186BF5892C1108"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall establish annual reporting requirements under 1332A(a)(2)(B) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act that include information on affordability, access, and transparency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H521BA9D0CCE04788B737C970EFF96F2B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1332 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EF140E99976409D82DDE0F35AD48FBD" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1332A. Options for State flexibility.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96A1550EE55C441AB17D57FD5F33BA62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsidies for individuals enrolled in permissible health plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H006C674086084B20A59DBB6FEAD6E3A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Premium assistance tax credits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H331DB1E1C88D4D3BB3016721E8BB8F92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACA3C68542A44955984278C3CF147C4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED9A8CD689E14785B9C6D7FF35164772" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H0ECA4757A3FC4119B98ED8934C57B3FA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special rules in case of waivers under section 1332A of PPACA</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE9FDFCD3FCC44EF1AC5177A8730C4326"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limiting eligibility to taxpayers with income at or below 300 percent of FPL</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a section 1332A State, subsection (c)(1)(A) shall be applied by substituting <quote>300 percent</quote> for <quote>400 percent</quote> for a taxpayer who obtains coverage through a plan issued under the law of such State for a year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D861BEF4BE54D3EBD4A6DC79EAB0B11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible health plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a taxpayer who obtains coverage with respect to a section 1332A State, for a coverage month, a permissible health plan, as defined in section 1332A(c)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, shall be treated as a qualified health plan with respect to such taxpayer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25405F72B82F4D4994F8F2E896E2D077"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjusted monthly premium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State that has in effect a health-flex waiver described in section 1332A(b)(1) of such Act, subsection (b)(3)(C) shall be applied as if the adjusted monthly premium calculated under such subsection were multiplied by the ratio of the full actuarial value of the benefits provided under the plan being offered to the full actuarial value of essential health benefits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F451690F5334428BFFA884FFBC7523A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eliminating certain requirements in the case of an exchange waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State that has in effect an exchange waiver described in section 1332A(b)(2) of such Act for a coverage month, the following shall apply:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB12F50DB2DF2402DB22B1ED66E8503A5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eliminating exchange references</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (b)(2)(A), (c)(2)(A)(i), (d)(3)(B), and (e)(3) shall be applied by treating the permissible health plan as if it were offered through an Exchange.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3E46B8B2692C48D8AC923762C6B85D2D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable second lowest cost silver plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b)(3)(B) shall be applied by substituting—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HF9684918D4B34004A91D7C4463C77EBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>qualified health plan for which, if the adjusted monthly premium, taking into account subsection (g)(3), were multiplied by the ratio of 70 percent to the level of coverage expressed as a percent of the full actuarial value of the benefits provided under the plan, the product of such multiplication would be the second lowest such product for any plan offered in</quote> for <quote>second lowest cost silver plan of</quote>, and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H83CCB1ADD88A4B14821C4B27F935BF95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><quote>is offered in such rating area</quote> for <quote>is offered through the same Exchange through which the qualified health plans taken into account under paragraph (2)(A) were offered</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C44D42BE655416387BBDC94E05E1ECB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a permissible health plan which is not offered through an Exchange, such plan shall provide to the Secretary and to the individual enrolled in the plan the information described in subsection (f)(3) with respect to such plan and such individual.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4BBCDA0165984B9B820FB590A1EC88C0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special rule for part-time resident taxpayers with income above 300 percent of FPL</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a taxpayer who, during a taxable year, obtains coverage with respect to a 1332A State and with respect to a State which is not a 1332A State, paragraph (1) shall not apply and the premium assistance amount (otherwise determined under subsection (b)(2)) for such taxpayer for a coverage month shall be 0 if—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H360BC5C4911843D1B86B3BC1EB73B746"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the household income of the taxpayer for the taxable year equals or exceeds 300 percent of an amount equal to the poverty line for a family of the size involved, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA48B8D18E9CC42F0B4C012A841B977FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the taxpayer receives coverage with respect to a section 1332A State for such coverage month.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A2A7141A4384C65A506CEE96BE1CAF3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Section 1332A State defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>section 1332A State</term> means a State has in effect a waiver under section 1332A of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FD3F61873B04C5F913DC76F007E3EA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduced cost-sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1402(f) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H392B4E15A2EE46B3A95E2EA4E533677F" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFE4F92E969084B0C8F3B9204138DD1E0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>1332A waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State has in effect a waiver under 1332A, the following shall apply with respect to a coverage month with respect to individuals residing in the State on the first of the month:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCBAC2328275448A5B7907B4D7BA4BD4B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eliminating reduced cost-sharing for individuals with income above 300 percent of FPL</header><text>No individual whose household income exceeds 300 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved may be considered an eligible insured under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H583D52489A3E4B3E92227FB1F4247EC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Permissible health plans</header><text>For the purposes of this section, a permissible health plan, as defined in section 1332A(c)(A), shall be treated as a qualified health plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H819A18DDDCEB4F518ED246EC303396AF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exchange waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State has in effect an exchange waiver described in section 1332A(b)(2), subsections (b)(1), (d)(1), and (e)(3) shall apply as if there were no references to an Exchange.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8386D9D1B50A44799F871DF1EE5BBD6C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Acceleration of innovation waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1332(a)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18052">42 U.S.C. 18052</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>January 1, 2017</quote> and inserting <quote>the date of the enactment of the <short-title>State Health Care Options Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


