<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF2CA2A4016FC467CBF6E6F760CC2279F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3015 IH: The EPA Regulatory Domestic Benefit Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3015</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150709">July 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to primarily consider, and to
			 separately report, the domestic benefits of any rule that addresses
			 emissions of carbon dioxide from any existing source, new source, modified
			 source, or reconstructed source that is an electric utility generating
			 unit, in any such rule, and in the regulatory impact analysis for such
			 rule, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H55674821F851438CB274B3EBBAC2BC55" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9AD8377AEC4040A5ABBC2608BDC8DEA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The EPA Regulatory Domestic Benefit Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9C1268F1ADC74138B1473E61A6DBCF27"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rules addressing carbon dioxide emissions from electric utility generating units</header> <subsection id="H575133E44B27475BAA1215BF63BC1A1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header> Consideration of domestic benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency may not issue, implement, or enforce any proposed or final rule addressing emissions of carbon dioxide from any new source, existing source, modified source, or reconstructed source that is an electric utility generating unit unless the Administrator in such rule, and in the regulatory impact analysis for such rule—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE22BD2D0CD4548F28D46DED432D66D15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes an analysis and an estimate of any domestic benefits of such rule that are associated with the carbon dioxide emission reductions projected to occur under such rule;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H033DA990E90A41D7810B3356945AF8E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reports domestic benefits separately from any analysis or estimate of the global benefits of such rules;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F7F1421E79F4F1D87BEFCD53D8C019A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>primarily considers the domestic benefits of such rule as opposed to the global benefits of such rule; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0447BB23537E4BE6B2A47C7C9A9361A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes an estimate of the difference between monetized benefits and costs of such rule that is based on analyses and estimates of domestic benefits and domestic costs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H680C40209C044D8F9A87245D74D5B491"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nullification of proposed rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following rules of the Environmental Protection Agency shall have no force or effect and shall be treated as if such rules had never been issued:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0400072B42E544FAB72E8EC15105F9D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The proposed rule entitled <quote>Standards of Performance for Greenhouse Gas Emissions From New Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> published at 79 Fed. Reg. 1430 (January 8, 2014).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA09EB2F4AB0A45C4AC6E874BA15F8ED9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The proposed rule entitled <quote>Carbon Pollution Emission Guidelines for Existing Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> published at 79 Fed. Reg. 34830 (June 18, 2014).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H23680137B1B44B6D8C51F4566FF1E23F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The proposed rule entitled <quote>Carbon Pollution Standards for Modified and Reconstructed Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> published at 79 Fed. Reg. 34960 (June 18, 2014).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3B2FBCCFC894F288668010F73C3BE85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H32E231C9D0E2404DA6D04D24DD15121E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing source</header><text>The term <term>existing source</term> has the meaning given such term in section 111(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CDDC4D9E6AB4B05BECFBC00ECBDD22C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New source</header><text>The term <term>new source</term> has the meaning given such term in section 111(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(a)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DD33A3C1ABA43EEAC19BD8B7EFEFC90"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Modified source and reconstructed source</header><text>The terms <term>modified source</term> and <term>reconstructed source</term> mean any stationary source the modification or reconstruction of which causes such source to be treated as a new source for purposes of section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


