<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA884F88E4930463A8CD940EB8D014922" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 408 IH: Support Making Assessments Reliable and Timely Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 408</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150120">January 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to award grants to States to improve delivery of high-quality assessments, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H762545E10CB049CFBD575BD7FA2981DD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA46C9C3861F54254827841EC659BEBCE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support Making Assessments Reliable and Timely Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SMART Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6B134841CD8F437E961ACB1A0A9E57E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Accountability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 1 of part A of title VI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7301">20 U.S.C. 7301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C631FD350DD48939CC6E85B7FA7D42F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1E1AD7835409477A9F8E2D20DD28225B"><enum>6111.</enum><header>Grants to improve delivery of high-quality assessments and for related activities</header> 
<subsection id="H9634B7D0911A45AA9C518680A6102560"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount reserved under section 6114(b)(5) and subject to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such section, the Secretary shall make grants by allocating funds in accordance with subsection (b) of this section to States to enable the States to—</text> <paragraph id="HFF402BDB6F374317A3EA3EF7CC100571"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop, administer, and further align State assessments required by section 1111(b)(3) to State content standards required by section 1111(b)(1);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H231808388AEC4729AF45FCBD2B86ED66"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the provision of appropriate accommodations as required by section 1111(b)(3)(C)(ix) to students with limited English proficiency and students with disabilities to improve the rates of inclusion in State assessments of such students;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB15E07AABB3B4A46B7149E360B5D5F6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop State assessment systems aligned to the State’s content standards that support systems of continuous improvement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H883FE492EA9D4507AB818EA268DE75D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support local educational agencies in identifying uses of assessment data, which may include appropriate use of student assessment data as one of multiple measures of student learning for teacher and school leader performance and evaluation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CA814222C5F420487408DFFB1FD12C1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>carry out the activities described in the report required under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H22789468C08E494F97D63B06CFA54456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount reserved under section 6114(b)(5), each State shall receive an allocation for each fiscal year in an amount equal to—</text> <paragraph id="HB036CC33E0214A24970DD08A3B6D7C35"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$4,000,000; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35A204EC3D524B46AB57A443F7911ED1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to any amounts remaining after the allocation is made under paragraph (1), an amount that bears the same relationship to such total remaining amounts as the number of students ages 5 through 17 in the State (as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data) bears to the total number of such students in all States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB6CC0983BACF4DC5B809A67B75623985"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after a State receives a grant under this section, the State shall, in consultation with education stakeholders, prepare and make publically available a report, that explains how the State has used, or will use, the grant to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9986F5D701644D64B7EDD9386E9DFC74"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the quality and use of the State’s assessment system, including assessments not required by section 1111(b)(3), and for related activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1C698E2B7564D8BB1994638BB5566A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that all summative assessments that are used for accountability purposes are valid and reliable, and consistent with relevant, nationally recognized professional and technical standards; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CA8F4ED1C8443368D880A6E04E11CDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve the use of State assessment data by school leaders, educators, and parents, and for related activities, such as—</text> <subparagraph id="H29D09160CD77432D8D1A483067D1C4AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disseminating the assessment data in an accessible and understandable format for educators, parents, and families;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34525747FE764EAA8DB759320217DBD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>decreasing time between administering such State assessments and releasing assessment data;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7380C988E72647B4B367DB735A9B8993"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting the dissemination of promising practices from local educational agencies that have successfully used assessment data to improve individual student and overall school performance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H91700E12C64741BCBCD0C2C5EC00C188"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying appropriate uses of assessment data, which may include appropriate use of student assessment data as one of multiple measures of student learning for teacher and school leader performance and evaluation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB267B36590E5496A806EF18DA30796D5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing professional development on assessment and data literacy to teachers and school leaders, including on the development and effective use of formative and classroom-based assessments aligned with State content standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H69F61AA7458A45CBA0A0BBEED3309F7B"><enum>6112.</enum><header>Grants for assessment system alignment, quality, and use</header> 
<subsection id="HAC2FA52E36FB4922AA124719EDCB0F97"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount reserved under section 6114(b)(3), the Secretary shall make grants to States to—</text> <paragraph id="H7A04FA6A21FE454BBCB02494C0546010"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a grant awarded under this section to a State for the first time—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8B519782674B48A6A5684DD8D848D914"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out audits of State assessment systems and ensure that local educational agencies carry out audits of local assessments under subsection (e)(1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC73D1D3CB208459FA52C408324E9D703"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prepare and carry out the State plan under subsection (e)(6); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3240B45442E64421885E367F088E4C5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>award subgrants under subsection (f); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48E0F59AFE3F4EE1A6546DFD60056855"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a grant awarded under this section to a State that has previously received a grant under this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCD68FE6FB3BE474EADF0045B98385173"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out the State plan under subsection (e)(6); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFAE693B9AA94A70AF903B125FC2A46A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>award subgrants under subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4FBC2B3F22824B38AC19B3A7614493E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State with an approved application shall receive a grant amount of not less than $2,000,000.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H69DBBED3CD9947CEAD92FC7D8FE52122"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>If a State chooses not to apply to receive a grant under this subsection, or if such State’s application under subsection (d) is disapproved by the Secretary, the Secretary shall reallocate such grant amount to other States with approved applications.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3D572D74C34449BE8DA1B1E605B45C5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State desiring to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H04BA5475C7994FF69925DA2D7E31C769"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Audits of State assessment systems and local assessments</header> <paragraph id="H22A57C9C2DB3482FAA97946D56C44FE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Audit requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after a State receives a grant under this section for the first time, the State shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H12E8872C6F3F419EAB3FD4FE371ABB55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an audit of the State assessment system;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0AD4E1037FD4FA6B28B341579612EB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that each local educational agency under the State’s jurisdiction and receiving funds under this Act—</text> 
<clause id="H1A71246A60074A6EA37D750F15C3D854"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducts an audit of each local assessment administered by the local educational agency; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB4A19D24C28C4484AE54E3398925669D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submits the results of such audit to the State; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF78288DF28C4E16AEDAEBBE67FF666D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>report the results of each State and local educational agency audit conducted under subparagraphs (A) and (B)—</text> <clause id="H79FCDF58B6D24A038F285220B9A2E0CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a publicly available format, such as a widely accessible online platform; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFF22124D3A024E1E89064B8A084E8034"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with appropriate accessibility provisions for individuals with disabilities and individuals with limited English proficiency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E9D4799BF61424C83F7E7FFC7CE18E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resources for local educational agencies</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1)(B), each State shall develop and provide local educational agencies with resources, such as guidelines and protocols, to assist the agencies in conducting and reporting the results of the audit required under such paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB589A55A3CAE4AF687A02627A4BCFEE9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State assessment system description</header><text>An audit of a State assessment system conducted under paragraph (1) shall include a description of each State assessment carried out in the State, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H2AD6939C9DB6473A8C670D0BB4F7CFB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the grade and subject matter assessed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDAC9284DED35461789526BE9D93019EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the assessment is required under section 1111(b)(3);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C3A68EEB16B415F9378FDB9443341F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the annual cost to the State educational agency involved in developing, purchasing, administering, and scoring the assessment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H350585E6845841B4A8B16A4243886458"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the purpose for which the assessment was designed and the purpose for which the assessment is used, including assessments designed to contribute to systems of continuous improvement of teaching and learning;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D417DC98BDC44EE812ACB4824C863B7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the time for disseminating assessment results;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H14D5FCB629564C36B002EC282B45BC58"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of how the assessment is aligned with the State’s content standards;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCB50B40FD594437AEC4E81BAA0A404B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of any State law or regulation that established the requirement for the assessment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8CC70FD69A5E4C859F32D65175FA6AE1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the schedule and calendar for all State assessments given; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H962F06FF019D40259955A90CED2A81DB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the State’s policies for inclusion of students with limited English proficiency and students with disabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0188464CE0B4D26B158E349A4CDCA19"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local assessment description</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An audit of a local assessment conducted under paragraph (1) shall include a description of the local assessment carried out by the local educational agency, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5461AC8443E4629BDC14916712B5556"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the descriptions listed in subparagraphs (A), (D), and (E) of paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB92FF848979D4F049EDBE3206635669B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the annual cost to the local educational agency of developing, purchasing, administering, and scoring the assessment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7354DC412D4444E8AB4AF5A54C0F7D11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which the assessment is aligned to the State’s content standards;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H243E73821F2E4CE7B2F45F32D86EB585"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of any State or local law or regulation that establishes the requirement for the assessment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F040F580E0B457BB352B79305E138F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a summative assessment that is used for accountability purposes, whether the assessment is valid and reliable and consistent with nationally recognized professional and technical standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F68CB8E97BB441E8E03DE7F36F41632"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Stakeholder feedback</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each audit of a State assessment system or local assessment system conducted under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) shall include feedback on such system from education stakeholders, which shall cover information such as—</text> <subparagraph id="HEE142D65B17A44B5910A08EE7B83E81A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how educators and administrators use assessment data to improve and differentiate instruction;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38374F223DED4DEA85DD1ED52CDEBB0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the timing of release of assessment data;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H847A0FA8189E436E8526C11BECD30180"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which assessment data is presented in an accessible and understandable format for educators, parents, students, if appropriate, and the community;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82DBA0B6DE184092B44D35F10F5802C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the opportunities, resources, and training educators and administrators are given to review assessment results and make effective use of assessment data;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAE1A34FB5F641909FB6FC23B3188A24"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the distribution of technological resources and personnel necessary to administer assessments;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H705821A506FF4ABF8D84E47285373973"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the amount of time educators spend on test preparation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC32E1FC04AD4CAF886A250F77216439"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the assessments that administrators, educators, parents, and students, if appropriate, do and do not find useful;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5661DA6E28C4841B44AAE391F58DE21"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the amount of time students spend taking the assessments; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB6B9094A2BF4743B86E80D85B0B4B58"><enum>(I)</enum><text>other information as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD77B66232EF748A5840009D6643EB701"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State plan on audit findings</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF0344A5896874DB2A7766607C620E1A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Preparing the State plan</header><text>Not later than 6 months after a State conducts an audit under paragraph (1) and based on the results of such audit, the State shall, in coordination with the local educational agencies under the jurisdiction of the State, prepare and submit to the Secretary, a plan to improve and streamline State assessment systems and local assessment systems, including through activities such as—</text> <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDFDE602EEA14DBE99DE1D303A5049CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>eliminating any assessments that are not required by section 1111(b)(3) (such as by buying out the remainder of procurement contracts with assessment developers) and that—</text> 
<subclause id="HB694787B747A45BAA02D1D19043F26F0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are low-quality;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEBDD81D5BA9248A294EFA1F52FAAB42A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not aligned to the State’s content standards;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H257873495CB147EDBF6E433FB5462498"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of summative assessments used for accountability purposes, are not valid or reliable and are inconsistent with nationally recognized professional and technical standards;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE7BE42BC6F984081815A8D5AC0E54973"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>do not contribute to systems of continuous improvement for teaching and learning; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H59B7231FD6C34F90A59A88090D6B9D8D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>are redundant;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1D5B44E60DAD458E834A992186E3E87C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supporting the dissemination of promising practices from local educational agencies or other States that have successfully improved assessment quality and efficiency to improve teaching and learning;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB8ABB69C4E2A45AEAFD53BDF3680DDCA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>supporting local educational agencies or consortia of local educational agencies to carry out efforts to streamline local assessment systems and implementing a regular process of review and evaluation of assessment use in local educational agencies;</text></clause> <clause id="H77543522F5F246ADA41F31FF208E9914"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting appropriate uses of assessment data, which may include appropriate use of student assessment data as one of multiple measures of student learning for teacher and school leader performance and evaluation; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDCA2FB740A7D4486B35A2590685344E0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>providing professional development to teachers and school leaders on selecting and implementing formative assessments, designing classroom-based assessments, and assessment and data literacy.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9FFD6977911E42E4946EB566DA10A9A8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Carry out the State plan</header><text>A State shall carry out a State plan as soon as practicable after the State prepares such State plan under subparagraph (A) and during each grant period of a grant described in subsection (a)(2) that is awarded to the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5923324282B497BB6A8D021D6D4365D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subgrants to local educational agencies</header> 
<paragraph id="HDCB32A7D21214D7299F3FD08F17A2482"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount awarded to a State under this section, the State shall reserve not less than 20 percent of funds to make subgrants to local educational agencies in the State, or a consortium of such local educational agencies, based on demonstrated need in the agency’s or consortium’s application to improve assessment quality, use, and alignment with the State’s content standards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC270C1274D554C86AEC1144C35DCA74B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local educational agency application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each local educational agency, or consortium of local educational agencies, seeking a subgrant under this subsection shall submit an application to the State at such time, in such manner, and describing that agency’s or consortium’s needs to improve assessment quality, use, and alignment (as described in paragraph (1)), and such other information as determined by the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1FFC160A3D147F0813C1B6387A62BF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A subgrant awarded under this subsection to a local educational agency or consortium of such agencies may be used to—</text> <subparagraph id="H29B1F005C8E94AB891BB5554B03F4A0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an audit of local assessments under subsection (e)(1)(B);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7DCD2512A56642FDBBA78DD9E71C2067"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eliminate any assessments identified for elimination by such audit, such as by buying out the remainder of procurement contracts with assessment developers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DD0890C1C894D808663289512B031F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disseminate the promising practices described in subsection (e)(6)(B);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEAB85420C0694789B3A522093F1CE1E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improve the capacity of school leaders and educators to disseminate assessment data in an accessible and understandable format for parents and families, including for individuals with disabilities or individuals with limited English proficiency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H279F040BFD264DEE8A9144D0BBC7AF03"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the appropriate use of assessment data, which may include appropriate use of student assessment data as one of multiple measures of student learning for teacher and school leader performance and evaluation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H464B0F549C1748B78318267B63573509"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide professional development to, and time for teacher collaboration on designing classroom-based assessments and improving assessments and data literacy for, teachers and school leaders, which may include providing additional planning time to analyze student and team data and designing instruction based on data analysis;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D9A9583FC8A487C947D11C8BDB5B10B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>improve assessment delivery systems and schedules, including by increasing access to technology and exam proctors, where appropriate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C35C766740A4928B0C61ADE5D06EC27"><enum>(H)</enum><text>hire instructional coaches, or promoting educators who may receive increased compensation to serve as instructional coaches, to support educators to develop classroom-based assessments, interpret assessment data, and design instruction; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H054ADBFF7B4C4F4D81C1384130E334D7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide for appropriate assessment accommodations to maximize inclusion of students with disabilities and students with limited English proficiency, including by providing the assessments described in section 1111(b)(6).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0F828C2091044271A1C95ADF0228FACB"><enum>6113.</enum><header>National activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">From the amount reserved under section 6114(b)(4), the Secretary shall provide technical assistance to States to improve State understanding of existing flexibility in design and implementation of high-quality, streamlined State assessment systems to meet the requirements of section 1111(b)(3), including by—</text> <paragraph id="HEC4F068AEED24272923936DECA06E7A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>informing States of innovative designs in State assessment systems that meet the requirements of section 1111(b)(3);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4F89E7FD42B4B4D857B64733990C1B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to States on including appropriate assessment design and accommodation strategies that meet the requirements of section 1111(b)(3) and provide for inclusion of all students in State assessments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39B0033140DF48119A7C090DEA9AD104"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing technical assistance to States conducting audits of State assessment systems under section 6112(e), including by providing resources such as templates and guidelines for data collection and for making audit results publicly available;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H953970EB3B7B4476B633B9B1DC94A1A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting Departmental review of existing regulation and guidance for any language that unnecessarily confuses or inhibits innovation and flexibility in assessment design and implementation, and making revisions where needed, consistent with the requirements of section 1111(b)(3);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1162AB8BC03D4D6FBD7C8D984D40E7AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collecting information on State development of new and innovative assessment systems that meet the requirements of section 1111(b)(3); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H486CFBE159D04FA2AC88E333637311BE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reporting on such new and innovative assessment systems to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD95C63597126479BB4E3846FCA8EA7CC"><enum>6114.</enum><header>Funding</header> <subsection id="HCF0BCE9BC8CA44FFB5A670382AAF98B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph id="HF7ED92D52B0341BB814E81261866F06D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National assessment of educational progress</header><text>For the purpose of administering the State assessments under the National Assessment of Educational Progress, there are authorized to be appropriated $72,000,000 for fiscal year 2016, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE98965A828E34C328B451230119E21AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State assessments and related activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of carrying out this subpart, there are authorized to be appropriated $600,000,000 for fiscal year 2016, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEDA9CFC3CD65460D9FCB237DAED8A991"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservation of appropriated funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts made available for each fiscal year under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3C04C6E8F00A4A958CF881A0785EDD0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reserve one-half of 1 percent for the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEC52B7910094F6D9F872057C469CD7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reserve one-half of 1 percent for the outlying areas;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0AC1C718C574503B561BF91B5A3EF67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reserve 20 percent to carry out section 6112;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4FB218EE0664ACC9519B5CD9813F754"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reserve 3 percent to carry out section 6113; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CE043C13248484EA8C2ADB78F270857"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reserve the remainder (after reserving funds under paragraphs (1) through (4)) to carry out section 6111, except that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA797EFD493E04000A4E47F8777AC03B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for any fiscal year for which the funds appropriated under subsection (a)(2) of this section are equal to or greater than $450,000,000, each State that receives a grant under section 6111 shall use the grant to carry out paragraphs (1) through (5) of section 6111(a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2DE87DAA67374D18BCDE9618BA827A6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for any fiscal year for which the funds appropriated under subsection (a)(2) of this section are less than $450,000,000, each State that receives a grant under section 6111 shall only be required to use the grant to carry out paragraphs (1) through (3) of section 6111(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H9221379A70CE4B1EAFF025B29B172725"><enum>6115.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC1F70E140C434CAE9754A6BCA32A136F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local assessment</header><text>The term <term>local assessment</term> means an academic assessment carried out by a local educational agency that is separate from an assessment required by section 1111(b)(3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3BAAE10468D5422294FEDBFE0012733D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

