<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B9AA48B5DC24C0B82EED7B74A23A09C" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3260 IH: Eleanor Smith Inclusive Home Design Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3260</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require all newly constructed, federally assisted, single-family houses and town houses to meet minimum standards of visitability for persons with disabilities.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H922C785389EE485481A693850E7C21EF" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H531969D1A5F841FF81C3374C78AAEF70" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eleanor Smith Inclusive Home Design Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H979E1DFE142D4FEE81FDB0A9B80E0BE6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HE5C25B2348324D39819FB2244781002B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered dwelling unit</header><text>The term <term>covered dwelling unit</term> means a dwelling unit that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1A6F120CF2A43D5A6F70E5BD63CE858"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a detached single family house, a townhouse or multi-level dwelling unit (whether detached or attached to other units or structures), or a ground-floor unit in a building of three or fewer dwelling units;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7EBE0C45D61C4CF4A209EA561E5FCEB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designed as, or intended for occupancy as, a residence;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7220F7C041DF4BE29E00A58CE63400DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was designed, constructed, or commissioned, contracted or otherwise arranged for construction, by any person or entity who, at any time before the design or construction, received or was guaranteed Federal financial assistance for any program or activity; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H921B53A1D53049808B990153EDA44C95"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is made available for first occupancy after the expiration of the one-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63EFDFBA77014400B7F7056C8F6A85E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal financial assistance</header><text>The term <term>Federal financial assistance</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H62C988943962410B972969C8D474957E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any assistance that is provided or otherwise made available by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, or any program or activity or such agencies, through any grant, loan, contract, or any other arrangement, after the expiration of the one-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, including—</text> <clause id="H9AD9058A04E541319C159F831A8EEBF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grants, subsidies, or any other funds;</text></clause>
<clause id="HEE645AE1A666495B8F05E7345E8F5F3A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>services of Federal personnel;</text></clause> <clause id="H807453E26FE740C8BD66621687EB80DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>real or personal property or any interest in or use of such property, including—</text>
<subclause id="HF990BD4AD62144F19AC1D92F68EA8A83"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transfers or leases of the property for less than the fair market value or for reduced consideration; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0F85245C467A4F8FB5A2F03F614CCC5B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>proceeds from a subsequent transfer or lease of the property if the Federal share of its fair market value is not returned to the Federal Government;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H8650EB0A13B2454C8879841505760684"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any tax credit, mortgage or loan guarantee or insurance; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA046E92518604CF4A43D66735802A488"><enum>(v)</enum><text>community development funds in the form of obligations guaranteed under section 108 of the <act-name parsable-cite="HCDA">Housing and Community Development Act of 1974</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5308">42 U.S.C. 5308</external-xref>); or</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD06BE5B8BD914D23BE2F719A190109FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any assistance that is provided or otherwise made available by the Secretary of Agriculture under title V of the <act-name parsable-cite="HA49">Housing Act of 1949</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1471">42 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B901514E3FF4D359A30F35389BF2469"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Person or entity</header><text>The term <term>person or entity</term> includes one or more individuals, corporations (including not-for-profit corporations), partnerships, associations, labor organizations, legal representatives, mutual corporations, joint-stock companies, trusts, unincorporated associations, trustees, trustees in cases under title 11 of the United States Code, receivers, and fiduciaries.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H56BE3D6CF793466A8C3599B6740684EA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Visitability requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person referred to in section 2(1)(C) with respect to a covered dwelling unit to fail to ensure that such dwelling unit contains at least one level that complies with the Standards for Type C (Visitable) Units of the American National Standards Institute (ANSI) Standards for Accessible and Usable Buildings and Facilities (1005–ICC ANSI A117.1–2009) and any future revisions thereto.</text></section> <section id="H140E00DE75F7464CA013D08D3C5C65FB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="H362C2FE68DC845598ED9C3B7F1A088BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for Federal financial assistance</header><text>Each applicant for Federal financial assistance shall submit an assurance to the Federal agency responsible for such assistance that all of its programs and activities will be conducted in compliance with this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE383446D111D478DBAD7C3BD931B260E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval of architectural and construction plans</header>
<paragraph id="H61632E795E88477DBF47EF04580B42DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Any applicant for or recipient of Federal financial assistance for a covered dwelling unit shall submit for approval the architectural and construction plans for such unit to the State or local department or agency that is responsible, under applicable State or local law, for the review and approval of construction plans for compliance with generally applicable building codes or requirements (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>appropriate State or local agency</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63DEFF5CC55A4315986AA94B93F535BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of compliance</header> <subparagraph id="HC9A6E414B002407B8BEA173DC5707469"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Enforcement actions</header><text>The enforcement actions under this subparagraph are—</text>
<clause id="HE21BF53D8EFC4676A9BF91266E61F29E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reviewing any plans for a covered dwelling unit submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) and approving or disapproving such plans based upon compliance of the dwelling unit with the requirements of this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H81E768D7298E48B6842B5C20614A5178"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consistent with applicable State or local laws and procedures, withholding final approval of construction or occupancy of a covered dwelling unit unless and until such compliance is determined.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H26AF6B17C2D149F1AFA95D5D60D57157"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Condition of Federal housing assistance</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may not provide any Federal financial assistance under any program administered by such Secretary to a State or unit of general local government (or any agency thereof) unless the appropriate State or local agency thereof is, in the determination of the Secretary, taking the enforcement actions under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3D68FA4C4BAC4C7AB05AFAA27178986D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil action for private persons</header> <paragraph id="HCB9F03FD60DF45FD8549633E971B1DE9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person aggrieved by an act or omission that is unlawful under this Act may commence a civil action in an appropriate United States district court or State court against any person or entity responsible for any part of the design or construction of a covered dwelling unit no later than two years after the occurrence or termination of the alleged unlawful conduct under this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEF698427BAD848B095B87EDB4904B141"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>In any action under this subsection for a violation involving architectural or construction plans for a covered dwelling unit that were approved by the appropriate State or local department or agency—</text> <subparagraph id="H36FE170507E74D65B48DC8A320F5AAF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if such approved plans violate this Act and any construction on such dwelling that violates this Act was performed in accordance with such approved plans, such State or local department or agency shall be liable for such construction in violation; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H562E6C685D2B4179A02503E43A935A1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such approved plans comply with this Act and any construction on such dwelling violates this Act, the person or entity responsible for the construction shall be liable for such construction in violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H17FD405359E942FAB70164E52CCDC2CE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement by Attorney General</header><text>Whenever the Attorney General has reasonable cause to believe that any person or group of persons has violated this Act, the Attorney General may commence a civil action in any appropriate United States district court. The Attorney General may also, upon timely application, intervene in any civil action brought under subsection (c) by a private person if the Attorney General certifies that the case is of general public importance.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDD5B7E569B954A379B86927A77F729BF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In any civil action brought under this section, if the court finds that a violation of this title has occurred or is about to occur, it may award to the plaintiff actual and punitive damages, and subject to subsection (g), may grant as relief, as the court finds appropriate, any permanent or temporary injunction, temporary restraining order, or other order (including an order enjoining the defendant from violating the Act or ordering such affirmative action as may be appropriate).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9DCF1808AF364D6DA6521B6061E6FA9A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Violations</header><text>For purposes of this section, a violation involving a covered dwelling unit that is not designed or constructed in conformity with the requirements of this Act shall not be considered to terminate until the violation is corrected.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA067DD86A23146E3BE2ACB5941249CB0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees</header><text>In any civil action brought under this section, the court, in its discretion, may allow the prevailing party, other than the United States, a reasonable attorney’s fee and costs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD0A6C2C6E7AF4ACE983C50F9E3FB4A33"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effect on certain sales, encumbrances, and rentals</header><text>Relief granted under this section shall not affect any contract, sale, encumbrance, or lease consummated before the granting of such relief and involving a bona fide purchaser, encumbrancer, or tenant, without actual notice of a civil action under this title.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HC858C9AA9C7C4D22B5808BD0E39C95C8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effect on State laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be constructed to invalidate or limit any law of a State or political subdivision of a State, or of any other jurisdiction in which this Act shall be effective, that grants, guarantees, or provides the same rights, protections, and requirements as are provided by this Act, but any law of a State, a political subdivision thereof, or other such jurisdiction that purports to require or permit any action that would violate this Act shall to that extent be invalid.</text></section> <section id="H2757C5CC77194B09B4AC58EA52F005B3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Disclaimer of preemptive effect on other acts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall limit any right, procedure, or remedy available under the Constitution or any other Act of the Congress.</text></section>
<section id="HBE9A48EBA34646349B1948764F332993"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability of provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act of the application thereof to any person or circumstances is held invalid, the remainder of the Act and the application of the provision to other persons not similarly situated shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

