<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H04EE3E22AD2A41C8A981C23D0A8C8046" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3529 IH: To require the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to study the feasibility of constructing an aramid synthetic fiber aqueduct to transport water from Oregon to California, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3529</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150916">September 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to study the
			 feasibility of constructing an aramid synthetic fiber aqueduct to
			 transport water from Oregon to California, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H90A3005FE6AC4D54B30873FC2327C53A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE9DD344BDDA74B7C88297C4D16AA49FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall conduct a study of the feasibility of constructing an aqueduct using aramid synthetic fiber for the purpose of transporting water from Oregon to California.</text>
 </section><section id="HA1F1B6CDF968412AAC075D955146845D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report describing the results of the study required under section 1.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


