<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3DAC37FA96A0437AB39C2E22D98A1656" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 579 IH: THRIFT Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 579</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150128">January 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for incentives for agencies and the judiciary to increase operating efficiency.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HF1C2987BB1FB401899ADA471614036A5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HABE3F5B7C1CC459B8A0408992F697E3A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>To Help Reduce Inefficient Federal Tendencies Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or as the <quote>THRIFT Act of 2015</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEECDFB015B5C42E98DE15E997F955328"><enum>2.</enum><header>Agency incentive and savings program</header> <subsection id="HC4545446FE6A4CBCB91C341B839AB79C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>In order to provide an incentive for agencies and the judicial branch to re-engineer business processes and otherwise increase operating efficiency, it is the intent of the Congress to allow agencies and the judicial branch to retain a portion of the savings produced by internally generated agency or judicial branch program efficiencies and cost reductions.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H44C5B87C58B44CB38C103C3E37FE1CB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retention of funds</header><text>To be eligible to retain funds, an agency or the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court must submit a plan and an associated request to amend its approved operating budget to the committees of Congress having jurisdiction over appropriations specifying—</text> <paragraph id="HB501BB45638144F8BDA72CB74AD66A6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the modifications to approved programs resulting in efficiencies and cost savings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H19D4572D6ECC4932869ED5FAAF996828"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount and source of the funds and positions saved;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB84AD7B7D4264F80803681B4EF164E23"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the specific positions, rate, amounts, and sources of funds the agency or the judicial branch wishes to include in its incentive expenditures;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB016C0CA4FD941D186BA0E506FE7B743"><enum>(4)</enum><text>how the agency or the judicial branch will meet the goals and objectives established in its strategic plans;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6CF8144C82E44A5BBC3F4A6D7B362D4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>how the agency or the judicial branch will meet performance standards, including those in its performance plans; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0BEAEB2BA8FC423DAFB9A17EF2015698"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other incentive expenditures which the agency or the judicial branch believes will enhance its performance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8BCA9B0076C1405A834BE7262B0DA827"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>All plans and budget amendments submitted to the committees of Congress having jurisdiction over appropriations pursuant to this section shall be delivered at least 30 days prior to the date of the committee meetings at which the request will be considered.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0868585C69D04672B8B6F157803BE081"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>In determining the amount the agency or the judicial branch will be allowed to retain, the committees shall consider the actual savings projected for the current budget year and the annualized savings.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA3A20E94D8844FB089F3F13C53073454"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amount of funding retained</header><text>The amount to be retained by the agency or the judicial branch shall be no less than 5 percent and no more than 25 percent of the annual savings and may be used by the agency or the judicial branch for salary increases, including awards authorized in section 4512 of title 5, United States Code, or other expenditures specified in the agency’s or the judicial branch’s plan if the salary increases or other expenditures do not create a recurring cost to the Treasury in excess of the recurring savings achieved by the agency or the judicial branch in the plan.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDEA7B0663EA74F95BC920A23C8A65307"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Submission of budget request</header><text>Each agency or judicial branch allowed to retain funds pursuant to this section shall submit in its next budget request a schedule showing how it used such funds.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

