<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCDFBBF8234A84F78AD63FD0962CBB764" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3089 : Grants Oversight and New Efficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3089</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20150929">September 29, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To close out expired grants, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC2A62111C37E441697811E9BC3212C37" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA765C6DA06A54D8887A38212E6D6882A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grants Oversight and New Efficiency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GONE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8CC7201BFF63428384673503A6C19906"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identifying and closing out expired grants</header> <subsection id="H0896FEC37DFB44E0A0EC95B9BDE87840"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expired grant report</header> <paragraph id="H80877629AF39480C84BEB858CCFBB577"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall instruct the head of each agency, in coordination with the Secretary, to submit to Congress and the Secretary a report, not later than December 31 of the first calendar year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8396379C144F4D25ADA15CE8E1C30334"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lists each covered grant held by such agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H96FD0A97DF0D4187B293F73B5CFD0EE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides the total number of covered grants, including the number of grants—</text>
 <clause id="H724CB95B3DC649388DFC09F8656DE7B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by time period of expiration;</text> </clause><clause id="HED07023C796B406FB2484E46E47B7C08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with zero dollar balances; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H706B4189F50140568D0D8BA8A99EE6BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with undisbursed balances;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05380DD73FD9460B8DC8D09E3D1966AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for an agency with covered grants, describes the challenges leading to delays in grant closeout; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0428FF5451774A539D6C5C1E049FEBE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for the 30 oldest covered grants of an agency, explains why each covered grant has not been closed out.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D33DC7192BA4E8BA54814B5CC466325"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of data systems</header><text>An agency may use existing multiagency data systems in order to submit the report required under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46CDC31E0CAF409B8808A7661245537A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Explanation of missing information</header><text>If the head of an agency is unable to submit all of the information required to be included in the report under paragraph (1), the report shall include an explanation of why the information was not available, including any shortcomings with and plans to improve existing grant systems, including data systems.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6547596AC9024A8280B290EFC25F92BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice from agencies</header>
 <paragraph id="H666735F0EA1546FD8A98E8B9C49A7239"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the head of an agency submits the report required under subsection (a), the head of the agency shall provide notice to the Secretary specifying whether the head of the agency has closed out grant awards associated with all of the covered grants in the report and which covered grants in the report have not been closed out.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F65F488706142EBA46633020FA0DCAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which all of the notices required pursuant to paragraph (1) have been provided or March 31 of the calendar year following the calendar year described in subsection (a)(1), whichever is sooner, the Secretary shall compile the notices submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) and submit to Congress a report on such notices.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53BE4CAB75FC47C8AFF4B1DA2779BD41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inspector General Review</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the head of an agency provides notice to Congress under subsection (b)(2), the Inspector General of such agency with more than $500 million in grant funding shall conduct a risk assessment to determine if an audit or review of the agency’s grant closeout process is warranted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H250DFA2470B544FCB57E70624C2CBFA8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on accountability and oversight</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date on which the second report is submitted pursuant to subsection (b)(2), the Director of Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall submit to Congress a report on recommendations for legislation to improve accountability and oversight in grants management, including the timely closeout of a covered grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H37DFBB5C563F49F3B2A39FDF4FD60F3E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H89E00FDE419A42DEAF9C0D45D6EB7B43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD05E9E9B3848968CAF20687467CFBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Closeout</header><text>The term <term>closeout</term> means a closeout of a grant account conducted in accordance with part 200 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations, including sections 200.16 and 200.343 of such title, or any successor thereto.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37F274ED023D4704B641E9F615AD6FCB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered grant</header><text>The term <term>covered grant</term> means a grant in an agency cash payment management system held by the United States Government for which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEF73CB4759984A0987267DA3F8DC41DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the grant award period of performance, including any extensions, has been expired for not less than 2 years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F0C21058CF048EF845F84D2B591E196"><enum>(B)</enum><text>closeout has not yet occurred in accordance with section 200.343 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4FDCD0CA1F249F5A8D640131EFAAC04"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20150928">Passed the House of Representatives September 28, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

