<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBDAAE2176E5E458593CE41F5C1857BCC" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3528 IH: Congress Leads by Example Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3528</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150916">September 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to provide enhanced enforcement authority for
			 occupational safety and health protections applicable to the legislative
			 branch, to provide whistleblower protections and other antidiscrimination
			 protections for employees of the legislative branch, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H00C262CF4CE349AA9ABAFD43B8814E4B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD54CF022953842AAB4BB4D0B0D6765ED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congress Leads by Example Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H19A7E15C5EEC49CD8DC9E2F8119B2863"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhanced enforcement of protections of Occupational Safety and Health Act applicable to legislative branch</header> <subsection id="H1CB7CEEA73BE479BBE2D0A203678022F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Subpoena Authority for Office of Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 215(c)(1) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1341">2 U.S.C. 1341(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9B6C878EB1514E0282BD05B38DE024FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>subsections (a),</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (a), (b),</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H22A1E916B5E1414B9C131B1119FFB989"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>657(a),</quote> and inserting <quote>657(a), (b),</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69C8B8B97786436AB34B0298220F1270"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recordkeeping Requirements for Employing Offices</header><text>Section 215(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1341">2 U.S.C. 1341(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H779749CA838D47359AF4C43C90D014AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (6) as paragraphs (4) through (7);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H901BFC872130467C86829D7F6AF72872"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (3) or (4)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (4) or (5)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8F047D1428345E1AC6F060AD0C313AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H942D6B4A90664E16A5FDBB5EEDD64AAA" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HC6FE911A8D2441098E37A18494050A1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recordkeeping requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each employing office shall be subject to the requirements of subsection (c) of section 8 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/657">29 U.S.C. 657(c)</external-xref>) that are applicable to employers under such section, and the General Counsel shall exercise the authorities granted to the Secretary of Labor under such subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BA7C711DDFC409297ABD8580823A49C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibiting Retaliation</header>
 <paragraph id="HE8F9977E8C0143CE828D57F5F426406E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 215 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1341">2 U.S.C. 1341</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E56E7786A49479092503070A55EAB9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d), (e), (f), and (g) as subsections (e), (f), (g), and (h); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9449DEAC0EC41A2A6927DA09AAB248E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A8D77A1564E4549906F50DBAF737977" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HBCCE0E63AA784E9BB031E4C111EA05DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibiting retaliation</header> <paragraph id="H0C89D4C6F72F4B1CABEF9F4E93A193AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employing office may not discharge or in any manner discriminate against any covered employee because such employee has requested the General Counsel to take any action authorized under this section, or has instituted or caused to be instituted, or has testified or is about to testify in, any proceeding that arises from the application of this section to the employing office, or because of the exercise by such employee on behalf of himself or others of any right provided under this section.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H5FBFB0B0F5194759864A7131831FB23A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
 <subparagraph id="H55BA6C51A4354D379735EF2856B8A6E6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Charge filed with general counsel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered employee who believes that he has been discharged or otherwise discriminated against by an employing office in violation of paragraph (1) may file a charge against the employing office with the General Counsel not later than 180 days after the occurrence of the alleged violation. The General Counsel shall investigate the charge.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3175B9C0551140999C82A6F54037D365"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mediation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, upon investigation under subparagraph (A), the General Counsel believes that a violation of paragraph (1) may have occurred and that mediation may be helpful in resolving the dispute, the General Counsel may request mediation under subsections (b) through (e) of section 403 between the covered employee and the employing office.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB99A80F727C34A769E437BF8B27A0281"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Complaint; hearing; Board review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If mediation under subparagraph (B) has not succeeded in resolving the dispute (or if the General Counsel does not request mediation under such subparagraph) and the General Counsel believes that a violation of paragraph (1) may have occurred, the General Counsel may file with the Office a complaint against the employing office. The complaint shall be submitted to a hearing officer for decision pursuant to subsections (b) through (h) of section 405 and any person who has filed a charge under subparagraph (A) may intervene as of right, with the full rights of a party. The decision of the hearing officer shall be subject to review by the Board pursuant to section 406.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H704271E00C13488C8FDBD3FA0C58C984"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is aggrieved by a final decision of the Board under subparagraph (C) may file a petition for review in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, pursuant to section 407.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89DAEE62F5E847A282C15075E54F0062"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 215 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1341">2 U.S.C. 1341</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8E999D52439743D6AB0EE1D957B89A01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (g), as redesignated by paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>subsection (e)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (f)(1)</quote> and by striking <quote>subsection (e)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (f)(2)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E5C600DCA26469CBB4376D466914888"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h)(1), as redesignated by paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>(e)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>(f)(3)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1BCB53A99CC442D86A6A1C5F8C05452"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective Date</header> <paragraph id="HCF5380A8342540F5845CEA19101C7B67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall take effect upon the adoption of regulations promulgated by the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance to implement the amendments in accordance with section 304 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1384">2 U.S.C. 1384</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A0352AA5064C76A717246DF3DA9341"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interim applicability</header><text>During the period that begins on the date of the enactment of this Act and ends on the effective date of the regulations referred to in paragraph (1), the amendments made by this section shall be implemented by the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance, the General Counsel of the Office of Compliance, or a hearing officer or court under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (as the case may be) by applying (to the extent necessary and appropriate) the most relevant substantive executive agency regulations promulgated to implement the provisions of law that are made applicable to employing offices and covered employees (as such terms are defined in the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995) by such amendments.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3B02732C4A95425AADD77BF65AC1EEA8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Application to legislative branch employees of whistleblower protection rules and restrictions on
			 discharge by reason of garnishment and discriminatory treatment by reason
			 of bankruptcy</header>
 <subsection id="H49585C108F8B403B8C614686E3A5F336"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Part A of title II of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1311">2 U.S.C. 1311 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0EC5F83F07BA46D6A3FB0FF97B99914C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text>fair labor standards,</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote><header-in-text>and other protections and benefits</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H979AA0E24A0B4F6FA3660B982562A3D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating section 207 as section 209; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F6C439BF554479B8642500EC094CDE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 206 the following new sections:</text> <quoted-block id="H189004B97D074051B9F9B89FF7A5C4C7" style="OLC"> <section id="H67441708ACD342AEA692B3E203FDCB39"><enum>207.</enum><header>Rights and protections under whistleblower protection rules</header> <subsection id="HA6F51D5FA4A64F709F9A9CEA3655F723"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rights and Protections Described</header> <paragraph id="H3B798A6FEA3649958DFA57A220344986"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No employing office may take or fail to take, or threaten to take or fail to take, a personnel action (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/23">chapter 23</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code) with respect to any covered employee or applicant for employment because of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6C59237BA7DF4631AA31EAC13EE1669C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any disclosure of information by a covered employee or applicant which the employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</text>
 <clause id="H24C5FC6E831049FBB1EAD30A1C9A2BCA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or</text> </clause><clause id="H1B1A3D005FA94812B205F66C6123A033"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety,</text>
										</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">if such disclosure is not specifically prohibited by law and if such information is not
			 specifically required by Executive order or the rules of the House of
			 Representatives or Senate to be kept secret in the interest of national
 defense or the conduct of foreign affairs; or</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC0398AD6CB84F87A1472C0E72E2A6F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any disclosure to the General Counsel, or to the Inspector General of an executive agency or office of the legislative branch or another employee designated by the head of the agency or office to receive such disclosures, of information which the employee or applicant reasonably believes evidences—</text>
 <clause id="HDAFACE2461944961AD77E7EFEEF2BECC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or</text> </clause><clause id="H4FD05FC5B4A749758F6F8191679F6E16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB883182500DD49C191FD41D592CE3546"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section and for purposes of applying the procedures established under title IV for the consideration of alleged violations of this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H70245F44FD1C491B8BB8865CB95E5243"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered employee</term> includes an employee of the Government Accountability Office or Library of Congress; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H257C826EE8DC4D1EA615F4586FBDDB7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>employing office</term> includes the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF74078A78FF847ACB321C0BEB08FB8A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remedy</header><text>The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/12">chapter 12</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, with respect to a prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b)(8) of such title.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HF7C1B11FDF4145FD9F3F8FF3D2BE5604"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations To Implement Section</header>
 <paragraph id="H9BD50FA80C044D189A3F7363CA2DD8D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall, pursuant to section 304, issue regulations to implement this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C2305ACD9354202B305694588E31290"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as the substantive regulations promulgated by the Merit Systems Protection Board to implement chapters 12 and 23 of title 5, United States Code, except to the extent that the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBE6FBB4794234B6285FA1DEAB2598754"><enum>208.</enum><header>Restriction on discharge from employment by reason of garnishment or discriminatory treatment by
			 reason of bankruptcy</header>
							<subsection id="H5A45851FA1CE463D8FEBD9E2343567EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Garnishment</header>
 <paragraph id="H3BAFC56879EE46DDB387B27C473E9DA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rights and protections described</header><text>No employing office may discharge any covered employee by reason of the fact that the employee’s earnings have been subjected to garnishment for any one indebtedness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97871AD1AAEE4FB8AC5BECD3D04E5601"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Remedy</header><text>The remedy for a violation of paragraph (1) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under section 304(b) of the <act-name parsable-cite="CCPA">Consumer Credit Protection Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1674">15 U.S.C. 1674(b)</external-xref>).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H296583AFEA074E8AA82CFC6023B2E118"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bankruptcy</header>
 <paragraph id="H12551DBC309543D3A9A9307F870BAD14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rights and protections described</header><text>No employing office may deny employment to, terminate the employment of, or discriminate with respect to employment against, a covered employee who is or has been a debtor under title 11, United States Code, or a bankrupt or a debtor under the Bankruptcy Act, or another covered employee with whom such bankrupt or debtor has been associated, solely because such bankrupt or debtor—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3DF99186996F470AAB28E6C8F4351955"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is or has been a debtor under such title or a debtor or bankrupt under such Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91706799D9D04D7386132D9B19BCD358"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been insolvent before the commencement of a case under such title or during the case but before the grant or denial of a discharge; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H936C0C903E05412E97C1A9A6C7B5048B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has not paid a debt that is dischargeable in a case under such title or that was discharged under such Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H249D42D36BB44C179997624723AAEBF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Remedy</header><text>The remedy for a violation of paragraph (1) would be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded with respect to a violation of section 525(a) or (b) of title 11, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H106C994A9536413A903C64085DCCF11C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section and for purposes of applying the procedures established under title IV for the consideration of alleged violations of this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC267AF19C6234C018EB9D819C326AA2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered employee</term> includes an employee of the Government Accountability Office or the Library of Congress; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BC6F7FB8C5948929A2D35C2F666E661"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>employing office</term> includes the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEAD8D13FF7244189B3FF0086CEC760F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations To Implement Section</header>
 <paragraph id="H48C9CEC7E4D1416EA815692F7B7D241B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall, pursuant to section 304, issue regulations to implement this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D47EA90CEF04DB59B5CF7F91C42FF6D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as the substantive regulations promulgated to implement section 304 of the <act-name parsable-cite="CCPA">Consumer Credit Protection Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1674">15 U.S.C. 1674</external-xref>) and the substantive regulations promulgated to implement section 525 of title 11, United States Code, except to the extent that the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of any such regulation would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E3E1E688D52415394CFCA0D8D8F3A0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming Amendment to Bankruptcy Code</header><text>Section 525 of title 11, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H4A67C63C60E54EDEBA5AC0C392EE47DD" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HB80DF4D980BB439AAFDAAB405598AFB9"><enum>(d)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H53A1D4678EDF4EBAAADC69115BF49AFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of an alleged violation of subsection (a) or (b) by a governmental unit which is a legislative branch employing office with respect to an employee of such office who is a legislative branch covered employee, the procedures for consideration of the alleged violation shall consist of the procedures applicable under title IV of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC334B1964AE74C84B163D35F46E15577" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HD16D88A7254B4AF482637DD18545FF63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>legislative branch employing office</term> means an employing office described in section 101(9) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, and includes the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F94775024474CD0BB03BB30949E541C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>legislative branch covered employee</term> means a covered employee described in section 101(3) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, and includes an employee of the Government Accountability Office or the Library of Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8CE9A88DA6B94E5A98FDF9045E7272C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other Conforming Amendment</header><text>Section 102(a) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1302">2 U.S.C. 1302(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HD6EE791969FF4992B08031B40C8FA2E3" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H78257EBD38674057B91E70D015FF534F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Section 2302(b)(8) of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2524EA1E2E9423BA492E1F360B1720F"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Section 304 of the <act-name parsable-cite="CCPA">Consumer Credit Protection Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1674">15 U.S.C. 1674</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1BD670D16984E57B2064E0AA8CAADA0"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Section 525 of title 11, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H04D7CFFDEE7A48788AB9DB7BEBD89E2C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical Amendment</header><text>The table of contents for part A of title II of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE34A575973B14D2CBC984B5070CFE7DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the item relating to part A, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="title">Fair Labor Standards,</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="title">and Other Protections and Benefits</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA79F979B85E845C4AC38F7008F89CC29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating the item relating to section 207 as relating to section 209; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E38837DF8BA4EA898D1123B4E9EFB75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 206 the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H907717F9B32B498B9D7C9E7C512A04B6" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 207. Rights and protections under whistleblower protection rules.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 208. Restriction on discharge from employment by reason of garnishment or discriminatory treatment by reason of bankruptcy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H12D8CA2C711E46B88C3F52ADDDE7A28F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requiring retention of records necessary to administer anti-discrimination laws applicable to covered employees</header> <subsection id="H71153005BD9A40938D1F3D262CE95C07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title VII of the Civil Rights Act; Age Discrimination in Employment Act; Americans with Disabilities Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1311">2 U.S.C. 1311</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H084F16B35A5D4C938310DB661DC586D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF98441150CD04921919B167D07624114"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD7A736FCFBE42379398FFFF08E89FA1" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H2084AB9AC87D4F5D8CCB9B733D5D517E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Retention of Records</header>
 <paragraph id="HD769BCBD57DD4169A232A09B421A1F14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring employing offices to retain records necessary to administer rights and protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that the following provisions of law require the keeping of records necessary or appropriate for the administration of this section, such provisions of law shall apply to employing offices:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD75FD17B40EF480E96499CB5F9268ECE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 709(c) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-8">42 U.S.C. 2000e–8(c)</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC74C06BF9094443815E26F2CE6519AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 7(a) of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/626">29 U.S.C. 626(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H943E1448586D48A0B3377C22E3985F2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 107(a) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12117">42 U.S.C. 12117(a)</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H713E3E2D6CE74917AAF00CB633633276"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to records generated on or after the expiration of the 60-day period that begins on the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0DF376BF9054300AACCC8F70F4ABD91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993</header>
 <paragraph id="H9944E17D3E474F248A17BDA490A9A2D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 202(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1312">2 U.S.C. 1312(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>sections 101 through 105</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 101 through 105 and section 106(b)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H701CD6C8A8D6470E93CA2BD138E944D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <subparagraph id="H01B1D6624A424859AFDE198D146010CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the amendment made by paragraph (1) shall take effect upon the adoption of regulations promulgated by the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance to implement the amendment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4B4D8E9FD9945829206E64844C79034"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interim applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period that begins on the date of the enactment of this Act and ends on the effective date of the regulations referred to in subparagraph (A), the amendment made by paragraph (1) shall be implemented by the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance or a hearing officer or court under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (as the case may be) by applying (to the extent necessary and appropriate) the most relevant substantive executive agency regulations promulgated to implement the provision of law that is made applicable to employing offices and covered employees (as such terms are defined in the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995) by such amendment.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5906CFBC685B4113B52DE10D2E26F3A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</header>
 <paragraph id="H03C34AD88ECF4CB0B539D22811DB4667"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1313">2 U.S.C. 1313(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H43F329537E7C419AB8A6AB864F84C936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and section 12(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 11(c), and section 12(c)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABCC4A66852E4CDA914F2AA655741BA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>212(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>211(c), 212(c)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4F872E7B63C484BADC443A5EC522F7C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <subparagraph id="H96212B0A1AA74B1D9C05A8EBF290E2F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the amendment made by paragraph (1) shall take effect upon the adoption of regulations promulgated by the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance to implement the amendment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73BADC4F9DA348178E035ED6260E74C0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interim applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period that begins on the date of the enactment of this Act and ends on the effective date of the regulations referred to in subparagraph (A), the amendment made by paragraph (1) shall be implemented by the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance or a hearing officer or court under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (as the case may be) by applying (to the extent necessary and appropriate) the most relevant substantive executive agency regulations promulgated to implement the provision of law that is made applicable to employing offices and covered employees (as such terms are defined in the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995) by such amendment.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAAFE753D33B4802AFE99A5BCF86F4C5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requiring employing offices to post notice of rights of covered employees and provide training
			 regarding rights and remedies</header>
 <subsection id="HF8E5A2E243FB4B48898B87E8D988EC19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Title V of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1431">2 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 506 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HD001E9BA17E946548D8A0066E37762EB" style="OLC">
					<section id="HC05C2FD31E9145E4820308D57D7B0E83"><enum>507.</enum><header>Requiring employing offices to post notice of rights of covered employees and provide training
			 regarding rights and remedies</header>
 <subsection id="HC05EF0EC6A9B4505961C1E8A2AC99677"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notices of Rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each employing office shall post and keep posted (in conspicuous places upon its premises where notices to covered employees are customarily posted) notices provided by the Board that describe the rights and protections applicable to covered employees of the office under this Act or any other Federal law made applicable to covered employees pursuant to this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H483DB81EBFB14BC78E4687F131F97356"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each employing office shall provide to the covered employees of such office training regarding the rights and protections and remedies applicable to such employees under this Act or any other Federal law relating to the terms and conditions of employment.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBC251BBDBEC5485EBEE1C7A7FA3FB78D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H77EF606F07484EE68A0D7A56EA9A068D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical Amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by amending the item relating to section 507 to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HD615BDF9EDC747F8BC91A42EE000D38E" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 507. Requiring employing offices to post notice of rights of covered employees and provide
			 training regarding rights and remedies.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H828C27BAA6D9448A91FFB99BF2C44A57" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Coverage of legislative branch employees under rules protecting jurors’ employment</header>
 <subsection id="HA9562FD744AD4A67BDE2B3C585202D1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Section 1875(a) of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H03A35074415A468DB46B9E2B42152369"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)(1)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39D5EFC68D284A9A8A50603413982EFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HF465E8B9206D48DBA83CCA411C8990F0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H671F324D7B4242F2836FA38B3DDC7351" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBF77C853E65B4A8C8098A8218D464122"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>employer</term> includes an employing office under section 101(9) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, the Government Accountability Office, the Government Publishing Office, and the Library of Congress; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5923A1F511974521A4F518B1E2CC96F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>permanent employee</term> includes any covered employee under section 101(3) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 and any employee of the Government Accountability Office, the Government Publishing Office, and the Library of Congress, without regard to whether the employee’s term of service or appointment is permanent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H767CA514AA0445EBAD1D7CDC2FB6FC6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) apply with respect to individuals summoned for juror service or serving on juries on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


