<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6DF79426A3B7462ABF075B188A6A4416" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3165 IH: Safer DC Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3165</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150722">July 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the apprehension, detention, and removal of certain aliens arrested by the District
			 of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1F8AE357738D4D0BB69A97C0E00B80C3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H547CCF6A335945E4A705302119DD8093" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer DC Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H94A1244A3F4842A9A47AFD8279A8A6C8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Apprehension, detention, and removal of certain aliens arrested by the District of Columbia</header> <subsection id="HE9E00A0179DC46038078566629FC7D76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>District of Columbia To Promptly Notify Homeland Security on Apprehension of Removable Aliens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The District of Columbia, upon arrest of an individual, shall provide the Secretary of Homeland Security information necessary to determine the citizenship and immigration status of that individual. The information provided shall include, at a minimum, the name of the individual, any aliases used by that individual, and the individuals fingerprints, if available or readily obtainable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9CFCFBBA3031488AB2B6ACEC03C518B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Homeland Security issuance of detainer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving notice under subsection (a) that an inadmissible or deportable alien is in the custody of the District of Columbia, the Secretary, notwithstanding any other provision of law, regulation, or policy, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7BE63D74E1DD4EA0BF7C87746E3F90E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a detainer to detain the alien to the District of Columbia requiring the detention of the alien for not more than 48 hours (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) after the conclusion of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFEB598C7A564488CAC31B5776076B3B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any criminal or other legal proceeding under District of Columbia law (including circumstances where the alien is released on bail following the conclusion of the charging process), after which the alien may be released; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H525451194DEE46648EAB048EEBA87379"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the completion of any term of imprisonment to which the alien may be sentenced under District of Columbia law; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB6BD7E7D8EED486896969C614EFD9FE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take the alien into custody when the alien is released from the custody of the District of Columbia.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAB2D785DF40436095323745CD725034"><enum>(c)</enum><header>District of Columbia To Hold Certain Criminal Aliens</header><text>Upon receipt of a detainer under subsection (b), the District of Columbia shall—</text> <paragraph id="H07265BBFD5BA4FF08DDCBB1A08754E57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hold an alien who has been arrested for a period of up to 48 hours (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) following the conclusion of the District of Columbia charging or dismissal proceeding; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96BD65B26C6F4B9FB6AE346B3021B8E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hold an alien who has been arrested for a period of up to 48 hours (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) after the alien has completed the alien’s sentence under District of Columbia law.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF6B1A51091564AECA589325B66FA53A8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Penalties for failure to take into custody</header>
 <subsection id="H0BC779B4AABD4705A58ABD1D993FA5A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary fails to issue a detainer under section 2(b), no political appointee of the Department of Homeland Security may perform any function described in subsection (b) until such alien is taken into custody.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC41AD4925494434FA20552D87F198931"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The functions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H5BEBDA662CAA4ECB88911867997AF290"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Travel using Government aircraft.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7F77D753C884DE6A0FAF67FFA015476"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Receipt of any non-essential training.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H46314718EFAE43438718BE995F89E48B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Receipt of bonus pay, excluding overtime pay.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DFAFD1E55A343F69298ACF18622F05B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Receipt of any salary increase.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H83866A65107D4C03886DA908E17AAC6E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Fine for violation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any officer of the District of Columbia, acting in his or her official capacity, who knowingly violates section 2 shall pay a civil penalty of not more than $10,000 for each such violation.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


