<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A2501010B654875B8FB887476F3CB18" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2033 IH: Nepal Temporary Protected Status Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2033</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150427">April 27, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To designate Nepal under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit nationals of Nepal to be eligible for temporary protected status under such section.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3BE45C91D4CA4021A4469AED1E4CE22C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBC5D098EB179439ABD16C0478F1E6220" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nepal Temporary Protected Status Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC42A9991BF754ADDB19066ADD98B8BD9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that the extraordinary and temporary conditions caused by the magnitude 7.8 earthquake, its aftershocks, and additional damage in Nepal qualifies Nepal for designation under subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 244(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(b)(1)</external-xref>), pursuant to which nationals of Nepal would be eligible for temporary protected status in the United States.</text></section> 
<section id="HA1235C3063804F71A8AB2275485A5CE2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation for purposes of granting temporary protected status</header> 
<subsection id="H2DB17C1564FA4269810D39711807442D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header> 
<paragraph id="H461C83F3862049318DD6004375105115"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>), Nepal shall be treated as if it had been designated under subsection (b) of such section, subject to the provisions of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D18939E122A4F13BDE71C777E193972"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of designation</header><text>The initial period of such designation shall begin on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall remain in effect for 18 months.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC6046ABDF3947F0871BC083137D7B7A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aliens eligible</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying section 244 of such Act pursuant to the designation made under this section, subject to section 244(c)(3) of such Act, an alien who is a national of Nepal shall be deemed to satisfy the requirements of section 244(c)(1) of such Act only if the alien—</text> <paragraph id="H3F52EFB085074F588462866A0521DA33" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has been continuously physically present in the United States since April 25, 2015;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D345EED0DF2437B9AEA4C8C60BF7C66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is admissible as an immigrant, except as otherwise provided under section 244(c)(2)(A) of such Act, and is not ineligible for temporary protected status under section 244(c)(2)(B) of such Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BFA5F084B3B469695BDED3CA4C76124"><enum>(3)</enum><text>registers for temporary protected status in a manner that the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H855533FA2BF54649B39E08AF7ACEBD90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consent To travel abroad</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall give the prior consent to travel abroad described in section 244(f)(3) of such Act to an alien who is granted temporary protected status pursuant to the designation made under this section, if the alien establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Homeland Security that emergency and extenuating circumstances beyond the control of the alien require the alien to depart for a brief, temporary trip abroad. An alien returning to the United States in accordance with such an authorization shall be treated the same as any other returning alien provided temporary protected status under section 244 of such Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

