<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0E6018FD0D9B400D94396E558807C59C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3698 IH: Military Enlistment Opportunity Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3698</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151007">October 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000622">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize the enlistment in the Armed Forces of
			 additional persons who are residing in the United States and to lawfully
			 admit for permanent residence certain enlistees who are not citizens or
			 other nationals of the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H44E08474934C430DBC05AB532B622254" style="OLC">
 <section id="H69D634E982FF4A81960BD54201502917" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Enlistment Opportunity Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H49DFC431521442A5B058C6437D9534A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Qualifications for enlistment in the Armed Forces</header> <subsection id="HB7CFFB61488147A09A94B8BB86D54D79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional qualified persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of subsection (b) of section 504 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF0EA0E1E8E7C48CB95B3D207B4BC154E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (E); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B8EEB0A5AF94FE98A697FE765147C82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D30410BA42E41D587FA24B49A461014" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HBD0F3FDEC9D3403BA0FD68C1693B2443"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who, at the time of enlistment in an armed force, has resided continuously in a lawful status in the United States for at least two years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53AABBF93FD647BA9D5242EC12B7CF38"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who, at the time of enlistment in an armed force, possesses an employment authorization document issued by United States Citizenship and Immigration Services under the requirements of the Department of Homeland Security policy entitled <quote>Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals</quote> (DACA).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0DC78812FE947DAAC7063EB97B9F206"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Admission to Permanent Residence of Certain Enlistees</header><text>Such section is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F50E68126B84FDEA4B0C33C179DD9F7" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H111AF07E443743B9BAC5DBBD8D691F9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Admission to permanent residence of certain enlistees</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1E008C742120426883954AD5C119EBF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person described in subsection (b) who, at the time of enlistment in an armed force, is not a citizen or other national of the United States or lawfully admitted for permanent residence shall be adjusted to the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under the provisions of section 249 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1259">8 U.S.C. 1259</external-xref>), except that the alien need not—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCBC381CA384F4F4BA8728785F2B12F1E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish that he or she entered the United States prior to January 1, 1972; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7757B6D189E44B348D7A9B0056AAFB63" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comply with section 212(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(e)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F61166220B2421C836027B792C3B0C3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall rescind the lawful permanent resident status of a person whose status was adjusted under paragraph (1) if the person is separated from the armed forces under other than honorable conditions before the person served for a period or periods aggregating five years. Such grounds for rescission are in addition to any other provided by law. The fact that the person was separated from the armed forces under other than honorable conditions shall be proved by a duly authenticated certification from the armed force in which the person last served. The service of the person in the armed forces shall be proved by duly authenticated copies of the service records of the person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26644B4C20EE4EF3841158317005D7E3" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to alter the process prescribed by sections 328, 329, and 329A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1439">8 U.S.C. 1439</external-xref>, 1440, 1440–1) by which a person may naturalize through service in the armed forces.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF442BC04E623483199DCE26FB1200FB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H9B1070D0849142FCA964767B1A3696DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section heading</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heading of such section is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H152735D824ED42F5852CE7D14585DC87" style="USC"> <section id="HCA333A242F3344378E03C87360285636"><enum>504.</enum><header>Persons not qualified; citizenship or residency requirements; exceptions</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H014F0F508DB7483E8CFA279505F28D31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 31 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 504 and inserting the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2C273B31F2D4A77A62C32F78CB8E52A" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">504. Persons not qualified; citizenship or residency requirements; exceptions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


