<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H00A8C7BD00774F1195E259B49D225686" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 930 IH: School Principal Recruitment and Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 930</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To recruit, support, and prepare principals to improve student academic achievement at eligible schools.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H41EAD1E4787B486095CA2A10BBC2F9CC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF9540A62179A410094ACA034EFC12D63" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>School Principal Recruitment and Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H9E25E59F7E6F49169A17B43F02EBB489"><enum>2.</enum><header>Principal recruitment and training</header> <subsection id="H60D7199F718047399E6B7A5F67043DD3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part A of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6601">20 U.S.C. 6601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCED67118BC64A07BD17986D5042591B" style="OLC"> 
<subpart id="HA030CF94D76F468F93911DAEE50714D9"><enum>6</enum><header>Principal recruitment and training</header> 
<section id="HA7CF639C2BB44C479F3FF99161DB619E"><enum>2161.</enum><header>Principal recruitment and training grant program</header> 
<subsection id="HA471311F6D574AD4B343F7993544C534"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1388A84B1FFB4F52AC0A422376E391B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aspiring principal</header><text>The term <term>aspiring principal</term> means an individual who is enrolled in a principal preparation program’s preservice residency that provides training in instructional leadership, organizational management, and the development of teachers.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H868B87E957854A7EB603D3B2B5A7287D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current principal</header><text>The term <term>current principal</term> means an individual who, as of the date of the determination of participation in a program under this section, is employed as a principal or has been employed as a principal.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H19BDBB82CC7F4A13B3A6296A1A708F68"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0E602DB47C0143E59F1D6F37B04726BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local educational agency, including an educational service agency, that serves an eligible school or a consortium of such agencies;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39BC3507930847EA866FDF11BC920565"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State educational agency or a consortium of such agencies;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4E2316B842F74CE4BDCD51CCE940138E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State educational agency in partnership with 1 or more local educational agencies or educational service agencies that serve an eligible school;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69759FE1DDE04321AD4575EB4B772F35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) in partnership with 1 or more nonprofit organizations or institutions of higher education; or</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA608B44431344B3CB2DC19A729BE7F39"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an institution of higher education or a nonprofit organization, if the institution or nonprofit organization can demonstrate a record of—</text> <clause id="H9BC989EF77A0409EBADBAEFE9B6466C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>preparing principals who have been able to improve student achievement substantially; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="HC8D5FDF1C0A74CB98CFBED9661FA3278"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>placing a significant percentage of such principals in eligible schools.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB7E54B65EBC14CB3918C46E8927B7A21"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible school</header><text>The term <term>eligible school</term> means a public school, including a public charter school, that meets 1 or more of the following criteria:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H7055BB91501E46C9BDE4806314D4848C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Is a high-need school.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDF27B42F446848839DA4908CC9689800"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Is a persistently low-achieving school, as determined by the State educational agency.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HDAB80A278E144F33A907298E2D31C99A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Is an achievement gap school, as determined by the State educational agency.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2A23C88E9FD246A1AACFD9C7E65DAFD5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In the case of a public school containing middle grades, feeds into a public high school that has less than a 60 percent graduation rate.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H802DB49C86A945DC96C502A65EB8CF5C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Is a rural school served by a local educational agency that is eligible to receive assistance under part B of title VI.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA418382B3E3F4BE3934BBC9A0B169628"><enum>(5)</enum><header>High-need school</header> <subparagraph id="H0EAA56EF7BCA415188BAFB7052AA4CA1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>high-need school</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H3A97B523D58340ACBFA610E65B7EDB4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an elementary school or middle school in which not less than 50 percent of the enrolled students are children from low-income families; or</text> </clause> <clause id="H0141964141644A418F11D1EFEDC30268"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a high school in which not less than 40 percent of the enrolled students are children from low-income families, which may be calculated using comparable data from feeder schools.</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5DA1BD24A5DE4A34BEBE9309ED6FB5E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Low-income family</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>low-income family</term> means a family—</text> <clause id="H97ADAC5272704F2A977915B704FFF25E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in which the children are eligible for a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>);</text> </clause>
<clause id="H3363D1E0FD5A46CDA2CA6F45B35E9485"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receiving assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text> </clause> <clause id="H41A70083F0E8480B9A17DD917004E2C8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in which the children are eligible to receive medical assistance under the Medicaid program.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF38D293461504A29AF137CADEEBCF686"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Mentor principal</header><text>The term <quote>mentor principal</quote> means an individual with the following characteristics:</text> <subparagraph id="HC0E3ED85E48F4C5985E859822D5235B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Strong instructional leadership skills in an elementary school or secondary school setting.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H839DE6922F564DD2B1549EA665162DF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Strong verbal and written communication skills, which may be demonstrated by performance on appropriate assessments.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H234FDFBF61884C1A8BD577201BFAA782"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Knowledge, skills, and attitudes to—</text> 
<clause id="HBE57CE8BED88487287C92DBB25F5AECD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish and maintain a professional learning community that effectively extracts information from data to improve the school culture and personalize instruction for all students to result in improved student achievement;</text> </clause> <clause id="H674EAB8AB59047419D09B128CB2C8262"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>create and maintain a learning culture within the school that provides a climate conducive to the development of all members of the school community, including one of continuous learning for adults tied to student learning and other school goals;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H224236A3D51B4B23A4237BB711FBDFFB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>engage in continuous professional development, utilizing a combination of academic study, developmental simulation exercises, self-reflection, mentorship and internship;</text> </clause> <clause id="HA239C1A60D12434D9849BE2B6668C94B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>understand youth development appropriate to the age level served by the school and from this knowledge sets high expectations and standards for the academic, social, emotional, and physical development of all students; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H02932A3ACC6447E891D1DE0E0DA8A3F9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>actively engage the community to create shared responsibility for student academic performance and successful development.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F762DCE7911462885706C49560EA31A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Middle grade</header><text>The term <term>middle grade</term> means any of grades 5 through 8.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H01980D9866544A2EB3E6B2966DD09FD2"><enum>(8)</enum><header>School-level student outcomes</header><text>The term <term>school-level student outcomes</term> means, at the whole school level and for each subgroup of students described in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(v) who are served by the school—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF46A79A631F4D7A82C30D60EB2C78A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>student academic achievement and student growth; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H670B90E2210547CD948FB3E60E924076"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional outcomes, including, at the high school level, graduation rates and the percentage of students taking college-level course­work.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8FEB0167E9B04F30AC050C457EB20B66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header> <paragraph id="H10BF40838673446890E42FC257876EF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Principal recruitment and training grant program</header><text>From amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to recruit, prepare, place, and support principals in eligible schools.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H22C67FA7292D44EC9F02EB30BEC23BF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9085B8CB84EB423CA1A9CFC8B78E8E91"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<clause id="HA64639171AB640AB91445FD697EB3A17"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Not more than 5 year duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be not more than 5 years in duration.</text> </clause> <clause id="H5A8CD33B83F547ACBF020DEBEB46D21B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>The Secretary may—</text> 
<subclause id="HD4386AE67F6B40F78AAC47867FA5EBED"><enum>(I)</enum><text>renew a grant awarded under this section based on performance; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HF722858030244B7ABD0FB12B79280564"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in renewing a grant under subclause (I), award the grantee increased funding to scale up or replicate the grantee's program.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC5347A27631B4D4A95D8B78C754317D3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Performance</header><text>In evaluating performance for purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii)(I)—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HD95B59B463694C55942B104E2E52F304"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary's primary consideration shall be the extent to which the principals recruited, prepared, placed, or supported by the grantee have improved school-level student outcomes in eligible schools; and</text> </clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HEE7FA98CE5CC45A684B44591106AD1FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary shall also consider the percentage of program graduates—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H3BF4DC8872D944AD9B18AD370DD598EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>who become principals in eligible schools;</text> </subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H9F9059C0062B48F283377C078B0EB2EA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>who remain principals in eligible schools for multiple years; and</text> </subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H659A8FC4EFCB49BA85C3AEEA7C41C65B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>who are highly rated principals, as determined by the State educational agency.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HF7875719956F4A46B3BB41EF005DE4A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application and selection criteria</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H16126130328A4B9E96363AF19B4AF3CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity that desires a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8656F3CE6C9541BAA556186ABC1E1713"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H419FBD210D2B49E1A664E569DABFE820"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which the entity has the capacity to implement the activities described in subsection (e) that the entity proposes to implement;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H27BD135D8FCE4A1AB9FED69B3E4FC644"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which the entity has a demonstrated record of effectiveness or an evidenced-based plan for preparing principals to improve school-level student outcomes in eligible schools;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H43ED7E1E41B34B5E93F82B636B312C9C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which the entity has a demonstrated record of effectiveness or an evidence-based plan for providing principals trained by the entity with the guidance, support, and tools they need to improve school-level student outcomes in eligible schools, including providing principals with resources, such as funding to ensure supports for quality teaching, access to best practices, and decisionmaking authority over areas such as personnel, budget, curriculum, or scheduling;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC7E39BA2E03D44F4929B81D10A0AB6CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the likelihood of the entity sustaining the project with funds other than funds provided under this section, which other funds may include funds provided under this title other than this section, once the grant is no longer available to the entity; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4F4AB267E9894E0FAB0155001B5CA551"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which the proposed project will serve rural areas or high-poverty areas.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0909474C257D4F1598640D0EF1598942"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Awarding grants</header> <paragraph id="H46DA94E8552C40EAB1D5E6740941A7D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an eligible entity with a record of preparing or developing principals who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFA556F62A3074AE88F501BF230049AA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have improved school-level student outcomes;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99411EACF60A4698875F67B9443B649C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have become principals in eligible schools; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H23F09F792EDD4256A66F79441A3F621A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>remain principals in eligible schools for multiple years.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9D87FAC97F5E4D31AEF67A18BCB33A8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants for rural schools and lowest performing schools</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall, consistent with the quality of applications—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5A90F0496DE44E73A5827E46C219AFEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>award not less than 1 grant to an eligible entity that intends to establish a program that focuses on training or supporting principals and other school leaders for rural schools; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H07CF6D9372644E628C4ABB671BFB55E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>award not less than 1 grant to an eligible entity that intends to establish a program to train and support principals and other school leaders to lead reform efforts in persistently low-achieving schools in a State or more than 1 State.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA1E2B78849A94E39BA8198260A4ED40C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reform efforts</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section to carry out a program described in paragraph (2)(B)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4B9E43A44CA84CA9BC4A2D454CD2CFCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the first year of the grant, shall use grant funds—</text> 
<clause id="H2E2BBE6983334304A53C88E53978EB0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to bring together experts and stakeholders who are committed to dramatic and effective reform of persistently low-achieving schools who can provide input about what the evidence base shows regarding effective school leadership in such schools;</text> </clause> <clause id="HA2E6C944F6654CB285215AF51B0C84F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to collect and develop, in consultation with experts and stakeholders, a core body of knowledge regarding effective school reform leadership in persistently low-achieving schools, which is evidence based; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H17215B582F0F4EDC99E4DCC7FE36FECE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to develop, drawing on the core body of knowledge developed in clause (ii), a leadership training program for principals, mentors, and other school leaders, to prepare and support the principals, mentors, and leaders to lead effective school reform efforts in persistently low-achieving schools; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA9D466940FD4229898B70DC8FF138C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during each year of the grant after the first year, shall use grant funds—</text> 
<clause id="H3789659054954F888473A609DC67633C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to carry out the leadership training program described in subparagraph (A)(iii);</text> </clause> <clause id="HE51FC551254A42349CB972C7BAF54D89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to ensure that the leadership training program described in subparagraph (A)(iii) is informed, on an ongoing basis, by consultation with experts and stakeholders, and by the program’s tracking of the performance of its graduates in leading school reform efforts in persistently low-achieving schools;</text> </clause>
<clause id="HAC323EB0A0B8493FA64B6A3178C49024"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to select cohorts of trained or experienced principals to lead school reform efforts in persistently low-achieving schools;</text> </clause> <clause id="H3D048386BA2D48309BF47B9C801FE52C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to provide support for, and encourage interaction among, cohorts of principals after completion of the leadership training program described in subparagraph (A)(iii); and</text> </clause>
<clause id="HE2AB840B42D443C781DDCBEEABE754C2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to disseminate information to principals, mentors, and other school leaders engaging in reform efforts in persistently low-achieving schools.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H67DE54FF11CF4B1787216D8EB88859F2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use grant funds to carry out all of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H765D9C2AF2F346B5B494EFF722214E22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Recruiting and selecting, using rigorous, competency-based, selection criteria, and training and supporting a diverse group of aspiring principals or current principals, or both, for work in eligible schools.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E31F70D55B74CC59E152434014EDE37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Tracking participants to determine if such individuals are attaining, or have attained, the competencies needed to complete the training and enter into an effective leadership role, and providing counseling and, if appropriate, separation, to participants who the entity determines will not attain, or have not attained, those competencies.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC1A598A45DD74D1FB0F965BC3D139E7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the eligible entity provides a program for aspiring principals—</text> <subparagraph id="HB7643DC5A1C74CD193557E173A04109E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>candidates shall demonstrate awareness of and have experience with the knowledge, skills, and attitudes to—</text> 
<clause id="HC80618DD348B4AB6B247779542229176"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish and maintain a professional learning community that effectively extracts information from data to improve the school culture and personalize instruction for all students to result in improved student achievement;</text> </clause> <clause id="HE028F9A101AF4673BD331E9B09C5CD04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>create and maintain a learning culture within the school that provides a climate conductive to the development of all members of the school community, including one of continuous learning for adults tied to student learning and other school goals;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H54CF9261474E43A9A855471740CA4FE4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>engage in continuous professional development, utilizing a combination of academic study, developmental simulation exercises, self-reflection, mentorship, and internship;</text> </clause> <clause id="H7131111DF66B45D5B1D2317620142F39"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>understand youth development appropriate to the age level served by the school and, from this knowledge, set high expectations and standards for the academic, social, emotional, and physical development of all students; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="HCD702DC36E9A45E1B13972FB1A2312B0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>actively engage the community to create shared responsibility for student academic performance and successful development; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD716442FA494C95ABFD58D9768B290D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the program shall provide aspiring principals with—</text> 
<clause id="H81483D4A35B34540BFE9F8FC219FE3E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a preservice residency that is not less than 1 year in length, and that includes coaching from a mentor principal, and instructional leadership and organizational management experience;</text> </clause> <clause id="H71605B073DFC4151A7FB862897C4BA4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>focused coursework on instructional leadership, organizational management, and the use of a variety of data for purposes of—</text> 
<subclause id="H230FC863B8514E65A440D762E0FB79CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>instruction;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HF93D2DA4DF4D4AFE99F936D2A5CD775F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>evaluation and development of teachers; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="H1455FB700F0848AF84A6251BA0F10868"><enum>(III)</enum><text>development of highly effective school organizations; and</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="H88AED121DD2C43EF8F9927396384B53E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ongoing support, mentoring, and professional development for not less than 2 years after the aspiring principals complete the residency and commence work as assistant principals and principals.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F72B3D0E56149A9868C075B55FCCD3F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Training mentors for principals who are serving or who wish to serve in eligible schools or for aspiring principals who wish to serve in such eligible schools, or for both.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF4FB384DAA44551AC557AAE73C78296"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Providing differentiated training to participants in competencies that evidence shows are critical to improving school-level student outcomes in eligible schools, such as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H52453791ED844C33B4E885FDC755245F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recruiting, training, supervising, supporting, and evaluating teachers and other staff;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A74CD18631D48808B795E873F84C961"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing teams of effective school staff, and distributing among members of such teams responsibilities for leading and improving their schools;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H617A4FDF588947F483CB2D5BCDB49031"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing learning communities where principals and teachers—</text> <clause id="H22C02DA3885247B293EB4A515A7FC176"><enum>(i)</enum><text>share a school mission and goals with an explicit vision of quality teaching and learning that guides all instructional decisions;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H021700A3AFE248D09C036291F1AD72CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commit to improving student outcomes and performances;</text> </clause> <clause id="H72E4B0EC1D584986B4CBE39FB697B8BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>set a continuous cycle of collective inquiry and improvement;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H9619C458E96B4BD5BCB2E26C7F7DD2E4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>foster a culture of collaboration where teachers and principals work together on a regular basis to analyze and improve teaching and learning; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HE3CA29624CAB43DB850890D065F7B8F3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>support and share leadership;</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H89E004B02F20431E965CA146F2E4523F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>where applicable for participants serving elementary schools, offering high-quality early childhood education to the students such participants are serving and facilitating the transition of children from early learning settings to elementary school;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8DB9E5336A2F452396C1FC969CCD710D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>setting high expectations for student achievement;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H37AEFFFF2B0F47ABA25EDEBE2D724E75"><enum>(F)</enum><text>addressing the unique needs of specific student populations served, such as students who are children with disabilities, students who are limited English proficient, and students who are homeless or in foster care;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC96444EC1025488A88D79157CD0F220F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>managing budget resources and school time to support high-quality instruction and improvements in student achievement, such as by extending the school day and year and providing common planning time to teachers and staff;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2D8EF7E9E16C42BEAB8C90743558DBA4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>working effectively with students’ parents and other members of the community;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7AC806AF1044B08B625155907F592E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>using technology and multiple sources of data to personalize instruction;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H74280AA18CA740E2BEDFC4B17EFA22E2"><enum>(J)</enum><text>monitoring and improving the alignment and effectiveness of curriculum, instruction, and assessment, using a variety of data providing evidence of student and school outcomes; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E6B53D17D6B4546B881E5B818C15221"><enum>(K)</enum><text>developing and maintaining a positive school culture where students, teachers, and other staff are motivated to collaborate and work together to achieve goals.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD1EFA75929FB41FAB7690BA313CB5C33"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Delivering high-quality, differentiated, school-level support services and training to current principals of eligible schools, if the eligible entity provides a program for current principals, or during the period described in paragraph (3)(B)(iii) to individuals who have completed the aspiring principal residency, if the eligible entity provides a program for aspiring principals, to help meet the specific needs of the eligible schools they serve, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="HA27CF6C2B33E4CD09F0B84DDEB92A405"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training and support for the design of school-wide improvement plans based on the diagnosis of school conditions and needs informed by data and analysis of classroom and school practices; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA1AC009159AE4E30B7125BCA6F8A008E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support in organizing and training the teams described in paragraph (5)(B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H55E8E8BEB15749B392CE88571ADFC4A4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Making available any training materials funded under the grant, such as syllabi, assignments, or selection rubrics, to the Department for public dissemination.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADE783B3846A486D84ED2C9463A46B41"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Tracking the effectiveness of the program based on, at a minimum—</text> <subparagraph id="H806E36C6EFB64A8794F370536B6293BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>school-level student outcomes at the schools where program graduates have served as principals;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H6EEDA7E240E049C489BF7921C7509D85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the percentage of program graduates who become principals in eligible schools; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBB7862CC9FA3466EA806A83F4E340A82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the percentage of program graduates who remain principals in eligible schools for multiple years.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H62029E9AC0674077A9CB43AF4DBA6F40"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Using the data on the effectiveness of the program for, among other purposes, the continuous improvement of the program.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H566BA740CF7C402E8B962F454CBF4C45"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall submit an annual report, beginning in the third year of the grant, to the Secretary regarding—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC88F929A14F046C996BF518E9A380685"><enum>(1)</enum><text>school-level student outcomes resulting from implementation of the grant activities; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBBA1BDF67E5448ECB89216E0FCA79C47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>data on—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF42EF839988D46229607D2DFBE9D6B02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the percentage of program graduates who become principals in eligible schools;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD4B36DEB0CCF4D4C8144D2E6FB908175"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the percentage of graduates who remain principals in eligible schools for multiple years; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HFFF6AA24FAA04D6EAB088EADC3F1D3F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the percentage of program graduates who are highly rated, as determined by the State educational agency.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1B3E615F4B6A4F2AB17B7792F2A68AD6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header> <paragraph id="H16F287356F814CC5BBB3D9C998B7654E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header> <subparagraph id="H16DE6A3EF0ED4DCB9F39DA4427410B42"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall contribute annually to the activities assisted under such grant matching funds from non-Federal sources in an amount equal to not less than 20 percent of the amount of the grant.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H17B0B15B229D498E98364993BAF27B5A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text>The matching funds requirement under subparagraph (A) may be met by—</text> <clause id="H0F12E5BD0B0947058D73FAAC1DB5C6ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contributions that are in cash or in-kind, fairly evaluated; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H1CF79CBC67DE4F45BAC1AED849530AC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>payments of a salary or stipend to an aspiring principal during the aspiring principal’s residency year.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93B032A873AA41598F85ED1D1075CED4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive or reduce the matching requirement under paragraph (1) if the eligible entity demonstrates a need for such waiver or reduction due to financial hardship.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DF052AC6A184E2D8B4C88C47DA760CC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Grant funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, any other Federal, State, or local funds otherwise available to carry out the activities described in this section.</text> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16D1D510839A4AE7ACD360B1F99DFB1A"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research, evaluation, and dissemination</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8D13FE6D7A94161BD99C7A20F829503"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Available funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts appropriated to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary may use not more than 5 percent to carry out this subsection.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H725CD8F5833E4A55B8D62E8ABFF8A69B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of performance metrics</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall establish performance metrics to evaluate the effectiveness of the activities carried out under this program.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3999AE2B9C49436C87B7CF311D3253CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall, in the entity's annual report to the Secretary required under subsection (f), submit information relevant to the performance metrics described in paragraph (2).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24FB03F06A094040AA3EC9B3C455A5FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2598A7847E1412BAB40E8597D0203F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences—</text> 
<clause id="H095F421888494CCBA103842A19E5F016"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities supported under the grant program authorized under this section, including progress measured by the metrics established under paragraph (2); and</text> </clause> <clause id="H66D2CC79C666406CB8B570026B2DC532"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify best practices to improve school leadership; and</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8D425E727691406DA5AC2A4EBDF03FCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disseminate, in consultation with the regional educational laboratories established under part D of the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 and comprehensive centers established under the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002, research on best practices in school leadership.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H52D9BF5C7C2C4168B7BDC21BE792DF36"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>School Principal Recruitment and Training Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, on lessons learned through programs funded with grants awarded under this section.</text> </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HEE921DA86D024933AA68BA4D278B0F7E"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2016 and each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H09DA645794FB46129ED69754A9975698"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2151 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H73673345F12B433DBF428C4B6F10C121" style="OLC"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry idref="HA030CF94D76F468F93911DAEE50714D9" level="subpart">SUBPART 6—Principal recruitment and training</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA7CF639C2BB44C479F3FF99161DB619E" level="section">Sec. 2161. Principal recruitment and training grant program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection>
<subsection id="HA03FED88AB2D4A8ABA215937C61667AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 2103(a) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6603">20 U.S.C. 6603(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or subpart 6</quote> after <quote>subpart 5</quote>.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

