<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFCF2412DC2E94457A1EEDD909F81ADEB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1705 IH: Clean Water Affordability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1705</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to assist municipalities and regional sewer authorities that would experience a significant hardship raising the revenue necessary to finance projects and activities for the construction of wastewater treatment works, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HAF6EE35375834B43B6AFBA392D99638E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H947B8ACEADEB4EDAA66119974B9CEA01" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H6C9A0C0F2264484986C185BFC7847BC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Water Affordability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEFC4E243AF0445B9A5692D0CAEAFB022"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H947B8ACEADEB4EDAA66119974B9CEA01" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2C0955E8A719469BB1ABD51B69624A57" level="title">Title I—Clean Water Affordability</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HBD5D570FAFF04159BAD7DB8305925F30" level="section">Sec. 101. Integrated planning process.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H072CAAEDD1FC4A5BA14D54CF944A4277" level="section">Sec. 102. Updating of guidance.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7154B335C52141AC8791E2072A276D04" level="section">Sec. 103. Capitalization grant agreements.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF68D9A552AF54C73B992ADF07B8A8233" level="title">Title II—Wet Weather Management</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5D66E0AE73EC4CBEA28C2416C4F8C9F4" level="section">Sec. 201. Technology-based controls for peak wet weather management.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB848CAF2701E4B4C83C283FE025E4B66" level="section">Sec. 202. Wet weather water quality-based standards.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9F090411CF444D29B5A95C1247F202E5" level="section">Sec. 203. Peak wet weather waste water management techniques.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<title id="H2C0955E8A719469BB1ABD51B69624A57"><enum>I</enum><header>Clean Water Affordability</header> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD5D570FAFF04159BAD7DB8305925F30"><enum>101.</enum><header>Integrated planning process</header> 
<subsection id="HBB4D8F48C0DF4F51B8BBC136B2D27BCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 402(a) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CA97276ECAC485B9D2B33656C0D8815" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC72B01C3308F44F9A51223312BE31D0C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Integrated Permits</header> <subparagraph id="HAEC6EF9FDEF7497BA397E34A5A057B59"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of publicly owned permittee</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>publicly owned permittee</term> means either—</text> 
<clause id="HC078CAAD073F4D97BD7340B06CEAD348"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a treatment works (as defined in section 212) that is publicly owned; or</text></clause> <clause id="H293FAD09A1634A28BD4E6211E69FE63C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a municipal separate storm sewer system referred to in this section.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H217B5EC8F2FB40C89517B3E3172DFCE6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Planning approach</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a comprehensive and integrated planning approach to the obligations under this section of a publicly owned permittee—</text> <clause id="H46603EEC4C1A442AB0E5B8DF738248FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under which permit obligations may be implemented according to a schedule that—</text> 
<subclause id="H3A1B219824AA44278851FEDCCCF46475"><enum>(I)</enum><text>accounts for the financial capability of the publicly owned permittee;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8D6CB3B0316E49828F7E7C3683F54F1E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>prioritizes permit obligations according to the most cost-effective and environmentally beneficial outcomes;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H91818FB6775D4CBE9F9BF364A99BE5A5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>accounts for the preexisting maintenance, operational, and regulatory obligations of the publicly owned permittee under this section; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBAE3344DF64A44B2BBCC42D0775BAE84"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>enables the publicly owned permittee to implement innovative approaches to meet those obligations; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HC731FD4A4A6B4CD1BF63DA701C907D20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that accounts for changed circumstances in the obligations of the publicly owned permittee, such as—</text> <subclause id="H64C5916F37D24E278CCDA602916156E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>new innovative treatment approaches;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H43C7545641AA4ECFAD24C69FD48AEAC0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>new regulatory requirements; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF2E669585D0541F4BF21707A1CD64603"><enum>(III)</enum><text>changes in financial capability.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7A1FC53F25A43C099A46C9986C1DA89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration of permits</header><text>Section 402(b)(1)(B) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, except that a permit with a term of more than 5 years but not more than 25 years may be approved if the permittee has an approved integrated plan established under subsection (a)(6)</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H072CAAEDD1FC4A5BA14D54CF944A4277"><enum>102.</enum><header>Updating of guidance</header> <subsection id="HF013D080ECC249B78BEF6B1705F709FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB565117823FA45ED978E71404B8A8893"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1033E84AC5974DA5B124B2E0A61F82DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affordability</header><text>The term <quote>affordability</quote> means, with respect to payment of a utility bill, a measure of whether an individual customer or household can pay the bill without undue hardship or unreasonable sacrifice in the essential lifestyle or spending patterns of the individual or household, as determined by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H552361BCD214486D996F7D0F12F68D35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial capability</header><text>The term <quote>financial capability</quote> means the financial capability of a community to make investments necessary to make water quality-related improvements, taking into consideration the criteria described in subsection (b)(2)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EB74A0EFC294652BF36DA99262E0857"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The term <quote>guidance</quote> means the guidance published by the Administrator entitled <quote>Combined Sewer Overflows—Guidance for Financial Capability Assessment and Schedule Development</quote> and dated February 1997, as applicable to combined sewer overflows and sanitary sewer overflows.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H091713106C67434FB9AAA7EAAE86C838"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updating</header> 
<paragraph id="H80F591E4715441469E9E57545EB85F6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall update the guidance to ensure that the evaluations by the Administrator of financial capability assessment and schedule development meet the criteria described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A34D8BEB78D4ABBB2C65CA4DDCF0317"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The criteria described in this paragraph are that, under the updated guidance—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFCEBC1688CB7421FA20CC8EE0206CDB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in assessing the financial capability of a community—</text> <clause id="HE6CF949AB5EF4695813DFE8CDCA6AAD1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>greater emphasis should be placed on local economic conditions;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0158E8876296430C86BDD8DFBBCCB7D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for regional systems, consideration should be given to the economic conditions of political jurisdictions and significant demographic groups within each region;</text></clause> <clause id="HCB0447BB48B14A949F0E3929DD3A266E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prescriptive formulas for use in calculating financial capability and thresholds for expenditure should not be considered to be the only indicator of the financial capability of a community;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7CF24B871E6D4EE1AEF868542D9336BE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>site-specific local conditions should be taken into consideration in analyzing financial capability;</text></clause> <clause id="HEE1B6A20DD9444879B4EA7F984DC0BB4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a single measure of financial capability or affordability (such as median household income) should be viewed in the context of other economic measures, rather than as a threshold to be achieved; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA09911998DA84E2EA7CAFA7E8EC30827"><enum>(vi)</enum> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H47D9A46647B542F0A8849EB210107BE3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consideration should be given to the economic outlook of a community, including the potential impact of program requirements over time, in the development of implementation schedules; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3AC22D6585FC474383C559247CF4235F" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the assessment should take into consideration other essential community investments relating to water quality improvements;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6151C2EA4074FB1A8863DCE56882783"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the timing of implementation of water quality-related improvements—</text> <clause id="HA31B25035F7F47C4898639512C902D71"><enum>(i)</enum><text>environmental improvement implementation schedules should be structured to mitigate the potential adverse impact on distressed populations resulting from the costs of the improvements;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEF4130C260754873A6D330C5944CFD81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>implementation schedules should reflect local community financial conditions and economic impacts;</text></clause> <clause id="H1F81A730E4A74A1C869E1269309466E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>implementation schedules should allow permittees up to 30 years to implement water quality-related improvements in appropriate cases in which the cost of implementing the improvements places a high financial burden on the permittee; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H93B0F273E8324C7682EE97F4647232CA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>existing implementation schedules should be modified in appropriate cases taking into consideration the criteria set forth in this subparagraph;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H146F0DC2AB8C412D83E74A84156C4F4E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to implementation—</text> 
<clause id="HBA1EF95B8129436FAF162F1040CB79D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a determination of local financial capability may be achieved through an evaluation of an array of factors the relative importance of which may vary across regions and localities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H48F6E61E1B784D789D8AAB54832F4661"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an appropriate methodology should give consideration to such various factors as are appropriate to recognize the prevailing and projected economic concerns in a community; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C9FCA097EDD47A39DCC1D2FA01B91EF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the residential indicator should be revised to include—</text> <clause id="H159A3A871F184F27B040D09D1032BA81"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a consideration of costs imposed upon ratepayers for essential utilities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H78C9EA959CC7461CA5AAF3C5E49EC174"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increased consideration and quantification of local community-imposed costs in regional systems;</text></clause> <clause id="H558C37B417804DAB84D312B72C9F0E12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a mechanism to assess impacts on communities with disparate economic conditions throughout the entire service area of a utility;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2D31C2D295EB461E8CCE722953DAFB42"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a consideration of the industrial and population trends of a community;</text></clause> <clause id="HE3A57EC97E5847A2BF3B5F7C7DE580D3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>recognition that—</text> 
<subclause id="HD046165E8A3B46FAA553450900F01B61"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the median household income of a service area reflects a numerical median rather than the distribution of incomes within the service area; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA10450CA14554B609C9BB7E1B14ED7F6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more representative methods of determining affordability, such as shelter costs, essential utility payments, State affordability criteria, and State and local tax efforts, should be considered;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H167A03BB8725419C88558A66C9DB82A8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a consideration of low-income ratepayer percentages; and</text></clause> <clause id="H79366A225C24450085C114CB985E09CC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>impacts relating to program delivery, such as water quality infrastructure market saturation and program management.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86993482AD85459DBAFA5B091FD32333"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The updated guidance should indicate that, in a case in which a previously approved long-term control plan or associated enforceable agreement does not prohibit modification of the plan or terms of the agreement (including financial capability considerations), and all parties are in agreement that a change is needed or that the plan or agreement does not prohibit reopening to address changes in the economic or financial status of the community since the effective date of the plan or agreement, reconsideration and modification of financial capability determinations and implementation schedules based on the criteria described in paragraph (2) is appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H886F4DB6C91B460EA801FB36327FD792"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall apply the updated guidance, including the criteria described in paragraph (2), to each determination and analysis of affordability, financial capability, or widespread and substantial economic impact related to implementation of a program under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB72F9321D22646038B59F46B3E608664"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication and submission</header><text>Upon completion of the updating of guidance under subsection (b), the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register and submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives the updated guidance.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7154B335C52141AC8791E2072A276D04"><enum>103.</enum><header>Capitalization grant agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 602(b) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1382">33 U.S.C. 1382(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2094D7B8438147A999A732DE52CBB16F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (9);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H081A67CF56264C6DA0B5A98F0DCD7411"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (10) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DCDC55485F14044B0D0DC71A2BC8552"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H89B0B1BCD0534483845AB737ECBD9954" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H337EBFB90AA346C19415094D48286900"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the State will use at least 15 percent of the amount of each capitalization grant received by the State under this title after September 30, 2016, to provide assistance to municipalities of fewer than 10,000 individuals that meet the affordability criteria established by the State under section 603(i)(2) for activities included on the State’s priority list established under section 603(g), to the extent that there are sufficient applications for such assistance.</text> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </title> 
<title id="HF68D9A552AF54C73B992ADF07B8A8233"><enum>II</enum><header>Wet Weather Management</header> 
<section id="H5D66E0AE73EC4CBEA28C2416C4F8C9F4"><enum>201.</enum><header>Technology-based controls for peak wet weather management</header> 
<subsection id="H9AED0707E72F486E8391EC8CC53CEF73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability of effluent limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301(b)(1)(B) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1311">33 U.S.C. 1311(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>, which effluent limitations shall apply at the final point of discharge from the treatment facility and not to flows within the treatment facility;</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9E6813C73A104D5DBE4838BC0569D9DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of effluent limitations during peak wet weather</header><text>Section 301 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1311">33 U.S.C. 1311</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H73C6163BD85148A49EE10A57494E9D13" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HE7220007755E42EB92D8F79DAEB187F7"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Modification of effluent limitations during peak wet weather</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, with concurrence of the State, may issue permits pursuant to section 402 that modify the requirements of subsection (b)(1)(B) with respect to the discharge of any pollutant from a collection system servicing a publicly owned treatment works during periods of peak wet weather, if the applicant demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Administrator that the applicant has a peak wet weather management plan approved by the Administrator or State that—</text> <paragraph id="H73D5AA1BCB6143B1A9280595A66F3BF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>defines the peak wet weather event during which the plan will apply; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD33936337713467F86E7FDE66E6C09D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the management practices to be used by the applicant during peak wet weather events pursuant to guidelines established by the Administrator under section 304(d)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HB848CAF2701E4B4C83C283FE025E4B66"><enum>202.</enum><header>Wet weather water quality-based standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303(c)(2) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1313">33 U.S.C. 1313(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE40BCE2F5D8A4143A9EC5A01E3823E6C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H129D80861A0043E7BE04CA7C11DCD7F4" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum> 
<clause id="HFEB1785AC1FA4A579E4050C85DAF7D29" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>States may adopt peak wet weather-related water quality standards for receiving waters during periods of peak wet weather events (as determined pursuant to section 304(d)(2)).</text></clause> <clause id="H574DEFCEF07E49448CD5AEBD2B6BE881" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Administrator, after consultation with States and not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, and from time to time thereafter, shall develop and publish guidance to States on developing and implementing peak wet weather-related water quality standards to accommodate peak wet weather discharges. </text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H9F090411CF444D29B5A95C1247F202E5"><enum>203.</enum><header>Peak wet weather waste water management techniques</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304(d) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1314">33 U.S.C. 1314(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB6672F748AB24FEA9A2DA50D57D6D502"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (4) as paragraphs (3) through (5), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05781A52DABB431C8AC40944ECECC6BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4975C3760F3B4B55B04DC633D58C4833" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H5BA75D4A4B944E30839B29F4F2147525"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Peak wet weather flow practices and techniques</header> <subparagraph id="HA5607408621145C89F58B67F0BA8D2FE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Information and guidelines</header><text>The Administrator, after consultation with appropriate Federal and State agencies and other interested parties, shall publish not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Clean Water Affordability Act of 2015</short-title>, and from time to time thereafter, information and guidelines for peak wet weather waste water management practices available for use during periods of peak wet weather events by a collection system servicing a publicly owned treatment works to—</text> 
<clause id="H4D6BE2A64BB44C6FB79CFAFE79152112"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prevent damage to the treatment facility;</text></clause> <clause id="H352B3FEE0C2142B89E8A2A1B0FCA537B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maximize the delivery of flow to the treatment facility; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H153ABD18B44743158D0EF27BCBDDE2A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide for appropriate cost-effective controls during peak wet weather events. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEBB5E89A9ABD426E9CF388DAAA6F280F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of guidelines</header><text>The guidelines shall include options for the types of technologies and management approaches available to manage peak wet weather-related wastewater flows, including—</text> 
<clause id="H3EEE42CED2B241709AEB448904ADDF6F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>technologies and management approaches relating to facility and collection system storage methods (including in-system treatment methods throughout the collection system);</text></clause> <clause id="H6DF9C34B872F450191409C803721DF43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>facility and collection systems operations and maintenance systems;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HECD5BF5ECD9F44198E7D9756276E1D56"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>monitoring and reporting systems; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB63181AFCF534198BE9A8936A082F809"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>alternative treatment methods and technologies that can achieve applicable water quality.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </title> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


