<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0F99B3A36EDC416390126C9E0311F10E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3846 IH: Historic Tax Credit Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3846</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151028">October 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve the Historic Rehabilitation Tax Credit, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7A149972E41F4DECAD7A710A965A6408" style="OLC">
 <section id="H88ED48AB2E3A4804985AFDA334D80F7D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Historic Tax Credit Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4786140CCDAF4738AD0D8CDAA85844F5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increase in the rehabilitation credit for certain small projects</header> <subsection id="H55A4F5013429416D9AAFFC956AF183D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/47">Section 47</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to rehabilitation credit) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HA11CB74842084977983A67F9946F2825" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H6768C27BA49B443DB3D2A6601C2FA233"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rule regarding certain smaller projects</header>
 <paragraph id="H712EE7F873F547AEB01E973E2E0233A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any qualified rehabilitated building or portion thereof—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4D64B221B304D85B30A5861EA3093F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is placed in service after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCB1F4C8C43D453AAC6888BC9ED19D92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is a smaller project,</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">subsection (a)(2) shall be applied by substituting <quote>30 percent</quote> for <quote>20 percent</quote>.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE368C39E32F4141AF9056C06B67C22E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum credit</header><text>The credit determined under this subsection with respect to any smaller project for all taxable years shall not exceed $750,000.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B6F8FC7828488BA7CB90F652EE9642"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Smaller project defined</header>
 <subparagraph id="H83CA4D3E129D478EB869F7F171F3791D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>smaller project</term> means any qualified rehabilitated building or portion thereof if—</text> <clause id="HF054EB89846B462E95C1253A04D297F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the qualified rehabilitation expenditures taken into account for purposes of this section (or would have been so taken into account if this subsection had been in effect for all prior periods) with respect to the rehabilitation are not over $3,750,000, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE807F6F4C8AC46D5B56B7EA1E1FB44DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no credit was allowed under this section for either of the 2 prior taxable years with respect to such building.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A5355FC4E224696AE9CFF363512FA69"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Progress expenditures</header><text>Credit allowable by reason of subsection (d) shall not be taken into account under subparagraph (A)(ii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC7A63F468C148BC8200C00CFDB4DFE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to periods after the date of the enactment of this Act, under rules similar to the rules of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48">section 48(m)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H5A7166D2661E4F72A6E9D076F8C72618"><enum>3.</enum><header>Allowance for the transfer of credits for certain small projects</header>
 <subsection id="H2DAEF16A2D7245DFB3F7DBFDA9F55220"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/47">Section 47(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 2, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HDEAA7CF9A925408AA60D1C040FD6A532" style="OLC">
					<paragraph commented="no" id="H0E16A355E6BB4F94BC1328122BDD7C32"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transfer of smaller project credit</header>
 <subparagraph id="H070C168C8985473986C807A77C5ACF39"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B) and such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary may provide, the taxpayer may transfer all or a portion of the credit allowable to the taxpayer under subsection (a) for a smaller project.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7EA4EF434CF403295FC11453AB6D274"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification</header>
 <clause id="H55F209D91BE04D80AC99E3B5A8EA5430"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A transfer under subparagraph (A) shall be accompanied by a certificate which includes—</text> <subclause id="H9B5BB8B420324CFBA1032B904808F58F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the certification for the certified historic structure referred to in subsection (c)(3),</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF1D4B1FBA5D446E98BFF9D7CD6A4743D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s name, address, tax identification number, date of project completion, and the amount of credit being transferred,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEB6481130A8B4EC4A47328A762DA2585"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the transferee’s name, address, tax identification number, and the amount of credit being transferred, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H759631363BD74EECB9C2F6AD707D3E2B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>such other information as may be required by the Secretary.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H0B5A46F984B14503BC48CCC84B35EC2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Transferability of certificate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certificate issued under this section to a taxpayer shall be transferable to any other taxpayer, except that a certificate may not be transferred more than once.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCBE14D7DB5E41C3BB5442409D22B1CD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Tax treatment relating to certificate</header>
 <clause id="H1F0FE8C76C5C4ADBBBA8C8BBEBD62329"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Disallowance of deduction</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed for the amount of consideration paid or incurred by the transferee.</text> </clause><clause id="H282083B857624500A44F186D78DBEAC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>The amount of credit transferred under subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <subclause id="HE6D0D06123E64389AD306EE3C81B678B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall not be allowed to the transferor for any taxable year, and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HAF5724CE64A448AF9313C693D71A65AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be allowable to the transferee as a credit under this section for the taxable year of the transferee in which such credit is transferred.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H93BC11CAB1324987BA6A0795A275D0F5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Recapture and other special rules</header><text>The taxpayer who claims a credit under this section by reason of a transfer of an amount of credit under subparagraph (A) with respect to a smaller project shall be treated as the taxpayer with respect to the smaller project for purposes of section 50.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BB45C47972F418A86BAB55B07FA49F1"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Information reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The transferor and the transferee shall each make such reports regarding the transfer of an amount of credit under paragraph (A) and containing such information as the Secretary may require. The reports required by this subsection shall be filed at such time and in such manner as may be required by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05F70AFCEB8641F8B019888C3F731696"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations or other guidance to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H5061F184957245F59E1BC90CCD079AB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to periods after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF772A6AEC7124073A46E2BE9B4154085"><enum>4.</enum><header>Increasing the type of buildings eligible for rehabilitation</header>
 <subsection id="H1EFD5638499C4BC1873D89797F0793E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/47">Section 47(c)(1)(C)(i)(I)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>50 percent of</quote> before <quote>the adjusted basis</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H97762A2461B64525BED25011C439A5EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9758B02A613C4988AC058FAFC39A5044"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reduction of basis adjustment for rehabilitation property</header>
 <subsection id="HA2EF1F6FBC13464EA6BE1486790F94A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/50">Section 50(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA71C9868AD8A43A6B3388C51EBE6D37D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA9297F81EB544A0DB74AE269384BE512"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rule relating to the rehabilitation credit</header><text>In the case of any rehabilitation credit—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2EAC09C568B644DEB299969053CF3EE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">only 50 percent of such credit shall be taken into account under paragraph (1), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE303F2A5BA0415CA7180E455AEF4D37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>only 50 percent of any recapture amount attributable to such credit shall be taken into account under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H95A5784141D948DCBD4CC5FF5C34B32B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with basis adjustment</header><text>Section 50 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88C233446AE647B09507E7F996E8E4FA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H9EF6644462FE491D85FD00B0AC6DC71C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with basis adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying the provisions of former section 48(d)(5)(B) pursuant to subsection (d)(5) to a lease of property eligible for the rehabilitation tax credit, the lessee of such property shall include ratably in gross income over the shortest recovery period that could be applicable under section 168 with respect to such property an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of the credit allowable under section 38 to the lessee with respect to such property.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9C7C6706CC674ADB826A74A69B2E93A6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Special rules for dispositions of state historic tax credits</header>
 <subsection id="H5A156DDD611140E0AEC3CE4CDC1ED823"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part III of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to items specifically excluded from gross income) is amended by inserting after section 139E the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H9A35B8B214B4426093F31500246146D4" style="OLC">
					<section id="H85FC521A827240B5BFC047A9348E0E9D"><enum>139F.</enum><header>Dispositions of state historic tax credits</header>
						<subsection id="H1C9DE42DC09A44D3830749D9D6CC734D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusion from income; basis reduction</header>
 <paragraph id="H2371467DCAAE4115AACB82214304C432"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a taxpayer who receives a State historic tax credit and transfers such credit by sale, allocation, or otherwise, or receives a refund of all or a portion of such credit—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H28E2E2B05BA148A8A9ED017F096BC771"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no portion of the net proceeds of such allocation, disposition, or refund of such credit shall constitute income to such taxpayer under section 61(a), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1BBF7B27CC246429B417BB980E12F2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s basis in the property with respect to which the State historic tax credit is allowed shall be reduced as determined under paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC06692968F1443EB1D9C4763B6B30EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of reduction in basis</header><text>The reduction in basis under paragraph (1) shall be applied—</text> <subparagraph id="H7678DB0098984CF8BC976FA5062D62DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>first, against the basis in the land,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89564639027747209B6C1D5BD46E611D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>second, against so much of the basis of any building or interest therein as was not treated as a qualified rehabilitation expenditure by reason of clause (ii) or (iii) of section 47(c)(2)(B), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1B8E76E208A4A52853D83697BE88A90"><enum>(C)</enum><text>third, against the remaining basis in the property.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AAC50D83E6942C89E45854B4F1B4996"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Adjustment in basis of interest in partnership or s corporation</header><text>The adjusted basis of—</text>
 <clause id="H7D8D8F182FD34029A757FBCC85CE36E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a partner’s interest in a partnership, or</text> </clause><clause id="H1A7F771290144DAC8F5ABCBD9339FA66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>stock in an S corporation (as defined in section 1361(a)(1)), shall be appropriately adjusted to take into account adjustments made under this subsection in the basis of property held by the partnership or S corporation (if any).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD27A7EDF8C1405A800C80667B3EB2BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Election To include in income</header>
 <paragraph id="HEB608723301A40B684242761E425429A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a taxpayer who elects to have this subsection apply—</text> <subparagraph id="HF192229329A643AAB5C92AF011764AB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the net proceeds of the allocation, disposition, or refund described in subsection (a) received by such taxpayer shall constitute income to such taxpayer under section 61(a), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68A589DADBA54D1B855784D06BFDD768"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsection (a)(1)(B) shall not apply.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26C79C7484B74531BA3421F5B7A55CE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Making of election</header><text>An election under this subsection shall be made at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe. Such election shall apply for the taxable year for which it is made and for all subsequent taxable years and may be revoked only with the consent of the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA617E0826BD9486FB13DDD0C0D01A7DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on qualified rehabilitation expenditures and rehabilitation credits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining the rehabilitation credit allowable to a taxpayer under section 47, the transfer or allocation of State historic tax credits with respect to any property by a taxpayer shall not affect or reduce the amount of qualified rehabilitation expenditures (as defined in section 47(c)(2)) incurred in connection with such property, nor shall such transfer or disposition, nor any basis adjustments under subsection (a), be treated as an early disposition of investment credit property for purposes of the recapture provisions of section 50, notwithstanding any reduction in basis pursuant to paragraph (a)(2)(C).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFD81B7F3CA2B419A98FACBEE4067A1FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State historic tax credits defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>State historic tax credit</term> means any credit against State or local tax liabilities which—</text> <paragraph id="H2C07494A2F1846D5ABC082AE94E5BD89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is allowable under the laws of any State or political subdivision thereof to a taxpayer with respect to expenditures made for the rehabilitation of property identified by such laws, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H440B1235022E402793A65C7ECE21A1A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>can be allocated, disposed, or refunded under such laws.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HFBE236E0764346ABAD6EE3085A46EABA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such part III is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 139E the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H02540A2BCE9E4FE3970B0E8F115AAB1F" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 139F. Dispositions of State historic tax credits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H163CC6E270274FB18F926BD16FB02112"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply to transfers or dispositions made, or refunds received, after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4732BD387D394E1197C29CE0D70E1F63"><enum>7.</enum><header>Modifications regarding certain tax-exempt use property</header>
 <subsection id="H4C78ECEA2FA648EBAB826A3635D1D6A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/47">Section 47(c)(2)(B)(v)(I)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to tax-exempt use property) is amended by inserting <quote>and subclauses (I), (II), and (III) of section 168(h)(1)(B)(ii) shall not apply</quote> after <quote>thereof</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9DE924C9E174F9B891C739093488C2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to property placed in service after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA8743120BC12465A988230F56B58BC7A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Eliminating functionally related properties</header>
 <subsection id="HA7AD1010D136416A99E2B61311E47C20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/47">Section 47</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to rehabilitation credit), as amended by sections 2 and 3, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H602D0E86A3E34EDE873FAEFE8BE50206" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HB3CEACD44E1D4E0BB8E5B279E38E4EE8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Related buildings</header><text>Buildings that are functionally related ( as defined in Part 67.6(b)(4) of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations) shall be treated as separate certified historic structures for purposes of the credit allowed under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E8B166A05404642BAE5E68D0EAB49FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to any application to the National Park Service received after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


