<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2CF2EAA6E65A4C888C0013586266ABA6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1060 IH: Sacramento Valley Water Storage and Restoration Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1060</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150225">February 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior to take actions to support non-Federal investments in water
			 infrastructure improvements in the Sacramento Valley, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H66F5E71CB812491AABD8014DA9064594" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1B926B247B85406D812186031FD067E0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sacramento Valley Water Storage and Restoration Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5E3D4B5E88947838BCB9DD6D1AF32DE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA084508A52F240AD84A4F643150F5914"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The State of California and much of the West are experiencing one of the driest years on record, exacerbating water supply problems caused by a lack of surface water storage infrastructure. The drought conditions have caused reductions in water supplies to almost all water users in the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA0D38A6AD5E4ED78F1D755E5F1DA9BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Sites Project has been identified by the State of California and the Federal Government as an important component to integrated water management in the Sacramento Valley that would advance the co-equal objectives of improving water management and restoring ecological health for beneficial uses of the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta and the Sacramento River watershed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A94486D8C524C23B4F1744501CF681F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Among other things, the Sites Project would—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DA68B6997BA4709AF11DE0D150713DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase surface water storage to enhance water management flexibility in the Sacramento Valley;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FB3078E74C24E76A317F75839CD162B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide flood control benefits;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H913B04B1704C45F1817BA3AC5593AEE7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve conditions for fish, waterfowl, and wildlife in the Sacramento Valley, including anadromous fish in the Sacramento River; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H235E645503E84305B411582AB5C8B38E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improve the operation of the State’s water system to provide improvements in ecosystem and water quality conditions in the Bay-Delta while providing a more reliable water supply for the State of California.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDD3E0683B6B456EA308A769BE2074B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Sites Project has been shown to provide approximately 1,300,000 of additional yield when the Sites Project is integrated into the operations of other State and Federal reservoirs upstream of the Bay-Delta.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E4E54AE9FFC4A46A5807E6BDDAA1595"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Healthy wetlands are of vital importance to wildlife in California and require a reliable supply of water, and additional surface water storage can help meet water supply goals under the Central Valley Project Improvement Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC600EE19B96C4D349652D1ECD4F9F091"><enum>(6)</enum><text>It is in the interests of the United States for the Federal Government to work with the Sites Project Authority, which has been established under laws of the State of California as an independent joint powers authority to, among other things, study, promote, develop, design, finance, acquire, construct, manage, and operate Sites Reservoir and related facilities, in order to advance the Sites Project in the most expeditious and cost-effective manner possible.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HEB7197088F49486BBCD6AFF36A47262A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB4294C5F2A3F4F98B1DCB367EA344302"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H658F7925AA014B42A09FE9F2D3FDF38B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <quote>Commissioner</quote> means the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H68608C11FFE34CAA9325BA01B92D823B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text>The term <quote>Bureau</quote> means the Bureau of Reclamation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB62DF09853D9404EBCCBAEC6CE86D4BC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The term <quote>Authority</quote> means the Sites Project Authority that entered into a Joint Powers Agreement on August 26, 2010, for the purpose of advancing the Sites Project as a non-Federal facility and includes Glenn-Colusa Irrigation District, Reclamation District 108, the Tehama-Colusa Canal Authority, Maxwell Irrigation District, the County of Glenn, the County of Colusa and Yolo County Flood Control and Water Conservation District.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD02E84F357324A08BB9EF3069B23E173"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sites project</header><text>The term <quote>Sites Project</quote> means the Sites Reservoir in Glenn and Colusa Counties, California, and related facilities, including associated water conveyance and hydropower generation and transmission facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC79A61D9D9884A6B9CE3BC5E5DE24EDD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the State of California.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B851962FB844A0F9BB1F86CE0502E64"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Central valley project</header><text>The term <quote>Central Valley Project</quote> means all Federal reclamation projects located within or diverting water from or to the watershed of the Sacramento and San Joaquin rivers and their tributaries as authorized by the Act of August 26, 1937 (50 Stat. 850), and all Acts amendatory or supplemental thereto, including but not limited to the Act of October 17, 1940 (54 Stat. 1198, 1199), Act of December 22, 1944 (58 Stat. 887), Act of October 14, 1949 (63 Stat. 852), Act of September 26, 1950 (64 Stat. 1036), Act of August 27, 1954 (68 Stat. 879), Act of August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 719), Act of June 3, 1960 (74 Stat. 156), Act of October 23, 1962 (76 Stat. 1173), Act of September 2, 1965 (79 Stat. 615), Act of August 19, 1967 (81 Stat. 167), Act of August 27, 1967 (81 Stat. 173), Act of October 23, 1970 (84 Stat. 1097), Act of September 28, 1976 (90 Stat. 1324) and Act of October 27, 1986 (100 Stat. 3050).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C272ED7EDD34EE88DB62FD33D72A02D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Repayment and water service contracts</header><text>The terms <quote>repayment contract</quote> and <quote>water service contract</quote> have the same meaning as provided in sections 9(d) and 9(e) of the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 (53 Stat. 1187, 1195), as amended.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3913A0CDDCB74B23B61C54208576213F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Feasibility study and environmental impact statement</header>
 <subsection id="H2D95250C9ED84135A746746C0DD7D394"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Feasibility study</header><text>No later than December 15, 2016, the Secretary, acting through the Bureau, shall finalize and publish in the Federal Register, the feasibility study authorized in section 103(d)(1)(i)(II) of title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/361">Public Law 108–361</external-xref>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE4FFA2B6B55A4874814516AACBFBE93A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Environmental impact statement and environmental impact report</header><text>No later than June 30, 2015, the Secretary shall work with the Secretary of Commerce, the Army Corps of Engineers and the Environmental Protection Agency Administrator to coordinate the efforts of the relevant agencies and work with the State, the Authority, and other stakeholders to complete and issue the final joint environmental impact statement and environmental impact report on the Sites Project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H48B2352892314DAEA63EFEA870FB56B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of documents</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that all documents associated with the preparation of planning and feasibility studies and applicable environmental reviews under the National Environmental Policy Act for the Sites Project shall be made available to the Authority.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD0D513E536F24CEAACDE5060D2D5FF72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Financial assistance and other agreements</header><text>To assist the Secretary in meeting the deadlines for completing the feasibility study and environmental impact statement identified in this section, no later than 90 days following enactment, the Secretary, acting through the Bureau, shall enter into such agreements with the Authority, including financial assistance agreements, to carry out such work as the Bureau and the Authority mutually agree is appropriate to ensure that all studies and environmental reviews are completed on an expeditious basis and that the shortest applicable process under the National Environmental Policy Act shall be utilized, including in the completion of the final feasibility study and final joint environmental impact statement and environmental impact report on the Sites Project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB46111D8ACA74777B595BEFD34252392"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Non-Federal cost-Share</header><text>The Secretary shall attribute all funds expended, or in-kind services provided, by the Authority or the State to advance the Sites Project, including the $42,379,999 in non-Federal funds provided to the North-of-Delta Offstream Storage Feasibility Study reflected in the Bureau’s fiscal year 2015 Budget Justification, to the non-Federal share of cost-share requirements for any Federal support provided to the Sites Project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAC42B100F3294B6D8BF9B2B26CF527E9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Requirements of existing law</header><text>Nothing in the section herein modifies existing requirements of Federal law.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H641DB09CA1EB43DE98DB2553B228FCAA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Construction</header> <subsection id="H0D7527AE11C142C1B8982A097B32F418"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of construction</header><text>Section 103(d)(1)(B) of title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/361">Public Law 108–361</external-xref> (the Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act, 118 Stat. 1681) is amended by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBC96D87815524B8EAB4EB2DBB8D49C64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>adding after clause (i) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFB024751651D47F6B4D6441A7119D8A1" style="OLC"> <clause id="HF7271860F5844C108650EAE91D2CEAC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Construction authorization</header><text>If the Secretary determines the project described in clause (ii)(I) of subparagraph (A) is feasible, the Secretary is authorized to carry out the project in a manner that is substantially in accordance with the recommended plan, and subject to the conditions described in the feasibility study.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE6826C8A6CA46B194CCE156886607E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>striking in clause (iii), <quote>the project</quote> and inserting <quote>a project described in clause (ii)(I) of subparagraph (A)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H648757EAEB9343B1A51B234291890A98"><enum>(3)</enum><text>redesignating clause (ii) and (iii) as clause (iii) and (iv), respectively.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3163672D6EF74DB9B4B932B7E80636D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project partnership agreements</header><text>At the request of the Authority, the Bureau shall—</text> <paragraph id="H166734DF786646B2ABD21E43E6A216F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enter into a project partnership agreement with the Authority for the Authority to provide full project management control for construction of the Sites Project, or a separable element of the project, in accordance with plans approved by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D835B024114ADCBABB9E678492E252"><enum>(2)</enum><text>following execution of the project partnership agreement, transfer to the Authority interest to carry out construction of the project, or a separable element of the project—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDC79E646493B4E9687BB6BB92EB51EAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if applicable, the balance of the unobligated amounts appropriated for the Sites Project, except that the Secretary shall retain sufficient amounts for the Bureau to carry out any responsibilities of the Bureau relating to the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CF5BAE76F134B7F8BE37EBE2DFD002F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional amounts, as determined by the Secretary, from amounts made available to the Secretary, except that the total amount transferred to the non-Federal interest shall not exceed the updated estimate of the Federal share of the cost of construction, including any required design.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FDD9AAEAFF848308AF91AD14C22B0B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Detailed project schedule</header><text>Not later than 180 days after entering into a Project Partnership agreement, the Authority, to the maximum extent practicable, shall submit to the Secretary a detailed project schedule, based on estimated funding levels, that lists all deadlines for each milestone in the construction of the project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEDF301D446D34A14A2454C33EBA23B9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>All laws and regulations that would apply to the Secretary if the Secretary were carrying out the project shall apply to Authority, if the Authority enters into an agreement with the Secretary to carry out the project under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HFB617A417DD14B35A3D58B7FCAA2999E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Non-Federal project</header>
 <subsection id="H50EA7CCEC78E455FB0B2C9F31AB0A7D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At any time, notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, if the Commissioner determines and the Secretary concurs, that the Sites Project can be expedited by the Authority as a non-Federal project, and that there is a demonstrable Federal interest for the Sites Project to be constructed and operated as a non-Federal project, the Bureau is authorized and directed to take any and all actions possible to advance the Sites Project as a non-Federal project, including, but not limited to, entering into cost-shared financial assistance agreements with the Authority to support construction of the Sites Project as a non-Federal project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D83AAA114AB4CA2926B6BAD7A8FE94A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Title; operations and maintenance</header><text>The Authority shall hold title to all facilities constructed under this section, and shall be solely responsible for the operation and maintenance costs of such facilities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H851DA454591649E7BE76E53F878F54F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal reviews and permits</header><text>The Bureau shall be the lead Federal agency for the purposes of all Federal reviews, analyses, opinions, statements, permits, licenses, or other approvals or decisions required under Federal law to allow the Authority to construct the Sites Project as a non-Federal project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H293B903ACDF843F1945DC1629C1594C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordinated operations</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to execute and implement a long-term agreement between the United States of America and the Authority that shall provide for the coordination of operations of the Central Valley Project and the Sites Project to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H16AAD1F20DE643FFB8B5776FCCF55A92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>satisfy any contracts entered into in subsection (e) of this Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0043D17A05544BD9947689E9EFDA332"><enum>(2)</enum><text>help meet any unmet needs for Sacramento Valley in-basin water uses;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3638DE29FFC442699F82B526EFCF7466"><enum>(3)</enum><text>help meet any unmet needs of existing Central Valley Project repayment and water service contracts; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAAC6DE136AD4C609F7E24BC792739C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that any surplus water supplies from the Sites Project are put to full and beneficial use.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89A915630B49401094A154148B81A813"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to enter into long-term contracts with the Authority to acquire water supplies made available from the Sites Project for the purposes of meeting the requirements section 3406(b)(3) and section 3408(j) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/575">Public Law 102–575</external-xref>, the Central Valley Project Improvement Act, and such other purposes as the Secretary may deem appropriate.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H99940196E8F84BC9ADD560D6FDB0608C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Environmental review and permitting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to the Sites Project, the Bureau shall—</text> <paragraph id="H5DFF54C1383D4CB7981D5E6D3D93E43C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be the lead Federal agency for the purposes of all Federal reviews, analyses, opinions, statements, permits, licenses, or other approvals or decisions required under Federal law to allow either the Bureau or the Authority to construct the Sites Project, including all requirements under—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H22AC9DFAB1EB45B5B8A8C406C71200F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCE70DAB984446A28C74BBDDB7C05C54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF970CF238DBA4DC5AF8767D06041A325"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other Federal law applicable to the construction of the Sites Project facilities by the Bureau or the Authority; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93D3DE1303BF497C91C5F247996350CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take such steps as are necessary to ensure that all Federal reviews, analyses, opinions, statements, permits, licenses, or other approvals or decisions required under Federal law to allow either the Bureau or the Authority to construct the Sites Project are completed on an expeditious basis and utilize the shortest applicable process.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H2A3465AF517947B7846B95A0FB41443C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Compliance with environmental laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act modifies or alters any obligations under—</text> <paragraph id="HCA2D44F00A9543C9843BC6F2401A7A09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FC7633A6E5640A6AE504A6EB3C5074C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H8762682CDF8F4EE59189AC4DCE12CE6B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preempt any existing State law, including but not limited to area of origin and other water rights protections.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


