<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H311D36C6F7F94309AA4E5F0F0698CB43" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2967 IH: Using Evidence to Move Welfare Recipients into Work Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2967</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150708">July 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000064">Mr. Young of Indiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To develop a database of projects that are proven or promising in terms of moving welfare
			 recipients into work.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H12048CDF366E413F9D139D7045360E7C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3425D0F845E04BFE83C564793FBEFD8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Using Evidence to Move Welfare Recipients into Work Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H31AED9CCA05F44489A6367F053F6744B"><enum>2.</enum><header>What Works Clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 413 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/613">42 U.S.C. 613</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86507C4A4DBA4443B15D1DB39320E4D1" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H4207443C065A4A86B431171D4C63B3C9"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Development of what works clearinghouse of proven and promising approaches into move welfare
			 recipients to work</header>
 <paragraph id="H518930E71D0F46E391329B93654C3C87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall develop a database (which shall be referred to as the <quote>What Works Clearinghouse of Proven and Promising Projects to Move Welfare Recipients into Work</quote>) of the projects that used a proven approach or a promising approach in moving welfare recipients into work, based on independent, rigorous evaluations of the projects. The database shall include a separate listing of projects that used a developmental approach in delivering services and a further separate listing of the projects that used an approach in delivering services that was proven to be ineffective in achieving positive outcomes. The Secretary shall add to the What Works Clearinghouse of Proven and Promising Projects to Move Welfare Recipients into Work data about the projects that, based on an independent, well-conducted experimental evaluation of a program or project, using random assignment or other research methodologies that allow for the strongest possible causal inferences, have shown they are proven, promising, developmental, or ineffective approaches.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87B4A2A4BD8D4B09A5EC78281957F30C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria for evidence of effectiveness of approach</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and organizations with experience in evaluating research on the effectiveness of various approaches in delivering services to move welfare recipients into work, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H54BBC4F2ECC6424BB0BC598E7D612636"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish criteria for evidence of the effectiveness of the approaches used in the demonstration projects; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1B69DDFE02644EDA089A454CCB400C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the process for establishing the criteria—</text> <clause id="H051B5C919BD64A569EB51811F72440BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is transparent;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H035AFE3C7ECF44EFB34B0A4671F4A688"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is consistent across agencies;</text> </clause><clause id="H80DE6E90338B48D1B70FF24F9A18ECC5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides opportunity for public comment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDD438C09392841E4837201524C498D89"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>takes into account efforts of Federal agencies to identify and publicize effective interventions, including efforts at the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Education, and the Department of Justice.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52B84EEE6B2E4A29A3F571123F06FE42"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HBA470C4E2B5C4BCABA165BD69293F573"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Approach</header><text>The term <term>approach</term> means a process, product, strategy, or practice that is—</text>
 <clause id="HE7FA19D4F7564297AC9E6B7E8EB27878"><enum>(i)</enum><text>research-based, based on the results of 1 or more empirical studies, and linked to program-determined outcomes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA26508E8C9054E53A817D1F322FDC2A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evaluated using rigorous research designs.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69834D0026C240E29254E289642B2540"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proven approach</header><text>The term <term>proven approach</term> means an approach used in a demonstration project conducted under this section that—</text>
 <clause id="HD1296DDD675C427CB795C34AB887556A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the requirements of a promising approach; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4E1FF70E3FE84C679EF125DF8E590B6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has demonstrated significant positive outcomes at more than 1 site in terms of increasing work and earnings of participants, reducing poverty and dependence, or strengthening families.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBD0D1FE266B4C7799163091F5AB7C0A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Promising approach</header><text>The term <term>promising approach</term> means an approach used in a demonstration project conducted under this section—</text> <clause id="HF92B739411D84C85971B4F0E7BA6C05D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that has been used in the project or elsewhere for at least 3 years;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4E4D69F8A0394308B2D325EF3BEF9710"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that meets the requirements of subparagraph (D)(i);</text> </clause><clause id="HA6CDB00367B94E94AC616F1A54EAA2D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that has been evaluated using well-designed and rigorous randomized controlled or quasi-experimental research designs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA8DD9CC7F60A491FA9F4E703455BD0D1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that has demonstrated significant positive outcomes at only 1 site in terms of increasing work and earnings of participants, reducing poverty and dependence, or strengthening families; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H94A9D150E2A74C92B49C240A06A94F80"><enum>(v)</enum><text>under which the benefits of the positive outcomes have exceeded the costs of achieving the outcomes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE82AE0645C794784B66D45267761210D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Developmental approach</header><text>The term <term>developmental approach</term> means an approach used in a demonstration project conducted under this section that—</text> <clause id="H25644C8279514161919B64B596204F10"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is research-based, grounded in relevant empirically based knowledge, and linked to program-determined outcomes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H55F68EE5724F4E3096FAF635EA179813"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is evaluated using rigorous research designs; and</text> </clause><clause id="H30C97E41AF9D444080953E886EC6C5EF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has yet to demonstrate a significant positive outcome in terms of increasing work and earnings of participants in a cost-effective way.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6254BC8FA5449F2BEAE420E6F2A0259"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts made available to carry out section 403(b) for fiscal year 2016 and each succeeding fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve such funds as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H703AA3030FC14C97968875B5BB86D278"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendment made by this Act shall take effect on October 1, 2015.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

