<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H62BB2010A8DF475C851681624E4FA4C3" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2798 IH: Strengthening Refugee Resettlement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2798</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150617">June 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To modify provisions of law relating to refugee resettlement, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H145DE7430B9B494D969574CAFCE1E5A7" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB063A0BA92384864BD251F3527184A02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HA9DDC86E8CA0429895A7C5E35D49E784"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Refugee Resettlement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE9E3F0A8C2E340FCBDBA8A836E58B411"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HB063A0BA92384864BD251F3527184A02" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9DDEF5AC004C4D3EA56591AF727F50C3" level="section">Sec. 2. Security checks.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9DA5856B93FF4E9F81A4E669CD3A404D" level="section">Sec. 3. English language and work orientation training for approved refugee applicants.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H84EF10452BFE4A878BD85FEB578F18E4" level="section">Sec. 4. Lawful permanent resident status of refugees and aliens granted asylum.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6DAA92CAB2C54D96A0A5C37A27DDA40F" level="section">Sec. 5. Update of reception and placement grants.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H599F28B65EE445799A735D4FE69656C4" level="section">Sec. 6. Coordination of refugee program agencies.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7BA984AFEEEF461FBCAFF79C3B819FC3" level="section">Sec. 7. Case management.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H680D2BD965E04CB490E08E1D93A6FA56" level="section">Sec. 8. Increase in cash payments.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA427F7B609CE45C090820AEB1297684C" level="section">Sec. 9. Refugee integration grants.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBAFFE6E8C87A4EC4AE4881F29C9995F2" level="section">Sec. 10. Matching grant program expansion.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7FB3DC6A1FE345158CCB44B5CA19AAAF" level="section">Sec. 11. Domestic Emergency Refugee Resettlement Fund.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H14F6337E4A4F414EA42C0DFA47E84E1C" level="section">Sec. 12. Supplemental Security Income benefits.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H96EC1DE15C8A421CA192747BDB867FC3" level="section">Sec. 13. Making special immigrant juvenile status beneficiaries and unaccompanied children granted <quote>U</quote> visa protection eligible for refugee benefits.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9DDEF5AC004C4D3EA56591AF727F50C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Security checks</header>
 <subsection id="H5FA3A73F04A64C7A86E5E1F126B390E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although effective security checks are needed to ensure that the United States and the Nation’s refugee admissions program are adequately protected, it is the sense of the Congress that the failure to properly coordinate security and non-security clearance procedures has had negative impacts on the processing of vulnerable individuals who are in need of, and eligible for, resettlement to the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H028EC1F7E2BD4DCFBE4833C80D82A995"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of refugee processing</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall work with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, including the Department of State, to conduct a review of refugee processing, including security clearances, with the goal of streamlining processing, consistent with maintaining thorough security vetting.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB85DF0A0E98A403392096B32E1AD6BB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Congress a report on the results of the review conducted under subsection (b). The report shall include a description of recommended changes to streamline processing and the costs associated with any unfunded needs.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9DA5856B93FF4E9F81A4E669CD3A404D"><enum>3.</enum><header>English language and work orientation training for approved refugee applicants</header>
 <subsection id="HF05359918A744BA9B54858878FF862D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish overseas refugee training programs to provide English as a second language and work orientation training for refugees who have been approved for admission to the United States before their departure for the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H342C7049523B4D5ABF1940332ACF2D5D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and implementation</header><text>In designing and implementing the programs referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with or use—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9815F28E5E394600B9452A00802C4120"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nongovernmental or international organizations with direct ties to the United States refugee resettlement program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59177848290F461B8B51CD5BD090FCBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>nongovernmental or international organizations with appropriate expertise in developing curriculum and teaching English as a second language.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1B6AD7D222F49A984077351A4EB7A52"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Impact on processing times</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that such training programs occur within applicable processing times and do not unduly delay the departure for the United States of refugees who have been approved for admission to the United States.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H347097612E124B5498B393886376F8D8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timeline for implementation</header>
 <paragraph id="H2E8990B91B2540758F1EE9A504BA5183"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial implementation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall ensure that such training programs are fully and continually operational in at least 3 refugee processing regions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD6CA4ABD0C4F25A5A094D1C1629563"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional implementation</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall notify the appropriate congressional committees that such training programs are fully and consistently operational in 5 refugee processing regions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D858C13114E4C5390E20B8BE764F7E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the implementation of this section, including an assessment of the quality of English as a second language curriculum and instruction, the benefits of the work orientation and English as a second language training program to refugees, and recommendations on whether such programs should be continued, broadened, or modified, and shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the findings of such study.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7142DC00ECCA41579E8984E0DD429887"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require that a refugee participate in such a training program as a precondition for the admission to the United States of such refugee.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H84EF10452BFE4A878BD85FEB578F18E4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Lawful permanent resident status of refugees and aliens granted asylum</header>
 <subsection id="H275D1F42095F4E64B0C8FB04DA3016F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Admission of emergency situation refugees</header><text>Section 207(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HAF93119533424727A10D0A8CA7E8A774"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2BDBB287C465403F8342D9F53ABD9662"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> the first time it appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE11492850234A0DBA1D9845CE90C8D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each additional place it appears and inserting <quote>Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE70B1C01AB6B44CA812DC35F762BB981"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(except as otherwise provided under paragraph (3)) as an immigrant under this Act.</quote> and inserting <quote>(except as provided under subsections (b) and (c) of section 209) as an immigrant under this Act. Notwithstanding any numerical limitations specified in this Act, any alien admitted under this paragraph shall be regarded as lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence as of the date of such alien’s admission to the United States.</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60C41AD94AD8415990612D2E567E30F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEB42B9B04B9C4970ADD6385A6B614669"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(except as otherwise provided under paragraph (3))</quote> and inserting <quote>(except as provided under subsections (b) and (c) of section 209)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H864C1614768843168BE2C8355060C2B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the last sentence and inserting the following: <quote>An alien admitted to the United States as a refugee may petition for his or her spouse or child to follow to join him or her in the United States at any time after such alien’s admission, notwithstanding his or her treatment as a lawful permanent resident as of the date of his or her admission to the United States.</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31BFCD7A49C44414BB27CEAD75D566EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA26BB4274A0542DDAAF982F614C72180"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12C362608E964C2287FAB6CF89673CA9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), as redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="HE1F8AA76A9124CEE99C43E1883C87F4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> the first place it appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF02F030F7CD048B599AB2B60BAFBA73C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each additional place it appears and inserting <quote>Secretary</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15DF1AE53C9E4FB4B243CFF130144335"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of spouse and children</header><text>Section 208(b)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB10B74A8D17F446BAA8C9BA5887327C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (E); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1401AA832F746BE8EA83DEF5AEBC023"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HF1F4C8DA8FC44D5DA7E4181D5237A09E" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H965FC0658B52475FAC5F9DDD3DCC0835"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Petition</header><text>An alien granted asylum under this subsection may petition for the same status to be conferred on his or her spouse or child at any time after such alien is granted asylum whether or not such alien has applied for, or been granted, adjustment to permanent resident status under section 209.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50BCA482CF9A422FBA8EBFE0A5575814"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Permanent resident status</header><text>Notwithstanding any numerical limitations specified in this Act, a spouse or child admitted to the United States as an asylee following to join a spouse or parent previously granted asylum shall be regarded as lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence as of the date of such spouse’s or child’s admission to the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H723C730EB2664CE4B1723D94F0AF33B2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Application for adjustment of status</header><text>A spouse or child who was not admitted to the United States pursuant to a grant of asylum, but who was granted asylum under this subparagraph after his or her arrival as the spouse or child of an alien granted asylum under section 208, may apply for adjustment of status to that of lawful permanent resident under section 209 at any time after being granted asylum.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EAF4BBFBFDB44E081E5EEA7D0FC17BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Refugees</header><text>Section 209 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1159">8 U.S.C. 1159</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HA451C9E7E606441596EB5966B48ED4D1" style="OLC"> <section id="H2EA7A3A3CFD945628B74D160815CD0A3"><enum>209.</enum><header>Treatment of aliens admitted as refugees and aliens granted asylum</header> <subsection id="H5C774D8F72994446B3F52301C2FEC7E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H99C4EDE2D5744BDABDA18CDC194D18C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment of refugees</header><text>Notwithstanding any numerical limitations specified in this Act, any alien who has been admitted to the United States under section 207 shall be regarded as lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence as of the date of such admission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC02277552B154AE8B21FBA2A2CD77C99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of spouse and children</header><text>Notwithstanding any numerical limitations specified in this Act, any alien admitted to the United States under section 208(b)(3) as the spouse or child of an alien granted asylum under section 208(b)(1) shall be regarded as lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence as of the date of such admission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50307DADFC5646CAA670D9242EB09D72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjustment of status</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General, in the discretion of the Secretary or the Attorney General, and under such regulations as the Secretary or the Attorney General may prescribe, may adjust, to the status of an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence, the status of any alien who, while in the United States—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H18BA4E71FA1E4233A6E0B985B7BBF790"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is granted—</text> <clause id="HBE0A61A6B6444E1CB04BF0E6B4A1C31B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>asylum under section 208(b) (as a principal alien or as the spouse or child of an alien granted asylum); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3D03ED6D99A43649E16289A3D2C2E28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refugee status under section 207 as the spouse or child of a refugee;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C9735B112DA49FD9DC3DDC2BDE911B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applies for such adjustment of status at any time after being granted asylum or refugee status;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7848FCE367F94AB1AFAB9148E6EFFAF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not firmly resettled in any foreign country; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D8CFDE51D7A4B7FA2D67DEA93017D79"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is admissible (except as otherwise provided under subsections (b) and (c)) as an immigrant under this Act at the time of examination for adjustment of such alien.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3C559931CED4841BC097EBC327080B9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Record</header><text>Upon approval of an application under this subsection, the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General shall establish a record of the alien’s admission for lawful permanent residence as of the date such alien was granted asylum or refugee status.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5587BA73068D42CC9C1CDD979FCDE56E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Document issuance</header><text>An alien who has been admitted to the United States under section 207 or 208 or who adjusts to the status of a lawful permanent resident as a refugee or asylee under this section shall be issued documentation indicating that such alien is a lawful permanent resident pursuant to a grant of refugee or asylum status.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE95906A691374B32B83060F64BCFCE88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inapplicability of certain inadmissibility grounds to refugees, aliens granted asylum, and such
 aliens seeking adjustment of status to lawful permanent resident</header><text>Paragraphs (4), (5), and (7)(A) of section 212(a) shall not apply to—</text> <paragraph id="H763DA7891CC448F9A7954247F44AC220"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any refugee under section 207;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0E5E7C1543D448EB4DC501B362170F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any alien granted asylum under section 208; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F37F35ADAC645688376456F0B6E15AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any alien seeking admission as a lawful permanent resident pursuant to a grant of refugee or asylum status.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F1825F4855F4CF988BFB8C77AE7CDDF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver of inadmissibility or deportability for refugees, aliens granted asylum, and such aliens
			 seeking adjustment of status to lawful permanent resident</header>
 <paragraph id="H5B590383D69941EC85505C08DC9A79BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General may waive any ground of inadmissibility under section 212 or any ground of deportability under section 237 for a refugee admitted under section 207, an alien granted asylum under section 208, or an alien seeking admission as a lawful permanent resident pursuant to a grant of refugee or asylum status if the Secretary or the Attorney General determines that such waiver is justified by humanitarian purposes, to ensure family unity, or is otherwise in the public interest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BD2F5C8AA3A4140A00DFD0580D9E751"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility</header><text>A refugee under section 207, an alien granted asylum under section 208, or an alien seeking admission as a lawful permanent resident pursuant to a grant of refugee or asylum status shall be ineligible for a waiver under paragraph (1) if it has been established that the alien is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5D5B086411314C36A8528F338C38C085"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(C) or subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (E) of section 212(a)(3);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AD2A95E5A204C23BF7C6691406D845C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deportable under section 237(a)(2)(A)(iii) for an offense described in section 101(a)(43)(B); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87DBC2BEBB40449B81377CC201CB1DD2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>deportable under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of section 237(a)(4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HA0DF9F7F89B1438F961E69928EDB9778"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical amendments</header> <paragraph id="H41BCA80A4B9944BD873EAC2E46AA006C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aliens not subject to direct numerical limitations</header><text>Section 201(b)(1)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H4B441979EA314D618B9A7DE546B936AA" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H03A5ED80F0684DC4BB5676ABF41DAE45" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Aliens who are admitted to the United States as permanent residents under section 207 or 208 or whose status is adjusted under section 209.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CB01368C29948FFBCA126A1750E20AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training</header><text>Section 207(f)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H56A15B7826EB4FDAB2D8F2636715FCFB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for such Act is amended by striking the item relating to section 209 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HE181AE6FBADC4509B277768ABBD21CCD" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 209. Treatment of aliens admitted as refugees and aliens granted asylum.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8CA3C94860A46E8AAF5309D3CE7CE9E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="H0CECBE73B92A42E8A4172DD0FEB60B92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in the amendments made by this section may be construed to limit access to the benefits described at chapter 2 of title IV of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1521">8 U.S.C. 1521 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0F456EDB52B4EE8BD884A37F8A71832"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Aliens admitted for lawful permanent residence under section 207 or 208 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>; 1158) or who adjust status to lawful permanent resident under section 209 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1159">8 U.S.C. 1159</external-xref>) shall be considered to be refugees and aliens granted asylum in accordance with sections 402, 403, 412, and 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1612">8 U.S.C. 1612</external-xref>; 1613; 1622; 1641).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8302951F5018423ABEAFDC26242814ED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall become effective on the earlier of—</text> <paragraph id="HADC5803ED7C3465EB9D80381A1F13163"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC879ACDCEA642B3887F67ECBB4CCE3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which a final rule is promulgated to implement this section.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6DAA92CAB2C54D96A0A5C37A27DDA40F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Update of reception and placement grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning with fiscal year 2016, the Secretary of State shall, when setting the amount of the reception and placement grants for refugees, ensure that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0851EE724F55480C85660E59B523F16D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the grant amount is adjusted so that it is adequate to provide for the anticipated initial resettlement needs of refugees, including adjusting the amount for inflation and the cost of living;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9639926C62E14C5C96047B357BD82E89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the administrative proportion of the grant is provided at the beginning of the fiscal year to each national resettlement agency that is sufficient to ensure adequate local and national capacity to serve the initial resettlement needs of refugees the Secretary anticipates the agency will resettle throughout the fiscal year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48A98C2684AD4DB0930BC6181BDF1616"><enum>(3)</enum><text>additional amounts are provided to each national resettlement agency promptly upon the arrival of refugees that, exclusive of the amounts provided pursuant to paragraph (2), are sufficient to meet the anticipated initial resettlement needs of such refugees and support local and national operational costs in excess of the estimates described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H599F28B65EE445799A735D4FE69656C4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Coordination of refugee program agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HB3BDB2FB4A1746A9A89256FF04AFD044"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President should appoint a White House Coordinator on Refugee Protection and grant such official the authority and staff necessary to coordinate, prioritize, and lead efforts to address refugee protection issues that involve multiple agencies, including the refugee admissions program, and to resolve interagency differences in a timely, efficient, and effective manner; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B26D2DBC8D407E89B16478CFCA6F67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>this position should be at a senior level and require as a condition for appointment a significant level of prior experience in the refugee protection field.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7BA984AFEEEF461FBCAFF79C3B819FC3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Case management</header>
			<subsection id="H89DCEBC82DC14B2E9C9D413BB5C42418"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="HD133A35470184E838164448B5901A95D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header><text>The Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement shall make grants to national resettlement agencies to operate a case management system to assist qualified individuals in accessing services, benefits, and assistance for which they are eligible that are provided by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2BA947EB08094E7DB7DB8858155CD7A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of Refugee Resettlement (the <quote>Office</quote>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB85853A0FF0F4337BA604634251AACB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other Federal, State, or local agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4816DEE8E33C455B80B486444F9C6EC1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>private or nonprofit organizations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D8698CF03CB4901B02E14C5A600B0F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified individuals</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), any individual who was at any time eligible for resettlement, acculturation, or subsistence services provided by the Office shall be qualified to receive the case management services described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD6F391F43E149DC8BAB79D816F7D578"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period of qualification</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (4), an individual described in paragraph (2) shall be qualified to receive the case management services described in paragraph (1) during the period beginning on the date such individual was determined to be eligible for resettlement, acculturation, or subsistence services provided by the Office, and continuing for 1 year after the date on which such individual ceases to be eligible for such resettlement, acculturation, or subsistence service.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H1058FF5E4CE7469B9DD20E5F12310003"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exceptions for exceptional circumstances</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE572F962092444959CBF5A6E126669BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (3), an individual described in subparagraph (B) shall be qualified to receive the case management services described in paragraph (1) during the period beginning on the date on which such individual was determined eligible for resettlement, acculturation, or subsistence services provided by the Office, and continuing for 3 years after the date on which such individual ceases to be eligible for such resettlement, acculturation, or subsistence services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3A9918B16394AD3A2E26F6FA026973C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptional circumstances</header><text>An individual described in paragraph (2) may be treated in accordance with subparagraph (A) if such individual—</text>
 <clause id="HFE425FA68ACC4DD89AC63B590EF33CC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is elderly;</text> </clause><clause id="HBB478BDA5B914A519608421E1058567D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has extraordinary resettlement or acculturation needs that impede such individual’s ability to achieve durable self-sufficiency;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H868F42392841445FA16D49D7CA5FEB44"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a refugee who was resettled from a situation of protracted displacement;</text> </clause><clause id="HF5808BCC7CA8468E9053367C5FE2407B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is a member of a family caring for an unattached refugee minor; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0E042F75517A4F0190CEA17D63C5E53C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>at the time of entry—</text> <subclause id="HE39CC6D87516437E87C6EB0C219F1953"><enum>(I)</enum><text>had a disability or serious medical condition;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE7B50E84296B4D7CA3B04337E1A29A42"><enum>(II)</enum><text>had mental health conditions;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7FC98C6C56B147FCB9E6FC056DDE10F7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>was part of a household headed by a single parent; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC74729C873234668A039B6A8D66FA61D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>had been the victim of a severe form of violence.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DA6F32FD2FA4032BD756C7FD1823D35"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definition of resettlement, acculturation, or subsistence services</header><text>For the purposes of this section, the term, <quote>resettlement, acculturation, or subsistence services</quote> shall include all of the services provided by the Office to aliens, with the exception of the case management services provided under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FD3B8D4F3FC4868A9673811B09ABB9F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H187DBA24D7EF466B91B11A27CA4F1C6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Director under section 412(e)(7)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1522">8 U.S.C. 1522(e)(7)(A)</external-xref>), or of any other section of such Act, to provide case management services to individuals who have been in the United States for longer than 36 months.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H680D2BD965E04CB490E08E1D93A6FA56"><enum>8.</enum><header>Increase in cash payments</header>
 <subsection id="H3E2263E681CB4EA3B38307D62CE0E7F6"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Section 412 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1522">8 U.S.C. 1522</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2729EC3A6C6B442E877CCB2F8FCB32C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)(B), by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5321337E0A1841259C4330BC6F9D471C" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H20D12D165380407CBBB629FE412192CD" indent="up2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of funds appropriated for this purpose, assistance and social services for employment, health and living expenses shall be available for a period of not less than 12 months.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50209503C5EC4BFF8DCD7DC5166F7D03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(5), by adding at the end the following: <quote>Subject to the availability of funds appropriated for this purpose, assistance and services shall be made available to refugees for a period of not less than 12 months.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE55FE9DC3CB44219DEEDCF23951B3F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5AD32414903C4815AD937D70766C0CDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>(1)(A)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A438D3ADE9A4CC1834D0F5CD4AC399A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0CD6F0DEACA454DBC4931C3C3AE51F2" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H942CA43C736A41CE9BC4CF439FB5FFE1" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of funds appropriated for this purpose, such assistance shall be provided for a minimum of 12 months beginning with the first month in which such refugee entered the United States.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56A339C868034CCC8E6D2227214B00CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall become effective on the earlier of—</text> <paragraph id="H42E866DF4E034005A015013D2A7737FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the first day of the first fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDDB2BA578BE491590A89C58EC1D55DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which a final rule is promulgated to implement this section.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF6100169A954B00AC8BDC46AF3A9686"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The 12-month specification contained in the amendments made by subsection (a) is a minimum standard for the provision of services to the refugee community. No part of this Act shall be interpreted as limiting or reducing assistance already provided for a period longer than 12 months.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA427F7B609CE45C090820AEB1297684C"><enum>9.</enum><header>Refugee integration grants</header>
 <subsection id="H2F89B626BCC04F268F2609CF9EBA01C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of refugee integration grants</header><text>The Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement is authorized to award grants to community-based organizations, national nonprofit organizations having experience and expertise in immigration law and the legal, social, educational, or cultural needs of immigrants, and national resettlement agencies for the design and implementation of programs to offer training and orientation to newcomers to the United States to assist them in integrating into the civic life of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBFD144A32B7C493588C92EB7B566574B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Services funded</header><text>Programs funded under subsection (a) shall be used—</text> <paragraph id="H2D30203A72154968A5855638FC71468C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to offer assistance and instruction to aliens described in subsection (c), on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEE0925FCCB61432584B20357D7A0A954"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the naturalization process;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9D70C74F74B4A43B848E16E9233D54D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the legal requirements for naturalization;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB04B718A0CE343C9B01114905840C097"><enum>(C)</enum><text>rights and responsibilities of U.S. citizens;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD19D335330841C4BCD806836C91C3E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>cultural orientation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CC8C55B54A04412BD42ACBFD5396C7C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>English as a second language;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8ABBDE4002D40B89E639D3FD5E518A0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>civics and United States history;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CFB45429BDF420AB10964C60E9CDCF9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>housing;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B1E64F89029445BBBE27B1F97A0B186"><enum>(H)</enum><text>transportation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DB864F62F1E46138D2D0C11B87CE1D6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>recertification;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FB43288026B45E093CBBD24ED83A014"><enum>(J)</enum><text>employment training;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6D798DD143B4AC4B2F17E9900886078"><enum>(K)</enum><text>mental health services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC73249F01ED94472B991427829E680EE"><enum>(L)</enum><text>childcare services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BA15CE1F74141378308172FD4C94AA9"><enum>(M)</enum><text>other topics the Director identifies as aiding the orientation and adjustment of new arrivals to the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1F0C92736424DD38C8AC02F19F68E54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to offer orientation and assistance to Federal, State, and local institutions that serve newcomers to the United States so as to assist such institutions in meeting their needs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BFFE5536AEB41A3ACC780F4DD70C65C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance and training to community-based organizations providing instruction in English as a second language, civics, and United States history and technical assistance and training to community-based organizations providing naturalization outreach and application assistance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE60C58B2E43A4CE0A3397E99886EFC5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible persons</header><text>Persons eligible for assistance and instruction under this subsection include—</text> <paragraph id="H73C2C7D77EC44C6FBCD5EC46515B923E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>aliens admitted as refugees under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF02D0AAB64D5469F9172A73E8760EAE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>aliens granted asylum under section 208 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DAD6C5B2D634DB0B7FA6C3FEAADD6D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aliens admitted as special immigrants from Iraq or Afghanistan pursuant to section 1244 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/181">Public Law 110–181</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 396);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF634544B7CF0430A8E8A648A7C2CD6F4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any alien who was at any time eligible to receive services from the Office of Refugee Resettlement; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4002C70F7D6E46C9A2C18820672C4AA6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>other aliens designated by the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74F02D77FB9545CBB03CC50EE39334E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application for grants</header><text>Each entity desiring a refugee integration grant under this section shall submit an application to the Director at such time and in such manner as the Director may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H97684DC01AF54D81B7992C2C6D95F0DA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting grantees, the Director shall give priority to organizations either with experience in resettling refugees or in administering services for refugees and asylum seekers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9DA201F17FD84DBAAE3E32933F97BD51"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director shall report to the Judiciary Committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of this section. The report shall include information regarding the grants issued pursuant to this section and the results of those grants.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HBAFFE6E8C87A4EC4AE4881F29C9995F2"><enum>10.</enum><header>Matching grant program expansion</header>
			<subsection id="H3F53D2D774914CF0B3455DA0C4AD4ACD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of the refugee matching grant program</header>
 <paragraph id="HCCDFCBEF6BA1462785497D63BFF92D89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In recognition of the positive outcomes achieved for individuals served through the refugee matching grant program, under which Federal funds are matched by private sector contributions of cash, goods, and volunteers, the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement shall ensure that the thresholds described in paragraph (2) are met with respect to participation by eligible individuals in such program.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD517C7258F41B48EBF6D23C3CBE013"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual thresholds</header>
 <subparagraph id="H94052A31611F48859C2365C70ED65FF2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds appropriated for this purpose, the percentage of eligible individuals who apply for services under the matching grant program who shall be served through such program is set at the following levels in each of the following fiscal years—</text>
 <clause id="H17FF391ABD0C4BF59D49AA1481DF51E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least 60 percent in fiscal year 2016;</text> </clause><clause id="H38AE2E4044304CBEB5871DAB9535C6C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least 70 percent in fiscal year 2017; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF4717B5744748FC8A808F59F5A05BCD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at least 80 percent in fiscal year 2018, and thereafter.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EB0954E0A5C40298C56D28C8554CC9E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>In determining the thresholds in this paragraph, the Director shall exclude individuals who are disabled, under the age of 18, or over the age of 65 unless such individuals are being served as members of an eligible family.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04D49E2F657B4E3D85E5080353C19DF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Length of eligibility for grant</header><text>Individuals as described in subparagraph (2)(B) shall be eligible for services under the matching grant program, and therefore be expected to achieve self-sufficiency, within 180 to 240 days of their enrollment in the program.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3969EEE3B27D4884A19D716DC20BA149"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF226ACFDEC8A464B8643BD8ECE3AAA37"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual update</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds appropriated for this purpose, beginning with fiscal year 2016, the Director shall, when setting the amount of the matching grants, ensure that the grant amount is adjusted annually so that it is adequate to provide for services intended to help refugees become self-sufficient within 180 to 240 days, including adjusting the amount for inflation and the cost of living.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0CC309C16B740E2BD0399B117F022DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall undertake an assessment of the per capita amount that is provided in the matching grant program. The assessment shall—</text>
 <clause id="H7746725C90A64CA181792DACC648FBB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>examine the adequacy of the current per capita grant amount to provide the assistance necessary to enable individuals who are served by the program to achieve self-sufficiency within 240 days;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF64BB3A19AE74F23BBDECBDF3974F5CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determine the per capita grant amount that would be necessary in order to provide the assistance necessary to enable individuals who are served by the program achieve self-sufficiency within 240 days; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD9AEAC5E88204DB48F51A8C625671E82"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assess the potential impact of any other changes to the operation of the program that the Director or the Office’s non-Federal partners suggest to improve the effectiveness of the program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC44AC48862DD4F4FB4CA709FCCA9FC3C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consultation with partners</header><text>In conducting the assessment referred to in subparagraph (B), the Director shall consult with representatives of national and local resettlement agencies with experience in providing services under the matching grant program to learn their views on the program, including their views with respect to clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D5F5E3AB59147ACB20549D6C92AF2B4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall report to the appropriate committees of Congress the results of the assessment made pursuant to subparagraph (B). Such report shall include—</text>
 <clause id="HFE1B93D1E30A432D851E1AFE00536515"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Director’s findings pursuant to subparagraph (B);</text> </clause><clause id="H3E572C2351804DB6854B8C3C520E60CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of the per capita grant that will be provided beginning on the first day of the first fiscal year that begins after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAC398361DD09413583EB4F3682381FB4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a summary of the views expressed by the entities described in subparagraph (C).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8795DF65ACC4A62BE77AD6351274D22"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Grant amount in absence of report</header><text>If for any reason the report described in subparagraph (D) is not filed with the appropriate committees of the Congress on or before the required date for the submission of such report, the per capita matching grant amount for the first fiscal year that begins after the date of enactment of this Act shall be set at the amount set for such grant on September 30 of the previous fiscal year and prorated to reflect a 180- to 240-day grant period.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7FB3DC6A1FE345158CCB44B5CA19AAAF"><enum>11.</enum><header>Domestic Emergency Refugee Resettlement Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H8FC6BB1BFC014F53A2F9BE51AD19791D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a Domestic Emergency Refugee Resettlement Fund that shall be available to the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement to meet unanticipated resettlement needs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H136EE86276B743BD96127AE0A5DDF883"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Drawdown of funds</header><text>Whenever the Director determines it to be important to the national interest, the Director is authorized to furnish on such terms and conditions as the Director may determine, assistance under this chapter for the purpose of meeting unexpected urgent resettlement needs of populations and communities served pursuant to this chapter, including communities experiencing high numbers of arrivals of refugees due to secondary migration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H773D351DBC5144ACBF38F09A3FE8945C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allowable uses</header><text>The Director may furnish assistance to eligible entities for the purposes of providing resettlement assistance to refugees, including transportation, housing, employment, health, mental health, English language training services, recertification, and other purposes as determined by the Director.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0D722AD1F9AE49E192E74658058E2E9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities defined</header><text>National resettlement agencies, community-based organizations, torture survivor rehabilitation centers and programs, and States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H50B486220B234D9B9DFEF0D239584DA7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>No amounts may be withdrawn from the fund authorized by subsection (a) unless the Director has determined that a domestic resettlement emergency exists and has certified such fact to appropriate committees of Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13EDEED60C884494B071ECA80DB5F79E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cap on fund</header><text>No funds may be appropriated which when added to the amounts previously appropriated but not yet obligated, would cause such amounts to exceed $50,000,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2D199C2BEC8448FBB1AC4D2C271663A9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Funds appropriated pursuant to this section shall be available until expended.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H14F6337E4A4F414EA42C0DFA47E84E1C"><enum>12.</enum><header>Supplemental Security Income benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402(a)(2) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1612">8 U.S.C. 1612(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H896A1D851542470B8B0454E0EE7D9380"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H64CE3305F65A497094BF677BEFE08D8A" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H0DFCFE70EDBA4500812C67C2AAB379BB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exception for refugees and asylees</header><text>With respect to the specified Federal programs described in paragraph (3), paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text>
 <clause id="HF4704DE79C6A4F6697847DCF06DC4120"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an alien admitted to the United States as a refugee under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H22A36B6CD77C4C289496EDC38B15D2B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an alien granted asylum under section 208 of such Act <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>;</text> </clause><clause id="H349C4C0ABF554C15B48D853F2B554673"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an alien whose deportation is withheld under section 243(h) of such Act 8 U.S.C. 1253 (as in effect immediately before the effective date of section 307 of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>) or section 241(b)(3) of such Act <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231(b)(3)</external-xref> (as amended by section 305(a) of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H292D36D368624DF98DB8C9D447F704A7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an alien who is granted status as a Cuban and Haitian entrant (as defined in section 501(e) of the Refugee Education Assistance Act of 1980); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4C77E6E9B6644896A1F308A09B9A5303"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an alien who is admitted to the United States as an Amerasian immigrant pursuant to section 584 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1988 (as contained in section 101(e) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/202">Public Law 100–202</external-xref> and amended by the 9th proviso under migration and refugee assistance in title II of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1989, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/461">Public Law 100–461</external-xref>, as amended).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBC5C176133E748CDB8BA46085D335754"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H3E344E44122144159605BCE15F5137A3" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H460BBC3CBB954823849EE12F106764A3"><enum>(N)</enum><header>SSI benefits for certain aliens and victims of trafficking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, any qualified alien (as defined in section 431(b)), victim of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 107(b)(1)(C) of division A of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7105">22 U.S.C. 7105(b)(1)(C)</external-xref>)), or alien granted status under section 101(a)(15)(T)(ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(T)(ii)</external-xref>) rendered ineligible for the specified Federal program described in paragraph (3)(A) solely by reason of the termination of the 7-year period described in subparagraph (A) prior to the enactment of this subparagraph shall be eligible for benefits under such program without regard to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H96EC1DE15C8A421CA192747BDB867FC3"><enum>13.</enum><header>Making special immigrant juvenile status beneficiaries and unaccompanied children granted <quote>U</quote> visa protection eligible for foster care and refugee benefits</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HD3231C8BBB3847939813B5F2831D9965"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility for benefits and services</header><text>Section 107(b)(1)(A) of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7105">22 U.S.C. 7105(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, an alien who has been granted special immigrant status under section 101(a)(27)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)(J)</external-xref>), a child who has been granted status under section 101(a)(15)(U) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15(U)),</quote> after <quote>trafficking in persons,</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7FD3D468F1614F4FAD585C7CB60ED3A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State reimbursement</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds appropriated for this purpose, if State foster care funds are expended on behalf of a child who has been granted special immigrant status under section 101(a)(27)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)(J)</external-xref>), the Federal Government shall reimburse the State in which the child resides for such expenditures by the State.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


