<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB2CDC3142C364423A73BA34984D4E8F4" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3717 IH: U.S.–Israel Global Neuroscience Partnership</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3717</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the establishment of a grant program to support United States-Israel cooperation for
			 neuroscience-related research and related technological innovation, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB3E5F07073F34990A437DBBA9B54133B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H34833D3090E541808FF0676A4885E4D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S.–Israel Global Neuroscience Partnership</short-title> Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEC519561421E494FB1A1C7F322A4D52A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <subsection id="HCDCCE43E3DE44A6B817EA3FC47AEC625"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFBE2B4EFEEC14C6980FD31D42DE5A776"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It is in the highest national security interests of the United States to develop neuroscience-related research and neurotechnology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BC4A9A602E94CE59D4D0BD59F06770B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The State of Israel is a steadfast ally of the United States.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H18D70C57276A44CF9E6F39EB4EBDAC5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The four existing bilateral research and development (in this Act referred to as <quote>R&amp;D</quote>) foundations are successful tools for implementation of diverse programmatic R&amp;D cooperation and include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H96EDBC44A8F94C999C27260E468ED80F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States-Israel Binational Industrial Research and Development Foundation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C75662D43304FB6A22596411F60C97D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States-Israel Binational Science Foundation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H434DF69A2DA44A11AB30AAADD0EBE868"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States-Israel Binational Agricultural Research and Development Foundation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D5B3230534E4393AE0499CAB465D72F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States-Israel Science &amp; Technology Foundation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B9B0F00498A461FAB38D05C7ED7643B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Given this proven success, it is in the economic interest of the United States to develop closer research, high-technology and innovation ties with Israel in strategic areas of mutual interest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4489C540930947FBA4B635D88F1613EF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Both governments agreed to reach an umbrella Science &amp; Technology Agreement under which existing R&amp;D and Innovation funding programs can operate jointly on common priorities, in order to intensify, further and deepen the science and technology (in this Act referred to as <quote>S&amp;T</quote>) and innovation links between the United States and Israel beyond the existing bilateral foundations operations. The United States Department of State is drafting this Agreement. Congress supports this agreement and its implementation through Federal R&amp;D and innovation programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36F41625032444FDB2C4ABC803E7D7C9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The State of Israel has a centralized mechanism for policy and funding industrial R&amp;D within the Ministry of Economy’s Industrial R&amp;D Administration, known as the Office of the Chief Scientist (in this Act referred to as <quote>OCS</quote>). The OCS is the State of Israel’s national authority in charge of policy and budgeting of industrial R&amp;D and innovation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H622C1828E8824B0DBB3C59BAE6B4F5CA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The U.S.–Israel Joint Economic Development Group, a binational economic dialogue between both governments (in this Act referred to as <quote>JEDG</quote>) to further enhance cooperation between the United States and Israel, requested the United States-Israel Science &amp; Technology Foundation map and identify mechanisms of research and development in neuroscience and neurotechnology that can support further collaboration between the countries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D01B063ADF647F398BBA1F75B8952E0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Israeli scientists and engineers are at the forefront of research and development in the field of neuroscience.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9268DA8A92043FC8055DBCB36872063"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Israel Brain Technologies is a nonprofit organization whose mission is to turn Israel into a global brain technology and research leader by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H607353F643BE4352801D8CAD9BBCDB4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting applied brain research;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5695F4B7853B4DA39E1D6BE9AADF2116"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accelerating brain technology development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96D302EB315E45CAB41115F830686B7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>creating and fostering a community around neurotechnology; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BB944157CC54FD58DF0D18D74155F8F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>attracting key stakeholders to partner and support brain technology in Israel.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DF061FDA7284EF58DFF6A7CC9AF0CF2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Enhanced cooperation between the United States and Israel for the purpose of research and development of neuroscience that would be in the national interests of both countries.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C0F636D5C124362A7C1C85355B3D88F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bilateral Industrial R&amp;D and Innovation Programs</header>
 <paragraph id="H38498529B5B342E9B1CF04F649BD3733"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress supports the expansion of U.S.–Israel industry driven R&amp;D with Federal and State entities through innovation linkages to promote economic growth and job creation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60EE1F42A3AF44628B7718A2917157F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It is in the best interest of the United States to hold a regular dialogue with Israel’s OCS aiming to identify potential synergies and coordinating bilateral cooperation between R&amp;D programs supported by the Federal Government and the Government of Israel detailing pathways to partnership with the OCS, and Israel’s Ministry of Science, Technology, and Space (in this Act referred to as <quote>MOST</quote>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0E85942ACBDF4EACBAA4501927CFADCD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for neuroscience-related research</header>
 <subsection id="H3EAE1E9B56134153BB5615AF7423AC92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, in consultation with their government counterparts at OCS and MOST, shall award grants to eligible entities for neuroscience-related research and related technological innovation.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H41DEA8ACE4894DA28E6A47DA5515C1CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="H435BEE17915E4B578CC5B0E69A6F18FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission of applications</header><text>To receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary containing such information and assurances as the Secretary, in consultation with the OCS and MOST, may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAADD2BF782C4C5198FBE8467DA2DD43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of eligible entities</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Directors of the OCS and MOST, may review any application submitted by any eligible entity and select any eligible entity meeting criteria established by the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, for a grant under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7B26A66E04C74D24B566023C15F3BD02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relation to SBIR and STTR programs</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section through the Small Business Innovation Research (<quote>SBIR</quote>) and Small Business Technology Transfer (<quote>STTR</quote>) programs of the National Institutes of Health.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBE4907897A8348458A8E8E530A280048"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header><text>The amount of each grant awarded for a fiscal year under this section shall be determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the OCS and MOST.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5906F77E99AA44A4A05A31F674AE25D8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Private funds</header><text>The Secretary may accept contributions of funds from private sources to carry out this Act.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H831D5D51F2F54B579318C885CDFA5A26"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving a grant under this section, each recipient shall submit a report to the Secretary—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE20FFF488234463080C99B3B61E3AFDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>documenting how the recipient used the grant funds; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9ACBE756EB4C40D1A4C34D5ACC823A44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluating the level of success of each project funded by the grant.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCC0054FDFBE548D9B507238034AD4BD9"><enum>4.</enum><header>U.S.–Israel neuroscience advisory committee</header>
 <subsection id="H5DB255188E724D1AA7A3725EC29D15D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the National Institutes of Health a U.S.–Israel Neuroscience Advisory Committee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2BCAF24515CA41D2A7B31B3F485AB6CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall advise the Secretary on—</text> <paragraph id="H03202BA28DB44E07944212332D1C2CA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>criteria for the recipients of grants awarded under section 3(a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18A726C478B846148882EBD72494188F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total amount of grant money to be awarded to all grantees selected by the Secretary, in consultation with the OCS and MOST.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63551519409E41628790D5AC67490F76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="H9CDBDCAE066245ABBE5DE3629B26B358"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be composed of—</text> <subparagraph id="H69669CC539B34639BF84890EB83E1CEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 members appointed by the Director of the National Institutes of Health; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H886D728157EE46F8B86C86B665EB0396"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in addition to the members appointed under subparagraph (A), 3 members who shall be Israeli citizens, appointed by the Director of the National Institutes of Health after consultation with appropriate officials in the Israeli Government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02351534CEA64B9C972B966BF42BCD7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for appointments</header><text>The initial appointments under paragraph (1) shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6705D648A1FA49249156D806AD687EC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Each member of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed for a term of 4 years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFD6797DB42B424C90C9A03D97DB0F1F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy on the Advisory Committee shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9BD7FA753EB64EA4A02159F040324C07"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Basic pay</header>
 <subparagraph id="H588E223784AB405DBA1C5CD4F7DC96D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>A member of the Advisory Committee shall serve without pay.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E3A19755E504B16A30310B69BAA36A3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member of the Advisory Committee shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21A5BE24919B42DC9BFFE994A77A8D51"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Three members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB81D1F1FDD884E9B8AB3CDC1821BE1D2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Chairperson of the Advisory Committee shall be designated by the Director of the National Institutes of Health from among the members appointed by the Director at the time of the appointment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9D7E5C81B41432D844B78D8549CB13B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall meet at least once annually at the call of the Chairperson.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4DDA1DE276BF472A9FC527AC073190DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Section 14(a)(2)(B) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Advisory Committee.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC4AB53333D07462792F1EF78B4875A34"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD029A99B43C644DC8EB2FE0788464530"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Committee</term> means the U.S.–Israel Neuroscience Advisory Committee established by section 4(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73E3FFA3215F4CB480CA1CA2CF3BCDFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a joint venture that—</text> <subparagraph id="H26682DC8B5564E6F80F05FAC22A9AC99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is comprised of—</text>
 <clause id="H0817552D569D479C9E2AFBE3280EFC61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Israeli and United States private business entities;</text> </clause><clause id="HA1E8FC3BFCDC427993661E96AA6B0D7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Israeli academic persons and United States academic persons;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB5AA577F3A9340689E6F7A1E3E6C4BD4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>one or more Israeli private business entities and one or more United States academic persons; or</text> </clause><clause id="HAF6C6A6B663546F48EBDC43AEEA9D73B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>one or more United States private business entities and one or more Israeli academic persons;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H369316E0388244CA8719E29F9311B7F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carries out an eligible project; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71E307A03F3C4015BCEB232FD64B2AF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is selected by the Secretary, in consultation with the OCS or MOST, using the criteria established by the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AA400F4EE75406CB50531144FFE0C51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible project</term> means a project to encourage cooperation between the United States and Israel on neuroscience-related research and related technological innovation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAB296E255BF4084AE9C8CFA81C10C1A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Israeli academic person</header><text>The term <quote>Israeli academic person</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HA17A57D88C82417E822472ACCD6BD3E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education that is located in Israel;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06B224F487DA41109C4734E4AEE13DF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a subsidiary or affiliate of such an institution that is located in Israel; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4881AC59CE64210A4A184549A235E36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual who—</text>
 <clause id="HA94F152695A149AD9D95C09F6E9E9810"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducts research for such an institution, subsidiary, or affiliate as an employee or contractor; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H69B1456B97D44410A0DA805DBF04A082"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resides and works in Israel.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD97A3262FA7A4A3180F13D44615C3B6B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B9265613E0A4BC6907A0653AD77DEA5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States academic person</header><text>The term <quote>United States academic person</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF4D2A4B06454A24AA7D4AB5C1ED3019"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education that is located in the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE3DA0A4BDE04151B04673B72E443232"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a subsidiary or affiliate of such an institution that is located in the United States; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83A07B249EB64E5CB76EC05DA8AC1DE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual who—</text>
 <clause id="H0749C3973B494977936DE0454CD647BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducts research for such an institution, subsidiary, or affiliate as an employee or contractor; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB30192BFB0E94F3495FF586ADB4F089A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resides and works in the United States.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HD7AD180097614ECA8DD8643573D28010"><enum>6.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The grant program authorized under section 3 and the Advisory Committee shall terminate upon the expiration of the 7-year period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="HEECA71D8DDDC4F6BB6D6BCEB8FB80F33"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to expend not more than $20,000,000 to carry out this Act for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2022.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


