<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5AD1EF77992449FC8525B55D01F4428B" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1125 IH: Start Saving Sooner Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1125</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for tax preferred savings accounts for individuals under age 18, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H00A27FD115E3449DBF9F37D867D4C8AA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1B0319913B8145378959F3EF51AF1188" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Start Saving Sooner Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7ECC97BC7B5A483D8E95B4FCB4546E94"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H373680AC865E469B96B2901F71ADCF31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Studies indicate that children as young as 3 years old are able to grasp financial concepts and that basic financial habits are largely formulated by age 7.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H405D8F6329D64ACF9C209C59BFDE411F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Research shows that children born to low-income parents who are good financial savers are more likely to move up the economic ladder than children from low-income households that do not save. According to a 2011 study controlled for income and demographic factors, youth who own financial accounts are 7 times more likely to attend college.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H644FE2C7D9E3453E9C84A6EEBC2FDF65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If tax-advantaged retirement accounts such as Roth IRAs could be opened for children between the ages of zero and 18, these individuals are likely to acquire substantially more tax-free assets by retirement age than their peers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A760CFC9C024D44952D3233A3ECB8A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Children who possess retirement accounts from a young age will benefit from longer exposure to compound interest and can be expected to attain higher levels of financial literacy, college graduation and retirement security in adulthood.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF44A195CF284278AE4255A6050D4BE3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Greater private retirement savings for Americans of all ages will increase personal financial security and responsibility, reducing the likelihood that seniors will need to rely solely on Social Security for their retirement income.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7253999CF5284669991BFED3BFE5635C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Federal policy should better enable parents, guardians and families of all income levels to encourage youth saving and investment for retirement at an earlier age.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B204D14FFCC44A2A3EC88F100ABDAB7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Federal policy should help create retirement savings incentives for low-income Americans because studies show that low-income Americans will save more for retirement if there are incentives and structures in place to help them do so. A refundable incentive like the Saver’s Credit would reach 50 million low-income households—nearly 10 times the number a non-refundable credit reaches.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEB92BC79211642FC975516C17F94277B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Young savers account</header> <subsection id="HEB5039461A704C8E83E3DAC6B76098E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of accounts</header> <paragraph id="HAF150D471B3E48CD92290B8CE373A533"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408A">Section 408A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D3D351DE1D449219ED8335023859A12" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H0AE2B3E68F0B4A768CFA561D3D2385C2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Young savers account</header> 
<paragraph id="H0FC2838C95AC48C0B9CDA900A8DC7BF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this subsection, a young savers account shall be treated in the same manner as a Roth IRA.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9ED87BEB9DB4400FA1E836936E1E87C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Young savers account</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>young savers account</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, a Roth IRA which is maintained on behalf of an individual who has not attained age 18 before the close of the taxable year and which is designated (in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) at the time of establishment as a young savers account.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF3AA8E2C3B44CD4A48EA52FD8BBEEA1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contribution limits</header><text>In the case of any contributions for any taxable year to 1 or more young savers accounts maintained on behalf of an individual, each of the following contribution limits for the taxable year shall be increased as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="HB720311378A14A9BA2E95DDD7827C03F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The contribution limit applicable to the individual under subsection (c)(2) shall be increased by the aggregate amount of qualified young saver contributions to such accounts for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1CE7A7E9AF248509C3BFFE2F78FEA3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The contribution limits applicable to the young savers accounts under subsection (a)(1) or (b)(2)(B) of section 408, whichever is applicable, shall be increased by the deductible amount in effect under section 219(b)(5) for such taxable year (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) thereof).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F4CD686519E4CE38DDF047CF5EDDE2D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified young saver contributions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5A3072333753408C9E1401E938224D83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified young saver contribution</term> means a contribution by an individual (with respect to whom a young savers account is not maintained during the taxable year) to a young savers account maintained on behalf of another individual.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H850CC0BF8139427887883AF1954B16F5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <clause id="H6679B78BE3FA4D5385C33467BB498C58"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limit on accounts with respect to individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate amount of contributions which may be made for any taxable year to all young savers accounts maintained on behalf of an individual shall not exceed the deductible amount in effect for the taxable year under section 219(b)(5) (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) thereof).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC67C92A4C4894873B84D1A907F0A9763"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limit on contributors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate amount of qualified young saver contributions an individual may make for any taxable year to all young savers accounts shall not exceed the deductible amount in effect for the taxable year under section 219(b)(5) (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) thereof), reduced by any contributions made by or on behalf of the individual to any Roth IRA maintained on behalf of the individual.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H591A6B8191964A1B92B2898BD1857519"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible for Savers Credit</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 25B(d) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B)(ii), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (C) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61BD605D34164B8AAAC7D7027A23FC8E" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H442EE5D42A7545688A8C9E158205FE24"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any contribution to a young savers account.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H79E1641025B34B4D829FF6D447330E1F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Refund payable to Young Savers Account</header> <paragraph id="HB4AA375F137041309BC813A8ED57AEDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/65">chapter 65</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73FA861B0130403A87BFD0601BA09686" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB1A734F36A46417D8BBA7D10A23291D2"><enum>6433.</enum><header>Young savers account refund payment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of any overpayment (or portion thereof) which is attributable to a credit allowed to an individual under section 25B by reason of a contribution to a young savers account, the Secretary shall pay the amount of such overpayment (or such portion) into the young savers account to which such contribution was made. The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H370E9DC6DF574847AD8425DD9E9A742B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of chapter 65 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H543D291031134CF59893F34E5E4369F6" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6433. Young savers account refund payment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9BC0CB3CDB444387B217CE4B5B5ABBBC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Young savers account information included with application for social security card</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall include with materials relating to the application for a social security card information describing young savers accounts (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408A">section 408A(g)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and related tax benefits.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H391A0D9612DE415586CCBCCAF2862AEC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Account funds disregarded for purposes of all means tested federal programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, assets accumulated in young savers accounts (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408A">section 408A(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) shall not be taken into account in determining any individual’s or household’s financial eligibility for, or amount of, any benefit or service, paid for in whole or in part with Federal funds, including student financial aid.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB1BDA2F945D4351BFCC25B301BE2BF5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2014.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

