<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H08CBB66502554E3FBA4E418E7D8C60F1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2490 IH: Bertie’s Respect for National Cemeteries Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2490</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001154">Mr. Shuster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that the prohibition against interment or
			 memorialization in the National Cemetery Administration or Arlington
			 National Cemetery of persons committing Federal or State capital crimes is
			 consistently carried out, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to
			 disinter the remains of George E. Siple from Indiantown Gap National
			 Cemetery, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC50E4A3D9C4545FBA3FA175DD2498ECD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H412CB23886A74725ACB77422A6B4B5B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bertie’s Respect for National Cemeteries Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD1981E4A25434515A073C2DD4D4BF759" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition against interment or memorialization in the National Cemetery Administration or Arlington National Cemetery of persons committing Federal or State capital crimes</header> <subsection id="H32BCD460A81A4F5FB2E4340644369261"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Responsibility of appropriate Federal official</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2411(a)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6B914C0A5F8C45D18375844169A2EE3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In the case</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) Except as provided by subparagraph (B), in the case</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F05961C3B624511A8D3AF7175E0D6A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EA9A88029F2496C91557C875E41141C" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="HF8B9A924A972440B9F3D689775016CB5" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate Federal official shall take every reasonable action, including by searching public records, to ensure that a person who will be interred in a cemetery in the National Cemetery Administration or in Arlington National Cemetery is not ineligible for such interment by reason of this section.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2760175BD0245FBB457F85E68C07AD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To disinter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2(c) of the Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/2411">38 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA488C4E328444F89BC1B1446CBCC1220"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>this section</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0B7E4C897F24C0FAA4A6B5F984105AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>Arlington National Cemetery</quote> the following: <quote>on or after the date of the enactment of such section 2411 and the amendment made by subsection (b) shall apply with respect to any such interment or memorialization conducted</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2C001F571A814348A78F9E514F51DCE4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disinterment of remains of George E. Siple from Indiantown Gap National Cemetery</header>
 <subsection id="HA614A243872A4593A31A43F81589B9C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disinterment of remains</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall disinter the remains of George E. Siple from Indiantown Gap National Cemetery.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H952F90AF3ECC4482A471DEC4BD2B9076"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification of next-of-Kin</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE2539EA07A5041D1834EC2A8C4688273"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the next-of-kin of record for George E. Siple of the impending disinterment of his remains; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE72F5CC3EB5E4A68BA5E9FD485A2C7B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon disinterment, relinquish the remains to the next-of-kin of record for George E. Siple or, if the next-of-kin of record for George E. Siple is unavailable, arrange for an appropriate disposition of the remains.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


