<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H716B8C349C7A4617ABE92C69B00444B4" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3514 IH: Workplace Action for a Growing Economy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3514</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150916">September 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the National Labor Relations Act to strengthen protections for employees wishing to
			 advocate for improved wages, hours, or other terms or conditions of
			 employment and to provide for stronger remedies for interference with
			 these rights, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4DCAAB6DE6454CEF8F5566E96012DC7D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCBF62F71B1434B1F8E8002FB8416E065" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workplace Action for a Growing Economy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WAGE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9973019288414FB5B012B402C96D4886"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD534FC9F66A44190B95247C5A9BBF2E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) was enacted to encourage the practice of collective bargaining and to protect the exercise by workers of full freedom of association in the workplace. Since its enactment in 1935, tens of millions of workers have bargained with their employers over wages, benefits, and other terms and conditions of employment and have raised the standard of living for all workers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CDB2B8BA25045C8904EAAB012927EDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Through acting collectively and bargaining with their employers, workers who are unionized earn 21.3 percent more than workers who are not covered by a collective bargaining agreement. They are 28.4 percent more likely to be covered by employer-provided health insurance and 30.9 percent more likely to have employer-provided pensions. The wage differential is even more pronounced for women and people of color. Unionized African-American workers earn 24.6 percent more than African-American workers who are not unionized, and unionized Latino workers earn 29.3 percent more than their peers who are not unionized. Unionized women earn 24 percent more than women who are not unionized, and the wage gap between men and women is much smaller at unionized workplaces. The wage gains achieved through collective bargaining benefit workers and their communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98B6316A6B264C658DF17EA1710C1B38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Unions and collective bargaining ensure that productivity gains are shared by working people. The decline in the percentage of workers covered by collective bargaining has contributed significantly to skyrocketing income inequality and flat wages.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07DC9BB5A64C49E19B3AE2D332C7AC1D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As enacted in 1935, the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) protects the right of all workers to join together with their co-workers to advocate for improvements in their pay, benefits, and working conditions, regardless of whether they seek representation by a union. The law protects the right of workers to discuss issues like pay and benefits without retaliation or interference by employers. However, the awareness of workers regarding their rights under the law is lacking, and many employers maintain policies that restrict the ability of workers to discuss workplace issues with each other, directly contravening these rights. Research shows that more than one-half of workers report that their employers have policies that prohibit or discourage workers from discussing pay with their co-workers. These policies and practices impede workers from exercising their rights under the law and impair their freedom of association at work.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H611576453B014AEC84E79CCCECEE7146"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Retaliation by employers against workers who exercise their rights under the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) persists at troubling levels. Employers routinely fire workers for trying to form a union at their workplace. In one out of 3 organizing campaigns, one or more workers are discharged for supporting joining a union. In fiscal year 2014, the National Labor Relations Board obtained reinstatement orders for 3,240 workers and obtained backpay awards totaling $43,800,000 for workers who faced illegal retaliation for exercising their rights. Discrimination for organizing hurts all workers, but minorities in particular, as minorities are more likely than Whites to seek to organize and receive a larger wage premium from collective bargaining.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55D9C75C5FFB467E8F3F476CA1B541F6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The current remedies are inadequate to deter employers from violating the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>). The remedies and penalties for violations of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) are far weaker than for other labor and employment laws, including the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a et seq.</external-xref>). Unlike other major labor and employment laws, there are no civil penalties for violations of the law. Workers cannot go to court to pursue relief on their own; they must rely on the National Labor Relations Board to prosecute their case.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD80CFAF5FB864ADFB131D2640BEA7FAD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In order to make the right to collective bargaining and freedom of association in the workplace a reality for workers, the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) must be strengthened.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HB752311491DB42208A330FE98BAF3C4E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="H292666F74CDB47F59314CBDC7E3F67A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to strengthen protections for employees engaged in collective action to improve their wages, hours, and terms and conditions of employment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B958F4AAAAC490F8A5C64263BC6D989"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide for stronger remedies for employees who face retaliation, discrimination, or other interference with the legal right of the employees to engage in collective action;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA25DF54D7AC64835907BD3DF47D0F9C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide for penalties against employers who violate the rights of employees to engage in collective action, in order to act as a meaningful deterrent against violating the law; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4158A9443C954259B47EBA6B3CE982D5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to streamline the enforcement procedures of the National Labor Relations Board to provide for more timely and effective enforcement of the law.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3E4CDDFA60A24D41BC22DC1FF3C438E5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strengthening remedies and enforcement for employees exercising their rights at work</header>
 <subsection id="H7DF36B81A0C142A4B58FF0FD286760D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Backpay</header><text>Section 10(c) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/160">29 U.S.C. 160(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote><italic>And provided further</italic>,</quote> and inserting “<italic>Provided further</italic>, That if the Board finds that an employer has discriminated against an employee in violation of paragraph (3) or (4) of section 8(a) or has committed a violation of section 8(a) that results in the discharge of an employee or other serious economic loss to an employee, the Board shall award the employee back pay and an additional amount as liquidated damages equal to 2 times the amount of such back pay, without any reduction (including any reduction based on the employee’s interim earnings or failure to earn interim earnings): <italic>Provided further</italic>,’’.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDFE56F457310422999E6E1A9E48C0959"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>Section 12 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/162">29 U.S.C. 162</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFFDADCA8FF1C4DE99DCA28A720528D03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Sec. 12.</header-in-text> Any person</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00D4B3AA749D4B67BC1331DE0D27CD76" style="OLC"><section commented="no" id="H63E7955BF67C4E01963C028B105F2B47"><enum>12.</enum><header>Civil penalties</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HC9466293E404406A8822290C1FFB4BBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Violations for interference with Board</header><text>Any person</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2F715F7D75174907B9978D358AA80316"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF43D98EFE0084985A8D76D1B5F4E3763" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H172CAF378B454C499C159266C4A9BE7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Violations of posting requirements</header><text>If the Board, or any agent or agency designated by the Board for such purposes, determines that an employer has willfully violated section 8(h), the Board shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H07A5EE7B6995479F839127EDB9EA792D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>state the findings of fact supporting such determination;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H89500DE7EE45451BBEBC57DD0FC68F9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue and cause to be served on such employer an order requiring that such employer post the notice described in such section and provide the information to new employees described in such section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H400F2C8F8F044E82BBE30FE47FCBE0E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>impose a civil penalty in an amount determined appropriate by the Board, except that in no case shall the amount of the fine exceed $500 for each such violation.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1876D0CA23D94796BD0496AF4C2AEEEE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Violations causing serious economic loss to employees</header>
 <paragraph id="H6C01FC05EFB24611941AC60401B7F6F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any employer who commits an unfair labor practice within the meaning of paragraph (3) or (4) of section 8(a) or a violation of section 8(a) that results in the discharge of an employee or other serious economic loss to an employee shall, in addition to any remedy ordered by the Board, be subject to a civil penalty. Such penalty shall be in an amount not to exceed $50,000 for each violation, except that the Board shall double the amount of such penalty, to an amount not to exceed $100,000, in any case where the employer has within the preceding 5 years committed another such violation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF1EE356941A425EAA62ADACED035F61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the amount of any civil penalty under this subsection, the Board shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF3F12FAD407462B80C7870356ABA191"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the gravity of the unfair labor practice;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC72ABAB218F4EC7BBA56A9BC62CE924"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact of the unfair labor practice on the charging party, on other persons seeking to exercise rights guaranteed by this Act, and on the public interest; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H714B6196AFE4407B96BF5F85B4BA8BB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the size of the employer.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B753E45B4674B2885389CDCE249C057"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personal liability</header><text>If the Board determines, based on the particular facts and circumstances presented, that personal liability is warranted, a civil penalty for a violation described in this subsection may also be assessed against any officer or director of the employer who committed the violation or had the authority to prevent the violation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0F15E0EAB6D4D269C0A1ED42D77F07A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joint and several liability</header><text>An employer shall be jointly and severally liable under this Act for any violations of this Act involving one or more employees supplied by another employer to perform labor within the employer's usual course of business, except for purposes of subsection (e).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD660BAAAED7443890000ECA39125A48"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Injunctions against unfair labor practices involving discharge or other serious economic loss</header>
 <paragraph id="H8BBA2FC3C42542CAAC4FC262562AAF61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 10(l) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/160">29 U.S.C. 160(l)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HCFDCFC4D33C342A9940FD3AFCCC34E7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>charged that</quote> the following: <quote>an employer has engaged in an unfair labor practice within the meaning of section 8(a) that significantly interferes with, restrains, or coerces employees in the exercise of the rights guaranteed under section 7 and involves discharge or other serious economic harm to an employee or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6CE361C54034F759877C581E343B5B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>as it deems just and proper, notwithstanding any other provision of law:</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>to protect the rights guaranteed by section 7, notwithstanding any other provision of law. The district court shall grant the relief requested unless the court concludes that there is no reasonable likelihood that the Board will succeed on the merits of the Board’s claim:</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H417D25933FFD44AE93F29E972D087974"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 10(m) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/160">29 U.S.C. 160(m)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>under circumstances not subject to subsection (l)</quote> after <quote>section 8</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H664EAA54A3A54010992E07C576881956"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private enforcement</header><text>Section 12 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/162">29 U.S.C. 162</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7080C4364524BC78AB515A4151CB986" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HB0C0597B713045859F36D862A1355708"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Right to civil action</header>
 <paragraph id="HEF0DE637B7AB4B6C9FCAAF1880A0E55E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who is injured by reason of any violation of paragraph (1) or (3) of section 8(a) may, in addition to or in lieu of filing a charge alleging such unfair labor practice with the Board in accordance with this Act, bring a civil action in the appropriate district court of the United States against the employer within 180 days of the violation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E97BC9C5D4442AA88EFDA8274AA7A1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Available relief</header><text>Relief granted in an action under paragraph (1) may include any relief authorized by section 706(g) of the Civil Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-5">42 U.S.C. 2000e–5(g)</external-xref>) or by section 1977A(b) of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1981a">42 U.S.C. 1981a(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H622876F160F4412D885DFF003FFB36E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Attorney's fee</header><text>In any action or proceeding under this subsection, the court may allow the prevailing party a reasonable attorney’s fee (including expert fees) as part of the costs.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2A20C1361DC64EA4A86C300721B8FB2E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Ensuring fair remedies for all workers</header><text>Section 10(c) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/160">29 U.S.C. 160(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>suffered by him:</quote> and inserting <quote>suffered by such employee: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That back pay shall not be denied on the basis that the employee is, or was during the time of relevant employment or during the back pay period, an unauthorized alien as defined in section 274A(h)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(h)(3)</external-xref>) or any other provision of Federal law relating to the unlawful employment of aliens:</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDD3BA626805C44E8A63E48A9B6E65522"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Remedying election interference</header><text>Section 9(c) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF695F45E604F4FECBD0F108BA8D65103"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (6) and (7), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDF9C43B4CC0450BA1CEF4D2D7BAB3A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46A469C98F3E46DCA31F52D852E1BE9D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H03FF85D40C6647B292374C498BDD9E65" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Bargaining order based on majority of votes</header><text>If the Board finds that, in an election under paragraph (1), a majority of the valid votes cast in a unit appropriate for purposes of collective bargaining have been cast in favor of representation by the labor organization, the Board shall issue an order requiring the employer to collectively bargain with the labor organization in accordance with section 8(d).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H445F235E40DF4ED2BC0FD02E36E0F525" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dismissal; bargaining orders in other situations</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD96DAB6B88FB426EA042B0A8E31C1468"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Dismissal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Board finds that, in an election under paragraph (1), a majority of the valid votes cast in a unit appropriate for purposes of collective bargaining have not been cast in favor of representation by the labor organization, the Board shall dismiss the petition, subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6FCAB88D1C441CE95AC246209E08D84"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rules for employer violations or interference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case where a majority of the valid votes cast in a unit appropriate for purposes of collective bargaining have not been cast in favor of representation by the labor organization and the Board determines that the election should be set aside because the employer has committed a violation of this Act, or otherwise interfered with a fair election, and has not demonstrated that the violation or other interference is unlikely to have affected the outcome of the election, the Board shall, without ordering a new or rerun election, issue an order requiring the employer to bargain with the labor organization in accordance with section 8(d) if, at any time during the period beginning 1 year preceding the date of the commencement of the election and ending on the date upon which the Board makes the determination of a violation or other interference under subparagraph (A), a majority of the employees in the bargaining unit have signed authorizations designating the labor organization as their collective bargaining representative.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE344A3526E0E4F7EABC00815D6CF0CD4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other election interference</header><text>In any case where the Board determines that an election under this paragraph should be set aside, the Board shall direct a rerun election with appropriate additional safeguards necessary to ensure a fair election process, except in cases where the Board issues a bargaining order under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE007E9C814DC4038B18C5E9D98EA6E40"><enum>5.</enum><header>Modernization</header>
 <subsection id="HD824AC1039B04BBC84A3AB4826B83D4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prevention of unfair labor practices</header><text>Section 8 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48F22CEAB6504B76869EAC5F574DED79" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H799393823A51498EB942600E3E63D975"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Postings of notice</header>
 <paragraph id="H0D4821E74D8148198624967E4E0CAFD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall promulgate regulations requiring each employer to post and maintain, in conspicuous places where notices to employees and applicants for employment are customarily posted both physically and electronically, a notice setting forth the rights and protections afforded employees under this Act. The Board shall provide to employers the form and text of such notice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C51920E66BA4931988C3173C4D87720"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification of new employees</header><text>The Board shall promulgate regulations requiring employers to notify each new employee of the information contained in the notice described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8F2C237BA17045AB989819AA2649D19B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcing compliance with orders of the Board</header>
 <paragraph id="H6A02F2CE46BF4DF7B04F9D83F55707AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 10 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/160">29 U.S.C. 160</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CD341A2F749446C9BF37FDA5211CC9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AE5F99C210349A695EB37BEAD1E2B4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08A95CFAEDC8405CAE840D7B7A4B6321"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C262DB0D7584857883F1BBAE93D14D5" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="H15B2AD1BE0F14C7FB9556848DA5D5C7E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcing compliance with orders of the Board</header>
 <paragraph id="H952BF4049E07492684910268082F6E55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each order of the Board shall take effect 30 days from the date upon which notice of the order is given, unless otherwise directed by the Board. Each such orders shall continue in force indefinitely or for the period of time specified in the order, or until the Board or a court of competent jurisdiction issues a superseding order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H01BBE60829A344728886B3FC64346AAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of the Board</header><text>If any person or entity fails or neglects to obey any order of the Board while such order is in effect, the Board shall apply to the district court of the United States in which the unfair labor practice or other subject of the order occurred, or in which such person or entity resides or transacts business, for the enforcement of such order. The Board shall file in the court the record in the proceedings, as provided in section 2112 of title 28, United States Code. Any person that was a party to the underlying Board proceeding may join in the proceeding initiated by the Board.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0382C5DD8FE40A48BBE8880B46B1C60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>If, after having provided a person or entity with notice and an opportunity to be heard regarding a request under paragraph (2) for the enforcement of an order, the court determines that the order was regularly made and duly served, and that the person or entity is in disobedience of the same, the court shall enforce obedience to such order by a writ of injunction or other proper process, mandatory or otherwise, to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD6815D92A63C4C758C2C02CD140C0AAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restrain such person or entity or the officers, agents, or representatives of such person or entity, from further disobedience of such order; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E4BEEAFE2294E9BBCA1CD33388246B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enjoin upon such person or entity, officers, agents, or representatives obedience to the same.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40F8E8CDADA244B6ABF2E312CBFC2F57"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Violations of orders by the Board</header><text>Any person or entity who willfully and knowingly violates any rule, regulation, restriction, condition, or order made or imposed by the Board under authority of this Act shall, in addition to any other penalties provided by law, be subject to a civil penalty of not to exceed $10,000 for each and every day during which such violation occurs, commencing with the effective date of any such rule, regulation, restriction, condition, or order. Such civil penalty may be imposed by the Board or by a court in a proceeding initiated by the Board under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBCC278381D2496FA59C4ACDE470ABD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>The National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8A239CFA3D184B59ADD7DD47E72806B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 9(d), by striking <quote>section 10(e) or 10(f)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (d) or (f) of section 10</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7088513D01864B919DCCFDF3E515FD29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 10—</text> <clause id="H71C3DEF5EB1E455FA0DA56516BFDE6E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>subsection (e) of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (d)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF0B0C063D384F58BD1727601AAF0E29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>subsection (e) or (f) of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (d) or (f)</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

