<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H620721AA43364735B156C033C4B9A734" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1232 IH: Stop Militarizing Law Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1232</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000367">Mr. Amash</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O’Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to make certain limitations on the transfer of personal property to Federal and State agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8544A389F7BF481F843DE102D7D5F8B5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9127AB74649B446D9C99F42A7C0520D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Militarizing Law Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0C4B9AD94BBD4DDF89E99E43F12DC3D0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3142D2D1BFA94F4B8E83E08925B68D08"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under section 2576a of title 10, United States Code, the Department of Defense is authorized to provide excess property to local law enforcement agencies. The Defense Logistics Agency, administers such section by operating the Law Enforcement Support Office program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA8CE39B2E044BF0A0E42E45674A9247"><enum>(2)</enum><text>New and used material, including mine-resistant ambush-protected vehicles and weapons determined by the Department of Defense to be <quote>military grade</quote> are transferred to local and Federal law enforcement agencies through the program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D0659D4307C4E07848A29267F0E6656"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As a result local law enforcement agencies, including police and sheriff’s departments, are acquiring this material for use in their normal operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31B4C4EEDE084B22B7BAAC2CDAAEAF0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a result of the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, military equipment purchased for, and used in, those wars has become excess property and has been made available for transfer to local and Federal law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFC19703B93C4E8B899DC34666032D5F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to public reports, approximately 12,000 police organizations across the country were able to procure nearly $500,000,000 worth of excess military merchandise including firearms, computers, helicopters, clothing, and other products, at no charge during fiscal year 2011 alone.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53BFAF5097EF423793EA5A21A961E3FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">More than $4,000,000,000 worth of weapons and equipment have been transferred to police organizations in all 50 states and four territories through the program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3783F2EE1CCF45B295622C7FE9642BAD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In May 2012, the Defense Logistics Agency instituted a moratorium on weapons transfers through the program after reports of missing equipment and inappropriate weapons transfers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCD8E5116FB24E32B583B46CCDFFB7BC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Though the moratorium was widely publicized, it was lifted in October 2013 without adequate safeguards.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFB2F94066F74FBAB92D4961A27AA5F2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>As a result, Federal, State, and local law enforcement departments across the country are eligible again to acquire free <quote>military-grade</quote> weapons and equipment that could be used inappropriately during policing efforts in which citizens and taxpayers could be harmed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09BBE2991DF841D3B021FB21BDA0398F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Pursuant to section III(J) of a Defense Logistics Agency memorandum of understanding, property obtained through the program must be placed into use within one year of receipt, possibly providing an incentive for the unnecessary and potentially dangerous use of <quote>military grade</quote> equipment by local law enforcement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7DD2112A0134581A2C78A68F32A85BB"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Defense categorizes equipment eligible for transfer under the 1033 program as <quote>controlled</quote> and <quote>un-controlled</quote> equipment. <quote>Controlled equipment</quote> includes weapons, explosives such as flash-bang grenades, mine resistant ambush protected vehicles, long range acoustic devices, aircraft capable of being modified to carry armament that are combat coded, and silencers, among other military grade items.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HFED1E665EB7744D9B983984391A5F334"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on Department of Defense transfer of personal property to local law enforcement agencies</header> <subsection id="H1DB1225490674E6886F25B966FB83137"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2576a of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5427C608C82C44F69E5E13B3A7DA5E18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H841D5E6F7FAB4DFD903DE128838C7C01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>counter-drug and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1C9E041854445D4B120DA348AD825C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and the Director of National Drug Control Policy</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BE45F8F0CCE4BD591BFFAB7F34E04CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HED2FAE9562C84EF0AF3D74CFFDB397EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF4C2385D50D4A9D9C702ABEDA911FC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1685B4150D0C461680C35F7B7314315B"><enum>(C)</enum><text> by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H4CA36FFD2D0C49B5BE450D2971BBD29A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H9C78EA0C0E064EDEB8E36A67DE8DDD25"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recipient certifies to the Department of Defense that it has the personnel and technical capacity, including training, to operate the property;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13F3FE11678A4E328A5F617962FD7FD0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the recipient submits to the Department of Defense a description of how the recipient expects to use the property;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D0659377E3D4845BA15A2AD785E76C9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the recipient certifies to the Department of Defense that if the recipient determines that the property is surplus to the needs of the recipient, the recipient will return the property to the Department of Defense; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBB71F6CC64D4FADA8574418E6651E1B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>with respect to a recipient that is not a Federal agency, the recipient certifies to the Department of Defense that the recipient notified the local community of the request for personal property under this section by—</text> <subparagraph id="H8ADC9948BFE948F59D3E736C310FB14A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publishing a notice of such request on a publicly accessible Internet website;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02EA2FB675484F4883E1216E053E9E6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>posting such notice at several prominent locations in the jurisdiction of the recipient; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E872B032E02494FB5A75C0F1D730E9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensuring that such notices were available to the local community for a period of not less than 30 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5DF8C8ED29A423F90BE14CA04649A25"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CC0A83AB52E4B66B24FFB27D4D96FCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H6C3A0BCB7E704B5D87615A2241A41989" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H8813AC93580D49BAAD4B5AB9389BB411"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual certification accounting for transferred property</header> 
<paragraph id="HB138DA1DDE1049C1A24B7EB9CA18D41C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress certification in writing that each Federal or State agency to which the Secretary has transferred property under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H116B0EA3840045BAB3068BBBA955DE38" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has provided to the Secretary documentation accounting for all controlled personal property, including arms and ammunition, that the Secretary has transferred to the agency, including any item described in subsection (f) so transferred before the date of the enactment of the Stop Militarizing Law Enforcement Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34F0ADCC3776472E8D88106304B205BC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a non-Federal agency, carried out each of paragraphs (5) through (8) of subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA9F34F234204975B145997066BB9E5B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the Secretary cannot provide a certification under paragraph (1) for a Federal or State agency, the Secretary may not transfer additional property to that agency under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E8E3BFA32964E2F89A1D72FDE5D480B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report on excess property</header><text>Before making any property available for transfer under this section, the Secretary shall annually submit to Congress a description of the property to be transferred together with a certification that the transfer of the property would not violate this section or any other provision of law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD79816C1BA2F475EB5A42581A25012E0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitations on transfers</header> <paragraph id="H2B91DB19CFE84AF1B142733301B826D4" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may not transfer the following personal property of the Department of Defense under this section:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7657490A3B6E493C952E25B3E2F461D9" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Controlled firearms, ammunition, grenades (including stun and flash-bang) and explosives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CC1029623DA4BF1AC57EB4182507F9D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Controlled vehicles, highly mobile multi-wheeled vehicles, mine-resistant ambush-protected vehicles, trucks, truck dump, truck utility, and truck carryall.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H183EF3BCA3B84A5EB054A98E0A04AB94" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Drones that are armored, weaponized, or both.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE42CE36F5BBC415D982305139B482F25" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Controlled aircraft that—</text> 
<clause id="H85157EFDD2DF4EE2B3CCC3F43259BE34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are combat configured or combat coded; or</text></clause> <clause id="H2795DB1476634064905B196FE89AA7E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have no established commercial flight application.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65AE2473DC1941CC8F5EA9237B118228" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Silencers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3E2DEE608094CE09B9772F56DC2CC59" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Long range acoustic devices.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0AEA75070CB1406CBD5522DDF58B4220" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Items in the Federal Supply Class of banned items.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DCB95F134E14C7E852F2CF7A62AC250" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may not require, as a condition of a transfer under this section, that a Federal or State agency demonstrate the use of any small arms or ammunition.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6DA54F7D08742A2AA77B574D5AD0B9D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The limitations under this subsection shall also apply with respect to the transfer of previously transferred property of the Department of Defense from one Federal or State agency to another such agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H700AF982FD99480AB42B5E9B38C33620" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum> <subparagraph id="H35F4217092FA49859998835EE2793B9B" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary may waive the applicability of paragraph (1) to a vehicle described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph (other than a mine-resistant ambush-protected vehicle), if the Secretary determines that such a waiver is necessary for disaster or rescue purposes or for another purpose where life and public safety are at risk, as demonstrated by the proposed recipient of the vehicle.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82019BC39A394ADEB1B01F5D590FAE69" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the Secretary issues a waiver under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HAABDB5EC59164819A19B285BA142BE85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit to Congress notice of the waiver, and post such notice on a public Internet website of the Department, by not later than 30 days after the date on which the waiver is issued; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2870515A5E064B1686896FA54DAFD6D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require, as a condition of the waiver, that the recipient of the vehicle for which the waiver is issued provides public notice of the waiver and the transfer, including the type of vehicle and the purpose for which it is transferred, in the jurisdiction where the recipient is located by not later than 30 days after the date on which the waiver is issued.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF12925AE8CE84930B39A1EEA11D059D0" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary may provide for an exemption to the limitation under subparagraph (D) of paragraph (1) in the case of parts for aircraft described in such subparagraph that are transferred as part of regular maintenance of aircraft in an existing fleet.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCAC4290EC3B641FCB6BFCBEF391064BC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Conditions for extension of program</header> 
<paragraph id="HFE50E81BBD19496AA6B4C88C9C3F4548" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year may not be obligated or expended to carry out this section unless the Secretary submits to Congress certification that for the preceding fiscal year that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCB0CAA91BE664DE6A90350653DC50B36" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each Federal or State agency that has received covered property transferred under this section has—</text> 
<clause id="H60278EC61B5340CF87A6ECA45B68AFB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrated 100 percent accountability for all such property, in accordance with subparagraph (B) or (C), as applicable; or</text></clause> <clause id="H5590326C8EEA42D09238447A7B5985D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>been suspended from the program pursuant to subparagraph (D);</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4F21CCA947442C18A135C38C6CFFF65" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each non-Federal agency that has received covered property under this section, the State coordinator responsible for each such agency has verified that the coordinator or an agent of the coordinator has conducted an in-person inventory of the property transferred to the agency and that 100 percent of such property was accounted for during the inventory or that the agency has been suspended from the program pursuant to subparagraph (D);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B468D3BD2A747AFAEE09ED763C40884" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each Federal agency that has received covered property under this section, the Secretary of Defense or an agent of the Secretary has conducted an in-person inventory of the property transferred to the agency and that 100 percent of such property was accounted for during the inventory or that the agency has been suspended from the program pursuant to subparagraph (D);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9C1BA3A8AAE4B0AB5319763887B4F36" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the eligibility of any agency that has received covered property under this section for which 100 percent of the property was not accounted for during an inventory described in subparagraph (A) or (B), as applicable, to receive any property transferred under this section has been suspended; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9862C453C5E4EB4B5ACFF591022B21F" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>each State coordinator has certified, for each non-Federal agency located in the State for which the State coordinator is responsible that—</text> 
<clause id="HC3E82D33476B474096268C375503C910"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency has complied with all requirements under this section; or</text></clause> <clause id="HB1CC8D5D3349449281552D555AA16581"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the eligibility of the agency to receive property transferred under this section has been suspended; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA816FFCE21834045BF53136D42C4766E" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense has certified, for each Federal agency that has received property under this section that—</text> <clause id="H5D7EF656BDF04356AC3859BBC8F58030"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency has complied with all requirements under this section; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA8BA93C8268A47C1B3AD38239770441C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the eligibility of the agency to receive property transferred under this section has been suspended.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56740F6030034526BE35438E76FECCDD" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>covered property</quote> means property classified as controlled equipment.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43564333F4634D43A4506A75FE4418A3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition on ownership</header><text>A Federal or State agency that receives property classified as controlled equipment under this section may never take ownership of the property.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0776F8140C474771A5FF65E56C0D174E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Website</header><text>The Defense Logistics Agency shall maintain an Internet website on which the following information shall be made publicly available:</text> 
<paragraph id="H80DA266CDD6B49C3A0E3FA1E9BDD4984"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of each transfer made under this section, including transfers made before and after the date of the enactment of the Stop Militarizing Law Enforcement Act, broken down by State, county, and recipient.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BB8958A5A6A4176BDE7C7AE036FCA65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During the 30-day period preceding the date on which any property is transferred under this section, a description of the property to be transferred and the recipient of the transferred items.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6692264E987436E9676C2672E846716"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Notice of any use of controlled equipment by the recipient of property transferred under this section as provided under subsection (l).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC426E176F2D04B5FBD06FC7FFB19B44F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Notice to Congress of property downgrades</header><text>Not later than 30 days before downgrading the classification of any item of personal property from controlled or Federal Supply Class, the Secretary shall submit to Congress notice of the proposed downgrade.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0E6B07EBE2D4B4E86F8C6E048BC6AE6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Notice to Congress of property cannibalization</header><text>Before the Defense Logistics Agency authorizes the recipient of property transferred under this section to cannibalize the property, the Secretary shall submit to Congress notice of such authorization, including the name of the recipient requesting the authorization, the purpose of the proposed cannibalization, and the type of property proposed to be cannibalized.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBBE7D71F093547B2B86C64D9C764250A"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Quarterly reports on use of controlled equipment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the last day of a fiscal quarter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on any uses of controlled equipment transferred under this section during that fiscal quarter.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H206F4C8C84FB4E3A8DCE55C50A7408B7"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the last day of a fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the following for the preceding fiscal year:</text> <paragraph id="H916D50DE130E4E8F902BE238466BD848"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The percentage of equipment lost by recipients of property transferred under this section, including specific information about the type of property lost, the monetary value of such property, and the recipient that lost the property.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A4312E152044D9B9F5CD0174733543F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The transfer of any new (condition code A) property transferred under this section, including specific information about the type of property, the recipient of the property, the monetary value of each item of the property, and the total monetary value of all such property transferred during the fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H73D28D973958439B81DC3FD594CE0480"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any transfer of property made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

