<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2BA7DAE418B54499BCE398AFE9DE9599" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4304 IH: Nuclear Worker Residual Contaminations Compensation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4304</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Department of Labor to conduct a study on residual contamination of workers at
			 certain facilities related to the Department of Energy’s processing and
			 production of materials that emit radiation.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H455CB56B92BD496FA731ADEEECFC1F10" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF4833C4698444DACBB71F27511E4F717" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nuclear Worker Residual Contaminations Compensation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H029F5DA9132B4F78A60462EC2984D921"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on residual contaminations of workers at certain contractor and subsidiary facilities</header> <subsection id="HEDEE663379D748879BDA7D6070F413A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall oversee a study on residual contamination of workers at certain facilities that are members of the Special Exposure Cohort (described in section 3621(14) of the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000) owned or operated by contractors of the Department of Energy and subsidiaries of such contractors. Such study shall be conducted by independent advisors and medical experts of each atomic energy employer designated by the Secretary of Energy under section 3621(4)(B) of such Act and Beryllium vendor (as defined in paragraph (6) of such section).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3205E7A8AD5F45FE90AED8FE6F2C4BF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report on the results of such study not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


