<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E7DE9AE228E4A5BA72A6F35E409DBE7" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2738 IH: Highways Bettering the Economy and Environment Pollinator Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2738</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150611">June 11, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 23, United States Code, to encourage and facilitate efforts by States and other transportation rights-of-way managers to adopt integrated vegetation management practices, including enhancing plantings of native forbs and grasses that provide habitats and forage for Monarch butterflies, native bees, and other native pollinators, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC0FAE2E28338429088213592E2EF64CF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H66F4A99AD48D47C189A36BF5D8E73E01" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Highways Bettering the Economy and Environment Pollinator Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB184CB74FD56401685C5FFE3D18CD2D2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB618AA2780CD4710AF35494D3E4935A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The roadside vegetation management practices of both State governments and the Federal Government aim to secure motorist safety, reduce the presence of noxious weeds, manage stormwater runoff, and stabilize the soil.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7AED969EAC348219524CC3A32264091"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Native forbs and grasses are less likely to encroach onto roads than invasive species, such as kudzu.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15BC6F8A031B4E2B8EA360754AF850F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Integrated vegetation management practices could reduce the cost of maintaining roadside vegetation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H762F0E6C8FA8459BBA0035D084E6071D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Native forbs and grasses are better adapted to local conditions and thus require less active management, reducing the need to replant, weed, and mow the areas adjacent to the road.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26E454BCDD8B4787916956AA7EA21E9B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Pollinators, such as native bees, honey bees, birds, bats, Monarch butterflies, and other butterflies, are suffering drastic population loss.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07CDFE50BF504BC4BDAD365BD9A8571F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Pollinators are vital for American agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC50C246A8A804FEC88AC6B8649CBECF3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Responsible for 1 out of every 3 bites of food we eat, a diverse pollinator population is necessary for maintaining the diversity of our plant life and food supply.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDB5748022BC49759149A897B44F4CBA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Studies have shown supporting native forbs and grasses along the roadside can be beneficial to the pollinator population by providing migratory corridors and habitat and forage connectivity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3650E13B982D46B0B3B61936915375FF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Plantings of noninvasive, locally appropriate milkweed species can create migratory way stations for the endangered Monarch butterfly and can facilitate migrations of other pollinators.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H038EEA73B0E44EFA8FC29D455DD45E1F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Enhancing pollinator populations on rights-of-way can result in improved pollination services for neighboring lands, including agriculture and wildlife ecosystems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EE87B9D0DDE4F0A85B6F90162CEDCD1"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Highway rights-of-way managed by States represent 17,000,000 acres of pollinator habitat conservation opportunity, and similar opportunities and benefits exist on other transportation rights-of-way.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H9F1F3AA2912F407E947E571AEFAF29C6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administrative provisions to encourage pollinator habitat and forage on transportation rights-of-way</header> <subsection id="H327A6D90F99145D5ABC4AF50F98AB376"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 319 of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7FBBA1359760428CA8ECDF1DF665DDA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a) by striking <quote>beauty adjacent</quote> and inserting <quote>beauty (including the enhancement of habitat and forage for pollinators) adjacent</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18477A6927544E14A19F1374A54F12AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1508F93483D44D6EB90A5B570E5AD38F" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HEB0B95B7E5554364BAB5CFAE65573ADE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Encouragement of pollinator habitat and forage development and protection on transportation rights-of-Way</header><text>In carrying out any program administered by the Secretary, the Secretary shall, in conjunction with willing States, as appropriate—</text> <paragraph id="HD3E7BF4936854E34A7A3FCD708EF76FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct or encourage integrated vegetation management practices on roadsides and other transportation rights-of-way, including reduced mowing;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5C506C2A12E4AE4BA170EFDE662B393"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance the development of habitat and forage for Monarch butterflies, other native pollinators, and honey bees through plantings of native forbs and grasses, including noninvasive, native milkweed species that can serve as migratory way stations for butterflies and can facilitate migrations of other pollinators;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB19DB14BD194B64A105970934588C0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage leveraging through partnerships and coordination with stakeholders in support of pollinators and plantings of native forbs and grasses, such as environmental groups, research institutions, other agencies, businesses, and community organizations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59C12384666E43088267B497E67188F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct or facilitate research and demonstration projects on the economic and environmental benefits and best practices for integrated vegetation management, reduced mowing, and plantings of native forbs and grasses for pollinator habitat, forage, and migratory way stations for Monarch butterflies and other migrating pollinators; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DB404C602824E7D89863DB812BC19A7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit participation in any activities outlined under paragraphs (1) through (4), by representatives of transportation landscape management, pollinator health, agriculture, horticulture, and other affected communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A6AE03F29324FE0A7F6286E9CE41F0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall transmit to Congress a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H31BFD5DA9E98494AB2D5806DFAD5339B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of current programs and authorities available to carry out section 319(c) of title 23, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82402639237043F6ADE902EB087CDE1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of programs and authorities being used to implement such section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE94CCC870B804484A921903A1B890278"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of actions being taken by willing State transportation departments and other managers of transportation rights-of-way to implement integrated vegetation management practices, reduce mowing, and enhance habitat and forage for Monarch butterflies, other native pollinators, and honey bees through plantings of native forbs and grasses and migratory way stations for Monarch butterflies and other migrating pollinators;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5921A397D7F40DAB2830A5CF1B02130"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a summary of Department of Transportation funds expended for activities undertaken pursuant to such section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H011B53C4E23342D285AD80B380A03EBC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any recommendations for further action.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD7BDCF9DB9604853B249904E115FF9C2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Provision of habitat, forage, and migratory way stations for monarch butterflies, other native pollinators, and honey bees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 329(a)(1) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>provision of habitat, forage, and migratory way stations for Monarch butterflies, other native pollinators, and honey bees,</quote> before <quote>and aesthetic enhancement</quote>.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

