<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6BC796577ED14FB397CF694D0B684F1F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1373 IH: Providers COMPETE Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1373</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150316">March 16, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to consider, within the annual rulemaking processes, the effect of regulatory changes to certain Medicare payment systems on provider consolidation.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H87054B6DDC8C46169C09FED673AD3217" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7DB2F6EA4BCF4B77B90F7C7CB74C43A8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providers Consolidation and Medicare Payments Examined through Evaluation Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote>Providers COMPETE Act of 2015</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0900FCFB5B904C548870AD97EE535ECE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rulemaking that implements certain Medicare payment changes to consider effects on provider consolidation</header> <subsection id="HE693F3EE319043429D8849EB9E24F156"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning for 2016, as part of any annual notice and comment rulemaking process to implement changes to payment systems under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) for items and services under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (including those for inpatient and outpatient hospital services, physicians’ services, and services furnished by other providers of services and suppliers), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall seek public comment on and evaluate the extent to which, and how, such a change is projected to affect provider consolidation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H500373683F634C1AA8DFCB7167A90B84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination and consultation</header> 
<paragraph id="H414FBB4E5FAA4B62A47D2ACBF11CE7F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Internal coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of conducting the evaluations under subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall ensure appropriate coordination within the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services such that experts with respect to the applicable payment system under title XVIII of the Social Security Act work collaboratively for purposes of such evaluations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CE4C99614B04AD39D8CF4C4E80AF59E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of conducting the evaluations under subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services may consult with the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission established under section 1805 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395b-6">42 U.S.C. 1395b–6</external-xref>), the Federal Trade Commission, other governmental agencies, and private sector entities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H316FD9067828462B8C8896065C844988"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provider consolidation defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>provider consolidation</term> includes the vertical or horizontal integration among providers of services and suppliers, including professional practices, health care settings, and ancillary services by any entity (such as a health system, group practice, or health insurer).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

