<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H395C8E1976B64910B68CAB206CF3D829" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1852 IH: 21st Century Investment Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1852</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent the credit for increasing research
			 activities, to increase such credit for amounts paid or incurred for
			 qualified research occurring in the United States, and to increase the
			 domestic production activities deduction for the manufacture of property
			 substantially all of the research and development of which occurred in the
			 United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3A09EC213D914F17BDC09C14F0DC4E3F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8305A4D0993144F7B221DFCD2E14BEAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Investment Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H87FFBE4911184EADB7616BB9504A894C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Research credit made permanent</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1407DDE87FC741C8B6ED90B8005D0FDF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/41">Section 41</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subsection (h).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA5F8EEF0F24B43B29FA26A094B16C937"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H6515F28B33A14F17AC34219F0BB86C1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 41(c) of such Code is amended by striking paragraph (4).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H30BBB9C25DD94A69A3D15ADDD421B814"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) of section 45C(b) of such Code is amended by striking subparagraph (D).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H833B8B20B5D44739804D571FB0190948"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after December 31, 2014.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HAB0ECA51C2F14D7DB84F90D28553BA31"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increase in research credit for contracted research with United States businesses</header>
 <subsection id="H5F217D4C6AAB438E8DBF4D69D19F8A07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/41">Section 41</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 2 of this Act, is amended by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9AA90BCF2DF4D2790702B87EDF7F6EE" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H44C3083C92794B48B5E1F36A2596DB37"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Special rule for contracted research with United States manufacturing business</header>
 <paragraph id="H251CEE5314934E94AE33BA09B5867F89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the taxpayer elects the application of this subsection, subsection (a)(1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>25 percent</quote> for <quote>20 percent</quote> with respect to qualified United States research expenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF684B79822D847CCA478FD7CBE861A7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified United States research expenses</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>qualified United States research expenses</quote> means any amount paid or incurred by the taxpayer to any person (other than an employee of the taxpayer) for qualified research, substantially all of which occurs in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34BBE3C1650944A8894927B8693A6A45"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Separate application of section</header><text>In the case of any election of the application of this subsection, this section shall be applied separately with respect to qualified United States research expenses.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF3FC8CD5D3C741D5976C26A26F3FE65C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred for taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6F7F007B67AC46DCBC8EC7D23F64052E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Increase in domestic production activities deduction for manufactured property researched and
			 developed in United States</header>
 <subsection id="H06434B34F16C4366B7FE316272D53D60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/199">Section 199(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating paragraph (10) as paragraph (11) and by inserting after paragraph (9) the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E4F3D60C1064C05AEEA4C25E096E34E" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H948C7D429EE34FAB85AF0FE8CD49E301"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Special rule for certain manufacturing</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3F8F0F7722D049069FCA25A64DC569C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of qualified production activities income attributable to the manufacture or production of qualifying production property substantially all of the research and development of which occurred in the United States, subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>15 percent</quote> for <quote>9 percent</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC515E1608E7C4DC7845A9CD097658AFE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule when taxable income used to determine deduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxable year for which the taxpayer’s qualified production activities income exceeds the taxpayer’s taxable income (determined without regard to this section), the amount of taxable income to which the 15 percent amount in subparagraph (A) applies under subsection (a)(1) shall be an amount equal to the amount which bears the same ratio to such taxable income (as so determined) as—</text>
 <clause id="H2F1E666FA95D4E2C8D71A90DD5FDB02A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of qualified production activities income of the taxpayer for the taxable year which is attributable to the manufacture or production of qualifying production property substantially all of the research and development with respect to which occurred in the United States, bears to</text>
 </clause><clause id="H683C14800E78469BB8200EE2F1F2AAEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all qualified production activities income of the taxpayer for the taxable year.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14115B5E60CC4E7E81550A726DED05E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2024.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAA453463D336414D808753B37C75DA45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


