<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2A1527764C1B4EF0A8BDBBCDB2AC4A85" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1407 IH: Regulatory Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1407</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150317">March 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000373">Mr. Ashford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish an independent advisory committee to review certain regulations, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H497D797EFD354899991E29C7E877B6B3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC9D31164ABB641B7BA696E746B5A3476" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulatory Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA8623E7B326F4BC485C51AFC179B5607"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H15DD2EBCAE2E4DC894431BA65A7CB7C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Commission</term> means the Regulatory Improvement Commission established under section 3;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A9DF1AEE96C47ECA8A5C429F5A0DBA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>commission bill</term> means a bill consisting of the proposed legislative language of the Commission recommended under section 4(h)(2)(C) and introduced under section 4(i)(1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAAF550DF0324F829F1FB5EE314A2037"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered regulation</term> means a regulation that has been finalized not later than 10 years before the date on which the Commission is established.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H555ABB11A5334CA591D4E3CEAD8CBC60"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Commission</header>
 <subsection id="H4FE3A91F4ACC46A3B5FC6DA8D9788754"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the legislative branch a commission to be known as the <quote>Regulatory Improvement Commission</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8E073D2EEAF74BF8AA3FF8E3A4655177"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="H725305138ADA4F76ACC3831BFFD79075"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 9 members, of whom—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H758098308BD4459B92F2AFE64A494DFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 member shall be appointed by the President, and shall serve as the Chairperson of the Commission;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD415E849F072488593C69B47F737032A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD98C5384CA5B41EAAB9F50748A9E709A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04D193AE60544EE1B1BBAA1BE61555A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF394FFA0871043D69FD453BB1EB3A940"><enum>(E)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H254C5A0717F74AFC94BB8036F4408640"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date</header><text>The appointment of the members of the Commission shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H7C6196E076D6495BBEAE3ADBF873B4D3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifications</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4848813A4D0E4CF98A077F5FA0313936"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Chair of the Commission shall be an individual with expertise and experience in rulemaking, such as past Administrators of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, past chairmen of the Administrative Conference of the United States, and other individuals with similar expertise and experience in rulemaking affairs and the administration of regulatory reviews.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2497BC983ADB4457916F23F7ADCD2CD5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Members</header><text>Members appointed to the Commission shall be prominent citizens of the United States with national recognition and a significant depth of experience and responsibilities in matters relating to government service, regulatory policy, economics, Federal agency management, public administration, and law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CD73C244C4542F38A1A643F44D8439D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 5 members appointed to the Commission may be from the same political party.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H749660B80CE641ADBB3E15B708DE553A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period of appointment; vacancies</header><text>Members shall be appointed for the life of the Commission. Any vacancy in the Commission shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6B314D0F613643C2A7EB3A4CCDEEAAAC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which all members of the Commission have been appointed, the Commission shall hold its first meeting.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H413E69FA4A394153AF218B89A91167BC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairman.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HF637062A37A24F3EBC843D26FC0F3C90"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Open to the public</header><text>Each meeting of the Commission shall be open to the public, unless a member objects.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4CDC87B5C34B44ACBA8D40292CEDABE1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Five members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1FE5B4C985054DD192E2820572782CC6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of the Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Commission.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HBECE4847F10746298941A663174F57D6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of the Commission</header> <subsection id="H8FCD3E086E5441B896905E6A99689D1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Commission is to evaluate and provide recommendations for modification, consolidation, or repeal of covered regulations with the aim of reducing compliance costs, encouraging growth and innovation, and improving competitiveness, all while protecting public health and safety.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H22DCAA001D074816AE484B45AD2CB8CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9BAEBEC369A24A2681209B0630FDFE0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give priority in its analysis of covered regulations to those that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4343769E3798484C86898BDCF636F1EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impose disproportionately high costs on a small entity (as defined in section 601 of title 5, United States Code);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39BADA6DA1CE499CA6EF5AA9C0664AA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose substantial paperwork burdens; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAE3CDD3333B4F259B53C5BBA6CEE8F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>could be strengthened in their effectiveness while reducing regulatory costs;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C06E85FB3FC474A968E1DC2C86E2827"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit and review comments from the public on the covered regulations described this section; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H470C0D36F9A04CAB9746D630BDB1B26F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop a set of covered regulations to modify, consolidate, or repeal to be submitted to Congress for an up-or-down vote.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H378672E9592E48128046251EABAEF9C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public comments</header>
 <paragraph id="H0648C5A60C1B44CA9BACBB9461B22B7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the initial meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall initiate a process to solicit and collect written recommendations from the general public, interested parties, Federal agencies, and other relevant entities regarding which covered regulations should be examined.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67D87FFA69584F37854786B3EF6B1A19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission of public comments</header><text>The Commission shall ensure that the process initiated under paragraph (1) allows for recommendations to be submitted to the Commission through the website of the Commission or by mail.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62C69C9E33DF42A38FCC993441953FF1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Length of public comment period</header><text>The period for the submission of recommendations under this subsection shall end 120 days after the date on which the process is initiated under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8124739752E4A49A0636F4E62385DDC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>At the end of the period for the submission of recommendations under this subsection, all submitted recommendations shall be published in the Federal Register and on the website of the Commission.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67573AB957374D44A1183EA41AAB6DDE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Commission outreach</header>
 <paragraph id="H4C39C766E0B141B090E7721B6E803ECE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the public comment period described in subsection (c), the Commission shall conduct public outreach and convene focus groups to better inform the Commissioners of the public’s interest and possible contributions to the work of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14E5E35238324D0EA5E873FDC117AA38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Focus groups</header><text>The focus groups required under paragraph (1) shall include individuals affiliated with the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, the Administrative Conference of the United States, the offices within Federal agencies responsible for small business affairs and regulatory compliance, and, at the discretion of the Commission, other relevant stakeholders from within or outside the regulatory entities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD23FB21F50AE49B387C0CEC7646E19B1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Commission review of public comments</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date on which the period for the submission of recommendations ends under subsection (c), the Commission shall convene to review submitted recommendations and to identify covered regulations to modify, consolidate, or eliminate.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3761692BA8D249E9889C14B12D666C3A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Examination of regulations</header>
 <paragraph id="H557CD8EB1C27442AAF57907AC797085E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Process for examination</header><text>In examining covered regulations under this section, the Commission shall determine the effectiveness of individual covered regulations, by using multiple resources, including quantitative metrics, testimony from industry and agency experts, and research from the staff of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1DE8723D2314D8C95887FEC464A5BDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Commission convenes under subsection (e), the Commission shall complete a substantial examination of covered regulations.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B44435ADDAB49D98E6815500B94FFA1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Initial report</header>
 <paragraph id="H6E064845CA0E4A2AB96DCA4EA09D1920"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Commission convenes under subsection (e), the Commission shall publish, and make available to the public for comment, a report, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B0861233FA04A99A6DEA7A2935C438E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions of the Commission for the improvement of covered regulations examined by the Commission; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA82A2544F264BDBA9CBC45CE2E47DEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of recommendations for changes to the covered regulations examined by the Commission, which may include recommendations for modification, consolidation, or repeal of such covered regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23A9CAAE00434090AC738BF0BD006B4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be approved by not fewer than 5 members of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C117F8B0C2B45C2AB0ECC85990EBD72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of report</header><text>The Commission shall make the report required under paragraph (1) available through the website of the Commission and in printed form.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H830E53E3536B423EBDC4D925732C64F2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public comment period</header><text>During the 90-day period beginning on the date on which the report required under paragraph (1) is published, the Commission shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H25AFA25B4808415FA37348410F05C1B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicit comments from the public on such report, using the same process established under subsection (c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF97378ED3B1B41E89F3D710B48F24D39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish any comments received under subparagraph (A) in the Federal Register and the website of the Commission.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CEA9D75676A4AF7A683518BF89F981F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consultation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA781B439F7CC46E78796D356C040C822"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the report required under paragraph (1) is published, the Commission shall complete a consultation with the chairman and ranking member of the committees of jurisdiction in the House of Representatives and Senate regarding the contents of the report.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E023146AC544B6B82D5DB90CE8D7B5A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The consultation required under subparagraph (A) shall provide—</text> <clause id="H10CEF6E01DC341E38B0AB2D2ED8745E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the opportunity for the chair and ranking member of the committees of jurisdiction to provide substantive feedback or recommendations related to the regulatory changes contained in the report required under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE4C6BD99AAB14EBC967C6966AAE109DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the opportunity for the chair and ranking member of the committees of jurisdiction to provide recommendations for alternative means of achieving a reduction in regulatory costs while maintaining the same level of benefits to society.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DF8B26914644C6EA0238C172E527952"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="HC0AD4D6EF8FB4DBF9EA4994555802D01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the 90-day period described in subsection (g)(4) ends, the Commission shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H46B9405304AC4DE7B0D6FF78D5166A73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review any comments received under subsection (g)(4);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H171561DA797E46F1894E142D3D2D16C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate any relevant comments received under subsection (g)(4) into the report required under subsection (g)(1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6425D0C8EBD048348CFAD224115DDDFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit the revised report to Congress.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H809AE8CEFEC44F07BA5C180F12F5814C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The revised report required to be submitted to Congress under paragraph (1) shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7B40EBE00DEF48F58517C6A2B26F15B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions of the Commission for the improvement of covered regulations examined by the Commission;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6EE6A0A2DE44B62A76F24586C101B8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of recommendations for changes to the covered regulations examined by the Commission, which may include recommendations for modification, consolidation, or repeal of such covered regulations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H981526AE46B9434C9A7F79C1A4F5EB5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommended legislative language to implement the recommendations in subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EFAA7F3D2794A9588BDCEBB358F9EE6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Congressional consideration of Commission report</header> <paragraph id="HA144B4261BF54A859A06E28E19D17638"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>If approved by 5 members of the Commission, as required under subsection (g)(2), the Commission bill shall be introduced in the Senate (by request) on the next day on which the Senate is in session by the majority leader of the Senate or by a Member of the Senate designated by the majority leader of the Senate and shall be introduced in the House of Representatives (by request) on the next legislative day by the majority leader of the House or by a Member of the House designated by the majority leader of the House.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HFC69E59071E74EB89C31B627E5D9D9AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration in the House of Representatives</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0A3969216742479396B8F14094A58BDA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Referral and reporting</header><text>Any committee of the House of Representatives to which the commission bill is referred shall report it to the House without amendment not later than 30 days after the date on which the commission bill is introduced under paragraph (1). If a committee fails to report the commission bill within that period, it shall be in order to move that the House discharge the committee from further consideration of the commission bill. Such a motion shall not be in order after the last committee authorized to consider the commission bill reports it to the House or after the House has disposed of a motion to discharge the commission bill. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion except 3 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. If such a motion is adopted, the House shall proceed immediately to consider the commission bill in accordance with subparagraphs (B) and (C). A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68542B5DB9764FE981DCB25162D7A469"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>After the last committee authorized to consider the commission bill reports it to the House or has been discharged (other than by motion) from its consideration, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the commission bill in the House. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed with respect to the commission bill. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA34990BC8BF440CB085F3FBD5ED3F64"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The commission bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against the commission bill and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the commission bill to its passage without intervening motion except 10 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent and one motion to limit debate on the commission bill. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the commission bill shall not be in order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H590DA6A51184449FB268B192ED582537"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>The vote on passage of the commission bill shall occur not later than 60 days after the date on which the commission bill is discharged from the last committee authorized to consider the commission bill.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H666109F1545F4C88BC6B12EED21EF475"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration in the Senate</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6F8E66AAD826435190994E12E0B5F53B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Committee consideration</header><text>A commission bill introduced in the Senate under paragraph (1) shall be jointly referred to the committee or committees of jurisdiction, which committees shall report the bill without any revision and with a favorable recommendation, an unfavorable recommendation, or without recommendation, not later than 30 days after the date on which the commission bill is introduced. If any committee fails to report the bill within that period, that committee shall be automatically discharged from consideration of the bill, and the bill shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB77AB11D72E049AAB42C85D05AF39FD2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Motion to proceed</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order, not later than 2 days of session after the date on which a commission bill is reported or discharged from all committees to which it was referred, for the majority leader of the Senate or the majority leader’s designee to move to proceed to the consideration of the commission bill. It shall also be in order for any Member of the Senate to move to proceed to the consideration of the commission bill at any time after the conclusion of such 2-day period. A motion to proceed is in order even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to. All points of order against the motion to proceed to the commission bill are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the commission bill is agreed to, the commission bill shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEE2278121AE4C36B490199672DCAEFC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>All points of order against the commission bill and against consideration of the commission bill are waived. Consideration of the commission bill and of all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith shall not exceed a total of 10 hours which shall be divided equally between the Majority and Minority Leaders or their designees. A motion further to limit debate on the commission bill is in order, shall require an affirmative vote of a majority of the Members duly chosen and sworn, and is not debatable. Any debatable motion or appeal is debatable for not to exceed 1 hour, to be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the motion or appeal. All time used for consideration of the commission bill, including time used for quorum calls and voting, shall be counted against the total 10 hours of consideration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H383E9BBB2B184556A404AB490C6D2D0F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No amendments</header><text>An amendment to the commission bill, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the commission bill, is not in order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8EA75E06BFB491E8C3FCD3B1C7E6112"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>If the Senate has voted to proceed to the commission bill, the vote on passage of the commission bill shall occur immediately following the conclusion of the debate on a commission bill, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested. The vote on passage of the commission bill shall occur not later than 60 days after the date on which the commission bill is discharged from all committees to which the commission bill was referred.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71E70359176E465B8FCACF5CDF67DDD6"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a commission bill shall be decided without debate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4D12E2CD4274F5D951CAAA14EEEC11C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>The commission bill shall not be subject to amendment in either the House of Representatives or the Senate.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBF392D9AF40D4148897799DD9A62A007"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration by the other House</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD69F39E1621945C48601D01572670D9F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, before passing the commission bill, one House receives from the other a commission bill—</text> <clause id="HDC4EA45BE1EC468291C0E34109301F06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the commission bill of the other House shall not be referred to a committee; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4998420E4D234CED83E8A2D7D2A47C90"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the procedure in the receiving House shall be the same as if no commission bill had been received from the other House until the vote on passage, when the commission bill received from the other House shall supplant the commission bill of the receiving House.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A8A01B7C3E443778F4632E57BDA003C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revenue measure</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to the House of Representatives if the commission bill received from the Senate is a revenue measure.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD93F35622C6943CCBB742009BCEA0AE2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rules to coordinate action with other house</header>
 <subparagraph id="H988F00804D0A405287D3E61B07E7D214"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Treatment of commission bill of other house</header><text>If the Senate fails to introduce or consider a commission bill under this section, the commission bill of the House shall be entitled to expedited floor procedures under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42878713D3F448F1B794AB4A24D29013"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of companion measures in the senate</header><text>If following passage of the commission bill in the Senate, the Senate then receives the commission bill from the House of Representatives, the House-passed commission bill shall not be debatable. The vote on passage of the commission bill in the Senate shall be considered to be the vote on passage of the commission bill received from the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7269D7D1BEB4292AE6FFA47664A6EDB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vetoes</header><text>If the President vetoes the commission bill, debate on a veto message in the Senate under this section shall be 1 hour equally divided between the majority and minority leaders or their designees.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0E13B9E3C234FD380ED059B30B54550"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Notice to regulatory agencies</header>
 <paragraph id="H44D15E4D0B00429492CFBD2140E938AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enactment of commission bill</header><text>If the commission bill is enacted into law, the President shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H92C995EDC07345AB9DB431DDA6B43FAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the date on which the commission bill is enacted into law—</text>
 <clause id="H04464BCB14684CD1B38CDAFA8CE60D17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide notice to the affected regulatory agencies; and</text> </clause><clause id="H207D3A3468F64AE89A387473DA19A7F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publish notice of enactment in the Federal Register and online;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCC9B00051F64E178B26D6AAA3CC3017"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require affected regulatory agencies to implement the commission bill not later than 180 days after the date on which the commission bill is enacted into law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFED9796713BD4C878EF91FFE3FFBEA68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to enact commission bill</header><text>If the commission bill is not enacted into law, the President shall provide notice of such failure to enact the commission bill in the Federal Register.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H573F5E48E8ED4AFB9298B8382A1CDE19"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Adjournment of Congress</header><text>If the commission bill is introduced less than 60 session days or 60 legislative days before the date on which Congress adjourns sine die—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD89DADE3E3E34DF7ADB83BF94EA5683B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the commission bill shall be introduced in both Houses on the date on which the succeeding Congress first convenes its next session; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1E1A368A2B04FC6AE76A8B62746F20B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subsection (i) shall apply to the commission bill during the succeeding Congress.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H77AAEA6EA8A74EAFB95AFA26B4925C1B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header> <subsection id="HE8CAE709640544D29097C6787A11E9DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Commission may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H9C50C90E21F64926A767476862FF427A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header>
 <paragraph id="HCC0AB189D0864D65969B7778C79C354F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission is authorized to secure directly from any executive department, bureau, agency, board, commission, office, independent establishment, or instrumentality of the Government, information, suggestions, estimates, and statistics for the purpose of this Act. Each department, bureau, agency, board, commission, office, independent establishment, or instrumentality shall, to the extent authorized by law, furnish such information, suggestions, estimates, and statistics directly to the Commission, upon request made by the chairman, the chairman of any subcommittee created by the Commission, or any member designated by a majority of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51DBC23E1EC649E2BF53712CEA5923ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Receipt, handling, storage, and dissemination</header><text>Information shall only be received, handled, stored, and disseminated by members of the Commission and its staff consistent with all applicable statutes, regulations, and Executive orders.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1827165E4A1144B19B094C075F0504E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H00AC7809B4E24873B4339C136AF27E0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Gifts</header><text>The Commission may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H98B81F750F6F419E90CA572D4F55371E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Space for use of Commission</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of General Services shall support on a reimbursable basis the operations of the Commission, including the identification of suitable space to house the Commission. If the Administrator is not able to make such suitable space available within the 60-day period, the Commission shall lease space to the extent that funds are available.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H047247EFC4CC44D294B1536F384E0D34"><enum>6.</enum><header>Commission personnel matters</header>
 <subsection id="H4FEB5F4A93CA45EFBE28F54C341489DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day (including travel time) during which such member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H598094DCC4754DFE9FACDCD12F917998"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>The members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF958EFA86B2C4CD6B04BD7D6C54D0BD5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Staff</header>
 <paragraph id="HA4445F2756C747119E97FA1C0F04761D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chairman of the Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws and regulations, appoint and terminate an executive director and such other additional personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to perform its duties. The employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB22C7ACF0C234FF7B0BFC6BC9D944853"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Chairman of the Commission may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC14E7C7995B42509EB344CE517AECEC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency assistance</header><text>Following consultation with and upon the request of the Chairman of the Commission, the head of any agency may detail an employee of the agency to the Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04790DD54A854C8094939E3DAF8EAE47"><enum>(4)</enum><header>GAO and OIRA assistance</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States and the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall provide assistance, including the detailing of employees, to the Commission in accordance with an agreement entered into with the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0E3DDCA771848DA857FF653C447C6A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</header><text>The Chairman of the Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals which do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H73F87BC73A8949E98B9AD691BC6F5243"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contracting authority</header><text>The Commission may acquire administrative supplies and equipment for Commission use to the extent funds are available.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD9AD119D1FC54FD3AB5D4193B754AD0B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative support</header><text>Upon the request of the Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Commission to carry out its responsibilities under this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H546EE1F0E6704E5FBA29EA474671E478"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination of the commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate 90 days after the date on which the Commission submits its report under section 4.</text>
		</section><section id="HD354581F6C2045B1897A1DAD3FFF940C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="HF158C042AC054CC894FA45913C95B5B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to the Commission to carry out this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H525D9F55C3474BF2A3FAAFC53E7B94B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Any sums appropriated under the authorization contained in this section shall remain available, without fiscal year limitation, until expended.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


