<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H364C767499A04A6098ED0803032B6A36" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1402 IH: Point Reyes Coast Guard Housing Conveyance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1402</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150317">March 17, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to convey certain property from the United States to the County of Marin, California.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD0D641778CBC47E89C394895837B42B2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFF312DF7D48C4BF08C8C33C5619C2E50" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Point Reyes Coast Guard Housing Conveyance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7213C257BA6C4B1BB0D26E732505AE8A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance of certain property in Point Reyes Station, California</header> <subsection id="HBB829B275F484FA6B99B52E01AF2C542"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance</header> <paragraph id="H208FEC494EF740F9B90FC44286D7B4B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall convey to the County of Marin all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the covered property—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2814629F8D084BD5B08A3C74DFE404DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for fair market value, provided for in paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C8D712C25954F9F9389938FFD07C881"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to the conditions required by this section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1757F216AE6941E2A76994505C329FFC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>subject to any other term or condition that the Commandant considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D64AA2CEAFD44C0999C3ECB9AFBC154"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fair market value</header><text>The fair market value of the covered property shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HED9CAF5120CF404E96B395224FFFF1D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determined by a real estate appraiser, selected by the County and licensed to practice in California; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D02EB58ED1B4DC2ACCAAF0B8FA173DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approved by the Commandant, who shall base such approval on considerations of equity and fairness, including the use required by this Act of the covered property.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B4B5691D3C64BAFBB6298B857100238" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Proceeds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commandant may deposit the proceeds from a conveyance under paragraph (1) in the Coast Guard Housing Fund established by section 687 of title 14, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF3A3F62979284FE8B711CC2CC646CD5D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Condition of conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of any conveyance of covered property under this section, the Commandant shall require that all right, title, and interest in and to the covered property revert to the United States if the covered property or any part thereof ceases to be used for affordable housing, as defined by the County and the Commandant at conveyance, or to provide a public benefit approved by the County.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H474BFC83C3274846AE24935D9E034F04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect or limit the application of or obligation to comply with any environmental law, including section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</external-xref>).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H06A53409C5FC4DFEB395B55903357F64"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H59D55CF43B5241ACB280FF2F01EDFB81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commandant</header><text>The term <term>Commandant</term> means the Commandant of the Coast Guard.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H248F663F0A1F4B62A0EBB5A1D5EAF7C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <term>County</term> means the County of Marin, California.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9381B1D4F3B4BD3BCAED7D24AF0B675"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered property</term> means the 32 acres of Federal land (including all buildings, structures, utilities, and miscellaneous facilities on the land) that is located in Point Reyes Station in the County of Marin, California, and that are under the administrative control of the Coast Guard and identified by the Coast Guard as “CAMSPAC Housing”.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HCCE6E01B6EE2409DA8BFEDAAC543059C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expiration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority to convey the covered property under this Act shall expire on the date that is four years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

