<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC60DFEC696864C8497FA65E9D62181E9" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 571 IH: Veterans Affairs Retaliation Prevention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 571</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the treatment of whistleblower complaints by the
			 Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4C12C8A67D214C62BDE1B54ACBEF10AA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H321F0942207B4A7FB07F39B7139A2D0B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Affairs Retaliation Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC1341CA3DD634D1BAE4B6D118613917F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of whistleblower complaints in Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HA8CF87FED6C4467084EB522E099C90E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4422B017D1B043F1B9FA3A29052250F5" style="USC">
					<subchapter id="H0BBD0F6805D844D7A4A54CAAFFB3E3A6"><enum>II</enum><header>Whistleblower complaints</header>
 <section id="H936B534487244B1988F37C23015AC7A9"><enum>721.</enum><header>Whistleblower complaint defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter, the term <term>whistleblower complaint</term> means a complaint by an employee of the Department disclosing, or assisting another employee to disclose, a potential violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or gross mismanagement, gross waste of funds, abuse of authority, or substantial and specific danger to public health and safety.</text>
						</section><section id="H4C062B6928934B1A9B40969F8368BDA2"><enum>722.</enum><header>Treatment of whistleblower complaints</header>
							<subsection id="H8FB4D35CA03B479A8223FCA31026467D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Filing</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF0D60345672B4DD594501F2E2DCD1D73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In addition to any other method established by law in which an employee may file a whistleblower complaint, an employee of the Department may file a whistleblower complaint with a supervisor of the employee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H633983A391C74D35AD90D56641D1D5EC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a whistleblower complaint under paragraph (1), an employee shall file the initial complaint with the immediate supervisor of the employee.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33AABECD5AA142D3A465C42713D152AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA43D4016B1E74CBAADA8358041F3CF5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than two business days after the date on which a supervisor receives a whistleblower complaint by an employee under this section, the supervisor shall notify, in writing, the employee of whether the supervisor determines that there is a reasonable likelihood that the complaint discloses a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, or gross mismanagement, gross waste of funds, abuse of authority, or substantial and specific danger to public health and safety. The supervisor shall retain written documentation regarding the whistleblower complaint and shall submit to the next-level supervisor and the Office of Accountability Review of the Department a written report on the complaint.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC580C17BFE6A4D8EAA8EECD6CDA4D3A2" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On a monthly basis, the supervisor shall submit to the appropriate director or other official who is superior to the supervisor a written report that includes the number of whistleblower complaints received by the supervisor under this section during the month covered by the report, the disposition of such complaints, and any actions taken because of such complaints pursuant to subsection (c). In the case in which such a director or official carries out this paragraph, the director or official shall submit such monthly report to the supervisor of the director or official and to the Office of Accountability Review.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAECEDA67B9064BA0BCC4343C8CF1A4EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Positive determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a supervisor makes a positive determination under subsection (b)(1) regarding a whistleblower complaint of an employee, the supervisor shall include in the notification to the employee under such subsection the specific actions that the supervisor will take to address the complaint.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HF4394851CE814FA4B908664E6918290A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Filing complaint with next-Level supervisors</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD0E8D6DD2C964C1B878B8360F6973FC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If a supervisor does not make a timely determination under subsection (b)(1) regarding a whistleblower complaint, or if the employee who made the complaint determines that the supervisor did not adequately address the complaint pursuant to subsection (c), the employee may file such whistleblower complaint with the next-level supervisor who shall treat such complaint in accordance with this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9E55A5C21204141AA67EB0A8924F2FF" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An employee may file a whistleblower complaint with the Secretary if the employee has filed the whistleblower complaint to each level of supervisors between the employee and the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC25E06775A6491A843574B705AE06E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transfer of employee who files whistleblower complaint</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a supervisor makes a positive determination under subsection (b)(1) regarding a whistleblower complaint filed by an employee, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAE7B7EBA6CA844A4A22F9046F4D898A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform the employee of the ability to volunteer for a transfer in accordance with section 3352 of title 5; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8F505D272784D51A2F5FE72E8FA6A98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give preference to the employee for such a transfer in accordance with such section.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H730F7C2543FA47A48D9BCC9EB7F792B7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibition on exemption</header><text>The Secretary may not exempt any employee of the Department from being covered by this section.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H5BA97392D5154512911A07A9233676D0"><enum>723.</enum><header>Adverse actions against employees who commit prohibited personnel actions relating to whistleblower
			 complaints</header>
							<subsection id="H01A9C4954E1D4AD991AC0C43CAC84C0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAE434ECF60814A0A98ED39FA43527617"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary shall carry out the following adverse actions against employees whom the Secretary, an administrative judge, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Office of Special Counsel, an adjudicating body provided under a union contract, a Federal judge, or the Inspector General of the Department determines committed a prohibited personnel action described in subsection (d):</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5B9D662006D240FF9252A1A06167BA6B" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to the first offense, an adverse action that is not less than a 14-day suspension and not more than removal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED2D4C33D22A4B9A8631362CAF5DCBC5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to the second offense, removal.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H95F3EDF0914C46BEA30C5915582D43FA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDA2644912D184CAEAB9B525A779EAA76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided by subparagraph (B), and notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c) of section 7513 and section 7543 of title 5, the provisions of subsections (d) and (e) of section 713 of this title shall apply with respect to an adverse action carried out under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00B16305A2C04F26A44E0E0789EDF6ED" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An employee who is notified of being the subject of a proposed adverse action under paragraph (1) may not be given more than five days following such notification to provide evidence to dispute such proposed adverse action. If the employee does not provide any such evidence, or if the Secretary determines that such evidence is not sufficient to reverse the determination to propose the adverse action, the Secretary shall carry out the adverse action following such five-day period.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8CFA46713DEC43D5955087C1ABA85A46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fees</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HABE439D6EBEC45BEB08157D7082B87E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any adverse action carried out under subsection (a), to recoup costs borne by the Federal Government by reason of prohibited personnel actions described in subsection (d), the Secretary shall charge a fee to each employee who is found to have committed such a prohibited personnel action by an administrative judge, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Office of Special Counsel, an adjudicating body provided under a union contract, a Federal judge, or, in the case of a settlement of a whistleblower complaint (regardless of whether any fault was assigned under such settlement), the Secretary. The Secretary shall afford such an employee notice and an opportunity for a hearing before charging such fee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEEFB3F307B1D4D649CD732A429484175" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prescribe a schedule of fees that takes into account the cost to the Federal Government of the prohibited personnel action committed by an employee described in such paragraph, including such costs paid by the Federal Government pursuant to an order to pay attorney fees described in section 1204(m) of title 5 or other similar order of an administrative judge or Federal judge.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5916B4AF15EC4506A12E160340AA5C4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on other adverse actions</header><text>With respect to a prohibited personnel action described in subsection (d), if the Secretary carries out an adverse action against an employee or charges a fee to an employee under a provision of law other than this section, the Secretary may carry out an additional adverse action or charge an additional fee under this section based on the same prohibited personnel action if the total severity of the adverse actions do not exceed the level specified in subsection (a) and the total fees charged do not exceed the amount prescribed under subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HED4C0D8543AA4047AC8B22D19F5A424B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibited personnel action described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A prohibited personnel action described in this subsection is any of the following actions:</text> <paragraph id="H57F0226522544EF7B23B97ACEC941B62"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taking or failing to take a personnel action in violation of section 2302 of title 5 against an employee relating to the employee—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB451A635453549A190B7D59800891D4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>filing a whistleblower complaint in accordance with section 722 of this title;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D4740C28B304EC3B0885D9386EF6AF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">filing a whistleblower complaint with the Inspector General of the Department, the Special Counsel, or Congress;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0C11DC0C3CF42E38831B9F937C6A507"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing information or participating as a witness in an investigation of a whistleblower complaint in accordance with section 722 or with the Inspector General of the Department, the Special Counsel, or Congress;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12BE8BCACE2B404C92372B5E1251567A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participating in an audit or investigation by the Comptroller General of the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F6DA23E2FBD4ED9BB9829C525E754D4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>refusing to perform an action that is unlawful or prohibited by the Department; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1F4227FF707546978EB13639CE3BF38A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>engaging in communications that are related to the duties of the position or are otherwise protected.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3F1CD58309541F3840DDF6632E86227"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interfering with an employee making an action described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (F) of paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADF882990D4A4A789951227071CAC6C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Conducting a peer review or opening a retaliatory investigation relating to an activity of an employee that is protected by section 2302 of title 5.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34F63B89E47B43A894ECBEEF3AEC8064"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Requesting a contractor to carry out an action that is prohibited by section 4705(b) or section 4712(a)(1) of title 41, as the case may be.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF738FD2EE3A44EF0B573A9D1A9A613E3"><enum>724.</enum><header>Evaluation criteria of supervisors and treatment of bonuses</header>
							<subsection id="HFE8BBB73F77A4C0A89DA6321034ADBF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation criteria</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC11B619998E541498CA877B69207B670"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In evaluating the performance of supervisors of the Department, the Secretary shall include the criteria described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F63555AD53C497B977AEC66A73B8292" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The criteria described in this subsection are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFCC83614E9D344A5A1E5CE340F066A4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the supervisor treats whistleblower complaints in accordance with section 722.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H109588AF67894C9FAD2F3A5E76923387"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the appropriate deciding official, performance review board, or performance review committee determines that the supervisor was found to have committed a prohibited personnel action described in section 723(c) by an administrative judge, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Office of Special Counsel, an adjudicating body provided under a union contract, a Federal judge, or, in the case of a settlement of a whistleblower complaint (regardless of whether any fault was assigned under such settlement), the Secretary.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17078B3A66CD4508A45E3CECE7C16989"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bonuses</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H25F48DAD83654EBFA513BC5AFEB285F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not pay to a supervisor described in subsection (a)(2)(B) an award or bonus under this title or title 5, including under chapter 45 or 53 of such title, during the one-year period beginning on the date on which the determination was made under such subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC9AB998A760408D956E5386150CBB30" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall issue an order directing a supervisor described in subsection (a)(2)(B) to repay the amount of any award or bonus paid under this title or title 5, including under chapter 45 or 53 of such title, if—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC8B00ACD534843F7BD0D1CBD0EE8B07C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such award or bonus was paid for performance during a period in which the supervisor committed a prohibited personnel action as determined pursuant to such subsection (a)(2)(B);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H274744ED94644680A3F660F995804DF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary determines such repayment appropriate pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary to carry out this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6428FA2552D34CF295336A78C8D2E96D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the supervisor is afforded notice and an opportunity for a hearing before making such repayment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H00F36F6FDBE8421F8F5BB4E029200643"><enum>725.</enum><header>Training regarding whistleblower complaints</header> <subsection id="H2A1551CA525E40BEB26C246EFB9592AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Whistleblower Protection Ombudsman designated under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Inspector General Act of 1978 /3">section 3(d)(1)(C)</external-xref> of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.), shall annually provide to each employee of the Department training regarding whistleblower complaints, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF1C2CE9E44D24AD1AA431E4943B6C800"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of each method established by law in which an employee may file a whistleblower complaint;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9A5CF5415E254E1388DD0112941DFDD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an explanation of prohibited personnel actions described by section 723(d) of this title;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDCFA7A9167A44419750B623CCF34C1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to supervisors, how to treat whistleblower complaints in accordance with section 722 of this title;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB461F73FE7641C9BA8BB25CE2ADBCAD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the right of the employee to petition Congress regarding a whistleblower complaint in accordance with section 7211 of title 5;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9FD2114F17748C1A2776B3B2C6EE84A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation that the employee may not be prosecuted or reprised against for disclosing information to Congress in instances where such disclosure is permitted by law, including under sections 5701, 5705, and 7732 of this title, under section 552a of title 5 (commonly referred to as the Privacy Act), under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/93">chapter 93</external-xref> of title 18, and pursuant to regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/191">Public Law 104–191</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H341E3E66EA254EF3955C9274646712AD"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of the language that is required to be included in all nondisclosure policies, forms, and agreements pursuant to section 115(a)(1) of the Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/2302">5 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref> note); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F8183FE6D5947C58A3EE697216E141B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the right of contractors to be protected from reprisal for the disclosure of certain information under section 4705 or 4712 of title 41.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H616FD21E5BC64EE2BE69D33A07924639"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The Secretary shall annually provide training on merit system protection in a manner that the Special Counsel certifies as being satisfactory.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB7811AA68A3C4915ACE3E524A189AF10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish on the Internet website of the Department, and display prominently at each facility of the Department, the rights of an employee to file a whistleblower complaint and to petition Congress regarding a whistleblower complaint as described in paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (a).</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H96892B66B08E487E8DC7E35F21D60E6C"><enum>726.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H3E6C2E8CEF094F5798818AEF94AC9973"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA97DF20C625E40F38C6994A07978726B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to whistleblower complaints filed under section 722 during the year covered by the report—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF8F548BEE7AE498EA2E8AE41DCD48979"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of such complaints filed;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C9BE332CB304128833710F8C58AEFC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the disposition of such complaints; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25DFC4C5FD1B44D99C3DE10125D9B9DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ways in which the Secretary addressed such complaints in which a positive determination was made by a supervisor under subsection (b)(1) of such section;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21FB9B34016749078B1EDE7AB92700C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of whistleblower complaints filed during the year covered by the report that are not included under paragraph (1), including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H00F5DF183DAA43E49BD73E72ED445CCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the method in which such complaints were filed;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B2EEC9BC379400F81DF20892B410259"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the disposition of such complaints; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3F2E7D591BD49CF9D9D80701CC6B419"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ways in which the Secretary addressed such complaints; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB502003E17BB4618BA92CF0ECE495B3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to disclosures made by a contractor under section 4705 or 4712 of title 41—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF1B5BB56B9C547A3A9CAE3CC3C49B49D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of complaints relating to such disclosures that were investigated by the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs during the year covered by the report;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4B1ED48FAB64D0F879D86A5ADE1BEA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the disposition of such complaints; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC62B39B3ECEF4BA3944D1749A0F22BEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ways in which the Secretary addressed such complaints.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97B1D472BC004416A4DA900A32047143"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice of Office of Special Counsel determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives from the Special Counsel information relating to a whistleblower complaint pursuant to section 1213 of title 5, the Secretary shall notify the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate of such information, including the determination made by the Special Counsel.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF57E6143835F4E0FA0A6856BDD256406"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming and clerical amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H74767671E5574A7BA06F4693AEEDA2BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such chapter is further amended by inserting before section 701 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BF4A933F9B1409DB809EE7A28104F5B" style="USC"> <subchapter id="H200F00525F80435FAE84521047BDBB5B"><enum>I</enum><header>General employee matters</header></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E5FC19C78264B5FAF0BEFEB4C29CBC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8416CC2D907349F7A130FCF7BE5FF72C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting before the item relating to section 701 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H107717348886437B9D7F4407E5C916BD" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter I—General employee matters</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">and</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD264C3EDE44C43EC948B323D8C073C0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding after the item relating to section 713 the following new items:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H912D02FA67874F8B88775C443EE8D1ED" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter II—Whistleblower complaints</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry idref="H936B534487244B1988F37C23015AC7A9" level="section">721. Whistleblower complaint defined.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry idref="H4C062B6928934B1A9B40969F8368BDA2" level="section">722. Treatment of whistleblower complaints.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry idref="H5BA97392D5154512911A07A9233676D0" level="section">723. Adverse actions against employees who commit prohibited personnel actions relating to
			 whistleblower complaints.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry idref="HF738FD2EE3A44EF0B573A9D1A9A613E3" level="section">724. Evaluation criteria of supervisors and treatment of bonuses.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry idref="H00F36F6FDBE8421F8F5BB4E029200643" level="section">725. Training regarding whistleblower complaints.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry idref="H96892B66B08E487E8DC7E35F21D60E6C" level="section">726. Reports to Congress.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


