<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H578B610D3EC3449BAB713428E5D2532F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2550 IH: Medical Imaging Modernization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2550</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide Medicare payment incentives to
			 transition from traditional x-ray imaging to digital radiography, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4ED287005794426CBCD8971A889A34EC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H14F6791BDF0C4D599BA47C2E46DBA658" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Imaging Modernization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB99538A874944DCEAE37478EBA61F75B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicare payment incentive for the transition from traditional x-ray imaging to digital radiography and other Medicare imaging payment provision</header> <subsection id="HB492707C9C4248AA9B8BEBC53AD1D2F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Physician fee schedule</header> <paragraph id="H2A510377C70940328732EC1AA1BC09F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment incentive for transition</header> <subparagraph id="H89EC0914644A4BEF9AED4B8C740EA248"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1848(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E4726E9DF264E4885BE37BEAD534EFB" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H1659F144BE004B939748E401BAC46AED"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Special rule to incentivize transition from traditional x-ray imaging to digital radiography</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAFA7252C99824258BDF51A0A4DD4A8D1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation on payment for film x-ray imaging services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of imaging services that are X-rays taken using film and that are furnished during 2017 or a subsequent year, the payment amount for the technical component (including the technical component portion of a global fee) of such services that would otherwise be determined under this section (without application of this paragraph and before application of any other adjustment under this section) for such year shall be reduced by 20 percent.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H904BDE848D914730B6D9BA30F781D64F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Phased-in limitation on payment for computed radiography imaging services</header><text>In the case of imaging services that are X-rays taken using computed radiography technology—</text> <clause id="HC9A6646F5AFA45018AB246970E8C2DBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of such services furnished during 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021, or 2022 the payment amount for the technical component (including the technical component portion of a global fee) of such services that would otherwise be determined under this section (without application of this paragraph and before application of any other adjustment under this section) for such year shall be reduced by 7 percent; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA4590F6F1744992A9B3B99108AEB622"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of such services furnished during 2023 or a subsequent year, the payment amount for the technical component (including the technical component portion of a global fee) of such services that would otherwise be determined under this section (without application of this paragraph and before application of any other adjustment under this section) for such year shall be reduced by 10 percent.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F4852CA6CAB4117A774BF83379A0A90"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Computed radiography technology defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>computed radiography technology</term> means cassette-based imaging which utilizes an imaging plate to create the image involved.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED9AE193E6C54635AFE02291FF049EEB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>In order to implement this paragraph, the Secretary shall adopt appropriate mechanisms which may include use of modifiers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5C188ACF4CA4DE193DC4F9EF6855960"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption from budget neutrality</header><text>Section 1848(c)(2)(B)(v) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(c)(2)(B)(v)</external-xref>) is amended, by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13F0679F1F8B43CF88FD092DC866D8FC" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="H31C8DD5C321F4F3E8EF2406A2A99D42A"><enum>(X)</enum><header>Reduced expenditures attributable to incentives to transition to digital radiography</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective for fee schedules established beginning with 2017, reduced expenditures attributable to subparagraph (A) of subsection (b)(9) and effective for fee schedules established beginning with 2018, reduced expenditures attributable to subparagraph (B) of such subsection.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94535F87F07B46AF803C5F57B03FE6E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elimination of application of multiple procedure payment reduction</header><text>Section 1848(b)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC431CFB7A264539B75436ED6B51757C" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="HF5D448056E1B4739B0859DD577F38C36"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Elimination of application of multiple procedure payment reduction</header>
 <clause id="HAAFD0F49DA554407893BE21FFEA02D6C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2016, the Secretary shall not apply a multiple procedure payment reduction policy to the professional component of imaging services furnished in any subsequent year that is prior to a year in which the Secretary conducts and publishes, as part of the Medicare Physician Fee Schedule Proposed Rule for a year, the empirical analysis described in clause (ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0D7B22D3940A47DFBF96F29B1DBB1A85"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Empirical analysis described</header><text>The empirical analysis described in this clause is an analysis of the Resource-Based Relative Value Scale (commonly known as the <quote>RBRVS</quote>) Data Manager information that is used to determine what, if any, efficiencies exist within the professional component of imaging services when two or more studies are performed on the same patient on the same day. Such empirical analysis shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="H6E29013312164B0E8305D2BAAD41D898"><enum>(I)</enum><text>work sheets and other information detailing which physician work activities performed given the typical vignettes were assigned reduction percentages of 0, 25, 50, 75 and 100 percent;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB044709DE3A942FCB04A6AB705BEA9DF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a discussion of the clinical aspects that informed the assignment of the reduction percentages described in subclause (I);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF72F93ACA33F469BA326293A3DAC53BA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an explanation of how the percentage reductions for pre-, intra and post-service work were determined and calculated; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H61E6CE54F5C64E659347240D959EE2AA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a demonstration that the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services has consulted with practicing radiologists to gain knowledge of how radiologists interpret studies of multiple body parts on the same individual on the same day.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01A2FD7F82FB40B7B0DB156EC63B5B49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment incentive for transition under hospital outpatient prospective payment system</header><text>Section 1833(t)(16) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395(t)(16)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H599FD3CEF8EB44F88727F07D74AA9DFF" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H8D8588398961406FB0E0C3DDC7A0B285"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Payment incentive for the transition from traditional x-ray imaging to digital radiography</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the previous provisions of this subsection:</text> <clause id="HC1C63B0FB6B946C49AB2795E29B08831"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation on payment for film x-ray imaging services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of imaging services that are X-rays taken using film and that are furnished during 2017 or a subsequent year, the payment amount for the technical component (including the technical component portion of a global fee) of such services that would otherwise be determined under this section (without application of this paragraph and before application of any other adjustment under this subsection) for such year shall be reduced by 20 percent.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBF3943A06373474EAF8139A551E61F8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Phased-in limitation on payment for computed radiography imaging services</header><text>In the case of imaging services that are X-rays taken using computed radiography technology (as defined in section 1848(b)(9)(C))—</text>
 <subclause id="HC3E4330434D946139F78558454E70CAD"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of such services furnished during 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021, or 2022 the payment amount for the technical component (including the technical component portion of a global fee) of such services that would otherwise be determined under this section (without application of this paragraph and before application of any other adjustment under this subsection) for such year shall be reduced by 7 percent; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE99C140BF9DE4B3B9CAB2FA8AFDE5ACA"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of such services furnished during 2023 or a subsequent year, the payment amount for the technical component (including the technical component portion of a global fee) of such services that would otherwise be determined under this section (without application of this paragraph and before application of any other adjustment under this subsection) for such year shall be reduced by 10 percent.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD6DF99B35ADE4C9A905089B4F69EE5CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Application without regard to budget neutrality</header><text>The reductions made under this paragraph—</text> <subclause id="H9E8D4B70A8424269B18CE42843BF5429"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall not be considered an adjustment under paragraph (2)(E); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H785265E886524BE5832154D5EB7D6B32"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall not be implemented in a budget neutral manner.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

