<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H023AC8EECCF242939E2FFB2FE1A4E8C6" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1174 IH: Law Enforcement Access to Data Stored Abroad Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1174</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150227">February 27, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to safeguard data stored abroad from improper government access, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB9D4CBF731A54D56BE9085D38417F44B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H651D04A2A7454617B28BE5F74B15C93F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Law Enforcement Access to Data Stored Abroad Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7A376D2B5C59441D874395DC1E8436F6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCAD313EA62C04E65AAEEBD65AF433D3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Electronic Communications Privacy Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/508">Public Law 99–508</external-xref>; 100 Stat. 1848) (referred to in this section as <quote>ECPA</quote>) was intended to protect the privacy of electronic communications stored with providers of electronic communications services and remote computing services, while balancing the legitimate needs of law enforcement to access records stored by such providers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EF8F437958549C9B877020F3EE7F85F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To strike this balance, ECPA authorized governmental entities to obtain certain categories of communications data from providers using established, pre-existing forms of process—warrants and subpoenas. It also created a new form of court order, in section 2703(d) of title 18, United States Code, that governmental entities could use to obtain additional types of communications data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0418CC6F68AC49A5A054CF73084EA56D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It has been well established that courts in the United States lack the power to issue warrants authorizing extraterritorial searches and seizures, and neither ECPA nor subsequent amendments extended the warrant power of courts in the United States beyond the territorial reach of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCC97671B277443FA6DF5BD8AB5AA619"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Nevertheless, Congress also recognizes the legitimate needs of law enforcement agencies in the United States to obtain, through lawful process, electronic communications relevant to criminal investigations related to United States persons wherever that content may be stored. Therefore, this Act authorizes the use of search warrants extraterritorially only where the Government seeks to obtain the contents of electronic communications belonging to a United States person.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCEBCC15DEA384087A263653289E71B17"><enum>3.</enum><header>Scope and clarification of warrant requirement</header> 
<subsection id="H1EBE69BF782A4CEC85AAAFCB98BCDE5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/121">Chapter 121</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6C3D013930564378A830CF62C307138D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2702(a), by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4C3145506DB4F53B456C637122FAA23" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HEE30113F0FC5472AB1AC505265C7E828"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a provider of remote computing service or electronic communication service to the public shall not knowingly divulge to any governmental entity the contents of any communication described in section 2703(a), or any record or other information pertaining to a subscriber or customer of such service.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF3892494A004CB6AF64C6DBD0298349"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2703—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC44B6ECE2F4D4B108E93D5D5613C282E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a) and (b) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB698C2505FFA42E796E17E2E6A8ED975" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HEF045F1C49DF42DBB7D6901E86E8146B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contents of wire or electronic communication in electronic storage</header><text>A governmental entity may require the disclosure by a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service of the contents of a wire or electronic communication that is in electronic storage with or otherwise stored, held, or maintained by the provider only pursuant to a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) by a court of competent jurisdiction. Subject to subsection (b), a warrant issued pursuant to this subsection may be used to require the disclosure of contents of a wire or electronic communication that are in the provider’s electronic storage within the United States or otherwise stored, held, or maintained within the United States by the provider.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5521355222A4724BEC45994D7C5F738"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Warrant requirements</header><text>A warrant issued under subsection (a) may require the disclosure of the contents of a wire or electronic communication, regardless of where such contents may be in electronic storage or otherwise stored, held, or maintained by the provider, if the account-holder whose contents are sought by the warrant is a United States person. A court issuing a warrant pursuant to this subsection, on a motion made promptly by the service provider, shall modify or vacate such warrant if the court finds that the warrant would require the provider of an electronic communications or remote computing service to violate the laws of a foreign country.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E013580C5884D46A72FE43D5AB55123"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d), in the first sentence—</text> 
<clause id="H8AA0BB904D784970B87D81DA4CDA5EA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(b) or</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H9C937E1206E64C5294213A536078DF8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the contents of a wire or electronic communication, or</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H76AF9205B5A9491792ED8BC4BEC899EA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>sought, are</quote> and inserting <quote>sought are</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AA70511035D477E9D85A2C08110F93F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0ADE386831B477791D962F29797B477" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H1C1B41437C744B17B3D7688965CBE111"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section or in section 2702 shall be construed to limit the authority of a governmental entity to use an administrative subpoena authorized under a Federal or State statute or to use a Federal or State grand jury, trial, or civil discovery subpoena to—</text> <paragraph id="HED52102117F64EF9BE35A3919BC8C61C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require an originator, addressee, or intended recipient of an electronic communication to disclose the contents of the electronic communication to the governmental entity; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H684FBB725E7F44E7AADAB42D7B712522"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require an entity that provides electronic communication services to the officers, directors, employees, or agents of the entity (for the purpose of carrying out their duties) to disclose the contents of an electronic communication to or from an officer, director, employee, or agent of the entity to a governmental entity, if the electronic communication is held, stored, or maintained on an electronic communications system owned or operated by the entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCE4FA254C2254501A685BEB3175926DC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Except as provided in section 2705, not later than 10 business days after a governmental entity receives the contents of a wire or electronic communication of a subscriber or customer from a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service under subsection (a), the governmental entity shall serve upon, or deliver to by registered or first-class mail, electronic mail, or other means reasonably calculated to be effective, as specified by the court issuing the warrant, the subscriber or customer—</text> 
<paragraph id="H675DC58A36724A1FB22DB0763491351E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a copy of the warrant; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H623DD0DDDF2741D38B1371800F79ACCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notice that informs the customer or subscriber—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFAD0846B3A184D3B9BB2BAA1F4F1719D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of the nature of the law enforcement inquiry with reasonable specificity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39615A9C065D445D9CE100CF2FAE6918"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that information maintained for the customer or subscriber by the provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service named in the process or request was supplied to, or requested by, the governmental entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H835CA88644B045A3975ABCC59CFD1D26"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 2704(a)(1), by striking <quote>section 2703(b)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2703</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6782CEA3D3364BC4BBBFE79C2F919B98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 2705—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H088DE67DBEDE4F86AF2AE237B270B1A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FD2C5A2127240959E1A3C86F93F1992" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H11F46072BB4F42EF8D2F02559EEA97C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A governmental entity that is seeking a warrant under section 2703 may include in the application for the warrant a request, which the court shall grant, for an order delaying the notification required under section 2703(i) for a period of not more than 90 days, if the court determines that there is reason to believe that notification of the existence of the warrant may have an adverse result described in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB3149CA68874A7EBCA95D25240EF906"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>under section 2703(b)(1)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6F3A39AA5F24A8DB35E2FD8C7EFCB64"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 2711—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9B8A1DEAFBDE4C69A279DDB65098479F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B) by striking <quote>warrants; and</quote> and inserting <quote>warrants;</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4BC0EFC0526F4712ABBB82A2A4CAC57F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) by striking <quote>thereof.</quote> and inserting <quote>thereof; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1DE4F0E9DF84372AD40A2552920CA9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FE4DCAB9C86433E952056F72B13257F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H96A0B3673352422C87A903924DF04057"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>United States person</term> means a citizen or permanent resident alien of the United States, or an entity or organization organized under the laws of the United States or a State or political subdivision thereof.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H56BE930F04DA4322A54927977D77B32E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mutual legal assistance treaty reforms</header> 
<subsection id="H75583A9D4C8842E49426A7850943C930"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mutual Legal Assistance Treaty Transparency and Efficiency</header> 
<paragraph id="HDD3382EDC1E64C2EA4D4D230B0882770"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish—</text> <subparagraph id="H65B556FA7146485ABE5BE399EB7627A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a form for use by a foreign government filing a mutual legal assistance treaty request (referred to in this section as an <quote>MLAT request</quote>), which shall—</text> 
<clause id="H9B6F070E33D34DE1A4E8A91E7D8A17D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be made available on the website of the Department of Justice; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDB41266E8CB6415EBCCFC023339E7EC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require sufficient information and be susceptible for use by a foreign government to provide all the information necessary for the MLAT request; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41624CB7BC894D39A0DCFB3522E798A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an online docketing system for all MLAT requests, which shall allow a foreign government to track the status of an MLAT request filed by the foreign government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BD2BC233366457396BE7F0F90C298AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual publication</header><text>Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, the Attorney General shall publish on the website of the Department of Justice statistics on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H155C4B6FC16241E2BC79B5B5881F651F"><enum>(A)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9DC5F1111CF146E4A5212EA9F89982C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of MLAT requests made by the Department of Justice to foreign governments for the purpose of obtaining the contents of an electronic communication or other information or records from a provider of electronic communications or remote computing services; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8C5D179DC3E140D0BC9479E4F510BC7C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average length of time taken by foreign governments to process the MLAT requests described in clause (i); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H86F384D50BDE4041BE05AF6569E5AF6C"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3D89A48146C649D1A0D61131909202AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of MLAT requests made to the Department of Justice by foreign governments for the purpose of obtaining the contents of an electronic communication or other information or records from a provider of electronic communications or remote computing services; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD7A951C4B4F4456691AC267B3C646679" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average length of time taken by the Department of Justice to process the MLAT requests described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3514F30AC1504436AAD1138FAB3CA726"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice to Department of State</header><text>The Attorney General shall notify the Secretary of State not later than 7 days after the date on which disclosure of electronic communications content to a foreign government is made pursuant to an MLAT request.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HECD909106C4D4EA8974211CF21404669"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preservation of Records</header><text>The Attorney General may issue a request pursuant to section 2703(f) of title 18, United States Code, upon receipt of an MLAT request that appears to be facially valid.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H90B79F380FF24F18866A28A1B4B19ED4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification to Provider of MLAT request</header><text>When the Attorney General makes use of the process provided in section 2703 of title 18, United States Code, to obtain information from an electronic communications provider or a remote computing provider based on an MLAT request, the Attorney General shall notify that provider in writing that the request has been made pursuant to a mutual legal assistance treaty.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE3F724F0E07B4514A8813F92C7F37DB2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H75A42A15DF084F7890BF7544AFCD7188"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data localization requirements imposed by foreign governments on data providers are—</text> <subparagraph id="H15005CB47A3744BF9D5B8679ACA885D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incompatible with the borderless nature of the Internet;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A9ED379887646819825BC4DDAF04D35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an impediment to online innovation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4A8CAF0E55A4451AA691295553B8026"><enum>(C)</enum><text>unnecessary to meet the needs of law enforcement; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D5F71A726D44E49805ADC41FA161628"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and the United States Trade Representatives should pursue open data flow policies with foreign nations.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

