<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H76D333ECC8A74A34A3CB1BD67B8948FE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3153 IH: Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial and Castaic Wilderness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3153</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150722">July 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize a national memorial to commemorate those killed by the collapse of the Saint Francis
			 Dam on March 12, 1928, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF982D7E79A94456AAC4FD5A8396BF1E8" style="OLC">
		<section id="HD16BC9E9EC1D404A96B18ED5590162CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HFCC7B9177BA7443EA64FEEE61F55E5C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial and Castaic Wilderness Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H002EDA7E4D0645C788FFEC95A33D10B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HD16BC9E9EC1D404A96B18ED5590162CA" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H22BE815461074DB7B4F2FD16DC5AFC92" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings and purposes.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2E31CBC8D33748E9A018B8B790908220" level="title">Title I—SAINT FRANCIS DAM ADVISORY COMMISSION</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H68B56DA5A4A547E4995A7756B15920FB" level="section">Sec. 101. Memorial to honor the victims of the Saint Francis Dam Disaster.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF3E452325B904277823D749F52809B01" level="section">Sec. 102. Saint Francis Dam Advisory Commission.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2A878B13DA24474F883315AFF2826EBC" level="section">Sec. 103. Duties of the secretary of the interior with respect to memorial.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H37F0B7A154754DE58BDD28F81DC72F0C" level="section">Sec. 104. Establishment of national monument.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB2B03DC5425443F4A026A784CD356F23" level="section">Sec. 105. Knapp Ranch potential wilderness area.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H49825C6204D545D8849872C18CB26D98" level="section">Sec. 106. General provisions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H22D4679D0BD14B9E93B24B763A1F65AD" level="section">Sec. 107. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8FA8037BF28A4AD799FC9855C7BE4CAD" level="title">Title II—DESIGNATION AND ADMINISTRATION OF WILDERNESS</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE028117BF6C94B6B8019B06CEDE711B8" level="section">Sec. 201. Designation and administration of wilderness.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H22BE815461074DB7B4F2FD16DC5AFC92"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header>
 <subsection id="H4199799B1E4F42BBBEAE87A6DC21C27F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H8764DD896AAB490BBC9761DFD2C92412"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On March 12, 1928, the Saint Francis Dam located in the northern portion of Los Angeles County, California, breached, resulting in a devastating flood that caused the death of approximately 425 individuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A59A5D8AEB94E30917274A4265322C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The residents of the Santa Clarita Valley, San Francisquito Canyon, Castaic Junction, Santa Clara River Valley, Piru, Fillmore, Bardsdale, Saticoy, and Santa Paula were directly impacted and suffered greatly from the worst flood in the history of the State of California.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4ADD09E6AD2D40938BBC436E94C33B39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The disaster resulted in a tremendous loss of human life, property, and the livelihood of local residents, and was surpassed in the 20th century only by the great San Francisco earthquake of 1906.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97036A3CE2D94DE9BB25CA537A12401C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The dam’s collapse may represent America’s worst civil engineering failure in the 20th century.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AC159CB5173442E8F1628B7C3E8F424"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The site is subject to the theft of historic artifacts, as well as graffiti and other vandalism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF154304D99194B9F86237EC09241B2B6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The surrounding area has important historic and environmental significance.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BB12B2EBF0D4EDB85CAE3BD3A292EFC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>It is right to pay homage to the citizens who perished, were injured, or were dislocated in the flood, and to bring to light and educate the general public about this important historical event.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB102C4B16B1E4833AE7EC1EC527CCD33"><enum>(8)</enum><text>It is appropriate that the site of the Saint Francis Dam and surrounding areas be designated a unit of the National Park System to commemorate this tragic event.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1898383005214064BEE8C6131F8F40BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HC300680369224D31A44334FAA5B30216"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To establish a national memorial to honor the victims of the Saint Francis Dam disaster of March 12, 1928.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDAE4B6F953E40E082C15DEC3D6039C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To establish the Saint Francis Dam Advisory Commission to assist with consideration and formulation of plans for a permanent memorial to the victims of that disaster, including its nature, design, and construction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43EB3C66AB80439396638304F27E01C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To permanently protect the site and surrounding area of the Saint Francis Dam and educate the general public about this tragic and historic event.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96BF7232295C41869C7536F262213A94"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to coordinate and facilitate the activities of the Saint Francis Dam Advisory Commission, provide technical and financial assistance to the Saint Francis Dam Task Force, and to administer a Saint Francis Dam memorial.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEACF4F908AF947A1B25D152FAEE260B5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To designate the Saint Francis Dam National Monument.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE37F2B7434504A56B1D1CD32DD57E2A3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To designate certain Federal lands administered by the United States Forest Service within Los Angeles County as wilderness.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><title id="H2E31CBC8D33748E9A018B8B790908220"><enum>I</enum><header>SAINT FRANCIS DAM ADVISORY COMMISSION</header>
 <section id="H68B56DA5A4A547E4995A7756B15920FB"><enum>101.</enum><header>Memorial to honor the victims of the Saint Francis Dam Disaster</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established a memorial at the Saint Francis Dam site in the County of Los Angeles, California, to honor the victims of the Saint Francis Dam disaster of March 12, 1928, which shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFD92C81BCF35457FB87BD417E0641373"><enum>(1)</enum><text>known as the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial and be managed by the National Park Service; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF5DE3A9E00401A89F8E47D6139BDD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>located within the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Monument.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HF3E452325B904277823D749F52809B01"><enum>102.</enum><header>Saint Francis Dam Advisory Commission</header> <subsection id="H78860867304F427DABABE833E868A7CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a commission to be known as the <quote>Saint Francis Dam Advisory Commission</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3A65EC83F1D24FCC89CDE5E5B2B70EC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Commission shall consist of no more than 15 members, including the Director of the National Park Service, or the Director’s designee, the Chief of the United States Forest Service, or the Chief’s designee, a designee of the Governor of the State of California, a designee of the County of Los Angeles Board of Supervisors, a representative of the Santa Clarita Valley Historical Society, a representative of the Community Hiking Club of Santa Clarita, and up to 8 additional members appointed by the Secretary of the Interior in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H98750EF2EDE443568447E5C655270D26"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of the members of the Commission shall be for the life of the Commission.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H0788F32A14354D28BF39B7190F22E19E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The members of the Commission shall select the Chair of the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0ACBEB9D0FE74DE3BA7376FCB7401A96"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Commission shall not affect its powers if a quorum is present, but shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5EE8E9AC849A4D1FB0DA968567FD47C4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairperson or a majority of the members, but not less often than quarterly. The Commission shall publish notice of the Commission meetings and agendas for the meetings in local newspapers in the vicinity of Los Angeles County and in the Federal Register. Meetings of the Commission shall be subject to section 552b of title 5, United States Code (relating to open meetings).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBD9B5904C56447E789E971E2C81350F5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members serving on the Commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any business.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC7EB03F88D7640E9992E68F86F67EAC8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No compensation</header><text>Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for expenses incurred in carrying out the duties of the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBB3F21CD82B5494E92DA9807F737F428"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Commission shall be as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HBE4713054BDB47F3B1F2C3E8C50B977A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, and Congress a report containing recommendations for the planning, design, construction, and long-term management of a permanent memorial at the dam site.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFEDD482AD424DEB84903EF53B4F199B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Commission shall advise the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture on the preferred nature of the Memorial, including the boundaries of the Memorial site, the desirability of a visitor center and educational facilities at the site, as well as ensuring public accessibility to the site.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE76D3168C204F89BA7FA8657D97C50B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Commission shall advise the Secretary of the Interior in the development of a management plan for the Memorial site.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE075EC99D1A41A7BDF78B10BF6BAB98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Commission shall consult and coordinate closely with all interested persons, as appropriate, as to how best to commemorate the Saint Francis Dam disaster.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31969900F369443CA17451381E2DBF8C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Commission shall provide significant opportunities for public participation in the planning and design of the Memorial.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA53440830F564AF191B1713619F8520C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Powers</header><text>The Commission may—</text> <paragraph id="HFB798BE43EA44F44A5B42BDD1BD9AD04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make such expenditures for services and materials for the purpose of carrying out this title as the Commission considers advisable from funds appropriated or received as gifts for that purpose;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D4CFFFFFA5A4FC49AA052BB9FB9A31F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to approval by the Secretary of the Interior, solicit and accept donations of funds and gifts, personal property, supplies, and services from individuals, foundations, corporations, and other private or public entities to be used in connection with the construction or other expenses of the Memorial;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H009DDCA7A78C4A54877BD77A7B3CCDD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hold hearings and enter into contracts for personal services;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H23B82A00C9264A478142F24201E74471"><enum>(4)</enum><text>do such other things as are necessary to carry out this title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C687BE98CF3452CBF5E8BE3F383F065"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by a vote of the majority of the Commission, delegate such of its duties as it determines appropriate to employees of the National Park Service and the United States Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA59FB0AED56E4B389C1ECC585AF372E5"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate upon dedication of the completed Memorial.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H2A878B13DA24474F883315AFF2826EBC"><enum>103.</enum><header>Duties of the secretary of the interior with respect to memorial</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, may—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFE30E581947645828AB2D9E83329ACB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide assistance to the Commission, including advice on collections, storage, and archives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9309BABD66C34078AB0E97889F2A92E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult and assist the Commission in providing information, interpretation, and the conduct of oral history interviews;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3AE40388D0D4317A94C228C981D299D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide assistance in conducting public meetings and forums held by the Commission;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF47EDCB9BAC44220B63EBAF0B3D3169D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide project management assistance to the Commission for planning, design, and construction activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1024D737B715413E8ABB53922FC27464"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide programming and design assistance to the Commission for possible Memorial exhibits, collections, or activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81F7F5102AE24A5A9F34E47B3AAA27BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide staff assistance and support to the Commission;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE317F392DBA1480F948E2E60A56DB3E0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>participate in the formulation of plans for the design of the Memorial, accept funds raised by the Commission for construction of the Memorial, and construct the Memorial;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E307FBC07F947BA899D8E7CA288F46D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>acquire from willing sellers the land or interests in land for the Memorial site by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD93BB2C2D74C45C0A8DEC0CA66A65E15"><enum>(9)</enum><text>administer the Memorial as a unit of the National Park System in accordance with this title and with the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H37F0B7A154754DE58BDD28F81DC72F0C"><enum>104.</enum><header>Establishment of national monument</header>
 <subsection id="H3ACCA8AEC2254DD6907EAD0C025B1EB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established as a national monument in the State certain land administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in Los Angeles County comprising approximately 440 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Proposed Saint Francis Dam National Monument</quote>, and dated June 18, 2015, to be known as the <quote>Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Monument</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H063369AE3A4C4F40A3C09AEDF1FE5AE7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Monument is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the cultural, archaeological, historical, natural, wildlife, geological, ecological, watershed, educational, scenic, and recreational resources and values of the Monument.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H808AEFACB72046FAB31E85EA340C1CB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header>
 <paragraph id="H544F610A0DED4DCE8E4CF2C6AF023591"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall manage the Monument—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H55AA1B5F07A1424F9F24FB7413FC17DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the cultural, historic, and ecological resources of the Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4CCDC7069604DD8A626DF85B6B160D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protects, preserves, and enhances the Memorial; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB75CBF5F3F96458B9A3BDF5142498BC6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text>
 <clause id="H34A55CE9258D46339FD3D0FE1F74D83B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text> </clause><clause id="HE2709027B6C64407AF90F1FB36B17A92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H04ADB22130F44728862C9B44D43E6BFD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other applicable laws.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BAE61EF8EEE4F6BBADF02074287CC39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header> <subparagraph id="H0062F048E9774A649EC5F2C0063DA039"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall allow only such uses of the Monument that the Secretary determines would further the purpose described in subsection (b).</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06FB960D8BD74EE8995CA8EADFC5E497"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of motorized vehicles</header>
 <clause id="HF8E3D2355C27436BAAEBA132CFF677CA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency, the use of motorized vehicles in the Monument shall be permitted only on roads designated for use by motorized vehicles in the management plan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF22652149BEF4BAC9B0AF2571E5F8121"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>New roads</header><text>No additional roads shall be built within the Monument after the date of enactment of this Act unless the road is necessary for public safety or natural resource protection.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F605E6618B04E2A81F6AADDDF3743DA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall permit grazing within the Monument, where established before the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <clause id="HC3888CE6B0E34A0F93F672BEC041F818"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to all applicable laws (including regulations) and Executive orders; and</text> </clause><clause id="H728ED5F739C74F7E86853C5D7C38A529"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consistent with the purpose described in subsection (b).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAA8830CDB67442EA7BD896309E7C713"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Utility right-of-way upgrades</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes the Secretary of Agriculture from renewing or authorizing the upgrading (including widening) of a utility right-of-way in existence as of the date of enactment of this Act through the Monument in a manner that minimizes harm to the purpose of the Monument described in subsection (b)—</text>
 <clause id="HB95FE3A0CB43462EB11AB6B407BC50BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <subclause id="H5EA0782DDF40412CBAAC619522C3C5BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEBF2BBBBC36D493BB9651E6846732285"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other applicable law; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H0F75F02D21DF4138B688C577560AD3DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary of Agriculture determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F50D93CB3274523B5179553BFF86D41"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rights-of-way</header><text>Subject to applicable law, the Secretary of Agriculture may issue rights-of-way for watershed restoration projects and small-scale flood prevention projects within the boundary of the Monument if the right-of-way is consistent with the purpose of the Monument described in subsection (b).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15AAC79116B44883A1A2D483EBD3C32F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H8B4D6645E2794353B6AE8731EA95E7C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall develop a management plan for the Monument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H850D0F24BB8C407ABCB0A16AF762F204"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The management plan shall be developed in consultation with—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF0D0347724F4380B956DD7AAE1550FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior and other interested Federal agencies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00704F395EB44D3C9527F1A1505B071F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State, tribal, and local governments; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE1DCFA16AA24731933E21FAEDC9ABD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the public.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H42A3B877CC95423196676DDEC621C52D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In preparing and implementing the management plan, the Secretary of Agriculture shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H956BEF40C8F046C4875ABCBFBE953A59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the recommendations of the Secretary of the Interior, Santa Clarita Valley Historical Society, and the Community Hiking Club of Santa Clarita on methods for providing access to, and protection for the St. Francis Dam Memorial site; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21CA67D82A394FC58F6C72B70811910A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a watershed health assessment to identify opportunities for watershed restoration.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3E50C85C6054A01A2AC05FBDAE433F6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests in land</header><text>Any land or interest in land that is within the boundary of the Monument designated by subsection (a) that is acquired by the United States shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H35CAC1F7A29E4B049EF0559661C4E63B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the Monument; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1E673BED1604EA8BAFA7B5A1EF5B391"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4ACD4B0936E944B9BDB639FEEF777D49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1E1D2C3354440BCB932560E38F8A3D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other applicable laws.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB2B03DC5425443F4A026A784CD356F23"><enum>105.</enum><header>Knapp Ranch potential wilderness area</header>
 <subsection id="H2E2BAEEA1E7743E1BA2442C83398DC8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), certain public land in the State administered by the United States Forest Service, comprising approximately 620 acres, as generally depicted as <quote>Restoration Area</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Castaic Potential Wilderness</quote> and dated June 18, 2015, is designated as a potential wilderness area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6C1476A956B649A9911D59F0E0DABEFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c) and subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall manage the potential wilderness area as wilderness until the potential wilderness area is designated as wilderness under subsection (d).</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HA2495DD2BA3D4F00BE4D2E257626EF86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ecological restoration</header>
 <paragraph id="H63C4E55C305640289B93107F5F40DE61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of ecological restoration (including the elimination of nonnative species, removal of unsafe or inappropriate structures, unused or decommissioned roads, and any other activities necessary to restore the natural ecosystems in the potential wilderness area), the Secretary may use motorized equipment and mechanized transport in the potential wilderness area until the potential wilderness area is designated as wilderness under subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49B72689D1384F0F88B6CC52F04EC193"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall use the minimum tool or administrative practice necessary to accomplish ecological restoration with the least amount of adverse impact on wilderness character and resources.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H579CC70A4D7B4A138BA79E91A5B3045B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eventual wilderness designation</header><text>The potential wilderness area shall be designated as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System on the earlier of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC271BEEB04FF4A65A410544EECAB04E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice that the conditions in the potential wilderness area that are incompatible with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) have been removed; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DD594894D864B65BC2EC973CB3EBD21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF16771933DA54CDB956D6EDF7A4E2287"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration as wilderness</header><text>On its designation as wilderness under subsection (d), the potential wilderness area shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFE2D9D2163994C1599D51E3F5E840A86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>known as a component of the Castaic Wilderness; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB342A48779E444A91848DB2646AE1EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>administered in accordance with section 201 and the Wilderness Act.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H49825C6204D545D8849872C18CB26D98"><enum>106.</enum><header>General provisions</header>
				<subsection id="HE2147A0902F846588397FD62C2B10F6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="HD6E8C6622ABE4C3EABF3FE9490A67314"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall file maps and legal descriptions of the Monument and the wilderness areas designated by this title with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H21B81A5D9049415B986CA79B278934DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2870635E0B7B4371B31380EABFBCB653"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H097F5A423FFF4C249A28EE32E268852C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary may correct errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5D57DA9FDA4438B8C4E7739E72D5460"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the United States Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D2540DB5C5441748D132205F4000781"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National landscape conservation system</header><text>The Monument and the wilderness areas designated by this title shall be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9DA336D5DFF14610921DA12F617DDE5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this title affects the jurisdiction of the State with respect to fish and wildlife located on public land in the State, except that the Secretary, after consultation with the California Department of Fish and Wildlife, may designate zones where, and establish periods during which, no hunting or fishing shall be permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, or compliance with applicable law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE397E5C3B1DC415B802A598420ABBD8B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Withdrawals</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land within the Monument, the wilderness areas designated by this title, and any land or interest in land that is acquired by the United States in the Monument or wilderness areas after the date of enactment of this Act is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="H99C757F17AE34650B07727D9DEA42F6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HACC79AD064194CDCBC49E3FF1140BC68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D90FCB5B5654EBC984197797BE019E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H22D4679D0BD14B9E93B24B763A1F65AD"><enum>107.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1A8CEB251CDA45898FCC5FA345E90A84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Memorial</header><text>The term <term>Memorial</term> means the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial established by section 101.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D19BF6092CE4AE4A18F48412BDF60B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monument</header><text>The term <term>Monument</term> means the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Monument established by section 104.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB153329F2D6F4FAF8C14232CF6A018E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California.</text> </paragraph></section></title><title id="H8FA8037BF28A4AD799FC9855C7BE4CAD"><enum>II</enum><header>DESIGNATION AND ADMINISTRATION OF WILDERNESS</header> <section id="HE028117BF6C94B6B8019B06CEDE711B8"><enum>201.</enum><header>Designation and administration of wilderness</header> <subsection id="H66C117272BA549AB8D4B57220B73439C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), certain lands in Los Angeles County, California, administered by the United States Forest Service, which comprise approximately 69,812 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Castaic Potential Wilderness</quote> and dated June 18, 2015, are hereby designated as wilderness and, therefore, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, which shall be known as the <quote>Castaic Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4B6F20D954C84234B4B67774CDCAE4FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal descriptions</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall file a map and a legal description for the wilderness area designated under this section with the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives. The map and description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this section, except that the Secretary of Agriculture may correct clerical and typographical errors in the legal description and map. The map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate office of the United States Forest Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HADFA992CF38A428AA61906D943960E4C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by this section shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in accordance with this title and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), except that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC53C9E339FFF4F6B8D1353D755D27FB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCAC0FE704A04C69BCB61D5ABA64B9EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be considered a reference to the Secretary that has jurisdiction over the land.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB49CCA41984B41D09356E2B44D7B63DC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fire management and related activities</header>
 <paragraph id="HF0483B578F5D44EB86E9D2BAD5F7693C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take such measures in a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 101 as are necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>) and House Report 98–40 of the 98th Congress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA91397EDB17643AFAE4CA9E4A5AE0B37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding priorities</header><text>Nothing in this title limits funding for fire and fuels management in the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FBC2A50CF2A41E8AC8B8870154EA4FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revision and development of local fire management plans</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the local fire management plans that apply to the land designated as a wilderness area or wilderness addition by section 101.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54554ACCA69A489EB2DBA223CF3BE301"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Consistent with paragraph (1) and other applicable Federal law, to ensure a timely and efficient response to fire emergencies in the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 101, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H06ED5602DDA84F72B0036D753309007F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, establish agency approval procedures (including appropriate delegations of authority to the Forest Supervisor, District Manager, or other agency officials) for responding to fire emergencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6E810EA2C4841A2999063B024B650C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into agreements with appropriate State or local firefighting agencies.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8E0CD44183341D1AF173C6AAAE1514A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 101, if established before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue, subject to such reasonable regulations as the Secretary considers necessary in accordance with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5BEE1BA0F3CB4BE4B8C93C31092D2E7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H20AE9C2857984386B4010FB4E4A71D1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in Appendix A of House Report 101–405, accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress for lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FB1ED6FC5E14FBDA1598F48A3E65ACF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in House Report 96–617, accompanying H.R. 5487 of the 96th Congress for lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D3ED27462C4457985E992641BEB7EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>all other laws governing livestock grazing on Federal public lands.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE03074F831C34CFDB47F3180376E8190"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header> <paragraph id="HD9D36977D9524114BE3E84427A3714A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this title affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife on public land in the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BFD0DBD3CD149A8B2F2A019DC1E4AFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management activities</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes and principles of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary may conduct any management activities that are necessary to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and habitats in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 101, if the management activities are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H71BF6D96F80F46A6888A0D35D6CA3D55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistent with relevant wilderness management plans; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H455F59C2324B400595213E03C1E1236A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducted in accordance with appropriate policies, such as the policies established in Appendix B of House Report 101–405.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H328AE2A7612F45B4AF4D98A07B0ED4D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Wildlife water development projects</header><text>Management activities to maintain water sources for wildlife may be carried out within wilderness areas designated by this title and may include the use of motorized vehicles by the appropriate agencies and their designees if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF7F3201B402140A597F5A755548D28D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the water sources will, as determined by the Secretary, enhance wilderness values by promoting healthy and viable wildlife populations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E79680EF7FA4F1DAEC0CDBC2756C038"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the visual impacts of the water sources on the wilderness areas can reasonably be minimized.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE05D28C1532D4665833DE0992A115982"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header> <paragraph id="H37BEAB76829E4085B2672AAF96533C8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress does not intend for designation of wilderness by this title to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around each wilderness area or wilderness addition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC589557AB75421082AEDD39CFA8CD8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities or uses up to boundaries</header><text>The fact that nonwilderness activities or uses can be seen or heard from within a wilderness area shall not, of itself, preclude the activities or uses up to the boundary of the wilderness area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7BA61F3DEC24E5CA7B1A0B46E466309"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Military activities</header><text>Nothing in this title precludes—</text> <paragraph id="H33018217DFB24178A5699356911EDC46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft over the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 101;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB732FC70E534C8D8BF32D24EADB35E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the designation of new units of special airspace over the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 101; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DD4B7DA14984256AABC02793EC6B8BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or establishment of military flight training routes over wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 101.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8BE4E5AC5784D34A2159343E1F02D93"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Horses</header><text>Nothing in this title precludes horseback riding in, or the entry of recreational or commercial saddle or pack stock into, a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 101—</text>
 <paragraph id="H351AB182267B427E93AE3463743C792D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with section 4(d)(5) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(5)</external-xref>); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE23E1BFC31BD402B84BF0014157B3958"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to any terms and conditions determined to be necessary by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H329C4FC59C9D4CB5999A7DAD3B455E59"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 101 are withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2164AE85ACD84B7E811F338418769520"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0E1D736D5BC4E1FBB96D38440C54480"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F56FBC3B13742FF8957C48F955683E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC014EC399B64696BA62C123036665B0"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land within the boundary of a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 101 that is acquired by the United States shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCA4323C542D64020B3E2C6EF7EA87B82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the wilderness area in which the land is located; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7803CD94B7F14DDDB114CBCF4E96F140"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with this section, the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), and any other applicable law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E347B3CC0AB40F89E18907622A2EB79"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Climatological data collection</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may authorize the installation and maintenance of hydrologic, meteorological, or climatological collection devices in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 101 if the Secretary determines that the facilities and access to the facilities are essential to flood warning, flood control, or water reservoir operation activities.</text>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


