<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H00B1D9071EF34D1AB2E94635F73EAA51" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1119 RH: Research and Development Efficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 86</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1119</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 114–121]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>May 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 26, 2015</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To improve the efficiency of Federal research and development, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HSY00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H56A2A9F0DAB3418BACC425C4AFF8ADE7" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3A7DB2303AD84673B74D2807E75E3341" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Research and Development Efficiency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H47178A123672489BBF1183DEA8065901"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulatory efficiency</header> <subsection id="H2356F50EC7654B3F95F5604591800A32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5EB5B43035BE4DE39E069002ABEF370E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>high and increasing administrative burdens and costs in Federal research administration, particularly in the higher education sector where most federally sponsored research is performed, are eroding funds available to carry out basic scientific research;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D664BE9A857481FBA441ED0D3060A1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>progress has been made over the last decade in streamlining the pre-award grant application process through Grants.gov, the Federal Government’s website portal;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79465051BD014D0C963528F65B1813B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>post-award administrative costs have grown as Federal research agencies have continued to impose agency-unique compliance and reporting requirements on researchers and research institutions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H692B803817684192ACB4BDD0E28245CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilities and administration costs at research universities can exceed 50 percent of the total value of Federal research grants, and it is estimated that nearly 30 percent of the funds invested annually in federally funded research is consumed by paperwork and other administrative processes required by Federal agencies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E721D8D8FB84215A53DCF96B905ECC0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>it is a matter of critical importance to American competitiveness that administrative costs of federally funded research be streamlined so that a higher proportion of taxpayer dollars flow into direct research activities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F6F071DAAA241909542B95D8F9538CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall establish a working group under the authority of the National Science and Technology Council, to include the Office of Management and Budget. The working group shall be responsible for reviewing Federal regulations affecting research and research universities and making recommendations on how to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF7B73C7D640E46C78398C39704FD687E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>harmonize, streamline, and eliminate duplicative Federal regulations and reporting requirements;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BF4A26BE296467A805226B54F4D2501"><enum>(2)</enum><text>minimize the regulatory burden on United States institutions of higher education performing federally funded research while maintaining accountability for Federal tax dollars; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1522FB866CA74F6FA4C3F34A1217A020"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and update specific regulations to refocus on performance-based goals rather than on process while still meeting the desired outcome.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0DCB48160CC4B21B34C13D0C84E8F75"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stakeholder input</header><text>In carrying out the responsibilities under subsection (b), the working group shall take into account input and recommendations from non-Federal stakeholders, including federally funded and nonfederally funded researchers, institutions of higher education, scientific disciplinary societies and associations, nonprofit research institutions, industry, including small businesses, federally funded research and development centers, and others with a stake in ensuring effectiveness, efficiency, and accountability in the performance of scientific research.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9B2090E2F5F54933A22B78AB10B111C1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Director shall report to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on what steps have been taken to carry out the recommendations of the working group established under subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>May 19, 2015</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


