<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6F79C78A0DA34E13BD7F3788F2E64659" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3766 PCS: Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 318</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3766</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>December 9, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the	calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the President to establish guidelines for United States foreign development and economic
			 assistance programs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD93836E1B9DA478CABDCE361E44E9542" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD3AC31CC2F914DE4B622D8B69E74EFED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5E10F0B0107342BCA818977645049F75"><enum>2.</enum><header>Guidelines for United States foreign development and economic assistance programs</header> <subsection id="H03689C4403EF4379A6252FB3597BE2B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this section is to evaluate the performance of United States foreign development and economic assistance and its contribution to the policies, strategies, projects, program goals, and priorities undertaken by the Federal Government, to foster and promote innovative programs to improve effectiveness, and to coordinate the monitoring and evaluation processes of Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H72D98F6EF8294D729E313B6BD366FB47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall set forth guidelines for the establishment of measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans that can be applied with reasonable consistency to United States foreign development and economic assistance. Such guidelines shall be established according to best practices of monitoring and evaluation studies and analyses.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H617ABDE563B24CE3AF8970DED8DC40CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Objectives of guidelines</header>
 <paragraph id="HD023EE2622764ECBA5E2F972CA3889F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines established under subsection (b) shall provide direction to Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance on monitoring the use of resources, evaluating the outcomes and impacts of United States foreign development and economic assistance projects and programs, and applying the findings and conclusions of such evaluations to proposed project and program design.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF93ECD2175C64C7BBBBD17C693F16B0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specifically, the guidelines established under subsection (b) shall require Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance to take the following actions:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4A4147BBCAA94053AE36D6A0B38D657C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Establish annual monitoring and evaluation agendas and objectives to plan and manage the process of monitoring, evaluating, analyzing progress, and applying learning toward achieving results.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE9552E34A4A74FB69A0EA2D9C7E41A16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Develop specific project monitoring and evaluation plans, to include measurable goals and performance metrics, and identify the resources necessary to conduct such evaluations, which should be covered by program costs, during project design.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98483702C32B472894263DF656DA81F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Apply rigorous monitoring and evaluation methodologies to such programs, including through the use of impact evaluations, ex-post evaluations, or other methods as appropriate, that clearly define program logic, inputs, outputs, intermediate outcomes, and end outcomes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C680727F73D479FAEBA89172A2AB29A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disseminate guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation programs to all personnel, especially in the field, who are responsible for the design, implementation, and management of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64BBB5632E0B42D8A640803C1614DA50"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Establish methodologies for the collection of data, including baseline data to serve as a reference point against which progress can be measured.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42807E95082648A4A008D7AE424FD8CD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evaluate at least once in their lifetime all programs whose dollar value equals or exceeds the median program size for the relevant office or bureau or an equivalent calculation to ensure the majority of program resources are evaluated.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC14C3426C0D94AFA824C3C2E6A5BD014"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Conduct impact evaluations on all pilot programs before replicating wherever possible, or provide a written justification for not conducting an impact evaluation where such an evaluation was deemed inappropriate or impossible.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFE5A25075734C4C85DEA2749A2E8AC3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Develop a clearinghouse capacity for the collection and dissemination of knowledge and lessons learned that serve as benchmarks to guide future programs for United States development professionals, implementing partners, the donor community, and aid recipient governments, and as a repository of knowledge on lessons learned.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D7E57D219FC4B19BDE0D11A913E54B6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Distribute evaluation reports internally.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDB960FE217443C7B04B318F4EB43074"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Publicly report each evaluation, including an executive summary, a description of the evaluation methodology, key findings, appropriate context (including quantitative and qualitative data when available), and recommendations made in the evaluation within 90 days after the completion of the evaluation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8044DA6F7B54409AA3402EC99E8D4D21"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Undertake collaborative partnerships and coordinate efforts with the academic community, implementing partners, and national and international institutions that have expertise in program monitoring, evaluation, and analysis when such partnerships provide needed expertise or significantly improve the evaluation and analysis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0361FBB6EB842709F5833A689D65EF9"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure verifiable, valid, credible, precise, reliable, and timely data are available to monitoring and evaluation personnel to permit the objective evaluation of the effectiveness of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, including an assessment of assumptions and limitations in such evaluations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86B128CCB36946E7BC5A2FDA4C359795"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Ensure that standards of professional evaluation organizations for monitoring and evaluation efforts are employed, including ensuring the integrity and independence of evaluations, permitting and encouraging the exercise of professional judgment, and providing for quality control and assurance in the monitoring and evaluation process.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H897120F13134417196F545EAD0B599FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Presidential report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains a detailed description of the guidelines established under subsection (b). The report shall be submitted in unclassified form, but it may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3DF9BCF0EA82420281E6991BAC2776CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comptroller general report</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall, not later than 1 year after the report required by subsection (d) is submitted to Congress, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that analyzes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7227E33220284326BB186B69AE3A5829"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE728C11053364E80956F0F4A7EAE3130"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a side-by-side comparison of the President’s budget request for that fiscal year of every operational unit that carries out United States foreign development and economic assistance and the performance of such units during the prior fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC74DB47DAA1C4F6A8D890F4728E02344"><enum>3.</enum><header>Information on United States foreign development and economic assistance programs</header>
			<subsection id="H94CC4B7D571545A7A9B70C3FD2BD9609"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Publication of information</header>
 <paragraph id="H6A9D3C97376147E7A81A9AF8FE9DB62C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Update of existing web site</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall update the Department of State’s Internet Web site, <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote>, to make publicly available comprehensive, timely, and comparable information on United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, including all information required pursuant to subsection (b) of this section that is then available to the Secretary of State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H725E345CD93841119ED3EFE103E68ED6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Federal department or agency that administers United States foreign development and economic assistance shall, not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, provide to the Secretary of State comprehensive information about the United States foreign development and economic assistance programs carried out by such department or agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF807E24266541A699F8FB9929D20A4E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates to web site</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall publish, through the <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote> Web site or a successor online publication, the information provided under subsection (b) of this section and shall update such information on a quarterly basis.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6774A1963344E99ACC7867B379BD7FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header>
 <paragraph id="H98DEFC84DAA0496583149895007A309B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The information described in subsection (a) shall be published on a detailed award-by-award and country-by-country basis unless assistance is provided on a regional level, in which case the information shall be published on an award-by-award and region-by-region basis.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA90CCBB63F4F15BAEC0CB5C1178944"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Types of information</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD0A32B074403454C881C8507943ED43A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure transparency, accountability, and effectiveness of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, the information described in subsection (a) shall include—</text>
 <clause id="H927B7A5986384B51A4801C538ACA9770"><enum>(i)</enum><text>links to all regional, country, and sector assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional budget justifications, evaluations and summaries of evaluations as required under section 2(c)(2)(J);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFA4170FA9E164A6EBA04042923B40871"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>basic descriptive summaries for United States foreign development and economic assistance programs and awards under such programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCA2DFB2FAE2649B7953F0069171436AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obligations and expenditures under such programs.</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Each type of information described in this paragraph shall be published or updated on the Internet Web site not later than 90 days after the date of issuance of the information.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H804E29449DA140428E345EC84252C6D3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to require a Federal department or agency that administers United States foreign development and economic assistance to provide any information that does not relate to or is not otherwise required by the United States foreign development and economic assistance programs carried out by such department or agency.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD81E74B57B94649872D00694542C928"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report in lieu of inclusion</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD4E9C9F7F699433993C4DDE52AAAD177"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Health or security of implementing partners</header><text>If the head of a Federal department or agency, in consultation with the Secretary of State, makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of information online would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program beneficiary or would require the release of proprietary information of an implementing partner or program beneficiary, the head of the Federal department or agency shall provide such determination in writing to the appropriate congressional committees, including the basis for such determination and shall—</text>
 <clause id="H5C32C7CE06D44C6D8B7BD18D392E7BBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on such information; or</text> </clause><clause id="H409719C19F754FB493673CF36B14EE66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees such information in a written report.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9C74CBAD3DB4ABBA2286ECC7D1B1448"><enum>(B)</enum><header>National interests of the united states</header><text>If the Secretary of State makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of information online would be detrimental to the national interests of the United States, the Secretary of State shall provide such determination in writing to the appropriate congressional committees, including the basis for such determination and shall—</text>
 <clause id="HE3B21D35779E455A8FA45B3D33126DFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on such information; or</text> </clause><clause id="HC7C124CA205644259F8FEAB38EAE08D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees the item of information in a written report.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E0535E7961040049E235FDE1FDB3197"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Any briefing or item of information provided under this paragraph may be provided in classified form, as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63410768D63F49FAB07D3BDCBC99B034"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Failure to comply</header><text>If a Federal department or agency fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (a), paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, or subsection (c) with respect to providing information described in subsection (a), and the information is not subject to a determination under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (3) of this subsection not to make the information publically available, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the head of such department or agency, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees not later than September 1, 2016, a consolidated report describing, with respect to each required item of information not made publicly available—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1AFFCC89B3064D3CB66EFDB4622B5DAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of the reason for not making such information publicly available; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF02CD6C1C12E4E3BA99E8813169B94EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the department’s or agency’s plan and timeline for immediately making such information publicly available, and for ensuring that information is made publically available in following years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AA6A65130554865BC89462C0FE15799"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of information</header><text>The online publication required by subsection (a) shall, at a minimum, provide the information required by subsection (b)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7CE3262456FF4C508C01093FEAE350BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in each fiscal year from 2016 through 2019, such information for fiscal years 2012 through the current fiscal year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3E966B8367B493C866179F30C019CDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2020 and each fiscal year thereafter, such information for the immediately preceding 5 fiscal years in a fully searchable form.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H553A781DD32B4497B0C90B055427D6BB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE45E875CDCD44B24A4088198B1D04A86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7065D3C9A1374D0C81B2353644D8FCA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC59E994FE624B9E95CD2B2A455F401A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0F92AD146124D728A37E60C8FB9326B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>evaluation</term> means, with respect to a United States foreign development and economic assistance program, the systematic collection and analysis of information about the characteristics and outcomes of the program, including projects conducted under such program, as a basis for making judgments and evaluations regarding the program, to improve program effectiveness, and to inform decisions about current and future programming.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFC4AB9F9898346EAA68F5457857D71F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United States foreign development and economic assistance</header><text>The term <term>United States foreign development and economic assistance</term> means assistance provided primarily for the purposes of foreign development and economic support, including assistance authorized under—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H860C287FD5AE44A4B06BE202C41D6EE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>), other than—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H86D7DD6811944139921922C7B5D07A43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>title IV of chapter 2 of such part (relating to the Overseas Private Investment Corporation);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8323F2815DF649CEA0B9169516CE37A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>chapter 3 of such part (relating to International Organizations and Programs); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD0D8CAA5AB80402C96F7A5B7315BCC7A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>chapter 8 of such part (relating to International Narcotics Control);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD9E2D5344C5646459D7B0E7F17F78C4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2346">22 U.S.C. 2346 et seq.</external-xref>; relating to Economic Support Fund);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H89DB984EFBB148029433224A2FADCA31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7701">22 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD6E4A91D9412498CB773F21ABEE36615"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1721">7 U.S.C. 1721 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20151208">Passed the House of Representatives December 8, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
	<endorsement display="yes"><action-date>December 9, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the	calendar</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


