<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Received-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFF2CFF869F0744748E28DB05FC0DB35A" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1527 : Slain Officer Family Support Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1527</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>March 26, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To accelerate the income tax benefits for charitable cash contributions for the relief of the
			 families of New York Police Department Detectives Wenjian Liu and Rafael
			 Ramos, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFF386F3F856D4DAC94D09B27F7E1564D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H015BF33B1D2C4D00B16999BFDDD26FDE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Slain Officer Family Support Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2FE07CA43A4A4C75A8026CC02EB8C59B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Acceleration of income tax benefits for charitable cash contributions for relief of the families of New York Police Department Detectives Wenjian Liu and Rafael Ramos</header> <subsection id="HF72729C8ADA04A0DADA5188E7C6C8D6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 a taxpayer may treat any contribution described in subsection (b) made between January 1, 2015, and April 15, 2015, as if such contribution was made on December 31, 2014, and not in 2015.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H85828A98071846D69F009D4F8965CEE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contribution described</header><text>A contribution is described in this subsection if such contribution is a cash contribution made for the relief of the families of slain New York Police Department Detectives Wenjian Liu and Rafael Ramos, for which a charitable contribution deduction is allowable under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H586B3D9091BE4F168346750B15D29638"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text>In the case of a contribution described in subsection (b), a telephone bill showing the name of the donee organization, the date of the contribution, and the amount of the contribution shall be treated as meeting the recordkeeping requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170(f)(17)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H812E996925DE4D86A35EF23818ADDD20"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clarification that contribution will not fail To qualify as a charitable contribution</header><text>A cash contribution made for the relief of the families of slain New York Police Department Detectives Wenjian Liu and Rafael Ramos shall not fail to be treated as a charitable contribution for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and subsection (b) of this section merely because such contribution is for the exclusive benefit of such families. The preceding sentence shall apply to contributions made on or after December 20, 2014.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H93F6AA5A6366413E98D75832D464C229"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clarification that payments by charitable organizations to families treated as exempt payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, payments made on or after December 20, 2014, and on or before October 15, 2015, to the spouse or any dependent (as defined in section 152 of such Code) of slain New York Police Department Detectives Wenjian Liu or Rafael Ramos by an organization which (determined without regard to any such payments) would be an organization exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6FDF4111C7E34270947A91C611D9E642"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be treated as related to the purpose or function constituting the basis for such organization’s exemption under such section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H742029D4C79342F4B1130C0B17C57F08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not be treated as inuring to the benefit of any private individual,</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">if such payments are made in good faith using a reasonable and objective formula which is consistently applied with respect to such Detectives.</continuation-text></subsection></section></legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20150325">Passed the House of Representatives March 25, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

