<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61E8A7103D784DF68EA922270F5632B6" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3060 IH: Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3060</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150714">July 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require certain standards and enforcement provisions to prevent child abuse and neglect in residential programs, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9AB9700F4E00460FA0C592C43457185D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB0B1B4488FFE46A2A46E3A05F93FD85F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7BA620F968AF4C929D1A602D94A1D709"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H67494B9000DE4805A0FEA8C732A20E8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DA1C3AD50634FDBB32B116A2963F1DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE91F564E2598442DB04F880CA2636FD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Child abuse and neglect</header><text>The term <term>child abuse and neglect</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5101">42 U.S.C. 5101</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA966A9DE51C14DB982BF3131EED9ECD7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered program</header> <subparagraph id="HBFC9799BB4E94947832FB60AC5FA70C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered program</term> means each facility of a program operated by a public or private entity that, with respect to one or more children who are unrelated to the owner or operator of the program, purports to provide treatment or modify behaviors in a residential environment, such as—</text> 
<clause id="H3E3614C1621E4195A64B2596C7617674"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a program with a wilderness or outdoor experience, expedition, or intervention;</text></clause> <clause id="H205F11D1A0204BA7B9A2D30A2D44C3F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a boot camp experience or other experience designed to simulate characteristics of basic military training or correctional regimes;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6A3E5D5B221B4C8D90FB795F48738AE4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a therapeutic boarding school; or</text></clause> <clause id="H47EDBAA4AACE45738BAEDA1E4A225813"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a behavioral modification program.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H108DA5AADB1A49B0BF983C0F47B6C893"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>covered program</term> does not include—</text> <clause id="H3A3CA2E6D7904A5CBB6AB432DADE7B63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a hospital licensed by the State; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6E4E24F0B5FE4EAD8CCCE740348A6F1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a foster family home that provides 24-hour substitute care for children placed away from their parents or guardians and for whom the State child welfare services agency has placement and care responsibility and that is licensed and regulated by the State as a foster family home.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB06050836CF040BAACB0694E742275D0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mechanical restraint</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>mechanical restraint</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 595(d)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290jj">42 U.S.C. 290jj(d)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8D7ACD559E4470EB05FB48637AF25BF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Physical restraint</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>physical restraint</quote> means a personal restriction that immobilizes or reduces the ability of an individual to move the individual's arms, legs, torso, or head freely, except that such term does not include voluntary physical escort (as such term is defined in section 595(d)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290jj">42 U.S.C. 290jj(d)(2)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF678443E19A04CDBA09AD75959BB52BF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Protection and Advocacy System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>protection and advocacy system</quote> means a system established by a State under section 143 of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15043">42 U.S.C. 15043</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35BD579ACF7048B19E065CEFFFF37402"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Seclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>seclusion</quote> means the involuntary confinement of a child alone in a room or area from which the child is physically prevented from leaving.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F55479FF8DE49FBB6C47E696FDBC162"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5101">42 U.S.C. 5101</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HADB9D60185044327B8838C4911C48114"><enum>3.</enum><header>Standards and enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="HC180A0ED93DF46F5BBEB5627A849C2DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimum standards</header> 
<paragraph id="H1D4210CC5F5A48F3A1F9F927A973B4DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall require each covered program, in order to provide for the basic health and safety of children at such a program, to meet the following minimum standards:</text> <subparagraph id="H0064472B381D44CFB8C27A3F89EDFCEB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition on child abuse and neglect</header><text>Child abuse and neglect shall be prohibited.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H68606A203F0747D5B7241B391A8311EF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain disciplinary techniques</header><text>Disciplinary techniques or other practices that involve the withholding of essential food, water, clothing, shelter, or medical care necessary to maintain physical health, mental health, and general safety, shall be prohibited.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72EE549BE8254EFBA0B700BCC186FF0F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition on physical or mental abuse</header><text>Acts of physical or mental abuse designed to humiliate, degrade, or undermine a child’s self-respect shall be prohibited.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7D3D684CF9644134A45389F9104EC233" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on restraints and seclusion</header> 
<clause id="HBB60A5DBA4C34FB18C67BA46D6FFA748"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of seclusion, mechanical restraints, and physical restraints that impair breathing or communication is prohibited.</text></clause> <clause id="H1800947E497F4C6AB2CD4A158A341A92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Physical restraints other than the restraints described in clause (i) may be used (if not contraindicated) only in emergency situations in which a child presents an imminent danger of harm to self or others and only after less restrictive interventions have been determined to be ineffective.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEAB758EAECA7491D9C6F9AE3A1FA27E0"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Access to communications</header><text>Each child at such a program shall have reasonable access to a telephone, and be informed of their right to such access to maintain frequent contact, including making and receiving scheduled and unscheduled calls, unrestricted written correspondence, and electronic communications with as much privacy as possible, and shall have access to existing and appropriate national, State, and local child abuse reporting hotline numbers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD86A405AF09547DDB57CC9AB297899A2" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Staff-to-Child ratio</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An appropriate ratio of medical, clinical, and line staff to children, as determined by the Secretary, to ensure child safety and the efficacy of treatment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60A512513E404F4C9DFD888A8F52A165" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Senior management</header><text>Not less than one full-time licensed clinician or mental health practitioner, as defined by State law, shall be employed as a senior manager of such a program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21FF9CCDAA034180A1630DC39289E4F2" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Licensed clinician</header><text>Not less than one licensed clinician, as defined by State law, shall be present at all times at such a program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF15195734D3474FB3012986781C8699"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Program Policies</header><text>Policies to require—</text> <clause id="H3C116B51726941BC9E717917C6540D64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>parents or legal guardians of a child attending such a program to notify, in writing, such program of any medication the child is taking;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7C5C4BC096B045B89F998BEF15B8BB7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a licensed full-time clinician—</text> <subclause id="H384DF81F3E614191B350841AC4508112"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to obtain consent from the parents or legal guardians of the child to make any change to the child’s medical treatment, except in the case of an emergency;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8BA584A14BC14B189F43FDEA4FB49C19"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an emergency, to notify the parents or guardians within 24 hours after any change to the child’s medical treatment and the reason for such change; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF820456F80E6490B84ADE5DC7214B061"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to notify the parents or guardians within 24 hours after any changes to the child’s prescribed medication or any missed dosage of prescribed medication, and the reason for such change or occurrence; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1960EBD3ED9A4A679D2F91001E1D6249"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the covered program to notify parents or legal guardians of a child of any changes to their treating provider team within 48 hours.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBBD9A39BD181496A8FBE33DE56F8B006"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Notification procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Procedures for notifying immediately, to the maximum extent practicable, but not later than within 6 hours, parents or legal guardians with children at such a program and the appropriate protection and advocacy system of any—</text> 
<clause id="H6B188751A2BD4398A90CC746A5EF6D9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on-site investigation of a report of child abuse and neglect;</text></clause> <clause id="H8DF12FD78E034217B4F69C71DD336F92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>violation of the health and safety standards described in this paragraph; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC2D97B40536343CAA631B78C4D29C603"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>violation of State licensing requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE0EBCE34A1B4BDD825B28CC693F5348"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Staff disclosures</header><text>Full disclosure, in writing, of staff qualifications and their roles and responsibilities at such a program, including any medical, emergency response, and mental health training received by such staff, shall be given to parents or legal guardians of children at such a program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FAA95AB24574ADDB155EEB6C3EC0A86"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Disclosure of right of action</header><text>Full disclosure, in writing, of the private right of action established under subsection (b)(3) of this Act, shall be given to parents or legal guardians of children at such a program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6BE8821D00D74024961D325DA4399469"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Child abuse response training</header><text>Each staff member, including volunteers, at such a program shall be required, as a condition of employment, to become trained in what constitutes child abuse and neglect, State law relating to mandated reporters, and procedures for reporting child abuse and neglect in the State in which such a program is located, and information on existing and appropriate national, State, and local child abuse reporting hotline numbers.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H95D4E6B4E8E74D028C7A513FA60A20E0"><enum>(N)</enum><header>Medical response training</header><text>Each staff member, including volunteers, at such a program shall be required, as a condition of employment, to become trained in recognizing the signs, symptoms, and appropriate responses associated with common medical emergencies and mental health crisis, including suicide and worsening symptoms of mental illness.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF0F75567F6C4CFC9CD417DD619BA44D"><enum>(O)</enum><header>Criminal history check</header> <clause id="HD9F62451F5C04DCC89F59FF1DE6D696F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each staff member, including volunteers, shall be required, as a condition of employment, to submit to a criminal history check, including a name-based search of the National Sex Offender Registry established pursuant to the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>), a search of the State criminal registry or repository in the State in which the covered program is operating, and a Federal Bureau of Investigation fingerprint check. An individual shall be ineligible to serve in a position with any contact with children at a covered program if any such record check reveals a violent felony conviction that, by virtue of its nature, proximity in time, or other factor, presents a direct increase to a child’s risk of harm in the program as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H77B0849D480446318960395044BA9F67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The covered program shall provide an independent process by which an applicant or staff member who is determined to be ineligible as a result of a criminal history check under clause (i) shall have the right—</text> <subclause id="HBC3B93184F444FDF9B4065029F97F749"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to obtain a copy of the report resulting from the check; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBF25200BDD14455CADBACEA84BD5F095"><enum>(II)</enum><text>within 10 business days after receipt of the report, to appeal, in order to dispute the accuracy of the information obtained through the check.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72482370D2E24675A2DE414CDC7302BA"><enum>(P)</enum><header>Informational materials</header><text>Full disclosure, in writing on promotional and informational materials produced by such a program, shall be given to parents or legal guardians of children at such a program, which shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H88C1D2FC6EB045D0BCF0D25B3C02D57B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name and location of a covered program, including the names of any owners and operators;</text></clause> <clause id="HAD86A36755DE41868283F7A040A03AAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the numbers and percentages of children who terminated participation prior to completion of that program in the past 5 years, including discharges against medical advice;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H81A062CD5AD5480EBC1BB7755E810CDC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any past violations of the standards under section 3(a)(1) and any penalties levied against the program as a result of such violations;</text></clause> <clause id="H0C79045BD6E74144889DB24EB36A16AD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>its most updated status with State licensing requirements;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0E761E85879F4EDABC45D7097621D5C9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of deaths that occurred in that program for up to a period of 10 years, including the cause of each death;</text></clause> <clause id="HE873946EA86E495FB2D8A679508C6DDA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the names of owners and operators that have violated State licensing requirements;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H320717DA984A40459275175EC7AD4B3A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>information on evidence-based or promising practices employed as treatment of a covered program, including information to aid parents in finding community-based resources; and</text></clause> <clause id="H80AB9E3C4639434EADF1A83658BD8274"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any national, State, and local telephone hotline numbers made available to children and staff to report complaints of abuse and violations.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2C018FEB6BB4672A22EF55994AF28F5"><enum>(Q)</enum><header>Treatment and discharge plans</header><text>Covered programs shall work with the parent or legal guardian and the child’s community providers in the development, modification, and implementation of treatment and discharge plans, including a plan for community reintegration and linkage to community-based providers and supports.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2861C96D998249DFA076C9889F2FE3F9"><enum>(R)</enum><header>Prohibition on discrimination</header><text>Ensure that no person shall, on the basis of actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, or disability, be subjected to discrimination under any program or activity, in whole or in part, covered by this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C7BF1AD81364318BAC49232B04D3092"><enum>(S)</enum><header>Evidence-based practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure that covered programs employ safe, evidence-based practices, and that children are protected against harmful or fraudulent practices including isolation and restraints.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3748E5EDAB7645E5AD0D0A14012031A8"><enum>(T)</enum><header>Other standards</header><text>Any other standards the Secretary determines appropriate to provide for the basic health and safety of children at such a program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15299248AB864243B03309BF6D89D0C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9C81AB2B56AA464A978607C3DF6A920D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interim regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate and enforce interim regulations to carry out paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H455F609B62A64D93A126CA0BCC47C7F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>The Secretary shall, for a 90-day period beginning on the date of the promulgation of interim regulations under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, solicit and accept public comment concerning such regulations. Such public comment shall be submitted in written form.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA84B8AE58BE84D15ADC3F5FE76D5154D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Final regulations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the conclusion of the 90-day period referred to in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the Secretary shall promulgate and enforce final regulations to carry out paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBE04510273CC4E7F82C48E8AF9C8BF4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monitoring and enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H3D5A539B49EB4BEF9C8516A0A295003A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review process</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall implement a review process for overseeing, investigating, and evaluating reports of child abuse and neglect at covered programs received by the Secretary from the appropriate State, in accordance with section 114(b)(3) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act, as added by section 7 of this Act. Such review process shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H64FB08B92C284C6885307BD1831FCB91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include an investigation to determine if a violation of the standards required under subsection (a)(1) has occurred; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E54A4D9AE7A4FC583A574B2C1D7B5B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include consultation and collaboration with relevant Federal and State agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0774BC0576BD46BDA88581C4C6A67527"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations establishing civil penalties for violations of the standards required under subsection (a)(1). The regulations establishing such penalties shall incorporate the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAD8F021B140445BD8019F43BF8ECCAC4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>Any owner or operator of a covered program at which the Secretary has found a violation of the standards required under subsection (a)(1) may be assessed a civil penalty not to exceed $50,000 per violation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89726E14A31E4107B28A58EE7F2F9819"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deposit to Treasury</header><text>All penalties collected under this subsection shall be deposited in the appropriate account of the Treasury of the United States.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H58B5C663C1724271A5152AFF699FAB4A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who suffers injury by reason of a violation of this section may maintain a civil action against the violator to obtain appropriate compensatory damages and injunctive relief or other equitable relief.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF21308C64482492FB92F1AFB4C294B2C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Action</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process to assist States in the oversight and enforcement of this Act, which shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H7D3F8F8DE8E045959171FF88936AB638" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assisting States in implementing oversight mechanisms to ensure compliance with the standards under subsection (a)(1);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00A4F7891E8F4223A08EDDA6BF9D1C73" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintaining oversight of covered programs in cases in which a State has not established mechanisms sufficient to ensure compliance with the standards under subsection (a)(1) within 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2111636DB1CB4FF294B6D86831E9BE20" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encouraging the use of local, State, or national hotline numbers for the reporting of child abuse and any other resources the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HABF64E2CFD4247F4A6CD52B8A48E561A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement by the Attorney General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a violation of section (3)(a)(1) has not been remedied through the enforcement process described in subsection (b)(2) of such section, the Secretary shall refer such violation to the Attorney General for appropriate action. Regardless of whether such a referral has been made, the Attorney General may, sua sponte, file a complaint in any court of competent jurisdiction seeking equitable relief or any other relief authorized by this Act for such violation.</text></section> <section id="H28B12C26CFF242EF8A63CACE1A8D3328"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, a report on the activities carried out by the Secretary and the Attorney General, as authorized and mandated under this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="HBF1BBFA42AB940978F22D90BCDD24F2F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020 to carry out this Act (excluding the amendment made by section 7 of this Act).</text></section> <section id="H5BF9F7B35C0446E0979DF9D8996B88F7"><enum>7.</enum><header>Additional eligibility requirements for grants to States to prevent child abuse and neglect at residential programs</header> <subsection id="H09C1712D44BF4B1F9605D093ECAC1E38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5101">42 U.S.C. 5101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H39C4221711DC458F8EE40E89D20CC6BE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7DCE0F0733B94F9BA4957851F11BEC8E"><enum>114.</enum><header>Additional eligibility requirements for grants to States to prevent child abuse and neglect at residential programs</header> 
<subsection id="HBEBA412FA9BB4994A45FF46B6BCCCDCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HAF88CD06724F40A89E97FDDD7D620BDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F34A5B8531049A99BC45C185A36C394"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered program</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2C32248BCB3E47D7A612490B59BF827D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered program</term> means each facility of a program operated by a public or private entity that, with respect to one or more children who are unrelated to the owner or operator of the program, purports to provide treatment or modify behaviors in a residential environment, such as—</text> <clause id="HE6736C817AB04597AF767783FF9546F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a program with a wilderness or outdoor experience, expedition, or intervention;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE654041768744A9BA55AB94478660F71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a boot camp experience or other experience designed to simulate characteristics of basic military training or correctional regimes;</text></clause> <clause id="HB01386F7E99D4118A506880760599091"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a therapeutic boarding school; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9431E18E5790424F94CB5A4DC21E9F2D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a behavioral modification program.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE809B4F0A5DB413391841CDFD9BB131A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>covered program</term> does not include—</text> 
<clause id="H0323F4ADCE834D0784666B459FCD2F89"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a hospital licensed by the State; or</text></clause> <clause id="H51FD6B6DC0B7474EA819B9E749C17B5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a foster family home that provides 24-hour substitute care for children placed away from their parents or guardians and for whom the State child welfare services agency has placement and care responsibility and that is licensed and regulated by the State as a foster family home.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDE4CB532762140B7ACC8730B35EB6520"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under section 106, a State shall—</text> <paragraph id="H71CACE646ECE4AAF9BEE9546F37D5F82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, develop policies and procedures to prevent child abuse and neglect at covered programs operating in such State, including standards that meet or exceed the standards required under section 3(a)(1) of the Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2015;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FB5E5B3544D462BAAA11CE1DAE29269" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a private right of action under State law for any person who suffers injury by reason of a violation of the standards required under paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30122EBD30D4401DAF43C89B12BC6292"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop policies and procedures to enforce compliance with the requirements developed in accordance with paragraph (1), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HED57DFBDB18344B7B91C1CAD1CE8A2BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing and monitoring health and safety licensing requirements applicable to and necessary for the operation of each location of such covered programs in the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDB42495AA2B4E87A2AFAE45C3D2C2C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting unannounced site inspections at each location of a covered program;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71A460246CCE4BA38353A7064ECA52B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop policies and procedures for timely notification to the Secretary and the appropriate protection and advocacy system if—</text> <subparagraph id="H3CA667FC274A410F8D866E13F879F2EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State determines there is evidence of a pattern of violations of the standards required under paragraph (1) at a covered program operating in the State or by an owner or operator of such a program; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H396E8A178C404F839C7537EA141DA20F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there is a child fatality at a covered program operating in the State; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0B68C87D8B84F41B78918038731E402"><enum>(5)</enum><text>annually submit to the Secretary a report that includes all covered programs within their jurisdiction, including any violations by each program or any information deemed by the Secretary to be necessary for enforcement of this Act.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H21808ECC445C4A45BA5B7F90EF84B244"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>if the Secretary determines that the State is not satisfying the requirements of this subsection within 3 years of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide assistance to the State to satisfy such requirements or withhold funding until such policies and procedures are established.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB5E86DDF3BB14966B3A51D2E38062763"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>Section 112(a)(1) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106h">42 U.S.C. 5106h(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$120,000,000</quote> and all that follows through the period and inserting <quote>$200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4AEF6B5DB0504379907A18A9588A36BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H064D621A47534759A8C50062856A7B68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coordination with available resources</header><text>Section 103(c)(1)(D) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5104">42 U.S.C. 5104(c)(1)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>specific</quote> the following: <quote>(including reports of child abuse and neglect occurring at covered programs (except that such reports shall not contain any personally identifiable information relating to the identity of individuals who were the victims of such child abuse and neglect), as such term is defined in section 114)</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H416396B7FABA4D1D961C769FFF32A9D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Further requirement</header><text>Section 106(b)(1) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106a">42 U.S.C. 5106a(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HA959975AA1D747C9A62E362A5D7BE602" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HD76E4C0E72EE4182A55EE06C61077FFD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Further requirement</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State shall comply with the requirements under section 114(b) and shall include in the State plan submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A) a description of the activities the State will carry out to comply with the requirements under such section 114(b).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D8FB82B87994085949E2D5EE5AC5A4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual state data reports</header><text>Section 106(d) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106a">42 U.S.C. 5106a(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4721132735F64767A3AB10000633A8BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>(including reports of child abuse and neglect occurring at covered programs (except that such reports shall not contain any personally identifiable information relating to the identity of individuals who were the victims of such child abuse and neglect), as such term is defined in section 114)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16DFF44996804F029CC67E9D964971B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>or who were in the care of a covered program, as such term is defined in section 114</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8A71FCA90BAE4CE38CF9392E64B6AA18"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>Section 1(b) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5101">42 U.S.C. 5101</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 113 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8906C7FECA9747AFA7B0B6C3A346FACA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H39C4221711DC458F8EE40E89D20CC6BE" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="H7DCE0F0733B94F9BA4957851F11BEC8E" level="section">Sec. 114. Additional eligibility requirements for grants to States to prevent child abuse and neglect at residential programs.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

