<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H06226D2E98044311BEA40F55C1CD5A92" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3969 IH: To designate the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in Laughlin, Nevada, as the “Master Chief Petty Officer Jesse Dean Department of Veterans Affairs Community-Based Outpatient Clinic”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3969</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001055">Mr. Heck of Nevada</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001070">Mr. Hardy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To designate the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in Laughlin,
			 Nevada, as the <quote>Master Chief Petty Officer Jesse Dean Department of Veterans Affairs Community-Based Outpatient
			 Clinic</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5F40BFF3788A4C5083B4EB977DFE92C4" style="OLC">
		<section id="H6C31905DE89741D7B7B2256296F3649B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Master Chief Petty Officer Jesse Dean Department of Veterans Affairs Community-Based Outpatient
			 Clinic</header>
 <subsection id="H1CC40A884DB347FF99FD636E7E9EBFBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in Laughlin, Nevada, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Master Chief Petty Officer Jesse Dean Department of Veterans Affairs Community-Based Outpatient Clinic</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6AC59418C175446785C40C57CF618530"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the community-based outpatient clinic referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Master Chief Petty Officer Jesse Dean Department of Veterans Affairs Community-Based Outpatient Clinic</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


