<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H14C57576EFFD4EF5AA5396733BBAB705" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2035 IH: Supporting Colorectal Examination and Education Now Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2035</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150427">April 27, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend titles XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act and title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to improve coverage for colorectal screening tests under Medicare and private health insurance coverage, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HDB62B4272F174241B25B0250331A65BF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDD25708D85FC4688966166EDA1315E8E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H590517B8D2DD4400AAD7F4966491321E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Colorectal Examination and Education Now Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SCREEN Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HBC966AE437924BE1B7860D5037082061"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry idref="HDD25708D85FC4688966166EDA1315E8E" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8955C828F94C4786A17015631210ECF8" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB53767B201A4408BBEBC3918FA639BF4" level="section">Sec. 3. Maintaining calendar year 2015 Medicare reimbursement rates for colonoscopy procedures for providers participating in colorectal cancer screening quality improvement registry.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC65AF74D3D214EF6BD36BD2DDE978DF9" level="section">Sec. 4. Eliminating Medicare beneficiary cost-sharing for certain colorectal cancer screenings, colorectal cancer screenings with therapeutic effect, and follow-up diagnostic colorectal cancer screenings covered under Medicare.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD987552997A24B74AED9901AE3F95D56" level="section">Sec. 5. Medicare demonstration project to evaluate the effectiveness of a pre-operative visit prior to screening colonoscopy and hepatitis C screening.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H91BC7EB19DA14D10AEBD921BE6A044EE" level="section">Sec. 6. Budget neutrality.</toc-entry></toc> </subsection></section>
<section id="H8955C828F94C4786A17015631210ECF8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA0A1738553874C469DEF6677F34FC754"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Colorectal cancer is the second leading cause of cancer death among men and women combined in the United States.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H92FC44E7052B4729A20138E8980AFAEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 2015, more than 130,000 Americans will be diagnosed with colorectal cancer, and nearly 50,000 Americans are expected to die from it.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC51C04137397499EB368AABCD5EA882E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Approximately 60 percent of colorectal cancer cases and 70 percent of colorectal cancer deaths occur in those aged 65 and older.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF8A93212E380465CA0E257EABC565D9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Colorectal cancer screening colonoscopies allow for the detection and removal of polyps before they progress to colorectal cancer, as well as early detection of colorectal cancer when treatment can be most effective.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3919F0AD2DF44AF083F3EA072DF9A548"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to a 2012 study published in the New England Journal of Medicine, removing precancerous polyps through colonoscopy could reduce the number of colorectal cancer deaths by 53 percent.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA34DD9E6A29E42379049C8CB4D7E5E89"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Although colorectal cancer is highly preventable with appropriate screening, one in three adults between the ages of 50 and 75 years are not up to date with recommended colorectal cancer screening.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D471BACEE6E4B3E98142267D48CF472"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Over 200 organizations have committed to eliminating colorectal cancer as a major health problem in the United States and are working toward a shared goal of screening 80 percent of eligible Americans by 2018.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0256382314614FE69D84EC156CECBFA1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Hepatitis C is a liver disease that causes inflammation of the liver and results from infection with the Hepatitis C virus. Chronic Hepatitis C infection can lead to serious health problems, including liver damage, cirrhosis, and liver cancer. It is the leading cause of liver transplants in the United States.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H33D74E3E5E2A4281AA6336C4A70C46D0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), more than 75 percent of adults infected with the Hepatitis C virus in the United States were born between 1945 and 1965.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7F1A2BC7A5894AF190409F11B285C68A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The CDC estimates that up to 75 percent of individuals with Hepatitis C do not know that they are infected.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4C35790341044AB9ED34A58C47D265F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The CDC and the United States Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) recommend a one-time screening for Hepatitis C for all individuals born between 1945 and 1965.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0565B0FDAF644A8C8C34AE8BBA74DCFB"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A recent study suggests that offering Hepatitis C screening to patients in connection with screening colonoscopies may be an effective means of increasing Hepatitis C screening rates among individuals born between 1945 and 1965.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="HB53767B201A4408BBEBC3918FA639BF4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Maintaining calendar year 2015 Medicare reimbursement rates for colonoscopy procedures for providers participating in colorectal cancer screening quality improvement registry</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(d)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(d)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66BC04B7A1714EAAB86BE6D80576E85A" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HFBFEEACCEC784065AF5245AC2678311D"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Maintaining calendar year 2015 reimbursement rates for qualifying cancer screening tests furnished by qualifying providers</header> 
<clause id="H4AF545665AC84508BFA9E4849006430B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to a qualifying cancer screening test furnished during each of 2016, 2017, and 2018, by a qualifying provider, the amount of payment to such provider for such test under section 1833 or section 1848 shall be equal to the amount of payment for such test under such section 1833 or 1848 during 2015.</text> </clause> <clause id="H40521C000E7C4787A1246BCCC2243864"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualifying cancer screening test</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>qualifying cancer screening test</term> means an optical screening colonoscopy (as described in section 1861(pp)(1)(C)).</text> </clause>
<clause id="HC0A1AB45C9714730A442D21FE838BF45"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualifying provider defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>qualifying provider</term> means, with respect to a qualifying cancer screening test, an individual or entity—</text> <subclause id="H00B1F408420E4B1F85DD40CDA2D4609E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that is eligible for payment for such test under section 1833 or section 1848; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="HBD3E2582D76041B2BD4B78115F853D33"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that—</text> <item id="H3A6B5D0081094535A0DC114B96533184"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>participates in a nationally recognized quality improvement registry with respect to such test; and</text> </item>
<item id="H81F7A5EAB4CA4C1E96D418334C9110E7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, based on the information in such registry, that the tests were provided by such individual or entity in accordance with accepted outcomes-based quality measures.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> <section id="HC65AF74D3D214EF6BD36BD2DDE978DF9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Eliminating Medicare beneficiary cost-sharing for certain colorectal cancer screenings, colorectal cancer screenings with therapeutic effect, and follow-up diagnostic colorectal cancer screenings covered under Medicare</header> <subsection id="HBC5DD65916C341919120C313E244F77B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver of cost-Sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1833(a)(1)(Y) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)(Y)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including colorectal cancer screening tests covered under this part described in section 1861(pp)(1)(C) (regardless of the code that is billed for the establishment of a diagnosis as a result of the screening test, for the removal of tissue or other matter during the screening test, or for a follow-up procedure that is furnished in connection with, or as a result of, the initial screening test)</quote> after <quote>or population</quote>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H3BBB4E9214534D7FB06F22CA7C003848"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver of application of deductible</header><text>Section 1833(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H03A94E9D79AA44D6957328452F0959F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) of the first sentence, by striking <quote>individual.</quote> and inserting <quote>individual, including colorectal cancer screening tests covered under this part described in section 1861(pp)(1)(C)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD85D6E4C22934F4494FFBCD6A7A2BDAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the last sentence and inserting the following: <quote>Subsection (a)(1)(Y) and paragraph (1) of the first sentence of this subsection shall apply with respect to a colorectal cancer screening test covered under this part described in section 1861(pp)(1)(C), regardless of the code that is billed for the establishment of a diagnosis as a result of the screening test, for the removal of tissue or other matter during the screening test, or for a follow-up procedure that is furnished in connection with, or as a result of, the initial screening test.</quote></text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HDE90915AAB694362848F983F17685AEA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to tests and procedures performed on or after January 1, 2016.</text> </subsection></section>
<section commented="no" id="HD987552997A24B74AED9901AE3F95D56"><enum>5.</enum><header>Medicare demonstration project to evaluate the effectiveness of a pre-operative visit prior to screening colonoscopy and hepatitis C screening</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1115A(b)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H4BF56BE4DA3C4573B3032850F996F3E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the last sentence of subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, and shall include the model described in subparagraph (D)</quote> before the period at the end; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H26097A4993D84A6692189E6D41675D7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A0ED32673C542CCA5438EF5630D604B" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H38AFC61CB09646F49BDFD08135A209FC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Medicare demonstration project to evaluate the effectiveness of a pre-operative visit prior to screening colonoscopy and hepatitis C screening</header> <clause commented="no" id="H807CA3810A8240C3AD236DBB5179DF7F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The model described in this subparagraph is a demonstration project under title XVIII to evaluate the effectiveness of a pre-operative visit with the provider performing the procedure prior to screening colonoscopy to—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HC6BD24862412435EAC45340F66E059A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ease any patient concern or fears with respect to the procedure and answer any questions relating to the screening;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HFE9DC853E4684652806C3DC85FC38C00"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ensure quality examinations and avoid unnecessary repeat examinations by educating individuals on the importance of following pre-procedure instructions, such as bowel preparation, and addressing the individual's family history of or predisposition to colorectal cancer; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="HE885B30F8141491E8176863DE3337265"><enum>(III)</enum><text>increase Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) screening rates among Medicare beneficiaries by educating individuals about the importance of such screening during the pre-operative visit and having the pre-operative visit fulfill the referral requirement for such screening under title XVIII, allowing patients to be screened for colorectal cancer and HCV at the same time.</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="H48D856CE050D4A9EAD8243E605B70373"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with stakeholders who would be providing the pre-operative visit under the model described in this subparagraph on the implementation of such model, including payment for services furnished under the model.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" id="H91BC7EB19DA14D10AEBD921BE6A044EE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Budget neutrality</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H287D54B0203443CDB1196E1F33E3E2F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Adjustment of physician fee schedule conversion factor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall reduce the conversion factor established under subsection (d) of section 1848 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4</external-xref>) for each year (beginning with 2016) to the extent necessary to reduce expenditures under such section for items and services furnished during the year in the aggregate by the net offset amount determined under subsection (c)(5) attributable to such section for the year.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H956D63C774E04DAEA85A5FC7A050E551"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment of HOPD conversion factor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reduce the conversion factor established under paragraph (3)(C) of section 1833(t) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)</external-xref>) for each year (beginning with 2016) to the extent necessary to reduce expenditures under such section for items and services furnished during the year in the aggregate by the net offset amount determined under subsection (c)(5) attributable to such section for the year.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HF5668DEE3DB54D4F8286D9BC1AD7C0A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determinations relating to expenditures</header><text>For purposes of this section, before the beginning of each year (beginning with 2016) at the time conversion factors described in subsections (a) and (b) are established for the year, the Secretary shall determine—</text> <paragraph id="H8931D3B83E864A099D85C54487FAB56D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of the gross additional expenditures under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) estimated to result from the implementation of sections 3 and 4 for items and services furnished during the year;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD2C17981BDF4167BD2ED78BB1AB66DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any offsetting reductions in expenditures under such title (such as reductions in payments for inpatient hospital services) for such year attributable to the implementation of such sections;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEA2DF4A2B7C43A5801E3AB646067C12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the amount (if any) by which the amount of the gross additional expenditures determined under paragraph (1) for the year exceeds the amount of offsetting reductions determined under paragraph (2) for the year;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H70140A3A91C14420B765F91493095DBF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the amount of the gross additional expenditures determined under paragraph (1) for the year that are attributable to expenditures under sections 1848 and 1833(t) of such Act, the ratio of such expenditures that are attributable to each respective section; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF25EBA7DA78545928CD123D57A107259"><enum>(5)</enum><text>with respect to section 1848 and section 1833(t) of such Act, a net offset amount for the year equal to the product of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3AC38702DF4F4D9AB26C514BFA48E8BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of the net additional expenditures for the year determined under paragraph (3); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35D322C69C2D47C78B921DFDF2F30682"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ratio determined under paragraph (4) attributable to the respective section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


