<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H17A0701F161D4A45B091C470AE6B839F" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1445 IH: Land Acquisition to cut National Debt Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1445</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001070">Mr. Hardy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide that there shall be no net increase in the acres of certain Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Forest Service unless the Federal budget is balanced for the year in which the land would be purchased.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H20AAD7F2244A43B6A0588A4E2DCA2154" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2F771C4D5A00404E90F78898CFF09FD8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Land Acquisition to cut National Debt Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LAND Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6AB380C041C54B979BEF0F6D82AE0D2A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of the interior land acquisition</header> <subsection id="H4BC260DA8FA84294B159A6E80011F73C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may not use Federal funds to purchase land that would result in a net increase of land acreage that would be under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Bureau of Land Management unless the Federal budget is balanced for the year in which the land would be purchased.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H05755AA9E102481FA567ABB6D2B3A03D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duck stamp funds</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to land purchased with funds made available through the sale of Federal Migratory Bird Hunting and Conservation Stamps.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFA39302282CF4498A5242433CC5EFE6C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Easements</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to easements acquired by the Secretary of the Interior to facilitate management of Federal lands.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H35A9AD2EBD714C77961D48FACF1CC392"><enum>3.</enum><header>National forest system land acquisition</header> 
<subsection id="HE77FB875AA6C417C83E05343551F49B1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture may not use Federal funds to purchase land that would result in a net increase of land acreage included in the National Forest System unless the Federal budget is balanced for the year in which the land would be purchased.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6B73B77056344D37802438E5F29292B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Easements</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to easements acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture to facilitate management of Federal lands.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

