<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H63E725FD13394E7A9A4CC3CCB20112E0" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 428 IH: Export American Natural Gas Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 428</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150121">January 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide for the expedited approval by the Secretary of Energy of liquefied natural gas exports, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC974841B33664DE1AE5C4A151C8F6E68" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H65F148C9536C4DA0A3301AA815A8A423" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Export American Natural Gas Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBBCDC47E109C4B2885655F3D4C9A0F27"><enum>2.</enum><header>Liquified natural gas export approval</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H30DFC7E29A0342F4A925A169A3AE8317" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HC911BE6D6DA74247A471A532BAFE80B9"><enum>(g)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H4B42FFC62193480199D1397E1AA78B7A" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the Secretary shall approve or deny an application for approval of the export of liquefied natural gas, whether through an onshore or offshore terminal, not later than 60 days after the later of—</text> <subparagraph id="H00642699418F45DD9AC5E7B418B00A7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary receiving a completed application;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84FAF56B707B4C32A7C420916F123885"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applicant entering into a contract with a customer for the liquefied natural gas proposed to be exported; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H322750DCF9034896BF3F9A190797F72A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H726EE70CD4C041049B465072583613F6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the Secretary has not approved or denied an application by the deadline established under paragraph (1), the application shall be deemed to have been approved.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A5FF44E0C5B4794A6742FBCDB7C8F4D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>This subsection shall not apply to an application for export to a nation to which such export is prohibited by law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H25E221938EED4AF7AD86663BBA3F60C8"><enum>(h)</enum><text>Authorization shall be provided under subsection (a) separately from and simultaneously with authorization required from the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission or the Maritime Administration, as applicable.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HD1A4B5FFD2B042589CEEA6AC585D1663"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on global exports of natural gas production</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report on the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBC2BB0B7554C4846AEA319CD391A5123"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The economic policies of foreign countries with natural gas resources and reserves as such policies relate to the development and production of their natural gas resources and reserves and the extent and status of their natural gas resources and reserves.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E7E258F1EAA40DCAFAD0CDFA80BFEAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The potential to export the natural gas production of such foreign countries to the global market and the impact of the export of such natural gas production on the global market.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1816E43E1164C7292D48BBD1741C431"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of actions taken by the United States Government to foster natural gas exports to foreign countries that may have an interest in importing natural gas from the United States.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

