<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7572778B0DB9453F833D040120E23AAF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4297 IH: To impose certain requirements on the Secretary of the Treasury relating to transmittals of country-by-country reports for purposes of the Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Action Plan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4297</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To impose certain requirements on the Secretary of the Treasury relating to transmittals of
			 country-by-country reports for purposes of the Base Erosion and Profit
			 Shifting Action Plan.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCBAD7984252345A8BDD8402EBEF5EB61" style="OLC">
		<section id="H038C88FAACAF4A1B8D8317B025D8C93E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Required measures relating to transmittals of country-by-country reports and master file
			 information</header>
 <subsection id="H41990F6C3A93492A808DEDB07A965AC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Secretary is expressly prohibited from collecting from a United States person or transmitting to any foreign jurisdiction any country-by-country report information of any United States person with respect to taxable years beginning before January 1, 2017.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H63F4C47B878542F390A301F5517108DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Suspension of transmittal of CbCRs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall suspend the transmittal of country-by-country report information of any United States person to a foreign jurisdiction if the Secretary determines that the foreign jurisdiction is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H819D15BC53A6485299F9197F16001CA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">abusing master file documentation requirements; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H14ED430067A742499D2415CC43D36411"><enum>(2)</enum><text>failing to safeguard the confidentiality of information required in the master file.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA607BF76C76E43729498CDFA47979F8D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Factors in determining abuse of master file documentation requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a foreign jurisdiction is abusing master file documentation requirements if, in connection with the administration of the transfer pricing documentation standards set forth in Action 13 of the Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Action plan, the foreign jurisdiction is seeking—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB7686F0BD7D74E0781FACBD389580BC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any trade, business, industrial, commercial or professional secret or trade process;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F786C499A16484490164CEBFB3B1791"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">group consolidated financial statements that are not filed with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41F3C1ECDEC945438665A9BA05D3BC17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>confidential communications between a client and an attorney, solicitor or other admitted legal representative where such communications are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAEDB84E4326E4B7E990E330598C0376E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>produced for the purposes of seeking or providing legal advice, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12F7109AF2A34BF9B1024D2C6DB95731"><enum>(B)</enum><text>produced for the purposes of use in existing or contemplated legal proceedings;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF9674A472E6424ABE4C4B882EF04D78"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information if the disclosure would be contrary to United States public policy (ordre public); or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA584F5D62A894DA69FF6D0425A31FCDB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information the Secretary otherwise determines to be inappropriate for purposes of this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H237FA68796A840A59344073FE11295F7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 31 of each calendar year, the Secretary shall furnish to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and the Joint Committee on Taxation a report on allegations or reports received concerning abuse of master file requirements, and any actions taken with respect to such allegations, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4F8A1BDF7D994341AA31DA815D83CD1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the instances in the preceding calendar year the Secretary determined under subsection (b) the abuse of master file documentation requirements and failures to safeguard the confidentiality of information required in the master file, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36102B94B923414C82C301E38058D289"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nature of each such abuse or failure.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA95C2F5C3C24A03B06A43DE2AD3601F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3EAFBF2D17804B97A7FB75A80039420A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Base erosion and profit shifting plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Action Plan</term>, known as <term>BEPS</term>, means the plan released by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD1FB85FFB3842D4ABE077FC8E4A57B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Country-by-country report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>country-by-country report</term>, known as <quote>CbCR</quote>, means a report contemplated under Action Item 13 of the Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Action Plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H129129D415FE47FF9A4AD25C83B8A788"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Master file</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>master file</term> means the documentation contemplated under Action Item 13 of the Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Action Plan and necessary to provide a high-level overview in order to place a United States person’s transfer pricing practices in their global economic, legal, financial, and tax context, in order to provide backdrop to country-by-country report data reported.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE16A14889FE240E5AA3B07CE7AE416DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury, or the Secretary’s delegate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

