<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCECBEBDB86814C9F887078EAD2C0A2B9" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2888 IH: Internet Poker Freedom Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2888</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000213">Mr. Barton</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a program for the licensing of Internet poker by States and federally recognized Indian tribes, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HDE9CD9FC6BB140E9BC2B3BBEB5540BA3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE2AF43A4811E4632868F9F2E934F170B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HEF41EECFF1AF41B5810AFEB2FB73D6CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Internet Poker Freedom Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H88DC66B350E048CFAE35E10642BDF47F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="HE2AF43A4811E4632868F9F2E934F170B" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H6AB30EFE759A4765A3E97B18DC12D657" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8E911C8497D34483B92658C468511723" level="title">Title I—Prohibition on Unlicensed Internet Poker and Protections for Internet Poker Consumers </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7BC3D30744084F2391FB7A6CE204B945" level="section">Sec. 101. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB0FCF622DBEF4A539CC360FEFCE89263" level="section">Sec. 102. Prohibition on unlicensed Internet poker.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD7B855C5CA1D4935B171C810BE51CD39" level="section">Sec. 103. Department of Commerce qualification and oversight of Qualified Regulatory Authorities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H202828B3E22A48E594D36DACB478BB62" level="section">Sec. 104. Licensing by Qualified Regulatory Authorities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5D1823F6D9CC44578037CE733631BA21" level="section">Sec. 105. Enforcement.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2B712EF4B2FD445FB2AE51EA8834CD85" level="section">Sec. 106. Compulsive gaming, responsible gaming, and self-exclusion program requirements.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3AA3B595150A4139AF0CE718C5809E7A" level="section">Sec. 107. Prohibitions and restrictions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD201779565444A9D84159FBA456AAAE8" level="section">Sec. 108. Safe harbor.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H39D5B08ED79C4423AB373B19C3B59107" level="section">Sec. 109. Relation to subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H036C50F48DC148CBADA4ED2A41D27B80" level="section">Sec. 110. Cheating and other fraud.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H717A9847F526453D8A1CFE8B4854F5C1" level="section">Sec. 111. Construction and relation to other law.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4FD161F2B9EC44D0A9BAAFB0B7B9607C" level="section">Sec. 112. Regulations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2BF3A033CF5A4A6284082D30E9240473" level="section">Sec. 113. Annual reports.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF7AF8632B8A742E1B7B92E58BCA46C3A" level="section">Sec. 114. Effective date.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H068223C4D20C46A79E70FC2423899EC9" level="title">Title II—Strengthening of Unlawful Internet Gambling Enforcement Act of 2006</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB3BAD5177FEE4E319DEF4A708B767720" level="section">Sec. 201. Financial transaction providers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDC36B361D90A459AB69B4EB962B7B7BF" level="section">Sec. 202. List of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H39F6D8806F4746C098347644E4ECD2F0" level="section">Sec. 203. Regulations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB5D0A0B1515842C7A3C93B1D813415FB" level="section">Sec. 204. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6AB30EFE759A4765A3E97B18DC12D657"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HCA51FB3E8DC546B0ADB081DC3DF4DC9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since the development of the Internet, online Web sites offering Internet poker have raised numerous policy, consumer protection, and enforcement concerns for Federal, State, and tribal governments as such Web sites are run by operators located in many different countries and have sought to attract customers from the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F9A4BB2C56A4B7680768239D505F058"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Unlawful Internet Gambling Enforcement Act of 2006 (title VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/347">Public Law 109–347</external-xref>; 120 Stat. 1952) was intended to aid enforcement efforts against unlawful Internet operators and to limit unlawful Internet gaming involving United States persons. However, that Act has only been partially successful in doing so.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EB6826C53D34C2F82F064FBD392AA58"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Justice has found that it is legal for States to license Internet poker and other forms of non-sports Internet gaming within their borders, and to compact with each other for interstate play. In response to this finding, three States have enacted legislation to license commercial operators to provide Internet poker or other Internet gaming services, and several other states are providing lottery services over the Internet.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H886B160900C6417F8A67783415C99B92"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Additional tools to assist law enforcement in the prevention of unlawful Internet gaming activities would be important and beneficial. Maintenance of a list of unlicensed Internet poker enterprises and the owners, operators, and key personnel of such enterprises (as well as entities and related personnel found unsuitable) would aid those law enforcement efforts and would make the Unlawful Internet Gambling Enforcement Act more effective.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0033DCC16DA348929288DD15D4DA7D8D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Poker is distinct from the class of games of chance traditionally defined as gambling in that players compete against each other, and not the person or entity hosting the game (sometimes called <term>the house</term>), and that over any significant interval the outcome of a poker game is predominantly determined by the skill of the participants.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H912CB5E751514DF18789382CBA22F5D9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States consumers would benefit from a program of Internet poker regulation which recognizes the interstate nature of the Internet, but nevertheless preserves the prerogatives of States and federally recognized Indian tribes. Such a system would require strict licensing of Internet poker providers and would require licensee operators to—</text> <subparagraph id="H44259DA307504A9FB3E44AD988F52835"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have effective means to prevent minors from playing poker on-line;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B5EBEA7B38F4639AC76400482DCA9EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify and help treat problem gamblers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E8444E1D7D44BF9AD71EBD712F3FAD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent minors and players in non-participating States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H26C7FF770A0D4EDC80CE384E2207460A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allow players to self-exclude and limit losses; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD04841C799774DD4832F2F142C4E6404"><enum>(E)</enum><text>prevent money laundering.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6CF3C94CD714F5C857FAC614E6D70D0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Such a program would create a new industry within the United States creating thousands of jobs and substantial revenue for Federal, State, and tribal governments.</text></paragraph></section> <title id="H8E911C8497D34483B92658C468511723"><enum>I</enum><header>Prohibition on Unlicensed Internet Poker and Protections for Internet Poker Consumers </header> <section commented="no" id="H7BC3D30744084F2391FB7A6CE204B945"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this title, the following definitions apply:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H617933FFB7D742168B5830B20898F138"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <term>applicant</term> means any person who has applied for a license pursuant to this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27EEC7DFD0EA4533919EAD3C3E66ABEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bet or wager</header> <subparagraph id="HACC48AEB652846AF98DC55BA11CB79E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>bet or wager</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5362 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC1CA2021EF046E99AF03F28A35B735E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>bet or wager</term> does not include the following:</text> <clause id="H9A79E8727CEA465A8BC3721775A5E462"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Interstate horseracing</header><text>A bet or wager that is permissible under the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3001">15 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H52C515EA62324C3CA3AE4AB91E916759"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain intrastate transactions</header><text>Placing, receiving, or otherwise transmitting a bet or wager—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H49B638DF856F40D2BF87750769193036"><enum>(I)</enum><text>as described in subparagraph (B) of section 5362(10) of title 31, United States Code, and clarified by subparagraph (E) of such section; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HD492BAB9A57E4D5E91C0C22B6F3BF487"><enum>(II)</enum><text>authorized under a license that was issued by a regulatory body of a State or federally recognized Indian tribe on or before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H8C3C0DF48BC146BDB2E5B12FE227760C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Intrastate lottery transactions</header><text>A bet or wager that is—</text> 
<subclause id="H4A3FEC066F1E43158A5531D2011CF5CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a chance or opportunity to win a lottery or other prize (which opportunity to win is predominantly subject to chance) authorized by a State or federally recognized Indian tribe; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1290614E42B24B50A19454D94EEDE553"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a placing, receiving, or transmitting of a bet or wager as described in such subparagraph (B) and clarified by subparagraph (E) of such section 5362(10).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H62AD2BB747BB48A6B97B49738B95E872"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Intratribal transactions</header><text>Placing, receiving, or otherwise transmitting a bet or wager as described in subparagraph (C) of such section 5362(10), as clarified by such subparagraph (E).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H067B70F361D6418A87923DAF5F029E56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Casino gaming</header> <subparagraph id="H3E9C850CFCE34B00878BB23B0C450F7D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>casino gaming</term> means the full range of casino gaming activity licensed by regulatory bodies of States or federally recognized Indian tribes that would be qualified as class III gaming under section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2703">25 U.S.C. 2703</external-xref>), if that Act were applicable to the gaming.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59986EA4D01E4CA0A4E8973191BC7654"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>casino gaming</term> does not include lotteries of States or federally recognized Indian tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56E02239E7FA481FB48502A4D4F10E3C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Casino gaming facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>casino gaming facility</term> means a facility that provides casino gaming on a riverboat, at a race track, or in another facility that hosts gaming devices in one physical location pursuant to a duly authorized license issued by a gaming regulatory authority of a State or Indian tribe and has not fewer than 500 slot machines.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB4641792C8C42A2932C910417A67B81"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the National Indian Gaming Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77FDB828A9AB4481B7D400C59FE51104"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Gaming device</header> <subparagraph id="HB7B78B36818F4F2E965A54CDEA4E167F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>gaming device</term> means any computer-based gambling machine, including slot machines and video lottery terminals that have been approved by a gaming regulatory authority of a State or federally recognized Indian tribe.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9394F898EE584995AEA396774E35E98F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gaming device</term> does not include—</text> <clause id="H34C3BAB9088B4C33B7EF1342D96E6B0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>machines that process bets or wagers for parimutuel betting pools or class II gaming devices qualified under section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2703">25 U.S.C. 2703</external-xref>); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1314FEBD8EA3478EBC15193AF5D10799"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a personal computer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3648301FB87149DF9FD8A46AB4AF7CF3"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Independent testing laboratory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>independent testing laboratory</term> means a testing laboratory that is accredited by an international accreditation body approved by the Secretary and is not owned or controlled by an Internet gaming facility, an electronic gambling equipment vendor, manufacturer, or retailer, or an Internet gambling operator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BB86E6CC3D0424C8A4740E2CA033E0F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Indian lands and federally recognized Indian tribe</header><text>The terms <term>Indian lands</term> and <term>federally recognized Indian tribe</term> have the meanings given the terms <term>Indian lands</term> and <term>Indian tribes</term>, respectively, in section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2703">25 U.S.C. 2703</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D21BA099EF94457BEE2B1451DB09C84"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Internet</header><text>The term <term>Internet</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5362 of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BCDB36DBC9149F2A795698370B781F5"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Internet poker</header><text>The term <term>Internet poker</term> means a poker game, hand, tournament, or other contest of poker offered through the use of an Internet poker facility.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A5F25185FCE44C280EBD963C8877257"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Internet poker facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Internet poker facility</term> means an Internet Web site, or similar communications facility in which transmissions may cross State boundaries, through which a bet or wager is initiated, received, or otherwise made, solely with respect to a game, hand, tournament, or other contest of poker, whether transmitted by telephone, Internet, satellite, or other wire or wireless communication facility, service, or medium.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1100422C3C0244E3A8CA03C7C29C43B9"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Licensee</header><text>The term <term>licensee</term> means a person who operates an Internet poker facility under a license issued by a qualified regulatory authority pursuant to this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA30827ACCC25451A872C24D90943DC1B"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Operate an Internet poker facility</header><text>The term <term>operate an Internet poker facility</term> means to conduct, direct, manage, own, supervise, or control an Internet poker facility.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H8A13DA35EB764B829B53C5C7A4A71603"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Poker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>poker</term> means any of several card games commonly known as poker in which players compete against each other, and not against any person, entity, or fellow player hosting the game (sometimes called <term>the house</term>), the outcome of which, over any significant interval, is predominantly determined by the skill of the players.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9F4E0D76C2F54C679C8D9599303F3981"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Qualified regulatory authority</header><text>The term <term>qualified regulatory authority</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H18D68605C9C64CD09D4E562040AEBA32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State agency or regulatory body that has been designated as a qualified regulatory authority under section 103(c);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA5C84D77029145739D55296612CD59DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the designated regulatory authority of a federally recognized Indian tribe authorized to game under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act and designated as a qualified regulatory authority under section 103(c); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEE765D95C4844CA882FE009FAFAFCF62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Office of Internet Poker Oversight established under section 103(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABE44287362E4EC5A75AE920EAA680C1"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Qualified card room</header><text>The term <term>qualified card room</term> means a facility that has been licensed by a State or federally recognized Indian tribe to provide at least 175 tables in one physical facility for bets or wagers on poker.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54224EEEDE384E1FA7579087120DD56B"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Remote gaming equipment</header> 
<subparagraph id="H16F2FCB671E146BA9D51CE121987BE95"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>remote gaming equipment</term> means electronic or other equipment principally used by or on behalf of an operator of an Internet poker facility, including by any significant vendor to such operator, to—</text> <clause id="HD05200BB6EA041C29AF255C80FFC39CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>register a person’s participation in Internet poker and to store information relating thereto;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2AA9E21A68384EC08E568D7CEFF838D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>present to persons who are participating or who may participate in Internet poker the game that is to be played;</text></clause> <clause id="HFD15130BC41F43AAA6E6C17008C7D8B1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>determine all or part of, or the effect of, a result relevant to a game, hand, tournament, or other contest of Internet poker and to store information relating thereto;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H466D689080AA43B7A212807A15E3CD14"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>accept payment with respect to Internet poker from the player; or</text></clause> <clause id="H1226C83BCCC1435B88754938B0276330"><enum>(v)</enum><text>authorize payment of any winnings in respect of Internet poker.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3DBAAD16E674E518A24FBA086413F27"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>remote gaming equipment</term> does not include the following:</text> <clause id="H6C47AB67A879429A9E283B4332B362CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Equipment used for business continuity, back-up, excess capacity, or other secondary use.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H59C53FA841D346159072717E71F540D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A computer which is used by a person to participate in Internet poker unless the computer is provided by or on behalf of the person who is conducting or providing the facilities for the game.</text></clause> <clause id="H2166F62BB31F4AB3B0F7E17B9D6B893B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Equipment operated in the ordinary course of providing banking, telecommunications, or payment processing services.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD21DC657A94D4430982380874D190053"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Such other equipment that provides ancillary services as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60FF59761D0E4307B854DF58F4C7F618"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70CB65057FC9404D9AA56DB66CADCFB4"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Significant vendor</header><text>The term <term>significant vendor</term> means a person who—</text> <subparagraph id="HD18FA33587F5490FAB299E3C98458679"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on behalf of a licensee, knowingly manages, administers, or controls bets or wagers that are initiated, received, or otherwise made within the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F9C05C30EF048C18971FF2B9E4BE70E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on behalf of a licensee, knowingly manages, administers, or controls the games with which such bets or wagers are associated;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB4FF19999A74696A8245D0E007EDC1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on behalf of a licensee, develops, maintains, or operates the software or other system programs or hardware on which the games or the bets or wagers are managed, administered, or controlled;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0A0B5590235D4308823DEE3A82705030"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides the trademarks, trade names, service marks, or similar intellectual property under which a licensee identifies its Internet poker facility to its customers in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84E6053B0E124514B0E221746FFC4312"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sells, licenses, or otherwise receives compensation for selling or licensing information via a database or customer list on individuals in the United States selected in whole or in part because they made bets or wagers with an Internet poker facility not licensed either pursuant to this title or by a State or federally recognized Indian tribe as permitted under this title;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71CD97CFC2994AF986FF2BAD581878D8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provides any products, services, or assets to a licensee and is paid a percentage of gaming revenue or Internet poker commission fees by the licensee (not including fees to financial institutions and payment providers for facilitating a deposit by a customer); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5BBECA410E14DA2B766F22041E4C12B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>with respect to an applicant, proposes to provide any of the activities, services, or items identified in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA16217EF97224176AA5DE1371C19EDA4"><enum>(20)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0FCF622DBEF4A539CC360FEFCE89263" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum><header>Prohibition on unlicensed Internet poker</header> <subsection id="H3638715EE2FB4E42B7924CB42F3AE858"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE96581B8D3D8464B936BEA1E712D8BDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for a person to operate an Internet poker facility without a license in good standing issued to such person by a qualified regulatory authority under this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0DF3732A0392429DA408C1D9E20C0D10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the operation of an Internet poker facility by a person located outside the United States in which bets or wagers are initiated, received, or otherwise made by individuals located outside the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6EF4EE2F6E74414B750605ABFEE23EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header><text>Any person who violates this section shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD7B855C5CA1D4935B171C810BE51CD39"><enum>103.</enum><header>Department of Commerce qualification and oversight of Qualified Regulatory Authorities</header> 
<subsection id="HDF8D4ED00F0C454EB3A48BEE5B327561"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Commerce responsibilities and powers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in the case of a State, and the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, shall have responsibility and authority for the following activities:</text> <paragraph id="HEDD203EED9D2486C9CA4B121A3D8FD36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Reviewing and qualifying regulatory authorities to issue licenses under this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H679509901722474D8A7AD152E3BB487A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Exercising oversight over qualified regulatory authorities to ensure that such authorities—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA80A0DF658ED49AEA02AE0BD7C6DDB14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comply with the requirements of this title; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7430C0514CE74AFBBFED1F5464881AF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out their regulatory and enforcement functions under this title with appropriate diligence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72E88E9689CF45BD8FB3501FBAA256D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Investigating and taking appropriate remedial action with respect to any qualified regulatory authority.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D6C29A29A0E47E5884354BBFECD373C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Prescribing such regulations as may be necessary to administer and enforce the provisions of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28FA3CB153694DDFB8D77758EA6916D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Internet Poker Oversight</header> <paragraph id="H27416663485D45BCAE88F53625FF6E0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an office in the Department of Commerce to be known as the <term>Office of Internet Poker Oversight</term> (in this subsection referred to as the <term>office</term>) to exercise the functions of the Secretary set out in this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3AAD0EDC507E40E99AA57303B97841E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director and delegation of authority</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint a Director of the office from among individuals who have demonstrated experience and expertise in regulating gaming activities and may delegate to the Director any authority, duty, or responsibility conferred upon the Secretary by this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4864138C7002412E8283A1A5BA8DDD40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation of qualified regulatory authorities</header> <paragraph id="HF3BF9EF161614E5FA5B3F73C15AE1C68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualification of regulatory authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, shall qualify any regulatory authority that is designated to the Secretary or the Commission by a State or federally recognized Indian tribe, respectively, that wishes to participate in the licensing program to carry out the licensing and other functions under this title if the Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, determines that such regulatory authority meets the minimum standards for qualification prescribed under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90CC86FF6C6F4235B99B14962603603C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum standards for qualified regulatory authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall prescribe minimum standards for qualifying a qualified regulatory authority under this subsection, including minimum standards—</text> <subparagraph id="HB7161B5505E240F4ABBEDF7EA031DA17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relating to the size and qualification of staff of the regulatory authority to ensure a sufficient number of enforcement agents with experience in gaming regulatory enforcement areas to discharge its intended functions and that the applicant have the sophistication and resources necessary to evaluate issues unique to the Internet environment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7536B79A4B04C95B5CA42FA04851D78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relating to the length of time the applicant has regulated other forms of gaming to ensure designations of only those applicants that have a history of demonstrated regulatory enforcement and oversight commensurate with the responsibilities imposed under this title;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FDA39C2573642098E429CE8D0B3CAF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for assessing the applicant’s experience and willingness to work with Federal authorities, including the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A3E1149AF3A4DEE9AB62E63205AF4F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prohibiting conflicts of interest to ensure that qualified regulatory authorities are not controlled, directly or indirectly, by persons that have any significant ownership interest in entities regulated under this title;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B9DD172A0FF4CE39F3AB9521BEF8E70"><enum>(E)</enum><text>for the capacity and experience of a qualified regulatory authority in conducting rigorous suitability reviews;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1018007445A469787D11DD584C30FF3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>for the enforcement and regulatory authorities provided to the applicant under the law of the applicable State or federally recognized Indian tribe, including investigative authority, authority to impose requirements on licensees, and authority to impose civil or other penalties; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC05BD0F841C240C1901B5AD0DD014D0F"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary, in consultation with the Commission considers relevant to the ability of a regulatory authority to serve as an effective qualified regulatory authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17DAC0B62E494137A6B6A471E364AD77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Withdrawal of qualification</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC9F6AAD0C28F47A19CBC7EE8D0FB07D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date on which the Secretary prescribes final regulations under this title, the Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, may, after providing 60 days notice to a qualified regulatory authority, withdraw the qualification of such regulatory authority under this section if the Secretary or Commission, respectively, determines that the regulatory authority is not in compliance with the minimum standards established under paragraph (2) or other requirements of this title.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E2919FB216148B396CE8EBE6F0E3B5D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Opportunity to comply</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, may provide a qualified regulatory authority who receives notice under subparagraph (A) with an opportunity to come into compliance for a period of not more than 180 days. The Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, may extend such period by not more than 180 additional days if the qualified regulatory authority has made substantial progress toward compliance as of the expiration of the first 180-day period.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H971E1E0E105A4C729F4AECFFE0ACCC7F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified regulatory authority that receives notice under subparagraph (A) may not issue any new licenses under this title until the Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, determines that the qualified regulatory authority is in compliance with the requirements of this title and regulations prescribed thereunder.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93499ED4907E44A997975529A9E45D58"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Right to appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified regulatory authority that has had its qualification withdrawn under this paragraph may appeal to the United States District Court for the District of Columbia that such withdrawal was an abuse of discretion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA094D5D8F185496BAA5EA5E456027200"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Action upon withdrawal of qualification</header> 
<subparagraph id="H636C2F36BF904EA5B38256E2B8239802"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, withdraws the qualification of a qualified regulatory authority under paragraph (3), each person with a license issued by the qualified regulatory authority shall—</text> <clause id="H67B447C6642E45068392454698846E74"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9229C3D64A7E45F6A48CFDC43A46F930"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cease offering, accepting, and providing services with respect to bets or wagers from persons located in the United States under such license; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB1001F08B30B4AFCAC1E72C033756D7B" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>return all customer deposits or place those sums the return of which to United States customers is not feasible due to change in customer address, bank details, or similar difficulty, in escrow in an account with a financial institution in the United States for safekeeping and orderly disposition by the Secretary; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9F0404A67EFC48E7B371D3D6AADCB29B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>apply for a new license from a different qualified regulatory authority.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEB6208B8DC184E988CCD1AE78BE7AAD1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interim operation</header><text>If a person applies for a new license under clause (ii) of subparagraph (A), the person need not cease offering, accepting, and providing services in accordance with clause (i)(I) of such subparagraph until final action is taken on the license application by the qualified regulatory authority.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H863BC9EF75CA41348BBF893C009B3636"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interim regulatory oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Until final action is taken under subparagraph (B) with respect to a person, the Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, shall have enforcement and regulatory authority over the licensed activities of such person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7E0F5455836418D94394C4F601654D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Oversight of qualified regulatory authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in the case of a State, or the Commission, in the case of a federally recognized Indian tribe, may investigate and take such action as the Secretary or Commission, as applicable, considers appropriate with respect to any qualified regulatory authority that appears, based upon the Secretary’s or Commission’s own inquiry or based upon credible information provided by other persons, including licensees or law enforcement officials, to be deficient or substantially less rigorous than other qualified regulatory authorities in the discharge of its responsibilities under this title.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H43F151389F8B4C30A6E2262BC1B5A065"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation with federally recognized Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing this title, the Secretary and the Commission shall conduct meaningful consultation with federally recognized Indian tribes regarding all aspects of this title which affect federally recognized Indian tribes.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H202828B3E22A48E594D36DACB478BB62"><enum>104.</enum><header>Licensing by Qualified Regulatory Authorities</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HFC7EB1DF7FB84923BDC245D3BF40CFF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Internet poker facility licensing program</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE3BC59AA8BFD42F984F3E194D69D82A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority to operate Internet poker facility under valid license</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to the provisions of this title, a licensee may accept a bet or wager with respect to Internet poker from an individual located in the United States and may offer related services so long as the license of the licensee issued under this title remains in good standing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H829634C7A16E423BBBE0267226419339"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Significant vendors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person seeks a certificate of suitability from a qualified regulatory authority to provide services to a licensee or applicant as a significant vendor with respect to an Internet poker facility, such person shall not be required to obtain a license under this title to provide such services with respect to that Internet poker facility.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H61E84867E24D49D18ECC1241B332C37F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibitions imposed by States or federally recognized Indian tribes</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H67CEC4DFD58F4C5D8947C95170FAF9C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Action by a State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No licensee may engage, under any license issued under this title, in the operation of an Internet poker facility that knowingly accepts bets or wagers initiated by persons who reside in any State which provides notice that it will prohibit such bets or wagers, if the Governor or other chief executive officer of such State informs the Secretary of such prohibition in a letter that identifies the nature and extent of such prohibition.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9A536D5544D947E88637483FFBDA9B46"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Changes to State prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment, repeal, or amendment by a State of any prohibition described in subparagraph (A) shall apply, for purposes of this title, beginning on the day that occurs after the end of the 60-day period beginning on the later of—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H8A9A992C6D62487DAB6FC669B519B725"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date a notice of such establishment, repeal, or amendment is provided by the Governor or other chief executive officer of such State in writing to the Secretary; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H1F2A3FE86B4446C19238C478BCA6DB69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effective date of such establishment, repeal, or amendment.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H462F78E4F64F454AB0E3983821671A0C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application of State action to tribal lands of federally recognized Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any State prohibition described in subparagraph (A) shall not apply to the acceptance by a licensee of bets or wagers from persons located within the tribal lands of a federally recognized Indian tribe that—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H9E54E5035DDE4062B3EE7C7FB4DAB901"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has itself not opted out pursuant to subsection (b); or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H7FADA3D631CC4597B8E15A3ABCCB726F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>would be entitled pursuant to other applicable law to permit such bets or wagers to be initiated and received within its territory without use of the Internet.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2836436FD68D4687AC1825764DB228B5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Actions by a federally recognized Indian tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Internet poker licensee knowingly may accept a bet or wager from a person located in the tribal lands of any federally recognized Indian tribe which prohibits such activities or other contests if the principal chief or other chief executive officer of such federally recognized Indian tribe informs the Secretary of such prohibition in a letter that identifies the nature and extent of such prohibition.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H94813074B787439FA9D531FBDC499DE6"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Changes to State and federally recognized Indian tribe prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment, repeal, or amendment by any federally recognized Indian tribe of any prohibition referred to in subparagraph (D) shall apply, for purposes of this title, beginning on the day that occurs after the end of the 60-day period beginning on the later of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE0C982ED4432450EA54DEDA313BF6990"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date a notice of such establishment, repeal, or amendment is provided by the principal chief or other chief executive officer of such federally recognized Indian tribe in writing to the Secretary; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H12ED1478D6A148148FADF6980CF9ED93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effective date of such establishment, repeal, or amendment.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H32F43950F45D47D8957CAA8E4E2C980B"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Notification and Enforcement of State and Tribe prohibitions</header> <clause commented="no" id="H7B2768AD7C6C497A90C73331B9C15E92"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notification and measures to ensure compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall notify all licensees and applicants of all States and federally recognized Indian tribes that have provided notice pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (D), as the case may be, promptly upon receipt of such notice and in no event fewer than 30 days before the effective date of such notice. The Secretary shall take effective measures to ensure that any licensee under this subchapter, as a condition of the license, complies with any limitation or prohibition imposed by any State or federally recognized Indian tribe to which the licensee is subject.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H58282B3A49264F27AFE938F2503FA613"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subparagraph (A) or (D) shall be a violation of this title enforceable under section 105.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF72F17CFA4B744D191D3937B5C897467"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application for license</header> <paragraph id="H88D70254B9FF488991A0B7C7BC22C8F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person seeking to operate an Internet poker facility under this title shall submit to the qualified regulatory authority of the State or federally recognized Indian tribe where servers for such Internet poker facility are located or will be located an application for a license at such time, in such form, and in such manner as the qualified regulatory authority considers appropriate, including at a minimum the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H81485C168F8A4BAE95B42622101DBB2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Complete financial information about the applicant.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE8603C2F1D640FC905D28194D01C9FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Documentation showing the organization of the applicant and all related businesses and affiliates.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27982D125A4A4120A26BC17FAD2FEF4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The criminal and financial history of—</text> <clause id="H24065185AF74414D99D7D3CFF5FE8859"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicant;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H01354A24D33444FBBB1A2497CD922464"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each of the senior executives and directors of the applicant;</text></clause> <clause id="H42EEDA92E71D49EF8B65A758827779CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other person who is in control of the applicant; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8B57C5F867F843DCAE566BD13DA5AA90"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such other persons as the qualified regulatory authority considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD68C606FB7DB400299B2DD2432945CCE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such other information as may be necessary for the suitability analysis required under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9157213E09A84110A275D74632740B15"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Disclosure of all other applications for licenses previously or simultaneously submitted under this paragraph to other qualified regulatory authorities and whether those applications are pending, were granted, or were denied.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E76AC775D344F4399DF23EE2A245445"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A detailed description of the applicant's plan for complying with all applicable requirements and regulations prescribed pursuant to this title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H101BC9164534454CB1B7AEDD1B61F3C4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A certification by the applicant that the applicant agrees to be subject to—</text> <clause id="H13D8AC845FE64F21B5E85A9F816F8321"><enum>(i)</enum><text>jurisdiction in Federal courts and in the courts of the State or federally recognized Indian tribe of the qualified regulatory authority to which the applicant has applied; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEDFDFAE6204147F9BA0A5E7AF97E82C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all applicable provisions of Federal law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF135503CC8F345DDB70C622D16561294"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to the Secretary</header><text>Each qualified regulatory authority shall report all applicants for licensure and the dispositions of their applications to the Secretary promptly upon disposition of each application or in such intervals as the Secretary may prescribe. Such report shall include such information or documentation as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF83EAA475C074441B099843422FEC912"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standards for license issuance; suitability qualifications and disqualification standards</header> 
<paragraph id="HB10777B7016A4AAA8249F4E79B40AE63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Suitability for licensing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No applicant shall be eligible to obtain a license under this title unless a qualified regulatory authority, with whom the applicant has filed an application for a license, has determined, upon completion of a background check and investigation, that the applicant, any person deemed to be in control of the applicant, all significant vendors of the applicant, and any other person determined by the qualified regulatory authority as having significant influence on the applicant are suitable for licensing or for receiving a certificate of suitability as applicable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7C90570CE5B43BD9736857C19335E0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigation</header> <subparagraph id="H0C6262778FBD4C3CB2F66484B5746877"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination of suitability</header><text>Prior to issuing a license under this section, a qualified regulatory authority shall conduct the investigation and analysis described in paragraph (1) to determine whether the applicant or person—</text> 
<clause id="H3B43C109CF914BA8BD6229ACB0F65AFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a person of good character, honesty, and integrity;</text></clause> <clause id="HC5B72A1CDBF94A138ED94B10CBC79270"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a person whose prior activities, criminal record, if any, reputation, habits, and associations do not—</text> 
<subclause id="H9A034574737443B381809279D5C3C16C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>pose a threat to the public interest or to the effective regulation and control of Internet poker facilities; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAD6DF78E6A134B56A89E8E94274CC0CF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>create or enhance the dangers of unsuitable, unfair, or illegal practices, methods, and activities in the conduct of Internet poker facilities or the carrying on of the business and financial arrangements incidental to such facilities;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HD059D7007CF64A989F93DAA0FFD1161E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is capable of and likely to conduct the activities for which the applicant is licensed or receives a certificate of suitability in accordance with the provisions of this title, any regulations prescribed under this title, and all other applicable laws;</text></clause> <clause id="H1662C91070E44FDBBF7AF36028D49CE1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with respect to applicants, has or guarantees acquisition of adequate business competence and experience in the operation of casino gaming facilities or Internet poker facilities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC06AD02C31374CF2AB932F2135D73A57"><enum>(v)</enum><text>with respect to applicants, has or will obtain sufficient financing for the nature of the proposed operation and from a source that the qualified regulatory authority has not found unsuitable under the criteria established under subparagraph (B); and</text></clause> <clause id="H56329728373E4BBB8AA1BC958B0AB050"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>has disclosed to the qualified regulatory authority all known affiliations or relationships, whether direct or indirect.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B73549016334179BE83FE790DBA5884"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unsuitable</header><text>An applicant or any other person may not be determined to be suitable under this subsection if the applicant or such person—</text> <clause id="H69C8EB38D2CD48A08478C290C1E21A33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has failed to provide information and documentation material to a determination of suitability for licensing under paragraph (1);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H63FE0463D05A4BF7BB8BFA14DAE3E265"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has supplied information which is untrue or misleading as to a material fact pertaining to any such determination;</text></clause> <clause id="H61A0CCE4FE12490AAB4F8064555F8E96"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has been convicted of an offense that is punishable by imprisonment of more than 1 year;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD33A8A725A964ACE8A53716FC87F6C09"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is delinquent in the payment of any applicable Federal or State tax, tax penalty, addition to tax, or interest owed to a jurisdiction in which the applicant or person operates or does business, unless such payment has been extended or is the subject of a pending judicial or administrative dispute;</text></clause> <clause id="H17DF2FBB84794CDD8EBB0634D6CA147B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>has not certified in writing that the person submits to personal jurisdiction in the United States; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8BD6BA7A546F48C9AF3CB2A6501ADD22"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>fails to comply with such other standard as the applicable qualified regulatory authority considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCCD89ECD1C3C4B8AA0B52607472F2E21"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Ineligibility due to prior engagement in unlawful Internet poker</header> <clause commented="no" id="HF46E00F3B3ED4D038F406E4E561DCAC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No applicant nor any other person may be eligible for a license or certificate of suitability under this section if such applicant or person has been convicted of accepting bets or wagers from any other person through an Internet poker facility in felony violation of Federal or State law. The ineligibility of an applicant or other person under this subparagraph shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the first license is issued under this section.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H709D3DEABECF4350A1E7B0D15A638D02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No applicant or person who has purchased the assets of a person described in clause (i) subsequent to the enactment of this Act shall be eligible for a license or certificate of suitability under this section until the date that is 5 years after the date on which the first license is issued.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4792BA709894BB28D898A04BA9AA807"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ongoing requirement</header><text>A licensee (and any other person who is required to be determined to be suitable for licensing in connection with such licensee) shall meet the standards necessary to be suitable for licensing or to receive a certificate of suitability, as the case may be, throughout the term of the license.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H108999CFAB274B37816947D44D596898"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certificate of suitability for significant vendors</header> 
<subparagraph id="H96D68EA749724B8981AE4CB021D95D03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a qualifying body determines under paragraph (1) that a significant vendor of an applicant is suitable under such paragraph, the qualifying body shall issue a certificate to such vendor that certifies the suitability of such vendor.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38B1FBC259B0453B9388C679DD6E86CF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revocation of certificate</header><text>A qualified regulatory authority that issues a certificate to a significant vendor under subparagraph (A) shall revoke the certificate if at any time the significant vendor no longer meets the standards necessary for a determination of suitability.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25E472A2FA3C487FA0A70B1A3D60BC83"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Certificates issued by other qualified regulatory authority</header><text>A qualified regulatory authority may, but need not, accept a certificate issued to a significant vendor by another qualified regulatory authority as evidence of the suitability of the significant vendor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01A8C153B462426FB932B2FAEA9BC5B2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Other vendors</header> <subparagraph id="H3A4F8531769841628AE4321949BCF142"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>A licensee shall promptly notify the qualified regulatory authority that issued the license to the licensee of all persons that are not significant vendors that—</text> 
<clause id="H11FDF7DB83D04344958A761FDBCF1FFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>direct, provide, or solicit customers to or for the licensee’s Internet poker facility, or materially assist in any of those tasks, in return for a commission or other fee;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H2EB02B25DF5C4B7AB4F9A0FA5DC8F4C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>hold themselves out to the public as offering bets or wagers on licensee’s behalf;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H2E5B7E8E9DB240FE8638064A7BA16334"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>offer bets or wagers under their own names or brands but using and relying on licensee’s Internet poker facilities;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HC27F436C99354C7BB02B3C2D60E42A51"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>license trademarks, trade names, service marks, or other similar intellectual property to the licensee; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD27D92C86AE84F17864B95D4C705DAF6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>own a substantial interest in or control a person described in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4AAF5AD632446919C44A30B51A68422"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Suitability of other vendors and persons</header><text>A qualified regulatory authority that reviews an application of an applicant for a license or issues a license to a licensee may, at the sole discretion of the qualified regulatory authority and on a case-by-case basis, require as a condition of such license that a person meet suitability requirements under paragraph (1) if the person—</text> 
<clause id="H98EADAE4216641E5B0D0FA71E4F95F5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is described in subparagraph (A) with respect to the applicant or licensee;</text></clause> <clause id="HCF5EB74117094700820D0A343FA824BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides services to an applicant or licensee and the qualified regulatory authority determines that with respect to such services, there is a substantial risk of circumvention of the suitability requirements applicable to significant vendors; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA67614F414C5462D8D33F001322A3363"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is associated with the applicant or licensee or one of the significant vendors of the applicant or licensee and the qualified regulatory authority determines such person may pose a threat to the integrity of Internet poker facilities operated by the applicant or licensee.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EE2F2D12872454984E96A76470E5B39"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information</header><text>A qualified regulatory authority may require such information from an applicant, licensee, significant vendor or other person identified in this paragraph as the qualified regulatory authority considers necessary to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A4D8D879C7C4638929ED225CB5B80B2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Enforcement actions</header> 
<subparagraph id="HACC2D3B9B7D84553BB21018EC1527F23"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary or the qualified regulatory authority that issued a license to a licensee finds that the licensee, or any other person that is subject to a required determination of suitability in connection with such licensee, fails to meet the suitability requirements of this subsection at any time during the tenure of the license, the Secretary or the qualified regulatory authority may take action to protect the public interest, including, if the Secretary or qualified regulatory authority considers necessary, the suspension or termination of the license.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59F7D6EDA08D4C969CC865E42024F013"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Imposition of conditions including removal of parties</header><text>Notwithstanding a determination under subparagraph (A), the Secretary or the qualified regulatory authority that issued a license to a licensee may allow the licensee to continue engaging in licensed activities by imposing conditions on the person to which subparagraph (A) is applicable under penalty of revocation or suspension of a license or certificate of suitability, including—</text> 
<clause id="HFE44E60CA13B47DE9EFD684999FFF0EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the identification of any person determined to be unsuitable; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3D4DB5C8360F489EA9211389DDB17305"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the establishment of appropriate safeguards to ensure such person is excluded from any management or involvement in operation of the licensed activities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8A76616B6DC49B689BC383A935F1F97"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header> 
<subparagraph id="H28517703F89C41D7A64000B9627B528D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Background check and investigation</header><text>Each qualified regulatory authority shall establish standards and procedures for conducting background checks and investigations for purposes of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AD080420BF242FF824A381CCBCB9809"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privilege</header><text>Any written or oral statement made in the course of an official proceeding of the Secretary or a qualified regulatory authority, by any member thereof, or any witness testifying under oath which is relevant to the purpose of the proceeding and relates to the review of an application for a license under this title, is privileged and shall not give rise to liability for defamation or relief in any civil action.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11BC34E1F04447C48534DA1CFD83DDED"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional privilege</header><text>Notwithstanding section 552 of title 5, United States Code, or any other Federal, State, or tribal law to the contrary, any communication or document of an applicant, licensee, significant vendor, or affiliate thereof, which is made or transmitted pursuant to this title to the Secretary or a qualified regulatory authority or any of their agents or employees, except information that is already public, shall be privileged and shall not be disclosed by the Secretary or the qualified regulatory authority without the prior written consent of the applicant, licensee, significant vendor, or affiliate thereof (as applicable), or pursuant to a lawful court order, grand jury subpoena, or similar procedure. To the extent practicable, the Secretary or qualified regulatory authority shall provide timely notice of the proceedings to the applicant, licensee, significant vendor, or affiliate thereof (as applicable).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B46FCED6BA44708A12135B0E98E806C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Preservation of privilege recognized under other provisions of law</header><text>Any privilege recognized under any other applicable provision of Federal, State, or tribal law, including attorney-client, physician-patient, and accountant-client privileges, shall not be waived or lost because a document or communication otherwise protected by the privilege is disclosed to the Secretary or a qualified regulatory authority.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40FA7741D0D84F8188880ECEB22E9BB5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>Any communication or document, except information that is already public, shall be treated as confidential and may not be disclosed, in whole or part, by the Secretary or a qualified regulatory authority without a lawful court order or as otherwise expressly required by law, if the communication or document is—</text> <clause id="HB1BA2FAD501A4BE0ACA4136AD1D79EF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>required by the Secretary or qualified regulatory authority to be disclosed by the applicant, licensee, or significant vendor, including applications, financial or earnings information, and criminal records, whether of the applicant or licensee or of any affiliate, employee, officer, director, or significant vendor thereof, or of any other third party; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8441EE595A024DDB9A411EBCE7808171"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prepared or obtained by an agent or employee of the Secretary or qualified regulatory authority that contains information described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H783384E5D9CE47A7B61491DC74154AAD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional requirements for a license</header><text>In order to obtain a license under this section, an Internet poker facility shall demonstrate to the qualified regulatory authority that such facility maintains appropriate safeguards and mechanisms, in accordance with standards established by the qualified regulatory authority, including appropriate safeguards and mechanism to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H17DD0AA6D34443F6B6AF13C2F71AE716"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that the individual placing a bet or wager is not less than 21 years of age;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H57D9661E25754290ACDF1496BE8F1560"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that the individual placing a bet or wager is physically located in a jurisdiction that has not prohibited such bets or wagers at the time the bet or wager is placed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6776991F2024FAB97BD1FCBA944473E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that all taxes relating to Internet poker from persons engaged in bets or wagers relating to such Internet poker are collected or reported, as required by law, at the time of any payment of proceeds of such bets or wagers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34ED8CF898514756840C21BBD84FE8DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that all taxes relating to the operation of an Internet poker facility from any licensee are collected and disbursed as required by law and that adequate records to enable later audit or verification are maintained;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC6D75DB479A4FDC9E3589ABBC14BFA2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>prevent, to a reasonable degree of certainty, fraud, money laundering, and terrorist financing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7266021DFDE346F0A45A0A8FD4EF8367"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, compliance with the requirements of section 106;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBEA3167034F477995577B243141D24F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>protect, to a reasonable degree of certainty, the privacy and online security of any person engaged in bets or wagers with the licensee’s Internet poker facility;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H085E843E383743AA98A3577F1D6A5DEC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>ensure that any user fee required under subsection (e) is paid to the qualified regulatory authority;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H946163E9A72047A5B88526522E1314B6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that Internet poker games are fair and honest, and to prevent, to a reasonable degree of certainty, cheating, including collusion, and use of cheating devices, including use of software programs (sometimes referred to as <term>bots</term>) that make bets or wagers according to algorithms; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7D0FA2467EF499EAFF8F2812F2F2013"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other mechanisms and safeguards as the qualified regulatory authority shall require, including independent testing of hardware, software, communication equipment, and other necessary devices to ensure the integrity, accountability, randomness of play and security of the network.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H14FB31D0C9DA472DBC81D72E817A0E95"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fees for administrative expenses</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HDA6F58639739488D99BA61FD29A9A76F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>User fees</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H6B7D1BCEE4664013AFDFEFC0DF011CEC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The cost of administering this title with respect to each applicant, licensee, and significant vendor, including the cost of any review or examination of a licensee or its significant vendors to ensure compliance with the terms of the license and this title, shall be assessed by the qualified regulatory authority receiving an application or issuing a license against the applicant, licensee, or significant vendor, as the case may be, by written notice in an amount that the qualified regulatory authority determines is necessary to—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE75C4FAC1E8E4642B48A6930A2AFC38B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meet the qualified regulatory authority's expenses in carrying out such administration, review, or examination; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H35A1FC58E6DC47EE9563E555EC45CD70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to cover the qualified regulatory authority’s share of the amount determined by the Secretary under paragraph (3) to cover the expenses incurred by the Secretary in carrying out the provisions of this title.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0F5669CD6F874393ABEFC8AB9AEEF84A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expenses for review or examination</header><text>Expenses that are attributable to review or examination of a particular applicant, licensee, or significant vendor shall be assessed under subparagraph (A) against that applicant, licensee, or significant vendor.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H9FF295EC486B4B4881BD04DA5BBD86A6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Expenses for general administration</header><text>Expenses for general administration shall be assessed against all licensees equally.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC784534D79B549AFA2528DBAC8ECAA30"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Disposition of user fees</header><text>Amounts assessed by a qualified regulatory authority as user fees under this paragraph shall—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="HBA8A0C85505B4BD19D88536AC58AFC77"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be remitted to the Secretary, in the amount of that State’s or federally recognized Indian tribe’s share as determined under paragraph (3) for deposit in the Treasury in accordance with subparagraph (B) of such paragraph; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1162F85ADF0E45E38DC663428CD3B561"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC688B38B08764AF9AECED73B2FF12E46"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be available to the qualified regulatory authority to cover expenses incurred by the qualified regulatory authority in carrying out the provisions of this title; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HDC136B0FD5154FB8B0C1F4EE573752DC" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not be construed to be Government funds or appropriated monies, or subject to apportionment for the purposes of any other provision of law.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8E05716BB0924211B72ED434E8E56F54"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Collection</header> <clause commented="no" id="HE4BC6309333B4833BCB8883642B98451"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>If a licensee or significant vendor fails to pay a user fee to a qualified regulatory authority under this paragraph after the assessment of the fee has become final—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H6A2F93913A8E4C3D8BAD0FB7B3D8A881"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the qualified regulatory authority may recover the amount assessed by action in any State or tribal court in the jurisdiction of the qualified regulatory authority, or in any appropriate United States district court, along with any costs of collection and attorney fees; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HB1EFA2FB92584BA69E263FD116251A44"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such failure may be grounds for denial of an application for a license under this title or revocation of a license or certificate of suitability under this title.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HEC2ADB3429844CA5A19E9EA0B7CA5EBF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Assessment reviewable</header><text>In any civil action under clause (i), a court may review the validity and adjust the amount of the user fees.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H64BABFEEB7F54B9989F0F2DF8745A072"><enum>(F)</enum><header>User fees of significant vendors may be paid by applicants and licensees</header><text>A user fee assessed against a significant vendor may be paid by an applicant or licensee on behalf of the significant vendor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H04427CA8FF1A4AC48F0A28A6F9E117FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct and exclusive obligation of licensee</header><text>With respect to a licensee, a user fee shall be the direct and exclusive obligation of the licensee and may not be deducted from amounts available as deposits to any person placing a bet or wager with the licensee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBE84C4AB4DF946DE9E9A12DE7D174A05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>User fees established by Secretary</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF97EEA1F02274392B06CB702EAB06B95"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the funding requirements necessary to meet the Secretary’s cost of administering this title and notify each qualified regulatory authority of its proportional share to be collected by such regulatory authority under paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC1A1BD1E434845868CFECC2F40C8E314"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disposition of user fees</header><text>Amounts remitted to the Secretary under paragraph (1)(D)(i) shall—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H4E185411D5AA49AC8A77AE7A292BE561"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be deposited into a separate account in the Treasury to be known as the <term>Internet Poker Oversight Fund</term>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H15F22D4F3A784957BE150D69DEAB41FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be available to the Secretary in such amounts, subject to appropriations, to cover expenses incurred by the Secretary in carrying out the provisions of this title.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HACA4FEE4CBC94BA9906BB61B487836A0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Approval of license</header> <paragraph id="HE4C5894D1B784734B63294004C49A120"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified regulatory authority may issue licenses under this title for the operation of an Internet poker facility to any applicant that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B48231D46484E068E4CB2356A605377"><enum>(A)</enum><text>owns or controls a company that operates a casino gaming facility or qualified card room and owned or controlled such facility or card room on the date that is 10 days before the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H108D5EF1E20F410C9A2E0473027FBB8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the duration of the 5-year period ending on the date on which the applicant submits an application under subsection (b)(1), owned or controlled a casino gaming facility or qualified card room;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H275CB7F17BBD4E56BED84BFADA79F47E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by a person who—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HD3BB7F55E4A7442B87EB0187E1C15DC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>owns or controls a company that operates a casino gaming facility or qualified card room and owned or controlled such facility or card room on the date that is 10 days before the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HD33A287A116B445A82F5094CF4BD5F0D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for the duration of the 5-year period ending on the date on which the applicant submits an application under subsection (b)(1), owned or controlled a casino gaming facility or qualified card room;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4BDE69B25D0B45DF941087BDC20E8605"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for the duration of the 5-year period ending on the date on which the applicant submits an application under subsection (b)(1), under license issued by a State or federally recognized Indian tribe manufactured and supplied to casino gaming facilities with not fewer than 500 slot machines; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8192E35567046FC82F1C189DD4E9DF0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>meets other criteria established by the Secretary or by the qualified regulatory authority under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C17D5DAFF3A4B5EA487299EB339CCB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expansion of licensees only if no risk to public</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of first issuance specified in section 115(b), the Secretary may, by rule, authorize the issuance of licenses to applicants other than those described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines, after providing the public with notice and an opportunity to comment, that such authorization will not significantly increase the risk that the standards described in subsection (d) will not be satisfied by licensees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H734FAF1723DF427FB78EF39EC342FDAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority of Secretary to revoke licenses</header><text>Notwithstanding any certificate of suitability or license issued by a qualified regulatory authority, the Secretary may suspend or revoke such certificate or license if the Secretary has reason to believe that the recipient does not meet the suitability requirements established under subsection (c) or, as applicable, any other requirement imposed on a licensee under this title. The Secretary may not overturn a decision by a qualified regulatory authority to deny or to terminate a license or to deny or revoke a certificate of suitability.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62FCDF6611C7438FB8322E62B0447366"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Conflicts between qualified regulatory authorities</header><text>If a qualified regulatory authority denies a license, terminates a license, denies a certificate of suitability, or revokes a certificate of suitability to a person and within 12 months of such denial, termination, or revocation another qualified regulatory authority grants such person a license or certificate of suitability, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBF8C8188DC114B839BA365DF6D8D621A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>commence a review of such license or certificate of suitability; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H995787E04E6C41B28BFC19FD1C29121C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after such commencement, determine whether to act under paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H7C03A6B6C41142F09945C86E6EAC0643"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Control defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>control</term> means, with respect to a person, the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or influence the direction of the management or policies of the person, whether through the ownership of voting securities, through a management, executive officer, or board position, by shareholders or similar agreement, or otherwise.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5DD1190633AC4DEC96829670A76AD55C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Location of remote gaming equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A licensee shall maintain its remote gaming equipment within the territory of the United States throughout the term of its license. A qualified regulatory authority shall require applicants that seek a license from such qualified regulatory authority to locate that equipment within the territory of the State or on the Indian land of the tribe of the qualified regulatory authority.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2EE19ADA95D2407D8E7EB91350C60834"><enum>(h)</enum><header>License is a privilege not a right</header><text>A decision by a qualified regulatory authority not to grant a person a license or certificate of suitability, or to terminate a license, or revoke a certificate of suitability, is not reviewable under Federal law or the law of any jurisdiction other than the jurisdiction of the qualified regulatory authority. The State or federally recognized Indian tribe of the jurisdiction of the qualified regulatory authority may, but need not, provide an opportunity to appeal.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H510C86C62EB94D29AA1272EDD0B5E013"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Term, renewal, and transfer of license</header> <paragraph id="H08FA506F3537473DBF34F37D4786FCB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Any license issued under this title shall be issued for a 5-year term beginning on the date of issuance. A license may be renewed in accordance with requirements prescribed by the qualified regulatory authority that issued the license under this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB011C5AF6F9245C98AF6A807DC84E919"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text>A transfer of a license, change of control of a licensee, or change in significant vendor shall require prior approval by the qualified regulatory authority that issued the license. The qualified regulatory authority shall at a minimum ensure the suitability requirements of subsection (c) continue to be satisfied before approving any such transfer or change.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCC6A43578A07463DB54E560608683A04"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header> <paragraph id="H3CC4DAE4B3604090B23538965DF7202D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of Internet poker</header> <subparagraph id="H62584B993E4E4A21963FFAD749948E55"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial determination by qualified regulatory authority</header><text>A determination of whether a game, hand, tournament, or other contest of a licensee is Internet poker shall be made in the first instance by the qualified regulatory authority that issued the license to such licensee under this title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BD7D4A11BF54B51A794516DF41D65DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Challenges</header> 
<clause id="HF0B844D1D1ED43B1B7000774DC59108E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Challenge made with Secretary</header><text>A licensee or qualified regulatory authority may file a challenge with the Secretary regarding any determination of the qualified regulatory authority under subparagraph (A) that a game, hand, tournament, or other contest of another licensee is Internet poker.</text></clause> <clause id="H42F8DB09B03C4F469ECC5B1333F44A02"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination made by Secretary within 30 days</header><text>If a challenge is made under clause (i), the Secretary shall make a determination of whether the game, hand, tournament, or other contest is Internet poker not later than 30 days after the date on which the challenge is made.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7BED970562E04DAEA12AFB3EFD9A73A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Operation until determination</header><text>A licensee that offers a game, hand, tournament, or other contest that is challenged under clause (i) may continue to offer such game, hand, tournament, or other contest until the Secretary makes a determination under clause (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06EC3475BE3F40B5A2B268BBA1897D1C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary makes a determination under subparagraph (B)(iii), a licensee or a qualified regulatory authority may appeal such determination to the United States District Court for the District of Columbia. Such court shall set aside the Secretary’s determination if the court determines that the Secretary's determination was—</text> 
<clause id="H7D6D811EFBE7495CA59291C802A1296F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not consistent with law; or</text></clause> <clause id="HE325833169004C0F9A95AF727733AC6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>without observance of procedure required by law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5100D16B8DAC463FB5236492B8411946"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Challenges under State or federally recognized Indian tribal law</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (1) and unless otherwise specifically provided in this title, actions taken by a qualified regulatory authority may be challenged by applicants and licensees only as permitted under the law of the State or federally recognized Indian tribe in which the qualified regulatory authority is located.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95E6B0A3258F4666BA8FB86958C5D52A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Summons</header> <subparagraph id="H12EC1AC8D6F54BAEA565A710707AD04C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may issue a summons with respect to an applicant or licensee necessary to carry out the provisions of this title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F355ECE81714B81AA6F99DC66348A3E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Production at designated site</header><text>A summons issued by the Secretary pursuant to this paragraph may require that books, papers, records, or other data stored or maintained at any place be produced at any—</text> <clause id="HF5AEF0C1B0A3477A8393D6C97CE79278"><enum>(i)</enum><text>business location of a licensee or applicant for a license;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4013387117164EB7B1FDB9DCDA63DF68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designated location in the State or Indian lands of the applicable qualified regulatory authority; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FF2F48BBFA64445B231800E97FA43DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>designated location in the District of Columbia.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25E5166F7CF743E7BA8F3A487427157A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No liability for expenses</header><text>The Secretary shall not be liable for any expense incurred in connection with the production of books, papers, records, or other data under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA52F7E13BF1B4D32981E3D0603A8548C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Service of summons</header><text>Service of a summons issued under this subsection may be by registered mail or in such other manner calculated to give actual notice as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F28EF1124C44AD18BB90133AC977B4D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Authorization to invoke aid of courts</header><text>The Secretary may invoke the aid of any court of the United States to compel compliance with the summons within the jurisdiction of which—</text> <clause id="HA0C16D5CA1EA4DD98EA134A9CF3D2956"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the investigation which gave rise to the summons or the examination is being or has been carried on;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF357718795DC4BD4BBBCE0FD512CD140"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the person summoned is an inhabitant; or</text></clause> <clause id="H026A4EDDD9F6423FB9EF4BE6D8394E01"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the person summoned carries on business or may be found.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4D2FDF7771B2450294951767B216E4E2"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Power of courts to compel appearance</header><text>The court may issue an order requiring the person summoned to appear before the Secretary—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HA9F9356FCB2B436DA7CB08CC0FB306D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to produce books, papers, records, and other data;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HBB39E91F830C4A5BB23DE82AB9521ED0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to give testimony as may be necessary to explain how such material was compiled and maintained;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H2509BB253733473689A54F2278AE535E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to allow the Secretary to examine the business of a licensee; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HAEAB05AD02A64AEEB207988560F77E42"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to pay the costs of the proceeding.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFF4CB7E808C541A791B480FDAC679011"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Contumacy or refusal</header><text>Any failure to obey the order of the court under this paragraph may be punished by the court as a contempt thereof. All process in any case under this subsection may be served in any judicial district in which such person may be found.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5D1823F6D9CC44578037CE733631BA21"><enum>105.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="HFF5FCBE4214A4C229F7F014DD48B942B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disciplinary action</header> 
<paragraph id="HF329B0BBA61C4388B189BA7BE0C28947"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A licensee may be subject to disciplinary action, including suspension or revocation of its license, by a qualified regulatory authority that issued a license to the licensee or by the Secretary if the licensee fails to comply with any provision of this title, any regulation prescribed thereunder, or any other applicable provision of State or tribal law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61E0D167CC88438C97E1B62D95BFD1D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initiating enforcement</header><text>Only the Secretary or the qualified regulatory authority which granted the license may initiate disciplinary action under this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBE2523042E24F41AA6FFE81AB655478"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit a law enforcement authority or regulatory body that has authority over a licensee or an affiliated person, independent from this title, from taking action under the law of that law enforcement authority or regulatory body.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD976C933631F41D491CA9E788BEA47CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disciplinary procedures</header> <subparagraph id="HE076F12A6B614825B23712A503CACB65"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified regulatory authority shall commence disciplinary action under this subsection against a licensee upon service of a formal written complaint upon the licensee, with a copy forwarded to the Secretary, that sets forth the grounds for the disciplinary action and the proposed penalty that is being sought, which may include any or all of the imposition of a fine as provided pursuant to subsection (m)(1) or limitation, condition, suspension, or revocation of the license.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FC9B00581F94305A221ACB4018935E9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>In accordance with law of jurisdiction of qualified regulatory authority</header><text>The disciplinary process shall proceed according to the law of the jurisdiction of the applicable qualified regulatory authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9311539FD881473C84901C8EB853EC01"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Finality of action and appeals</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H57D3D965D12B4B6592125F62060862FF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Finality</header><text>Any disciplinary action shall be treated as a final action.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C69591851DC40FC9A50BBFABB9C2C02"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Action by qualified regulatory authorities</header><text>A licensee aggrieved by disciplinary action by a qualified regulatory authority may file an appeal in the jurisdiction where the qualified regulatory authority taking such action is located only to the extent permitted by the law of such jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CFF47978D7947D39362390AC38C9D4A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Action by Secretary</header><text>A licensee aggrieved by disciplinary action by the Secretary may file an appeal in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia. Such court shall set aside the action if it determines that the action was—</text> 
<clause id="HBF3A6E240E4447B489FB3D542E1ED603"><enum>(i)</enum><text>arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not consistent with law; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H574B2469753C486D8AA3B5AF7B449257"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>without observance of procedure required by law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DD14CE1D0FF493F82878E6A194F212D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pending appeal</header><text>During the period in which a suspension or revocation of an existing license is being challenged through a pending judicial proceeding, the court handling the challenge may allow the licensee to continue offering bets and wagers in full compliance with the terms of its existing license and any other conditions the court considers necessary, if the court determines that—</text> <subparagraph id="H38B4D2C2695C4574A268D9BD1A14849D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appellant has a reasonable likelihood of success on the merits; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6878FD101971406BA33FB0244C10E7ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allowing the appellant to continue offering bets and wagers while the appeal is pending will not threaten the public interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EFF5573DFB3494BBFF3A2BFD261F4CF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Return of customer funds</header><text>If a licensee’s license is revoked and no appeal pursuant to paragraph (5) is pending, the licensee shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5BE3ECA3AD664B49A2394A4E4439322D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>return all customer funds in an orderly manner not later than 30 days after the date of the revocation of the license; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E83E0851ECA48E6BA839E04291A4F95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>place in escrow those sums return of which to United States customers is not feasible due to change in customer address, bank details, or similar difficulty, in an account with a financial institution in the United States for safekeeping and orderly disposition by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0EC967741E44D2F88AE5F652C252B0C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Referral to Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, in the course of carrying out the provisions of this title, the Secretary or a qualified regulatory authority finds a substantial basis to believe that a person has violated section 103, the Secretary or qualified regulatory authority shall refer such matter to the Attorney General.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H86FEF0EDCFE749E4B777E82A785627C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil money penalties</header> <paragraph id="H03632711E80A44498AC69AEC05180ADB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H5F20105C9C4345C1AFC98CD38210CA17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Penalties assessed by qualified regulatory authorities</header><text>A qualified regulatory authority may assess upon any licensee or other person subject to the requirements of this title for each violation of this title or any regulation prescribed or order issued under this title, a civil penalty of not more than the greater of—</text> 
<clause id="H9172A1A6D2954D4799C60E22145D460D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount involved in the violation, if any;</text></clause> <clause id="H00134C5765D74811A81CF0A812A599A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$250,000 for an individual and $750,000 for a corporation; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2138818675564E869B7856944ECE064D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other amount as provided under the applicable State or tribal law of the qualified regulatory authority.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA8C4319E8FE40A58B89A0A9F11CAAB7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalties assessed by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary may assess upon any licensee or other person subject to the requirements of this title for each violation of this title or any regulation prescribed or order issued under this title, a civil penalty of not more than the greater of—</text> 
<clause id="HF7BFDC341F9841B99F289230562B61C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount involved in the violation, if any; or</text></clause> <clause id="H8B44B80659CF4959AD9184B70CD52549"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$250,000 for an individual and $750,000 for a corporation.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38BBC13268F74EFA8D88AC6D89FA0548"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Not cumulative</header> 
<clause id="H85DA0D9039D34E529AA752294549266D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The penalties authorized under subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not be cumulative and only one such penalty may be assessed per violation.</text></clause> <clause id="HDFAECC1BDA6A4A0493599A2CEFFAB33A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Clause (i) shall not be construed to limit the authority of a qualifying body or the Secretary, as the case may be, to pursue a civil penalty for each violation of a related series of violations.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB7BA5A2914B34FD48BC3EAE1843FD383"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Failure to obtain a license</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may assess upon a person that is required to obtain a license under this title, but fails to obtain a license under this title, a civil penalty of not more than the greater of—</text> <clause id="H8B9221AB646F4876994ADA4E2DB1A13E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of bets or wagers taken by the person from players in the United States during the period that a license was needed but not held by the person; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF0C8398B46714F509D43A436D8EBC6BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$1,000,000 per day that the person accepts bets or wagers from players in the United States during the period that a license was needed but not held by the person.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73A9DA2002C04A36AE5928EA567FABB5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to affect the ability of a law enforcement official to seek criminal penalties against a person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0632B6FC5ACE4954B96477CC1E5908E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA4686851C86B4266ABCD094EBBB57120"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Enforcement by qualified regulatory authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Qualified regulatory authorities and such other entities as are authorized by applicable State and tribal law shall enforce the provisions of this title under the law of the applicable State or federally recognized Indian tribe, and penalties shall be determined, reviewable, collectable, and disposed of as provided under such law.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D39AA26227142A8A9B6E26816328E65"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement by Secretary</header> <clause id="H2539C84D3702489F99713A4DE8CD389C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Written notice</header><text>Any penalty imposed under paragraph (1)(B) shall be assessed and collected by the Secretary by written notice.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD4B293BAD98E4EF895D5B72AD55892D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Finality of assessment</header><text>If, with respect to any assessment under paragraph (1)(B), a hearing is not requested pursuant to clause (v) within the period of time allowed under such clause, the assessment shall constitute a final agency order.</text></clause> <clause id="H65B451261DBC40D8A2AC3783F6FAE8C2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Authority to modify or remit penalty</header><text>The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit any penalty which the Secretary may assess or has already assessed under paragraph (1)(B).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H00DF324BADB8449C905CAB525BA10786"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Mitigating factors</header><text>In determining the amount of any penalty imposed under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall take into account the appropriateness of the penalty with respect to the following:</text> <subclause id="HF7E3494CF5ED4F9BA25FFDFA5C534E20"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The size of the financial resources and the good faith of the person against whom the penalty is assessed.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H852E1EB70CC64FEBBB079ECF0AF40F13"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The gravity of the violation.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEE75579AAC564AE0BC4BE80187910C8A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The history of previous violations.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB922ED51748143DEAD04975AB65EB12D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Such other matters as justice may require.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD2035886BFF74FD08487C57D5AFB8CE0"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text>The person against whom any penalty is assessed under paragraph (1)(B) shall be afforded an agency hearing if such person submits a request for such hearing not later than 20 days after the date of the issuance of the notice of assessment.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF699B52C9C6A4F7C926852381292AAC2"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Collection</header> 
<subclause id="H4B3373F767244345991BD29369ED5810"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>If any person fails to pay an assessment after any penalty assessed under this subparagraph has become final, the Secretary shall recover the amount assessed by action in the appropriate United States district court.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB52D3D97F17545879237BEDC4E0C4597"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text>In any civil action under subclause (I), the validity and appropriateness of the penalty shall be subject to review for abuse of agency discretion.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H14FC6E0169B74A71AE1A2FFF25674DCE"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Disbursement</header><text>All penalties collected under authority of paragraph (1)(B) shall be deposited into the Treasury of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CC54400278D4815A57B0C347E6D401B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Condition for licensure</header><text>Payment by a licensee of any civil penalty assessed under this subsection that has become final shall be a requirement for the retention of its license.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2B712EF4B2FD445FB2AE51EA8834CD85"><enum>106.</enum><header>Compulsive gaming, responsible gaming, and self-exclusion program requirements</header> 
<subsection id="H2ECDDEDCF046446FA697928377AA29B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each qualified regulatory authority shall, before issuing any licenses under this title, establish requirements for the development of a gambling addiction, responsible gaming, and self exclusion program that each licensee of that qualified regulatory authority shall implement as a condition of licensure. Such requirements shall also provide for the establishment of a program to alert the public to the existence, consequences, and availability of the self-exclusion list established under subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1CD53D5B7A314AB88A64E46BB610FFC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum requirements</header><text>At a minimum, each qualified regulatory authority shall require that licensees—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDA33AC3C06244F229A84D8FD795AD4F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide informational materials written in plain language about responsible gaming, including information about the self-exclusion list established under subsection (c) and how a player may request placement on the list, each time a player signs in to make a bet or wager, which materials shall be provided via a prominently displayed hyperlink or comparable mechanism;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1A7F965EBC745FFBE3B80F649F11888"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide informational materials about responsible gaming to any player that requests such materials;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7481560B33C1453F8E429E41DD02772B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make continuously available individualized responsible gaming options that any customer may choose, including allowing customers to self-limit their deposit, time and bet amounts, as well as self-limit their access to the issuance of credit, check cashing, or direct mail marketing by the licensee, in each case as and to the extent that the qualified regulatory authority may consider appropriate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADEEC51FAD0041F2A209758A4942FDDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure to a reasonable degree of certainty that persons on the list of self-excluded persons established pursuant to subsection (c) are prevented from initiating any bets or wagers within the scope of this title;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCA3DF04B20F41C899A891C49D1A645D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure that the information required under this subsection is clearly and prominently made available by the licensee in each language in which services of the Internet poker facility of the licensee are offered; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD611313DF68F41EE840F2238058E65C8"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the qualified regulatory authority adopt any practices that the Secretary recommends to protect consumers, taking into account the National Council on Problem Gambling Internet Responsible Gambling Standards.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H76A13CCE7D014D12B5AF5D904D074C62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>List of persons self-Excluded</header> 
<paragraph id="H28F2C97C84C345D2A3AA2D42E25EABC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<subparagraph id="H745C5C584E934275986EA438118083A2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Lists maintained by qualified regulatory authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each qualified regulatory authority shall establish and maintain a list of persons self-excluded from playing Internet poker through Internet poker facilities licensed by the qualified regulatory authority. Each week, each qualified regulatory authority shall submit to the Secretary a current copy of the list.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC10C6E2078A1413199CBDEF86DF241EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Master list maintained by Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and maintain a master list of all persons self-excluded from playing Internet poker through Internet poker facilities licensed under this title. Such list shall consist of all persons submitted under subparagraph (A). The Secretary shall make the master list available to all qualified regulatory authorities and licensees.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0E0ECE982874A408BC97BE7E88BFB0E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Placement request</header><text>Any person may request placement on the list of self-excluded persons by—</text> <clause id="H3DEA3FDF7B7C4950B46D884AA2153A4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>acknowledging in a manner to be established by each qualified regulatory authority with respect to its licensees that the person wishes to be denied gaming privileges within the scope of this title; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD04A71A26002466BAB2DDFD359B28BED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>agreeing that, during any period of voluntary exclusion, the person may not collect any winnings or recover any losses resulting from any gaming activity at any Internet poker facility of a licensee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H837192FC93CB4B3694328C13667AB876"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on liability</header> <subparagraph id="H00079058D1B3427D8F531A4973BCB771"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the United States, the Secretary, a qualified regulatory authority, the State, or federally recognized Indian tribe in which that qualified regulatory authority is located, an enforcement agent, licensee, or any employee or agent thereof, shall not be liable to any self-excluded person or to any other party in any judicial or administrative proceeding for any harm, monetary or otherwise, which may arise as a result of—</text> 
<clause id="H4626EE2AAB794DE18E08FA62F0CA985D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any failure to withhold gaming privileges from, or to restore gaming privileges to, a self-excluded person;</text></clause> <clause id="H6C0FD0D9FFA64570B847BF58B2D4289B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise permitting a self-excluded person to engage in gaming activity while on the list of self-excluded persons; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD676ABCF89DD4AB7942D421A63F84361"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>disclosure of information about individuals placed on the list of self-excluded persons.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE06ACDC450244A2CAD04FADEDD786F44"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Licensees</header><text>A licensee or employee or agent thereof may be liable to a self-excluded person in a judicial or administrative proceeding for a harm described in subparagraph (A) to the extent provided under the law of the State or federally recognized Indian tribe of the qualified regulatory authority that issued the license.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDCD259FAFC914A5CA4428A81313B2AC2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prevent the Secretary or a qualified regulatory authority from assessing a regulatory sanction against a licensee or person for failing to comply with a provision of this section or a regulation prescribed thereunder or for misuse of any list of self-excluded persons for purposes not authorized under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2BA98A9D4CA4352BD5E7AF341253061"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosure provisions</header> <subparagraph id="H40DF75C3148D45AD80DC80E1A56C9061"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal, State, or tribal law, the list of self-excluded persons shall not be open to public inspection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7490CA82AB834A34930CCE37E87A3D70"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Affiliate disclosure</header><text>If necessary to effectuate the self-exclusion purposes of this subsection, any licensee may disclose the identities of persons on the self-excluded list to any significant vendor, service provider, or affiliated company to the extent that the significant vendor, service provider, or affiliated company maintains such information under confidentiality provisions comparable to those in this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD46332D9F5724714975B6F87872FE974"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Gaming by prohibited persons</header> <paragraph id="H7DB7F2045AFB408087912C6478A96634"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on benefitting from prohibited gaming activity</header><text>A person who is prohibited from gaming with a licensee by law, or by order of the Secretary, a qualified regulatory authority, or any court of competent jurisdiction, including any person on the self-exclusion list under subsection (c), shall not collect, in any manner or proceeding, any winnings or recover any losses arising as a result of any prohibited gaming activity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C17B358BA6E4890A5193C8D1C8DF743"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header><text>In addition to any other penalty provided by law, any money or thing of value that has been obtained by, or is owed to, any prohibited person by a licensee as a result of bets or wagers made by a prohibited person after the applicable prohibition has become effective shall be subject to forfeiture by order of the Secretary or a qualified regulatory authority, following notice to the prohibited person and opportunity to be heard.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4011A54B07D04A338B21789DBFF111DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deposit of forfeited funds</header><text>Any funds forfeited pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited into the Treasury of the United States, or, in the case of a forfeiture to a qualified regulatory authority, as provided by the applicable State or tribal law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H770F49334FEB41B69A2B974EA4F852C7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements with respect to Child Support Delinquents</header> 
<paragraph id="HFB333008FF6C44B7A9AC758BE8F34108"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When it is made known to the Secretary or a qualified regulatory authority by a Federal or State court or a competent qualified regulatory authority involved with the administration or enforcement of a court-ordered child support payment that a particular individual is delinquent with respect to court-ordered child support payments, the Secretary shall include that individual on the list established under subsection (c).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25DFE17D0D904F7E802F14E0DC796011"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal from list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals placed on the list pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be removed from such list if the court or agency that made such individual's delinquency known to the Secretary notifies the Secretary that such individual is no longer delinquent.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H20427829E46C4662924795CA08B57188"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authority To address gambling addiction in SAMHSA Authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 501(d) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBB057D0539934B82B85CB01896DDEEA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (17);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67F52BDE1DDC4EDBB8AF871E785C0CAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (18) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7120A2653F55420CB1C587E31CBD7FC4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD690DFBA978E48A59679C9FD64CCEEE2" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HDB72AD44AE544F629B503A439FE7D9E1"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and implement programs for the identification, prevention, and treatment of pathological and other problem gambling.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCE85CE4F526460B97756855C902BF1E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Compilation of datasets on player behavior</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall compile and make available to the public, on the Web site of the Secretary, datasets on player behavior from customer tracking data collected or generated by loyalty programs, player tracking software, online gambling transactions, or any other information system. The Secretary shall ensure that personally identifying information, including player name, street address, and bank or credit information is removed from the data. The data shall retain information on player characteristics including gender, age and region of residence, player behavior including frequency of play, length of play, speed of play, denomination of play, amounts wagered and, if applicable, number of lines or hands played and characteristics of games played.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA68ACB87C9594478904EF2B97D37D040"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header> 
<paragraph id="H5CB9DBD3050041D088BADE78149C5183"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>No provision of this section shall be construed as creating a legal duty in the Secretary, a qualified regulatory authority, a licensee, or any employee or agent thereof to identify or to exclude compulsive players not on the list of self-excluded persons.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAD911BFEAB5433E9C40DA7EC36E630F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No cause of action</header><text>The Secretary, a qualified regulatory authority, a licensee, and any employee or agent thereof, shall not be liable to any person in any proceeding for losses or other damages of any kind arising out of that person's gaming activities based on a claim that the person was a compulsive, problem, or pathological player.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3AA3B595150A4139AF0CE718C5809E7A"><enum>107.</enum><header>Prohibitions and restrictions</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H02E2E7F58E794577B1F7123D6BB9FE9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on bets or wagers on games other than Internet poker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No provision of this title shall be construed to authorize any licensee to accept a bet or wager on any game, event, or activity that is not Internet poker.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H1760C38B45F140EE9FA82DA8355318F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of credit cards for Internet poker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No licensee, no person operating on behalf of a licensee, and no person accepting payment for or settlement of a bet or wager who intends to transmit such payment to a person licensee, may accept a bet or wager or payment for or settlement of a bet or wager that is transmitted or otherwise facilitated with a credit card (as defined in section 5362(11) of title 31, United States Code).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H338C40E9BCD745C3A875970C2C6A9F12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public Internet poker parlors prohibited</header> 
<paragraph id="H2B484BF5FA9245468DB05823815ABC3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be considered a violation of this title to operate an unlicensed place of public accommodation, club (including a club or association limited to dues-paying members or similar restricted groups), or similar establishment in which computer terminals or similar access devices are made available to be used principally for the purpose of accessing Internet poker facilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD7EF4103A4E48CDAD6FF1E7A4F0BF3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Criminal penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who violates subsection (a) shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE3E163EBA0D45288DACCCDD39438944"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this title shall be construed to authorize or otherwise to permit the operation of places of public accommodation, clubs (including clubs or associations limited to dues-paying members or similar restricted groups) and similar establishments that permit access to Internet poker facilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9ECF8205407E42D0B21E0B87816B8EA9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relation to State, local, and tribal law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Places of public accommodation, clubs, or similar establishments described in paragraph (1) shall be subject to all otherwise applicable State, local, and tribal laws.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD201779565444A9D84159FBA456AAAE8"><enum>108.</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be an affirmative defense to any prosecution or enforcement action under any provision of Federal, State, or tribal law that the activity forming the basis of such prosecution or enforcement action is authorized under and has been carried out lawfully in accordance with and under the terms of this title.</text></section> <section id="H39D5B08ED79C4423AB373B19C3B59107"><enum>109.</enum><header>Relation to subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, shall not apply to any bet or wager occurring pursuant to a license issued under this title, subject to section 110.</text></section> 
<section id="H036C50F48DC148CBADA4ED2A41D27B80"><enum>110.</enum><header>Cheating and other fraud</header> 
<subsection id="HEEC784FA09404CDD8A597DB28F67BE1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cheating and cheating devices prohibited</header> 
<paragraph id="HE1F1A81976A1480E915ACF7B0644DC07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cheating prohibited</header><text>No person initiating, receiving, or otherwise making a bet or wager with a licensee, or sending, receiving, or inviting information assisting with a bet or wager with a licensee shall knowingly violate, attempt to violate, or assist another in violating the rules of play established by the licensee for the purpose of obtaining prohibited or unfair advantage in any game authorized under this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBDA7213E38C43888EC63A98ADF1E819"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cheating devices</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), no person initiating, receiving, or otherwise making a bet or wager with a licensee, or sending, receiving, or inviting information assisting with a bet or wager with a licensee shall knowingly use, possess, or assist another in the use of, an electronic, electrical, or mechanical device or software or other program or tool which is designed, constructed, or programmed specifically for use in obtaining an advantage in any game authorized under this title, where such advantage is prohibited or otherwise violates the rules of play established by the licensee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD58118A188874211BC70CE02C8273831"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permissible uses</header><text>It shall not be a violation of this subsection for a licensee, its agents, a qualified regulatory authority, or its agent to use or possess a device described in the preceding sentence if—</text> <subparagraph id="H05FBDC9518BD415EBDD4BB7073958AB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such use or possession is solely for purposes of testing an Internet poker facility;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB26C7B6ABA554C5DBEEEAE6CE7C4C038"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such device is not used in live play involving actual bets or wagers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50336DEF829F4F6C89735B7CBD500C2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such device is registered with the Secretary and the qualified regulatory authority that issued the applicable license.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCB07777DE4F48779EB895EEB556D74B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disclosure to public not required</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a registration under paragraph (3)(C) is not required to be made available to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H605846EDDF3E411AB359B04288224257"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional offense</header> <paragraph id="H0758FB7F605A448CB360E3CC6A3F7183"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), no person initiating, receiving, or otherwise making a bet or wager with a licensee, or sending, receiving, or inviting information assisting with a bet or wager with a licensee, shall knowingly use, possess, or assist another in the use of any cheating device with intent to cheat or defraud any licensee or other persons placing bets or wagers with such licensee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1C02060BCCF48D981B3CFC76FEA944C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bots</header><text>A software program that makes bets or wagers according to an algorithm shall constitute a type of cheating device under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF21700A0D1C4D8793C15ECB885B4F18"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permissible uses</header><text>It shall not be a violation of this subsection for a licensee, its agents, a qualified regulatory authority, or its agent to use or posses a device described in paragraph (1) or (2) if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB92C444798384ECE8A93A8D7EF535F5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such use or possession is solely for purposes of testing an Internet poker facility;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7197BAB0BC1E43F48EE3942BACDEFB32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such device is not used in live play involving actual bets or wagers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H01292F37C8374186A3188D3BF6C6A697"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such device is registered with the qualified regulatory authority that issued the applicable license.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40D75E82813A4CC0B48959ACBC474F81"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disclosure to public not required</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a registration under paragraph (3)(C) is not required to be made available to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H42477DCB9A7D484DB3555185C60393B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permanent injunction</header><text>Upon conviction of a person for violation of this section, the court may enter a permanent injunction enjoining such person from initiating, receiving, or otherwise making bets or wagers or sending, receiving, or inviting information assisting in the placing of bets or wagers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7236F01083EE4B81B6DF86925BA80974"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criminal penalty</header><text>Whoever violates subsection (a) or (b) shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned for not more than 3 years, or both.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H40FC9315D67F463C9F925433C2FD24FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H78F235F4F5454EA58FE4CC4ECFDF9A8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recommended minimum standards</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing the recommendations of the Secretary on what minimum standards qualifying bodies should adopt to carry out the requirements of subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99789A14B38940FC8CF128FA45053C5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification of threats to operation of Internet poker facilities</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date that licenses are first issued under section 118(a), the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall submit to Congress a report that identifies threats to the integrity of Internet poker facilities operated by licensees, including identification of technologies that could be used to hack computer networks, facilitate cheating, or otherwise place consumers at risk of fraud or monetary loss.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H717A9847F526453D8A1CFE8B4854F5C1"><enum>111.</enum><header>Construction and relation to other law</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H62D5F98FE4044D12AC15C0E994F74025"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No impact on existing lawful games</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H4997D2BE1B424F238162945C26237632"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If bets or wagers on certain games of skill are not regarded as gambling under all provisions of Federal, State, or tribal law in effect as of the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9F7237212DA941F189F0D8E2F900CE11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>nothing in this title shall be construed to require licensing under this title with respect to such games; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF6AB73CEA7AF4F59883C9CA213199AE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fees paid to participate in such games shall not be regarded as bets or wagers for purposes of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H25D22F2D5EC944B6AD0C92F83F1F5A80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reliance</header><text>Nothing in this title may be relied on as support for the legality or permissibility of games described in paragraph (1) without compliance with the licensing and other requirements of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H681FF02834714578B50250D30021DD2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No effect on existing law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to repeal, to amend, or to affect the interpretation of any provision of State, or tribal law that was in effect before the date of enactment of this Act that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC11122E8B49F438CBB1BEABC9DF1EB83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibits, restricts, or otherwise addresses bets or wagers; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HF3552EC979A044709965C223548F3EAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibits fraud, unfair or deceptive acts or practices, or other criminal activity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H77EACFB30001490EBDE94C93CAAA55A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preemption of State and tribal laws</header> <paragraph id="H3E04FB95E2024B67A64D47BF21098E2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise expressly provided in this title and excluding any prohibitions described in section 104(a)(3), the provisions of this title shall supersede any provisions of the law of any State or federally recognized Indian tribe expressly relating to the permitting, prohibiting, licensing, or regulating of Internet poker facilities, except to the extent such State or tribal laws are not inconsistent with this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1D3FE0EEC9649B3823B50B92FF54AE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lotteries</header><text>No provision of this title shall be construed to have any effect on the rights, privileges, or obligations of a State or tribal lottery as may be provided under other applicable Federal, State, or tribal law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C11AADCCF5D463AB9A7B018D603BA33"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this title may be construed to limit the applicability or enforcement of any State or tribal consumer protection law or preempt the applicability of State or tribal trespass, contract, or tort law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD2675F618F454327ADF57F3E4E03EB95"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relation to Gambling Devices Transportation Act</header><text>Equipment used by a licensee or significant vendor in the furtherance of licensed activities pursuant to this title (but not to the extent it is used for other purposes) shall not be considered a gambling device within the meaning of section 1 of the Act of January 2, 1951, prohibiting the transportation of gambling devices in interstate and foreign commerce (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1171">15 U.S.C. 1171</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H09545A62C7554A6E89BCB910A8101148"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No impact on Indian Gaming Regulatory Act</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0511FCF919A84DC8828B4FD6584732FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No provision of this title or decision or action taken by a federally recognized Indian tribe or State pursuant to this title shall have any effect on non-Internet gaming activities within the scope of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2710">25 U.S.C. 2710</external-xref>) or any successor provisions or on any tribal-State compacts or authorities pursuant thereto.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H4800EFE08EE34119AF44BC0FB5F5A355"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tribal status or category not affected</header><text>Tribal operation of Internet poker facilities under this title shall not be considered class II or class III gaming under such section, and a federally recognized Indian tribe’s status, category, or class under such section shall not impact its status or ability to offer bets or wagers pursuant to this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA13913C29A2644F69C50BDF244D74C29"><enum>(3)</enum><header>New negotiations not required</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2FA33A95A516402C90B33735FECD01FE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>federally recognized Indian tribes</header><text>The fact that a federally recognized Indian tribe is operating under a license issued pursuant to this title or that a tribal regulatory body is acting as a qualified body pursuant to this title shall not require a federally recognized Indian tribe to negotiate a new agreement, limitation, or other provision of tribal-State compact, agreement, or other understanding with respect to gaming or revenue-sharing, with regard to any bet or wager occurring pursuant to a license issued under this title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HBE9057D02D17479F8BC2BC1683A48C58"><enum>(B)</enum><header>States</header><text>The fact that a State has prohibited or limited Internet bets or wagers under section 104(a)(3) or that a State regulatory body is acting as a qualified body pursuant to this title shall not require the State to negotiate a new agreement, limitation, or other provision of tribal-State compact, agreement, or other understanding with respect to gaming or revenue-sharing, with regard to any bet or wager occurring pursuant to a license issued under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9051DFE7B98740C1B8A9D63250B9EAD6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No impact on intrastate regulatory regimes</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent or limit a State from establishing or maintaining regulations to permit wagering on Internet poker where participation is limited to individuals within the physical borders of that State.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4FD161F2B9EC44D0A9BAAFB0B7B9607C"><enum>112.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as the Secretary considers necessary and where expressly required or authorized to carry out this title.</text></section> <section id="H2BF3A033CF5A4A6284082D30E9240473"><enum>113.</enum><header>Annual reports</header> <subsection id="H1A28AD88FD634E8CB94888D5EDC93EF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Licensing and regulation of Internet poker facilities</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date that licenses first issue under this title and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report on the licensing and regulation of Internet poker facilities under this title, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2DBAC87F0F964E3C8F04642CC6318671"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount of fees collected under section 104(e) and, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Treasury, an estimate of the amount of income tax revenue that is attributable to the operation of Internet poker facilities during the period covered by the report;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H088CACDBEE794B008F71E228A0311910"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of qualified regulatory authorities, the number of licensees reviewed by the qualified regulatory authorities under this title, and the outcomes of such reviews;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA26FF35F9DD84BD6BB81AC34A01F5F00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the efforts the Secretary has undertaken to ensure that qualified regulatory authorities are properly issuing licenses and regulating licensees under this title;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC72854340AD043339E9A20DBA545270F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a detailed description of each type of game offered by licensees and how each type is consistent with the definition of poker under section 102; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E9F8A553B414E0AA0183DE7DACB1C91"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary determines may be useful to Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2650C3C485DD406A980DD6C0846DA4C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consumer protection</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date that licenses first issue under this title and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on commercial and regulatory practices carried out to protect consumers with respect to Internet poker, including the practices carried out pursuant to the requirements of section 106 and the regulations prescribed pursuant to such section. Such report shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H40A79FE5D5C44EECBB265D4BB0AB9B48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed description of the efforts of each qualified regulatory authority to protect consumers from unfair or deceptive acts or practices, including deceptive advertising and marketing to minors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H232B3FD30CA644DE97CEB699BEA7A30C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the practices that the Secretary recommends a qualified regulatory authority to adopt to protect consumers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC3105913C3D4593877397FA42E1A055"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such recommendations as the Secretary may have for legislative action as the Secretary considers necessary to protect consumers with respect to Internet poker; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44FB36BD135D45F68B575821D55F7B60"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF7AF8632B8A742E1B7B92E58BCA46C3A"><enum>114.</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<subsection id="H1B7C248DFF3A4592AD66C256AF3F2117"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this title, the provisions of this title shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3C72F0AA3D7B4B0F91371327B66A2E7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations required before issuing licenses</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, a qualified regulatory authority may not issue a license under this title before the later of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H95ED8CAF6E0E46A3A60B93899AA5F8F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary prescribes final regulations under section 113;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H6E9B3211760441AC93B75D4900362714"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary of the Treasury prescribes final regulations pursuant to subsections (a) and (d) of section 203; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HDCC7C33EFE234A3185F54A65E7146A6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the date on which the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network submits to the Secretary of the Treasury a list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises pursuant to section 5369(a)(1)(B) of title 31, United States Code, as added by section 202(a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title> <title id="H068223C4D20C46A79E70FC2423899EC9"><enum>II</enum><header>Strengthening of Unlawful Internet Gambling Enforcement Act of 2006</header> <section id="HB3BAD5177FEE4E319DEF4A708B767720"><enum>201.</enum><header>Financial transaction providers</header> <subsection id="H2DB974442D3F456393DDF9CDCE1A86D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03FD0D1B47D14AEE8B23A27D16ED2220" style="USC"> 
<section id="H3DC8439990B343C3B22FF4AA18341275"><enum>5368.</enum><header>Liability of financial transaction providers</header> 
<subsection id="HF349BDDE205E4BCE9FBBA511562E19A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Liability for certain financial activities and transactions</header><text>A financial transaction provider shall not be held liable for engaging in a financial activity or transaction, including a payments processing activity, in connection with a bet or wager permitted by the <short-title>Internet Poker Freedom Act of 2015</short-title> or the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3001">15 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>) unless the financial transaction provider has actual knowledge that the financial activity or transaction was conducted in violation of either such Act or any other applicable provision of Federal or State law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7EFFFC7F933B49BBBDC097E3389F12FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No liability for blocking or refusing To honor certain transactions</header> <paragraph id="HBD4F7C5246FD47E281C89FCD05B86192"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A financial transaction provider that takes an action described in paragraph (2) with respect to a transaction shall not be liable to any party for that action if the financial transaction provider takes the action because the originator of the transaction or a party to the transaction is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEB96C75831EB4102A31A788202C1BA5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a person or entity that is included in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by section 5369(a);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CD21CA0D6A34C60AD5EB1A7FB7ECC85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person or entity that is included in a list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises made available to the financial transaction provider by the Secretary under section 5369(a)(3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7EB2BCF83F2741979A6F5663470DD5E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a person or entity that the financial transaction provider reasonably believes is included in a list described in subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB80D34BE70446D28198AECB995AC002"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a person or entity that is demonstrated to be an unlicensed Internet gambling enterprise based on information, other than a list described in subparagraph (A), that is made available to the financial transaction provider.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CDEE0D905354DEFBAFE65F833E51D8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text>A financial transaction provider takes an action described in this paragraph if the financial transaction provider—</text> <subparagraph id="HEB13B9E7B35346F8B5CF39F6FC38BCE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies and blocks a transaction;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD70AC7C5B6C24860961B1ECA60D80255"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevents or prohibits the acceptance of its products or service in connection with a transaction or otherwise refuses to honor a transaction; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA94E4AC7CAB841D8A8650F4B2D1FC08E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>closes an account or ends a financial relationship.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H78F0F84D6FCE4AC79681543F796836B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A887006CCB04AC1A5A01D06AE9AE0DE" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry idref="H3DC8439990B343C3B22FF4AA18341275" level="section">5368. Liability of financial transaction providers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB6EC6FE5D7A843E7863A6164F460B5CF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical correction</header><text>Section 5362(11)(B)(i) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 903(6)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 903(7)(E)</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDC36B361D90A459AB69B4EB962B7B7BF"><enum>202.</enum><header>List of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises</header> 
<subsection id="HBF8A67172D7F4595B1586DDC201845C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, as amended by section 201(a), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H382739A773A3471689637980DCF875C0" style="USC"> <section id="HEA56F6441B9747AEA72734C8B8B34347"><enum>5369.</enum><header>List of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises</header> <subsection id="HAD01142D0DA74DF88ADB22F51A63E71E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>List of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises</header> <paragraph id="H654E0647E57246E8BAE1C94B639F5B79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8223A97121B445B9BA9436A1E6445D00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises in accordance with the procedures described in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H648D5B6EB91148F793757362027305C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Internet Poker Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>, submit to the Secretary a list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises that includes the information described in paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H26C05A5C23754BA498FBE3CB51DF337E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less frequently than every 60 days thereafter, submit to the Secretary an updated list that reflects the results of subsequent investigations carried out under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E5319561782441CAE7A251ED5B95495"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>The information described in this paragraph is, with respect to each unlicensed Internet gambling enterprise included on the list required by paragraph (1), the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H99D4EF3CCFEF47E1B063F59150438255"><enum>(A)</enum><text>All known Internet Web site addresses of the enterprise.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H682A1D4424464D1D80CE72CB9990180D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The name of any person who controls, finances, manages, supervises, directs, or owns all or part of the enterprise (as such terms are used in section 1955 of title 18).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B305F73E673401F8FD8CC92A9E19436"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To the extent known, information identifying the financial agents and account numbers of the enterprise and the persons described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AD53E9FD28341AEB6490F198904DC95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Distribution of list</header><text>Not later than 10 days after receiving the list or an updated version of the list required by paragraph (1) from the Director, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA188E7F0F75F4704B206DA5EC8C96578"><enum>(A)</enum><text>post the information provided under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2) on the Internet Web site of the Department of the Treasury; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20AD84D04E074018B55DB2B1AD99B698"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide to each person that is required to comply with the regulations prescribed pursuant to section 5364 a copy of the information included with the list required by paragraph (1) in an electronic format compatible with the list of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE6911D80115405BA0557A3746263F3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures for identifying unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises</header> 
<paragraph id="HA534E5B32B6943B18EE178291F6B3A1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investigations</header> 
<subparagraph id="H252ECBE63CAC48F99CCBCABABD38C35F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial investigation</header><text>Not later than the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Internet Poker Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>, the Director shall complete an initial investigation of entities that appear to be unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F3617335C464B289AFAE3BF73294FAA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent investigations</header><text>After completing the initial investigation required by subparagraph (A), the Director shall regularly investigate entities that appear to be unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62C8BB6BE8BD48E0AF142D233F5963C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requests</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9A0723C0D5254A81BB0FD48A3224AE32"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any Federal, State, tribal, or local law enforcement official, any affected sports organization, any person directly harmed by unlicensed Internet gambling, any financial transaction provider, and any interactive computer service shall have the right, but not the obligation, to make a written request to the Director for the addition of any person to the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD98B2A7D47BC4B7E8CC9F9C93B9569AB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determinations; notice to person that submitted a request</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a request under subparagraph (A), the Director shall—</text> 
<clause id="H484E763FE8E44191AC93907F688D4A3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine if the request contains information sufficient to constitute a prima facie case that an entity is an unlicensed Internet gambling enterprise; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB002E8A177104B318D32E45191E85698"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the person that submitted the request of the determination of the Director.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA43C342F9EE445018B45038E11E14961"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 30 days before including a person in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a), the Director shall provide written notice to the person of the determination of the Director to include the person in the list.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA119BEBE1194E96988260EBE13100F7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Opportunity to contest</header> <subparagraph id="H2212DD57BD4846F384761A0CDE15D099"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person that receives notice under paragraph (3) that the Director has determined to include the person in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a) may, not later than 30 days after receiving the notice, contest the determination—</text> 
<clause id="HE1E7B4BBD1644F1A802FF52E3309D879"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by submitting a written appeal to the Director; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9B85DFA3AFCB4027A78F971949C2BB95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by agreeing in the written appeal to submit to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3782BC69F8F049A78499470073BA2596"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of not contesting</header><text>If a person described in subparagraph (A) does not contest the determination of the Director to include the person in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a) in accordance with subparagraph (A), the Director shall include the person in the list.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4C2811B6EEC4A738AE66156CC0CC652"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Opportunity for hearing</header><text>The Director—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBAE3A52E053845149ED26A3237558A80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not include a person that submits a written appeal pursuant to paragraph (4) in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a) until the Director provides the person with an opportunity for a hearing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5EDA555C549440E8D787F5C80C8414C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall provide the person the opportunity for a hearing not later than 30 days after receiving the written appeal from the person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08D9261EDEEC480BA2F0C5CE2DEFC67A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Determinations after hearing</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the date of a hearing provided for a person under paragraph (5) (without regard to whether the person appears at the hearing), the Director shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6F1CC7C16BD46E8845D72FD8290FB71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine if the person should be included in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3844C639922B4A60BA07745198AB111E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Director determines that the person should be included in the list, add the person to the list.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFC18F9F83544E28B8BD5EC981FC3D00"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Injunctive relief</header> <subparagraph id="HFD5E40F8F7D44D918B0D3AF9F0E5D2D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person described in subparagraph (B) may petition for injunctive relief in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, which shall have exclusive jurisdiction to hear cases arising under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB70CF8C35C70411AADBA9A56DE785C1C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Person described</header><text>A person described in this subparagraph is a person that the Director determines to include in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H373441AAAC624F8EB660F8D95A31C09A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after the person appears at a hearing described in paragraph (5); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF961C911353E4C20808B158B8D3F8DC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that did not receive the notice required by paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9C0875282FB4A3CA74B4944ADDBEE0F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>The petitioner shall have the burden of establishing that the person should not be included in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEFC91DA9BB5C4666BDC5911CEB35967B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Standing</header><text>Only persons that the Director determines to include in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a) and owners or operators of such enterprises shall have standing to contest the determination of the Director.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D9E0936AE454E34A1CD82E74D2293FE"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Available relief</header><text>The court may direct the Director and the Secretary not to add, or to remove, the petitioner from the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H77C20B2ECE1949F19A6C101949DE173F"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Unavailability of other remedies</header><text>There shall be no judicial review of a determination under this section other than pursuant to this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H15E57A922289476FAEF041B471EC52E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect of list</header><text>A financial transaction provider shall be deemed to have actual knowledge that a person or entity is an unlicensed Internet gambling enterprise if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H569D5C712D7E429C881C016A2F5AE123"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the person or entity is included in the list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises required by subsection (a); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AC26CF67E1B4C67BB36D90BA8AA5CC8"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE96C87A482934ACA9F2F187290655726"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person or entity is included in a list of unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises made available to the financial transaction provider by the Secretary under subsection (a)(3); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H77FBED7C310E45039999ADA1A6BC9BAF" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information in addition to the list described in subparagraph (A) is available to the financial transaction provider that demonstrates that the person or entity is an unlicensed Internet gambling enterprise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF31A36258C6441F4B47FE6D6AEC12266"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D18EA965C3344BF82E1B46802E2E6C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network appointed under section 310(b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE526B8F576D4CA3AC5D91CE95F7AA96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sports organization</header><text>The term <term>sports organization</term> means an amateur sports organization or a professional sports organization (as those terms are defined in section 3701 of title 28).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76CAB20CEC584FC7B7286C830C1F6934"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unlicensed Internet gambling enterprise</header><text>The term <term>unlicensed Internet gambling enterprise</term> means any person who, on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Internet Poker Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>—</text> <subparagraph id="HB233D9FCC02F45B4A827FF7C735E7AE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>violates a provision of section 5363; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6CA097CB8F2D41E4BF981CF734006C03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>knowingly assists a person in conduct described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H65C3316358C246C2BD9A1E25159829ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter 53, as amended by section 201(b), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H8B6E26B546AF4171951EF68B83D73836" style="OLC"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry idref="HEA56F6441B9747AEA72734C8B8B34347" level="section">5369. Unlicensed Internet gambling enterprises.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H39F6D8806F4746C098347644E4ECD2F0"><enum>203.</enum><header>Regulations</header> 
<subsection id="H654B126D1F064411B4C23344757CFA86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6A99F66197354908BBFCD0ABE96CB66A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prescribe regulations to carry out sections 5368 and 5369 of title 31, United States Code, as added by sections 201(a) and 202(a), and publish such regulations in final form in the Federal Register; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49ABB5429FDB41DABA554EF567B3D359"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prescribe such regulations as the Secretary of the Treasury considers necessary to ensure compliance with chapter 2 of title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1951">12 U.S.C. 1951 et seq.</external-xref>) and subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code (commonly known, collectively, as the <quote><act-name>Bank Secrecy Act</act-name></quote>), by licensees, significant vendors to such licensees, and financial service providers to such licensees (as such terms are defined in section 102).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAD7AAD10EACC43F48A3CBDC5339A454B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion of Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from requirement To prescribe regulations concerning prevention of restricted transactions</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 5364 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Before the end of the 270-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this subchapter, the Secretary and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall prescribe regulations (which the Secretary and the Board jointly determine to be appropriate)</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H34EA49B32DFC45E5860EC483485B1E96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Temporary suspension of certain regulations</header> 
<paragraph id="H79F604A107164990BD73B264017B485E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date set forth in subsection (d), part 233 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, and part 132 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, shall have no force or effect to the extent that those regulations require or impose any obligation that is inconsistent with the provisions of title I.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DDDE6F5CB7C4707A6443AD5804F277A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Previous violation</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any violation of a regulation described in such paragraph that occurred before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4BD784BF8C844D93B5633F8856B7531A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Revision of regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall revise part 233 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, and part 132 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, to conform with the provisions of title I.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H83EC38EED2B64D01AACAFF04111979B3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of the Treasury prescribes regulations under this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the list required by section 5369(a) of title 31, United States Code, as added by section 202(a), including the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF7ADFCEE85A64C84BD7A77314FACA89E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The size of the list.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D9CE4032EF944A3A8DEC4E87814AAEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of persons and Web sites added to and removed from the list.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B105B857F28458882F9D28B85DFF4BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number and description of challenges to inclusion on the list and a description of how such challenges were resolved.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB5D0A0B1515842C7A3C93B1D813415FB"><enum>204.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subsection id="H9314D9806A3A44CFAFD23E01DCCEF3CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties and powers of the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 310(b)(2)(I) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>subchapter II</quote> and inserting <quote>subchapters II and IV</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF59C4F9B42464DBE8B36E10CE3EA5F88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion of licensed Internet poker facility operations from definition of unlawful Internet gambling enterprise</header><text>Section 5362(10) of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE40D90A992714728BFB938713FD0BF40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking clause (iii);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE540D24B02FE42B29425CC58E4AC8AA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF56240CD5F7640D2845DBC9B0F7431E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2E03EF4AD2D42DEA83255C6C6C38F96" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H54C2E94E99C645948F4261C964FA5577"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Licensed Internet poker facilities</header><text>The term <term>unlawful Internet gambling</term> does not include an activity carried out by an Internet poker facility, as such term is defined in section 102 of the <short-title>Internet Poker Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>, operated by a person under a license provided under title I of such Act in accordance with the provisions of such title.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></title> </legis-body> </bill> 

