<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H11FAA6199D7B485D8EA9007246750118" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3362 IH: Workforce Development Investment Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3362</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To allow employers a credit against income tax as an incentive to partner with community colleges or other educational institutions to improve workforce development and job training for students.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H879A33F5C9654E0BA9C9956FE94B99BD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H28330E0B76F14C2CB4CD524CB2B1F0C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce Development Investment Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2FCC5E2429CC4D049372C53D1D570DCB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit for employers which partner with community colleges or other educational institutions to improve workforce development and job training for students</header> <subsection id="H82BB11D5F2754938A8D154EFA5228769"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H07C56A13347640A5ACB0FE963357210F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3FCCE80C4B424F8BA925E39354CCD7F7"><enum>45S.</enum><header>Employers partnering with community colleges or other educational institutions to improve workforce development and job training for students</header> 
<subsection id="H92A941D4880844C8A0869E81B288026D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the employer partnering credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to $2,000 for each community college or other institution of higher education engaged in a qualified partnership with the employer.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA6B3724512544954853A51755338B503"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maximum credit</header> <paragraph id="H201B849704034331A21235FD0531C32B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The maximum credit determined under this section for the taxable year shall not exceed $10,000.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24D4732620934DC593584501893B5C2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Controlled groups</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), all persons treated as a single employer under subsection (b), (c), (m), or (o) of section 414 shall be treated as a single taxpayer.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFD1C89E53B7F4FF69A6C0B489279C686"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H57A4D28176D84D42A082C764EB595092"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community college</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community college</term> means an institution of higher education that—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A287C7E1A0A4FCFA94B7B4287A9C268"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">admits as a regular student an individual who is beyond the age of compulsory school attendance in the State in which the institution is located and who has the ability to benefit from the training offered by the institution, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE220958D0EE429BA938F62C1E517556"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offers a 2-year program in engineering, mathematics, or the physical or biological sciences designed to prepare a student to work as a technician or at the semiprofessional level in engineering, scientific, or other technological fields requiring the understanding and application of basic engineering, scientific, or mathematical principles of knowledge.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB05655E790C94A25A1ADD7E81CF61680"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9BBF246DFA6406682E5DC3F0F8F56B9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified partnership</header><text>Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall define the term <term>qualified partnership</term>. Such term shall include a partnership through which—</text> <subparagraph id="HF03C3BD4747C42899660EA103C91A7FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employer collaborates with an educational institution to help develop curriculum in order to improve workforce development and job training for students,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAEC79FEE90F45B3B06347B1EB95355F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an employer helps provide instruction to students in the classroom, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2375645F7054597B26E1282C2DFDB04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an employer provides internships, apprenticeships, or other similar educational opportunities in the workplace for students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8E29455DD6D4C5099ED175E439C9CD4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certain rules To Apply</header><text>For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of subsections (c), (d), and (e) of section 52 shall apply.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H218FE79E346D4D85814D35DCDBDFF6B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H777870D599A14C1581BA3C9B4613901A" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HD35AB7EC47984CD1BB808CE53729DBA6"><enum>(37)</enum><text>the employer partnering credit determined under section 45S.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA09034966D60450DA221C247F23A04F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H59B488CEA458480797D863E6C017BD24" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45S. Employers partnering with community colleges or other educational institutions to improve workforce development and job training for students.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1875191FB6D946D5BA087F8FEACE65C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

