<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H84FFB9D74E9D4A6CAA9A7990987EF670" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2494 : Global Anti-Poaching Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2494</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20151103">November 3, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To support global anti-poaching efforts, strengthen the capacity of partner countries to counter
			 wildlife trafficking, designate major wildlife trafficking countries, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9213D2ADC1E349ABA213F625C188CDC7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5D900505B4514A8A80EE0A9BAB21FE71" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Anti-Poaching Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7BE6505158FE4B1298AA8E1E92D6B680"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H768B1D5CE08F43CC88A94F8CA4E9BFAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Poaching and the illicit trade in endangered and threatened wildlife are among the most lucrative criminal activities worldwide, worth an estimated $7 to $10 billion annually.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68F127A18A644A649C92A16DB3A37C94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Poaching and wildlife trafficking have escalated in scale, sophistication and violence, risking the potential extinction of some of the world’s most iconic species.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC93D97587AAB4A1A9B5092E65A807901"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Wildlife poaching and trafficking threaten elephants, rhinoceros, and tigers greatly, but also have devastating impact on a number of other species, including sharks, great apes, and turtles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE8019665EE4FBD99B79CE6B14AFFDE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The high demand for rare wildlife products has driven prices to historically high levels.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H64F17E9BC5534C808CA86895515356A9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Much of the demand for wildlife products comes from Asia and is fueled by the perceived medicinal value and social status associated with these products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97CBAA743A544C1E98E565EE604D6A2A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Reporting indicates that a number of rebel groups and terrorist organizations, including Sudan’s Janjaweed militia, the Lord’s Resistance Army, the Seleka rebel movement in the Central African Republic, and Somalia’s al-Shabaab, either participate in or draw funding from illicit wildlife trafficking networks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA7E098EE9704D5A9C6532E7628FFB10"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Analyses suggest the high demand for illegal wildlife products, combined with weak law enforcement and security measures and corruption and governance failures, has led to the increased involvement of transnational organized crime in wildlife trafficking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H290A87078234447C858C63C29F411A87"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The United Nations Security Council has authorized multilateral sanctions against individuals and entities supporting armed groups through the illicit trade in wildlife, in addition to other natural resources, in the Democratic Republic of Congo and the Central African Republic.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB459243094E48ECAECF338F91A3AEC9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A National Intelligence Council analysis of wildlife poaching threats found that certain African government officials facilitated the movement of wildlife products, and that these governments’ ability to reduce poaching and trafficking was hindered by corruption and weak rule of law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DB04066D56E478899D3BD23FF256DA4"><enum>(10)</enum><text>On November 13, 2013, the Secretary of State announced the first reward under the Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program for information leading to the dismantling of the Xaysavang Network, a large wildlife trafficking syndicate that is based in Laos and spans Africa and Asia.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HABA13E2FABDA47D5AE98BEBE877DCB13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion of wildlife enforcement networks</header>
 <subsection id="H99A1387A49B74B868521755DA6F3E29E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H352FCE7D1B184B4585C2F67280B872D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wildlife enforcement networks are government-led, regionally-focused mechanisms that increase capacity and coordination efforts between law enforcement, environmental agencies, and other entities focused on countering wildlife trafficking of member countries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70FD1C51F9F94F168FF4E40B3DB604DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Currently there are active wildlife enforcement networks in Southeast Asia, South Asia, and Central America. The more mature wildlife enforcement networks, such as the Southeast Asia wildlife enforcement network, have proven effective in dismantling transnational wildlife trafficking networks and bringing to justice those individuals involved in the illegal trade of endangered and threatened species.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H290F558B810A47EB98BC4C1CDF318315"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Efforts are underway to establish additional wildlife enforcement networks in Central Africa, the Horn of Africa, South America, and Central and West Asia, among other regions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF0D9C631F894883A23326B30856D36D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>The Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and heads of other appropriate agencies should, in an effort to address regional threats to biodiversity and conservation, support strengthening existing wildlife enforcement networks and the establishment of new networks in other appropriate regions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEE60286409D54BB7894459039C61BE4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that in the process of strengthening and expanding wildlife enforcement networks, the appropriate agencies should—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB0B8B25EA1C04598B8307EE4990FA56F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the existing capacity of wildlife enforcement network member countries to gather baseline data that may be used for developing program activities for the wildlife enforcement network;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D30D89CDCA545628A90C0A6B9940EDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a central secretariat within each wildlife enforcement network that will coordinate the operational mechanisms of each such network;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCFD2413CDC0447AAACFD60ABDD9BD27"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish a focal mechanism in each member country of a wildlife enforcement network, that includes representatives from environmental and wildlife protection agencies, law enforcement agencies, financial intelligence units, customs and border protection agencies, and the judiciary system, that will serve as a conduit to the larger wildlife enforcement network and the central secretariat;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H384DA25253464F06A3BEA98F1BAF8790"><enum>(4)</enum><text>strengthen cooperation and the capacity of law enforcement agencies of the wildlife enforcement network;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6BB248E690D4FDCB34361C98E691F3F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>facilitate the sharing of intelligence and relevant case information within the agencies of a wildlife enforcement network;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC76294458A9C4145945EA6E2F595C59D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>support the cooperation and coordination between different regional wildlife enforcement networks;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CE397D0C90A46089449D7E2FB5CFF67"><enum>(7)</enum><text>incorporate and utilize expertise from international bodies and civil society organizations that have appropriate subject matter expertise;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56FD56AC16D742C99922CFEABC655B95"><enum>(8)</enum><text>eventually create an institutionalized, sustainable, and self-sufficient platform; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H66B9C439DC0A46E69A4B3CB39F24249B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>recognize that lawful, well regulated hunting can contribute to sustainability and economic development, and that enforcement policies should not discourage or impede this activity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H45E47653681C4DC3856EBE23D8138690"><enum>4.</enum><header>Supporting the professionalization of the wildlife law enforcement sector</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and heads of other appropriate agencies, including the National Park Service and the United States Forest Service, should, in an effort to address local and regional threats to biodiversity and conservation and support the rule of law and good governance, promote the professionalization of the wildlife law enforcement sector and professional ranger training in partner countries through support and technical assistance for the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5D27B2A493A542858E4DF1D42DAA0AA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The creation and adoption of standards for professional ranger training and qualifications, including in relevant international fora and multilateral agreements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDE9DD1951524BA0BEDA35006774853F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training and accreditation systems based on the standards described in paragraph (1) that produce professionally trained and qualified rangers and promote the overall professionalization of ranger forces, whether through existing United States institutions, such as International Law Enforcement Academies, or through partnerships with national or regional training institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7ECD97B3D1A84C999A03E1112C5D85CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legal reforms, where necessary, to provide rangers with authority to detain and arrest suspects, process crime scenes, present evidence in court, and defend themselves in life threatening situations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8086CFAA64554BD7AFAEF39BD3833219"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and institutionalization of reward and promotion systems for rangers based on performance and set competencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDEAD2E5A9C34518AEEA3C84608ADE49"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and institutionalization of national systems to provide insurance to rangers and their families and compensation for those rangers killed in the line of duty.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H369C589C58F249A5B6A3DB261B1D5713"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cooperation and coordination between local law enforcement tasked with wildlife or park protection and local defense forces, where appropriate, including training opportunities, logistical support, or provision of equipment.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HAC5C3CBD69BF4B4B8524323DADC26394"><enum>5.</enum><header>Designation of major wildlife trafficking countries and authority to withhold certain assistance</header>
 <subsection id="H4016E9C99B094188825FE014FCA48789"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 15 of each year, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce, shall submit to Congress a report that lists each foreign country determined to be a major source of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, a major transit point of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, or a major consumer of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9D384373397846BDB4FAC42432CA5568"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In each report required under subsection (a), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Interior and the Secretary of Commerce, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEE02240A355D45708EBF770314621DD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate each country listed in the report that has failed demonstrably, during the previous 12-month period, to make substantial efforts to adhere to its obligations under international agreements relating to endangered or threatened species; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8F1DCBCD2754CB3B83E90C0B664F21E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a short justification for each determination made under paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C9CEA456C67488DA95C28F4CD05BB78"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withholding of assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may withhold assistance described in subsection (d) with respect to each foreign country that is specially designated under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFFD5E1A8CE4C46C0BF45D92DF87777B9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assistance described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assistance described in this subsection are sections 516, 524, and 541 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</external-xref>, 2344, or 2347), chapter 6 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2348">22 U.S.C. 2348 et seq.</external-xref>), and section 23 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2763">22 U.S.C. 2763</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H25AF57E219224CED863DCD3ED1318381"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall notify—</text> <paragraph id="H3EF8B114422E4910BE1F4132D7A288AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the government of each foreign country that is listed in the report required under subsection (a) that the country has been so listed; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF48AC8493499410FBD7E42BADDA6B776"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the government of each foreign country that is specially designated under subsection (b) and is subject to the withholding of assistance described in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H898104BB7B694A168EB81F3AC357FFAD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting cost offset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/245">Public Law 107–245</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H6945588771FB409788DB175404D5F6DF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H291497E633D0421FA2790CE363B71388"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding security assistance to counter wildlife trafficking and poaching in
			 Africa</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the United States should continue to provide defense articles (not including significant military equipment), defense services, and related training to appropriate security forces of countries of Africa for the purposes of countering wildlife trafficking and poaching.</text>
 </section><section id="H111783B6486C413AABEE054C64BA2260"><enum>7.</enum><header>Updates to the Fishermen’s Protective Act of 1967</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8 of the Fishermen’s Protective Act of 1967 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1978">22 U.S.C. 1978</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4D1B74CA364246C88C366E286756DF17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B494CBED98B47E3949D1604D3BC885A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, in consultation with the Secretary of State,</quote> after <quote>Secretary of Commerce</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F732E4EFF434010A80E041B075DB682"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>, in consultation with the Secretary of State,</quote> before <quote>finds</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46B269E59DBD4780AA1ECC185507BA32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>in consultation with the Secretary of State,</quote> after <quote>, as appropriate,</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE332A92E93C8440A99D0EECF2B015C07"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5), and by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA415B02EC5F9430E97647C62572C65D5" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H05D5FC3C4DBC49D8B32919B1CAB4B969" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior shall each report to the Congress each certification to the President made by such Secretary under this subsection, within 15 days after making such certification.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ACA36604402474CA9256F5BC3E291FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), by inserting <quote>in consultation with the Secretary of State,</quote> after <quote>as the case may be,</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H42027977F7284624B2AF15D5C663A557" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Wildlife trafficking violations as predicate offenses under racketeering and money laundering statutes</header> <subsection id="H3D6C9E21310D4ED9B08CFC919D19ABBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Travel Act</header><text>Section 1952 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDDFD08B8B4F34ED79185E61B85202FC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF7095D1ED63E4801B6F385CA22CB2FA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>(3)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFD3A11F352247F5AEE9633E52039669"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of this title and (ii)</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>of this title, or (4) any act that is a criminal violation of section 9(a)(1) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1538">16 U.S.C. 1538(a)(1)</external-xref>), section 2203 of the African Elephant Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4223">16 U.S.C. 4223</external-xref>), or section 7(a) of the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5305a">16 U.S.C. 5305a(a)</external-xref>), if the endangered or threatened species, products, items, or substances involved in the violation and relevant conduct, as applicable, have a total value of more than $10,000 and (ii)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70F430DF32C74D4095F324E17524FD6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A7ABAB44AB443288A41FE52E9503D05" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7F468166914F434281177E655D454B88"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of amounts from fines, forfeitures, and restitution relating to wildlife trafficking violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amounts received by the United States as fines, forfeitures of property or assets, or restitution to the Government for any violation under this section that involves an unlawful activity described in subsection (b)(i)(4) shall be transferred by the Secretary of the Treasury, to the extent practicable, to the Multinational Species Conservation Fund and used as provided in advance in appropriations Acts for the benefit of the species impacted by the applicable violation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40DF97C381C24CEDBFD648BBE0E37C4D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Money laundering</header><text>Section 1956 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8A544A803EF6440D8EC339698D59C927"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(7)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H710E3822D7764ACD9E3504B2B18CF2B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H265E3A82416143C1A836FD80B6EA72D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92CCFAEC01974ACA9DCB12694250333D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5743A665870047FFAD12EF48AD03A01C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HFCE84A603CCE40EBBBA9C3B114267909"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any act or acts constituting a criminal violation of section 9(a)(1) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1538">16 U.S.C. 1538(a)(1)</external-xref>), section 2203 of the African Elephant Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4223">16 U.S.C. 4223</external-xref>), or section 7(a) of the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5305a">16 U.S.C. 5305a(a)</external-xref>), if the endangered or threatened species, products, items, or substances involved in the violation and relevant conduct, as applicable, have a total value of more than $10,000;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FD87F3143FB4C9E98E56ED8550776EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28A739191FEF43BF9C6AC5BF94F30382" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE5BBBABF104249949A69831C4B3CCE67"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Use of amounts from civil penalties, fines, forfeitures, and restitution relating to wildlife trafficking violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amounts received by the United States as fines, forfeitures of property or assets, or restitution to the Government for any violation under this section that involves an unlawful activity described in subsection (c)(7)(G) shall be transferred by the Secretary of the Treasury, to the extent practicable, to the Multinational Species Conservation Fund and used as provided in advance in appropriations Acts for the benefit of the species impacted by the applicable violation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6F7CC3A475445C58AA9AF785D2231EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>RICO</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/96">Chapter 96</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE3D369A520E545588D2A638F0DB210B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1961(1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H04031BF431C3444194E264AE2CDA1C84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (G)</quote> and inserting <quote>(G)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB43539479BAB441D8118EA829C2FA9B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, or (H) any act constituting a criminal violation of section 9(a)(1) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1538">16 U.S.C. 1538(a)(1)</external-xref>), section 2203 of the African Elephant Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4223">16 U.S.C. 4223</external-xref>), or section 7(a) of the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5305a">16 U.S.C. 5305a(a)</external-xref>), if the endangered or threatened species, products, items, or substances involved in the violation and relevant conduct, as applicable, have a total value of more than $10,000</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H217FD461F68044FE970E9AAD1C12C452"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1963, by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H256EF94EFDC04F9BB2D5BECC7395366D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H4AD1F1BEF4CB44A9B5B47188F3D5BEA4"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Use of amounts from fines, forfeitures, and restitution relating to wildlife trafficking violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amounts received by the United States as fines, forfeitures of property or assets, or restitution to the Government for any violation under section 1962 that is based on racketeering activity described in section 1961(1)(H) shall be transferred by the Secretary of the Treasury, to the extent practicable, to the Multinational Species Conservation Fund and used as provided in advance in appropriations Acts for the benefit of the species impacted by the applicable violation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E6F77F37C434D4B92730D54721F56F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HF830E7B84C8D45A19A716ACE544FDACE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of amounts from fines</header><text>Section 1402(b)(1)(A) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10601">42 U.S.C. 10601(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H00D47ED4E2DC4DAF8306E0E2C3948870"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC5650EC8FFB44F6AAEFEDF39D4DA332"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60CBB2EDD5F24CF1B5D4E14CB10E4518" style="OLC"> <clause id="H0C3E9788927D4D80A6B1A475D1A7DC97"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sections 1952(f), 1956(j), and 1963(n) of title 18, United States Code; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C36AA75EBF342DEB3430B6D16EED2A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of amounts from forfeitures</header><text>Section 524(c)(4)(A) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting before <quote>or the Postmaster General</quote> the following: <quote>or section 1952(f), 1956(j), or 1963(n) of title 18,</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8076B20022CE4E348FDCBD565EB27937"><enum>9.</enum><header>Other actions relating to wildlife trafficking programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should dedicate sufficient program resources to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H71E645F2E5954C588DDEB4D05EF2550C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct monitoring and evaluation, with a special emphasis where feasible on impact evaluations, of wildlife trafficking programs consistent with the Department of State’s January 2015 Evaluation Policy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50F5416F469C46DA9827E892220FC020"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish program information on wildlife trafficking programs on the Department of State’s Internet website, <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote> in a digital format consistent with the United States commitment to the International Aid Transparency Initiative (IATI); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBB807F1002B4366817AD7212A70E70D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and implement a learning agenda to improve the performance and impact of wildlife trafficking programs and to share best practices among relevant executive branch agencies.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20151102">Passed the House of Representatives November 2, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


