<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA7D1905CFC87467387671A227A09BA56" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2651 IH: Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention, Access, and Care Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2651</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150604">June 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000413">Mr. Whitfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to prevent and treat diabetes, to promote and improve the
			 care of individuals with diabetes, and to reduce health disparities,
			 relating to diabetes, within racial and ethnic minority groups, including
			 the African-American, Hispanic American, Asian American, Native Hawaiian
			 and Other Pacific Islander, and American Indian and Alaskan Native
			 communities.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC29867146E6A447A8E8FF1E653D0FE56" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC0C309CA4D5D432FAFEC6F878F9A592D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention, Access, and Care Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><title id="HD7967938290145F6BEBF048534BA3B27"><enum>I</enum><header>NATIONAL INSTITUTES OF HEALTH</header> <section id="H87CD9996D88B4DBFBFB2401D290A2BAF"><enum>101.</enum><header>Research, treatment, and education</header> <subsection id="H40FEA322DD654A5E814FBEEE30297DB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart 3 of part C of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285c">42 U.S.C. 285c et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HCC1448C4EE134BE3871E107930195182" style="OLC">
						<section id="HFE9C52FACC2D4A40998C544CA8FAEBB0"><enum>434B.</enum><header>Diabetes in minority populations</header>
 <subsection id="HD7A0B0C7EFD243E1BA3D661327DDD94E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of NIH shall expand, intensify, and support ongoing research and other activities with respect to prediabetes and diabetes, particularly type 2, in minority populations.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HED59837BA8D44B2AB74DF7E11CC290BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research</header>
 <paragraph id="H6B1D1C00BA7D458783C7C8BCEAB9BF8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Description</header><text>Research under subsection (a) shall include investigation into—</text> <subparagraph id="H3CC68D5627F4473C9E6497B1BB99B0A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the causes of diabetes, including socioeconomic, geographic, clinical, environmental, genetic, and other factors that may contribute to increased rates of diabetes in minority populations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5597D6BC0C2459AB82D1BA10CDCEF02"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the causes of increased incidence of diabetes complications in minority populations, and possible interventions to decrease such incidence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3685A55E047C43C6A2A85F4117C649D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of minority participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting and supporting research described in subsection (a), the Director of NIH shall seek to include minority participants as study subjects in clinical trials.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D6045EAF7B34081BE07CDD72A7CD3AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report; comprehensive plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H6009C67A33B043A3B6152F97B8341840"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Diabetes Mellitus Interagency Coordinating Committee shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB737B27FFE6E4A49A4743EDB44096513"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prepare and submit to the Congress, not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, a report on Federal research and public health activities with respect to prediabetes and diabetes in minority populations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H287F33DF30B54C35A8F1085D413E6FC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and submit to the Congress, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, an effective and comprehensive Federal plan (including all appropriate Federal health programs) to address prediabetes and diabetes in minority populations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H104446D1CE0B4BD18094FB2EC22776F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report under paragraph (1)(A) shall at minimum address each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H6C800B0C076A4FE09665D612108B5630"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Research on diabetes and prediabetes in minority populations, including such research on—</text>
 <clause id="H3178BED5AEF547F6BB02EF09B3266532"><enum>(i)</enum><text>genetic, behavioral, and environmental factors; and</text> </clause><clause id="H515EDE79B4BE42FCA589CF874EB76029"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prevention and complications among individuals within these populations who have already developed diabetes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H411BAC60F456413193B4D458F5D8DB71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Surveillance and data collection on diabetes and prediabetes in minority populations, including with respect to—</text>
 <clause id="H9E6D5734DA56432C91E0FD68C6AC87FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>efforts to better determine the prevalence of diabetes among Asian American and Pacific Islander subgroups; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD270443E0EE14F248108EAC8B6A0A045"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>efforts to coordinate data collection on the American Indian population.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC798BD55E0FE48DCB6BFDB201B83BF79"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Community-based interventions to address diabetes and prediabetes targeting minority populations, including—</text>
 <clause id="H9D59A43C912746378B5F363D791B7523"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the evidence base for such interventions;</text> </clause><clause id="HD8B0472A5FB54FB9BB3427A8E80D94F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cultural appropriateness of such interventions; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA597C4AB4E284061BC5D03E4D9C79100"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>efforts to educate the public on the causes and consequences of diabetes.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H135BEA2319C64EFDBB76FC3FAD7F4990"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Education and training programs for health professionals (including community health workers) on the prevention and management of diabetes and its related complications that is supported by the Health Resources and Services Administration, including such programs supported by—</text>
 <clause id="H2FCE8D96C5724D49B40E215A431144E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the National Health Service Corps; or</text> </clause><clause id="H6C5124DA3C5E43A4B28C0CAE8993E4E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the community health centers program under section 330.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BC9D81DEF1048BE87AE6AE58FD92FC9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Education</header><text>The Director of NIH shall—</text> <paragraph id="H214CEA52B88948D8801608211F4D69AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>through the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities and the National Diabetes Education Program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1D93F7B946A44A06816F53779B788AB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make grants to programs funded under section 464z–4 (relating to centers of excellence) for the purpose of establishing a mentoring program for health care professionals to be more involved in weight counseling, obesity research, and nutrition; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD027298B78C14C51AF665221D330E735"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide for the participation of minority health professionals in diabetes-focused research programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA58BF745B9A544DD862E7ED9E1415835"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make grants for programs to establish a pipeline from high school to professional school that will increase minority representation in diabetes-focused health fields by expanding Minority Access to Research Careers (MARC) program internships and mentoring opportunities for recruitment.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF9AD81AC32F24FD7941139DC13EDA486"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H840DC4732BB142D4841847BC6F040390"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <quote><short-title>Diabetes Mellitus Interagency Coordinating Committee</short-title></quote> means the Diabetes Mellitus Interagency Coordinating Committee established under section 429.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6684F0BC73934EDC87FCE0F4A363B64D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>minority population</term> means a racial and ethnic minority group, as defined in section 1707.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section></title><title id="HBA5902FBB5B94F308441D310C41DAA35"><enum>II</enum><header>CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL AND PREVENTION</header> <section id="H96472192FB4243A5818982E0FDACA086"><enum>201.</enum><header>Research, education, and other activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 317T the following section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H2D2DE25E0FA1427DA5705F4C30E468A0" style="OLC">
					<section id="HCF6DB35F66434E81A22968A959D9FE33"><enum>317U.</enum><header>Diabetes in minority populations</header>
						<subsection id="H0A38E7484BB04C2CB9048B67C58CE26D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research and other activities</header>
 <paragraph id="H886BB08BA3ED46AA8E3F3A4E7CDF1154"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall conduct and support research and public health activities with respect to diabetes in minority populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDA9A010D1534400A7B8FD092963725F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain activities</header><text>Activities under paragraph (1) regarding diabetes in minority populations shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5F1DE7DF0175465A89882B02BE4BCC4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Further enhancing the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey by over-sampling Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Other Pacific Islanders in appropriate geographic areas to better determine the prevalence of diabetes in such populations as well as to improve the data collection of diabetes penetration disaggregated into major ethnic groups within such populations. The Secretary shall ensure that any such oversampling does not reduce the oversampling of other minority populations including African-American and Latino populations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1CCC9932E9E40EC9785ABE05441DD69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Through the Division of Diabetes Translation—</text> <clause id="HD40D3E3EB1004230AD417F79920EF0B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing for prevention research to better understand how to influence health care systems changes to improve quality of care being delivered to such populations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB37780A7BE6F4B5A905B46BCB3CE1A41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>carrying out model demonstration projects to design, implement, and evaluate effective diabetes prevention and control interventions for minority populations, including culturally appropriate community-based interventions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H25DFA02A1D9D4A9EB9F9B85369B5D758"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developing and implementing a strategic plan to reduce diabetes in minority populations through applied research to reduce disparities and culturally and linguistically appropriate community-based interventions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H668677FBDAB94550B8F0424AF4E18F2C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting, through the national diabetes prevention program under section 399V–3, diabetes prevention program sites in underserved regions highly impacted by diabetes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6EB6D08A3BEC4B71A6D5F4C5AF659A49"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing, through the national diabetes prevention program under section 399V–3, a demonstration program developing new metrics measuring health outcomes related to diabetes that can be stratified by specific minority populations.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE0A2F43EDDE46529588E64A50B1A763"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall direct the Division of Diabetes Translation to conduct and support both programs to educate the public on diabetes in minority populations and programs to educate minority populations about the causes and effects of diabetes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4BE9C508CD3C491285F0CD5EB79F4559"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Diabetes; health promotion, prevention activities, and access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Diabetes Education Program, shall conduct and support programs to educate specific minority populations through culturally appropriate and linguistically appropriate information campaigns about prevention of, and managing, diabetes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBA0640A516284078AD36FD70FB1952A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>minority population</term> means a racial and ethnic minority group, as defined in section 1707.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></title><title id="H6CCBF1CE2F574B77B2D2CC65B08EB296"><enum>III</enum><header>HEALTH RESOURCES AND SERVICES ADMINISTRATION</header> <section id="HAE3D261BAECF4B3A85269B0BBE4963F5"><enum>301.</enum><header>Research, education, and other activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H82A9B3C21CCE4CCDAEE39DCFB3EDAC5C" style="OLC">
					<section id="HBA3DAF21DE554462AA7E594D89CB7B5F"><enum>399V–6.</enum><header>Programs to educate health providers on the causes and effects of diabetes in minority populations</header>
 <subsection id="H521666D4DCAD41E0AC60C34B3555659E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall conduct and support programs described in subsection (b) to educate health professionals on the causes and effects of diabetes in minority populations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1CA55829F4A5481583CEF3DE4C6F3073"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Programs</header><text>Programs described in this subsection, with respect to education on diabetes in minority populations, shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H252D5A5616974E2AAED1CE3FED1C5645"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Giving priority, under the primary care training and enhancement program under section 747—</text> <subparagraph id="HCDD5933F0B3C4F20BBB7337BBD7A3E60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to awarding grants to focus on or address diabetes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1C9DBAC54F24BA086E1EE09BBBCAB4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adding minority populations to the list of vulnerable populations that should be served by such grants.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BA14A1592DC4F7BB276503CFA81731B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing additional funds for the Health Careers Opportunity Program, Centers for Excellence, and the Minority Faculty Fellowship Program to partner with the Office of Minority Health under section 1707 and the National Institutes of Health to strengthen programs for career opportunities focused on diabetes treatment and care within underserved regions highly impacted by diabetes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A8170466B1E4E83A3D91E29928ED368"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Developing a diabetes focus within, and providing additional funds for, the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC1CBA5FACC3E4D99BB4DBDA8B054E3BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to place individuals in areas that are disproportionately affected by diabetes and to provide diabetes treatment and care in such areas; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05AE7051D4474F19B236C77CA878FFD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide such individuals continuing medical education specific to diabetes care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></title><title id="H0ACB94A84F944BD58F4130556541B38D"><enum>IV</enum><header>INDIAN HEALTH SERVICE</header> <section id="H31EB5204FF474240A76307760E9E8D38"><enum>401.</enum><header>Research, education, and other activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 301, is further amended by adding at the end the following section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H5D3A76A492A344D1A3A54A874335E863" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA6225404271B494083100A67885EC16E"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Research, education, and other activities regarding diabetes in American Indian populations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to activities under sections 317V–6 and 434B, the Secretary, acting through the Indian Health Service and in collaboration with other appropriate Federal agencies, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H21A3B260170B41D2873E04AA675C34DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct and support research and other activities with respect to diabetes; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H529D7ADF1B884F6F856757B3B0E4C9F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate the collection of data on clinically and culturally appropriate diabetes treatment, care, prevention, and services by health care professionals to the American Indian population.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H14D9CE9FCB894FE4A3EA6A199CEF8AFC"><enum>V</enum><header>INSTITUTE OF MEDICINE REPORT</header>
 <section id="HAF17909D1E634605AE94FD61FBA93C05"><enum>501.</enum><header>Updated report on health disparities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall seek to enter into an arrangement with the Institute of Medicine under which the Institute will—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB86C7D03EBAB4ABBB823C15275EB5A79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to the Congress an updated version of the Institute’s 2002 report entitled <quote><short-title>Unequal Treatment: Confronting Racial and Ethnic Disparities in Health Care</short-title></quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB51671A39A34EDE8E3395B9165DAD61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in such updated version, address how racial and ethnic health disparities have changed since the publication of the original report.</text>
				</paragraph></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


