<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H54065C7A3F394E2989E6B10081A4F427" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 350 EH: Human Trafficking Prevention, Intervention, and Recovery Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 350</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking to identify strategies to prevent children from becoming victims of trafficking and review trafficking prevention efforts, to protect and assist in the recovery of victims of trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA6AB73C839BC4A4CA568658B7F7E370F" style="OLC"><pagebreak/> 
<section id="H17F6920D4F124352868DAE8277AF63B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Human Trafficking Prevention, Intervention, and Recovery Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HBB0D4F1028B64C4ABE5EC1FF97DD4A83"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency task force report on child trafficking primary prevention</header> <subsection id="H9F23C4AFC8474D6E9AC31A8B5A157AF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, established under section 105 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7103">22 U.S.C. 7103</external-xref>), shall conduct a review that, with regard to trafficking in persons in the United States—</text> 
<paragraph id="H858329EC255E485FB18794473B8EEE92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with nongovernmental organizations that the Task Force determines appropriate, surveys and catalogues the activities of the Federal Government and State governments to deter individuals from committing trafficking offenses and to prevent children from becoming victims of trafficking;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DB87D0F7E2743B2B85869BD0AC84B87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>surveys academic literature on deterring individuals from committing trafficking offenses, preventing children from becoming victims of trafficking, the commercial sexual exploitation of children, and other similar topics that the Task Force determines appropriate;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H246327A324CF42D7B523155BDF322623"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies best practices and effective strategies to deter individuals from committing trafficking offenses and to prevent children from becoming victims of trafficking; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5E4D9396A6B471BB83467D39371E8F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifies current gaps in research and data that would be helpful in formulating effective strategies to deter individuals from committing trafficking offenses and to prevent children from becoming victims of trafficking.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H94FA919AE2F14C3898E25B6CDC9CAA8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking shall provide to Congress, and make publicly available in electronic format, a report on the review conducted pursuant to subparagraph (a).</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H727B2C4580DB413DBF90B5D3452B4F68"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO Report on intervention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report, which shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5EA6E177D9BC46338E4F7693E1889726"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on the efforts of Federal and select State law enforcement agencies to combat human trafficking in the United States; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A915C0FC3454C01B84A597FCB32E40F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on each Federal grant program, a purpose of which is to combat human trafficking or assist victims of trafficking, as specified in an authorizing statute or in a guidance document issued by the agency carrying out the grant program.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFEC02BD9959B41E9912933C3B7A2DEDD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Provision of housing permitted to protect and assist in the recovery of victims of trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 107(b)(2)(A) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7105">22 U.S.C. 7105(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, including programs that provide housing to victims of trafficking</quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H8F6F87D35328459F8F38D7FEFDDD8880"><enum>5.</enum><header>Victim of trafficking defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>victim of trafficking</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text> </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20150127" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 27, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


