<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD15D7EC5BBE40AE928CD068C53A5B08" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 559 IH: To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to designate New Jersey Task Force 1 as part of the National Urban Search and Rescue System.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 559</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000372">Mr. Frelinghuysen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000554">Mr. LoBiondo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to designate New Jersey Task
			 Force 1 as part of the National Urban Search and Rescue System.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H121FE7E5F9B544CBA69978147C525716" style="OLC">
		<section id="HC7B5AB2F4B3B4DF0AA3186C50425ABC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Addition of team to national urban search and rescue system</header>
 <subsection id="H8199FCBD5AF84906AF8D7248EF8EFD58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H911CB17A08A44F8BA46E566A1E1BD391"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, demonstrated the importance of enhancing national domestic terrorism preparedness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H657B2BD78375461F99947792983197F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Twenty-six of the 28 urban search and rescue teams included in the National Urban Search and Rescue System of the Federal Emergency Management Agency were called into action in the wake of the events of September 11th.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H807C7D71929C48D09A7C698794D6F970"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Highly qualified, urban search and rescue teams not included in the National Urban Search and Rescue System were the first teams in New York City on September 11th.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBA60265EACE4B7281F4CF75E4979220"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The continuing threat of a possible domestic terrorist attack remains an important mission for which the Nation must prepare to respond.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CF123872E304013A250EA9F73E547AB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Part of that response should be to increase the number of urban search and rescue teams included in the National Urban Search and Rescue System.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7595B3E23D8497F8A3DEB66B270EC67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Addition of new jersey task force 1</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall designate New Jersey Task Force 1 as part of the National Urban Search and Rescue System.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


