<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF24992E4CA9247ED98DA4C9CB028C3BC" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1359 IH: American Dream Accounts Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1359</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150313">March 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To authorize the establishment of American Dream Accounts.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H1E63702506F8412F85E09E041D5AC8A8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFD63AD897BBF4939BC5AA87886EC43D5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Dream Accounts Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAA2DCCAA22DB445DBB92E8EF5B6C7070"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6BF531C494C5467B959F12D4402748A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Only 9.8 out of every 100 individuals from low-income families will graduate from an institution of higher education before reaching the age of 24.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C826008CAB24E6EAAF0E2A16913E8D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Lack of knowledge about how to apply to, and pay for, an institution of higher education is a barrier for many low-income students and students who would be in the first generation in their families to attend an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49FD96DAA4564165B6CCAAA3D3093F3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to Public Agenda, most young adults give secondary school counselors fair or poor ratings for advice about attending an institution of higher education, including advice about how to decide what institution of higher education to attend, how to pay for higher education, what careers to pursue, and how to apply to an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4688A78444B54DD69C119D2A8F2CB993"><enum>(4)</enum><text>More than 1,700,000 students fail to file the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA), and about one-third of such students would qualify for a Federal Pell Grant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05C3D8AA0B6442CE8398D4488D28E598"><enum>(5)</enum><text>During the last 2 decades, costs of attending institutions of higher education have increased dramatically, but need-based financial aid has not kept pace with such increasing costs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F9B0EC0358F4E0D837B6BCDC2A5CE13"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In the 1990–1991 school year, the maximum Federal Pell Grant covered 45 percent of the average cost of attendance at a public 4-year institution of higher education (including tuition, fees, room, and board), but in the 2010–2011 school year, the maximum Federal Pell Grant covered only 34 percent of such cost.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC163937497F5422B97BC7160F205360F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Parental and youth college savings are strong predictors of a youth’s expectations about attendance at an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FA50169734045EA8B6DD330F1422254"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Only 32 percent of parents who earn less than $35,000 a year are saving for their child’s education at an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF02A61657F0F4047B958118E1E5FD43F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to the Center for Social Development, <term>wilt</term> occurs when a young person who expects to graduate from a 4-year institution of higher education has not yet attended such institution by the ages of 19 to 22.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED27DADAFA70433FA1EFEF194D5BF5FD"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Children who have savings dedicated for attendance at an institution of higher education are 4 times more likely to attend a 4-year institution of higher education and avoid <term>wilt</term>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF6BC9D20C0504027BD13459ED658D5FE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H16BC4C14F3AC4F138FA553D8F64AD0EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>American dream account</header><text>The term <term>American Dream Account</term> means a personal online account for low-income students that monitors higher education readiness and includes a college savings account.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3452AD06C08D49A19D3CDA7A6FA9C736"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and the Committee on Education and the Workforce, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, as well as any other Committee of the Senate or House of Representatives that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25F880BA96BC438FA6275375B092B631"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Charter school</header><text>The term <term>charter school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5210 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221i">20 U.S.C. 7221i</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H425A10DB070842D9966624B9251D98D8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>College savings account</header><text>The term <term>college savings account</term> means a trust created or organized exclusively for the purpose of paying the qualified expenses of only an individual who, when the trust is created or organized, has not obtained 18 years of age, if the written governing instrument creating the trust contains the following requirements:</text> <subparagraph id="H49148749093748DA8B0F6AF68793DF6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The trustee is a federally insured financial institution, or a State insured financial institution if a federally insured financial institution is not available.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46BAAFBA265C46129F2D56D159C9DF45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The assets of the trust will be invested in accordance with the direction of the individual or of a parent or guardian of the individual, after consultation with the entity providing the initial contribution to the trust or, if applicable, a matching or other contribution for the individual.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71502017911541E5B67139DEEA535236"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The assets of the trust will not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BC50ADB529B45F3BD67D452429190D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any amount in the trust that is attributable to an account seed or matched deposit may be paid or distributed from the trust only for the purpose of paying qualified expenses of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95D37CAE6C48444AB144EA5F98762FB4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dual or concurrent enrollment program</header><text>The term <term>dual or concurrent enrollment program</term> means a program of study—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H617F7B72FC1F462CBF1BEF4CF567A56B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provided by an institution of higher education through which a student who has not graduated from high school with a regular high school diploma (as defined in 34 C.F.R. 200.19(b)(1)(iv), as such section was in effect on November 28, 2008) is able to earn postsecondary credit; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4CA1D2FD8DA4BD6B7347990C716A5BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that shall consist of not less than 2 postsecondary credit-bearing courses and support and academic services that help a student persist and complete such courses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H911AC8EC353A4C3695AC15F5CB81A9BE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Early college high school program</header><text>The term <term>early college high school program</term> means a formal partnership between at least 1 local educational agency and at least 1 institution of higher education that allows participants, who are primarily low-income students, to simultaneously complete requirements toward earning a regular high school diploma (as defined in 34 C.F.R. 200.19(b)(1)(iv), as such section was in effect on November 28, 2008) and earn not less than 12 transferable credits as part of an organized course of study toward a postsecondary degree or credential.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CBAE1001A5F4BD5BCEA5CF23E1C55C6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7264B9D8848C4852A54A99C0130DBED1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State educational agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C8E952DEC094A59A13CA136E65C537A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a local educational agency, including a charter school that operates as its own local educational agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A9782AB9F71447BADB40D65E85C77CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a charter management organization or charter school authorizer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9CBEEE5B2434F108A2123267460FA52"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an institution of higher education or a Tribal College or University;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0030B9E229FA4C8C8AA40D8BB5402B40"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE073B54702154C98A1C2736303543C06"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an entity with demonstrated experience in educational savings or in assisting low-income students to prepare for, and attend, an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18ADCE91451845288847323FF9F6561F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a consortium of 2 or more of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (F); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB704C82691D2465BAA007D5BFBD1749C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a consortium of 1 or more of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) and a public school, a charter school, a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, or a tribally controlled school.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F6573FB98F04A1AA98E5522303A756A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BF3B348CB44443896CD80D881789A8D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF13533B5AF9B4611B1F77F68CDCD654B"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Low-income student</header><text>The term <term>low-income student</term> means a student who is eligible to receive a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FD571EBCB19472E94A3B5638156E674"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Parent</header><text>The term <term>parent</term> has the meaning given such term in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9AF05E53A2DC4124A6855B139C34B503"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Qualified expenses</header><text>The term <term>qualified expenses</term> means, with respect to an individual, expenses that—</text> <subparagraph id="H710D19BD741748AC8B780E6F7353116A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are incurred after the individual receives a secondary school diploma or its recognized equivalent; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9736DAD610A4914B9FA3FCA6159992A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are associated with attending an institution of higher education, including—</text> <clause id="H7AF2ADBCA4E84B6A8190832B0CDF12B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>tuition and fees;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H749CDAC7F5604CB19735F7CD6A089BB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>room and board;</text></clause> <clause id="H7DC9B3878C144C48AD295DE6AB8A54FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>textbooks;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAB2F2B34CE454C09887825DD2600027F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>supplies and equipment; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8E749AF1B897486CA4FFB86DB002E547"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Internet access.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H453DB5CAEAEB4345B6B7B8258B788AED"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFACA660227B545F8A128986686A72AC6"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4316D362D16646C88AACADB9C72F020F"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Tribal College or University</header><text>The term <term>Tribal College or University</term> has the meaning given such term in section 316(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EACF28FE20F4B229AC9700843DF55B1"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Tribally controlled school</header><text>The term <term>tribally controlled school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5212 of the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2511">25 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H876FFA2F5ECF4E669ABC66F354BB64A6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant program</header> 
<subsection id="HE8DD4B910FE04482A3A295FEA52C3C32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program Authorized</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities to establish and administer American Dream Accounts for a group of low-income students.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD4EB7C582AEA4AE4A7E62AC5AEC9A5AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>From the amounts appropriated each fiscal year to carry out this Act, the Secretary shall reserve not more than 5 percent of such amount to carry out the evaluation activities described in section 7.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5776543433B492EA8A075A2AC8DEBDD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this Act shall be for a period of not more than 3 years. The Secretary may extend such grant for an additional 2-year period if the Secretary determines that the eligible entity has demonstrated significant progress, based on the factors described in section 5(b)(11).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0EB54E710DAB4CF59B9538D972A83D9F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Applications; priority</header> <subsection id="H8F4FF33D90DF4500B285F73CB1FF0A0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Each eligible entity desiring a grant under this Act shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C9E3D7071C64C9DA33E68BA53FD194E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>At a minimum, the application described in subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEF7892C455824EDF81E34C5F0F86A917"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the characteristics of a group of not less than 30 low-income public school students who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3B6075F285E44D49AC47F5581F8A5AD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are, at the time of the application, attending a grade not higher than grade 9; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89C7D96C01564E80BB9277F23D51DE8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will, under the grant, receive an American Dream Account.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56E768D5137F42C7B5D0FB400F362D89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will engage, and provide support (such as tutoring and mentoring for students, and training for teachers and other stakeholders) either online or in person, to—</text> <subparagraph id="H4094CE737FCB42BEA2391C3A1DC044BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the students in the group described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48E99899E81A48A884BD1E1C09EBF8A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the family members and teachers of such students; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1ED4997F3E14BECA3A476695891191A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other stakeholders such as school administrators and school counselors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H226EF1EAADB2472B88EC070A6978C703"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An identification of partners who will assist the eligible entity in establishing and sustaining American Dream Accounts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECA85707FD4244D390FDE706F78A7A71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of what experience the eligible entity or the partners of the eligible entity have in managing college savings accounts, preparing low-income students for postsecondary education, managing online systems, and teaching financial literacy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF90E5792286E4C3D94034F393A9E4E42"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A demonstration that the eligible entity has sufficient resources to provide an initial deposit into the college savings account portion of each American Dream Account.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB2F5BFDD15D49D48C77ED1A3F5462BE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will help increase the value of the college savings account portion of each American Dream Account, such as by providing matching funds or incentives for academic achievement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H842E307A60EF49E09DB4F79278B5BC9A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will notify each participating student in the group described in paragraph (1), on a semiannual basis, of the current balance and status of the college savings account portion of the American Dream Account of the student.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A26C8022C0F4EE8BF1EC61DC3DDF4C3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A plan that describes how the eligible entity will monitor participating students in the group described in paragraph (1) to ensure that the American Dream Account of each student will be maintained if a student in such group changes schools before graduating from secondary school.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFA58AAAA4BC4642A301066DEF1B657A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A plan that describes how the American Dream Accounts will be managed for not less than 1 year after a majority of the students in the group described in paragraph (1) graduate from secondary school.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37ADD874A75B4521A3980279E916991B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will encourage students in the group described in paragraph (1) who fail to graduate from secondary school to continue their education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2C159903C9A4C65BB182A157F299455"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will evaluate the grant program, including by collecting, as applicable, the following data about the students in the group described in paragraph (1) during the grant period, or until the time of graduation from a secondary school, whichever comes first, and, if sufficient grant funds are available, after the grant period:</text> <subparagraph id="H6E11EC7F135549F8B0C08C8A1B0D5C1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Attendance rates.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7B40255632B429E81EC0DE14E053AFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Progress reports.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB85F28C583BE498D828E7851C4879358"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Grades and course selections.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HACE75B82B61A4E94B91C1AD18326F859"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The student graduation rate, as defined in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(vi) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(C)(vi)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF29893EFC3B4BCDB9EECCB307C4A825"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Rates of student completion of the Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1090">20 U.S.C. 1090</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6ABE8908861D491C8CB325CFD4E1981D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Rates of enrollment in an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71D60019B73E482D89F15B0A693397D6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Rates of completion at an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BF24C0FD7DF40B787028FC05C7A9CF1"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A description of what will happen to the funds in the college savings account portion of the American Dream Accounts that are dedicated to participating students described in paragraph (1) who have not matriculated at an institution of higher education at the time of the conclusion of the period of American Dream Account management described in paragraph (9), including how the eligible entity will give students this information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EC06201757C4491B365527E463E9BC2"><enum>(13)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will ensure that participating students described in paragraph (1) will have access to the Internet.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0D1B1393B6D471A91D8DE409CF99EB7"><enum>(14)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will take into consideration how funds in the college savings account portion of American Dream Accounts will affect participating families' eligibility for public assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H86B5C714F6C34D1DAB1466630C4975EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this Act, the Secretary shall give priority to applications from eligible entities that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDA614DFC363E4A42B1554B42829968F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are described in subparagraph (G) or (H) of section 3(7);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2295961A3EE41F3AAE7E3E27866921B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve the largest number of low-income students;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E27092775714030A16F86CD2FCD1675"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 3(7), provide opportunities for participating students described in subsection (b)(1) to participate in a dual or concurrent enrollment program or early college high school program at no cost to the student or the student's family; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C4E65C0503C45C8A68591862D6F88AB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>as of the time of application, have been awarded a grant under chapter 2 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-21">20 U.S.C. 1070a–21 et seq.</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>GEAR UP program</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBC870D4B25C448049EDBB64A097B7B6D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorized activities</header> 
<subsection id="H213CD9597D39488282414B1DBB4D33B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall use such grant funds to establish an American Dream Account for each participating student described in section 5(b)(1), that will be used to—</text> <paragraph id="H7BFCBBF970ED4B15A4EE6F738AB1EDD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>open a college savings account for such student;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4CCEC31C183447CA31D3BEE0033ABFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>monitor the progress of such student online, which—</text> <subparagraph id="H6B0A1DF78BE94597A313DC9FAE5EA636"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include monitoring student data relating to—</text> 
<clause id="H6811603F46B04920909501213E63DA93"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grades and course selections;</text></clause> <clause id="H48CB468D56D4448F9EFD76D4FCE62EF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>progress reports; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H51428AA7EDC6428AB9298A9904DAD719"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>attendance and disciplinary records; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CCFE6FB86D14181AD31EBD189E1E4D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may also include monitoring student data relating to a broad range of information, provided by teachers and family members, related to postsecondary education readiness, access, and completion;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDF18BE497CF4FC499879056E31995B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide opportunities for such students, either online or in person, to learn about financial literacy, including by—</text> <subparagraph id="H108D1FB9DB2E42D2B6800E3321DC92A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assisting such students in financial planning for enrollment in an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E3E6A0F234143BDA0FCA38FBEB148B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assisting such students in identifying and applying for financial aid (such as loans, grants, and scholarships) for an institution of higher education; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC024FF16F17145B0A4D87F964522F8F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhancing student understanding of consumer, economic, and personal finance concepts;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5335E452D00D4B4DBF228BC0049951FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide opportunities for such students, either online or in person, to learn about preparing for enrollment in an institution of higher education, including by providing instruction to students about—</text> <subparagraph id="HA11675C3A9E1498FABED83A720C68182"><enum>(A)</enum><text>choosing the appropriate courses to prepare for postsecondary education;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC98F987425D94A21B459158532139DEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applying to an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54B3755127FD485EBFCC9D27CDDF710C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>building a student portfolio, which may be used when applying to an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCD939D63B65543A0A402F3F55DA12E69"><enum>(D)</enum><text>selecting an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F79048714E3410F902BD64E4A909CAE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>choosing a major for the student's postsecondary program of education or a career path; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B5E34C2458F403688CB60071866F9A1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>adapting to life at an institution of higher education; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA617463E05334D8DABA5BD7D3E2A1EA2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide opportunities for such students, either online or in person, to identify skills or interests, including career interests.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1FEE937BE14E4E8396A706B7B8460579"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Access to American Dream Account</header> 
<paragraph id="HA1B2693EFECE451B978EA06B066AC66D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), and in accordance with applicable Federal laws and regulations relating to privacy of information and the privacy of children, an eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall allow vested stakeholders, as described in paragraph (2), to have secure access, through an Internet website, to an American Dream Account.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F4CC23736D145A295FA71A0B48D4350"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vested stakeholders</header><text>The vested stakeholders that an eligible entity shall permit to access an American Dream Account are individuals (such as the student's teachers, school counselors, school administrators, or other individuals) that are designated, in accordance with section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>, commonly known as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>), by the parent of a participating student in whose name such American Dream Account is held, as having permission to access the account. A student's parent may withdraw such designation from an individual at any time.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D1CAF82FED24D5C8EDFD594DA58A5D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for college savings account</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall not be required to give vested stakeholders, as described in paragraph (2), access to the college savings account portion of a student's American Dream Account.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB451308D3D6F4829A2F0B0D79266168B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adult students</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), if a participating student is age 18 or older, an eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall not provide access to such participating student's American Dream Account without the student's consent, in accordance with section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>, commonly known as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFB6603421E34C87AD0D9B3F43B034F4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Input of student information</header><text>Student data collected pursuant to subsection (a)(2)(A) shall be entered into an American Dream Account only by a school administrator or the designee of such administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H490C8945F8CC46AD9D978DC7C5EBBA41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of student information</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall not use any student-level information or data for the purpose of soliciting, advertising, or marketing any financial or non-financial consumer product or service that is offered by such eligible entity, or on behalf of any other person.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H04AB1121F85B4348ACB00E2E0BD7D432"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of grant funds</header><text>An eligible entity shall not use grant funds provided under this Act to provide the initial deposit into a college savings account portion of a student's American Dream Account.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1111C6104C5447A98326E805FA74DC1D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reports and evaluations</header> <subsection id="HB7566AA5A807434BA11802F7F6267313"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the Secretary has disbursed grants under this Act, and annually thereafter until each grant disbursed under this Act has ended, the Secretary shall prepare and submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress, which shall include an evaluation of the effectiveness of the grant program established under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1BB48AFACB5243FCACFE0A0146E11EA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0FE24116AAED4E35AC86014582C5A2B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>list the grants that have been awarded under section 4(a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCD0ECB895E4472AB97EE4E34F25CCAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include the number of students who have an American Dream Account established through a grant awarded under section 4(a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82A0AA0809A84910AA12EB6F38EAE627"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide data (including the interest accrued on college savings accounts that are part of an American Dream Account) in the aggregate, regarding students who have an American Dream Account established through a grant awarded under section 4(a), as compared to similarly situated students who do not have an American Dream Account;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14E2A5C5124E4411B841599DC32715F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify best practices developed by the eligible entities receiving grants under this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD564D1004FDF4278AAA151C66C68CC2F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify any issues related to student privacy and stakeholder accessibility to American Dream Accounts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A1572C4174B4DB8B4CACA0A97E083EA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide feedback from participating students and the parents of such students about the grant program, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HC0C1469E7E2B46EDB1E0DEE5C1F37FF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the impact of the program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C5E5AF17A694D6FA049E9491406AA62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>aspects of the program that are successful;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8E8625ADA8A47D4A44BC7DA85F6F8A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>aspects of the program that are not successful; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FFC759BDC2041479592C4C7D7715CC6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other data required by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0ED63116122C4D45BDEB0082177BF531"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide recommendations for expanding the American Dream Accounts program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF3B5F4C44DE04ABCBA9893F7CC17042A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Eligibility to receive Federal student financial aid</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any funds that are in the college savings account portion of a student's American Dream Account shall not affect such student's eligibility to receive Federal student financial aid, including any Federal student financial aid under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), and shall not be considered in determining the amount of any such Federal student aid.</text></section> <section id="H3D04FB9D6A784053BF3628EDF6CFFF31"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2016 and each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


