<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDFA0489C15DB434AA7F248FCCF6AF209" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1413 IH: Firearms Manufacturers and Dealers Protection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1413</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150317">March 17, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001057">Mr. Huelskamp</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To terminate Operation Choke Point.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H36D44FE737CB40F6820C2837F47C08C6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD932159F4B224E50A86E1B7DDDEB920C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Firearms Manufacturers and Dealers Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2517F767F603462BA14EF42E87A78DA9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H62428F0832564AA9B2113AD7FE05F174"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA6170E48A75148C8BD75752B30DA7268"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Because of the actions of the Department of Justice and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (referred to in this section as the <term>FDIC</term>), the program known as <quote>Operation Choke Point</quote> has become a threat to the Second Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and to firearms dealers and manufacturers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF12DA4B33D74825A1DDAC4538563434"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the summer of 2011, the FDIC published an article in which it designated firearms sales and ammunition sales as <quote>high-risk</quote> industries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FA9A5C46956428EBA9BC8B826F52F4C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The article published by the FDIC thus put manufacturers and dealers of firearms in the same category as cable box descramblers, credit card schemes, drug paraphernalia, escort services, get-rich products, home-based charities, lottery sales, online gambling, payday loans, Ponzi schemes, pornography, racist materials, and tobacco sales.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DA07B58DE7144FEB50BA9D5A4F91F31"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Most of the businesses grouped with the sale of firearms and ammunition involve activities that are inherently pernicious or patently illegal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97C2F17A3E934C94962EBC7AD2FA0C16"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The obvious intent, therefore, of the inclusion of businesses in the FDIC's <quote>high-risk</quote> category was the eradication of those businesses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F935E1B65574C53A22787945DB2B941"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The FDIC sought to achieve this eradication by encouraging banks to withdraw credit provided to targeted industries and otherwise terminate financial relationships with the businesses in question.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCB883BD9DFD490AA304C8E023988030"><enum>(7)</enum><text>FDIC officials discussed mechanisms for guaranteeing that bank officials saw the list and <quote>[got] the message</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H101ECE5D7EA543ADA2F5ED93D647ACCD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The FDIC and the Department of Justice worked together to implement Operation Choke Point to actively realize the objective of eradicating <quote>high-risk</quote> industries such as the sale of firearms and ammunition.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H136D5B8314AA422181AA77EF823CD53D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, the FDIC and the Department of Justice <quote>may have misled Congress about this partnership</quote> in connection with Operation Choke Point.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CB9FDEFD1384F6FA949DF057A367CEB"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Committee language in both the House of Representatives and Senate versions of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/235">Public Law 113–235</external-xref>) completely defunded Operation Choke Point.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C5B707E088B474D869AF34BB1AFF09B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In order to salvage Operation Choke Point, the FDIC removed firearms sales and ammunition sales from the list of <quote>high-risk</quote> industries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H809AA5B3A82F4632A95F12C8FC212313"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Even after that action, however, there is evidence that the FDIC and the Department of Justice continue to use Operation Choke Point to target firearms dealers such as Hawkins Guns LLC of Hawkins, Wisconsin.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HAD904BA9B9D6476DA2ECE103E2CB0AAB"><enum>(13)</enum><text>There is evidence that the targeting of Hawkins Guns LLC is far from an isolated incident.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89DCE13C194C4E7AAD0908C12A60CC48"><enum>(14)</enum><text>It has become clear that the FDIC and the Department of Justice can no longer be trusted to carry out Operation Choke Point without targeting the Second Amendment and firearm dealers and manufacturers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2F4E7BC2A22E4BF0BCD1346F0C40B372"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to terminate Operation Choke Point and any similar program that attempts to infringe upon the Second Amendment or eradicate the manufacture and sale of firearms and ammunition.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6D32575097AC446BAE800AE27063FF8C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection of the Second Amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No amounts appropriated or otherwise made available under any provision of law enacted before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act, nor any amounts derived from any fee or other source, may be used by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Department of Justice, or any other Federal agency to carry out Operation Choke Point or any other program designed to discourage the provision or continuation of credit or the processing of payments by financial institutions for dealers and manufacturers of firearms and ammunition.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


