<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H38AFF612520146DFBAA1F74F40E3E4C8" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3259 IH: To grant authority to the President to detain non-diplomatic officials of the Government of Iran in the United States and non-diplomatic officials of the Government of Iran in certain other countries until all United States citizens held by the Government of Iran are released and returned to the United States, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3259</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To grant authority to the President to detain non-diplomatic officials of the Government of Iran in the United States and non-diplomatic officials of the Government of Iran in certain other countries until all United States citizens held by the Government of Iran are released and returned to the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD75B3EE732A5412EB47D32C0A7188091" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HABEC6D14F4364940B884AA88612CE892" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Congressional finding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that the Government of Iran is unjustly holding at least three United States citizens, Jason Rezaian, Saeed Abedini, and Amir Hekmati, and possibly Robert Levinson, as hostages.</text></section> <section id="H45EACF341AA74821BFA7C2C9BF991A11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority to detain non-diplomatic officials of the Government of Iran</header> <subsection id="HA9524849235B418C8AC580FFE33636D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President is authorized to take such actions as may be necessary to detain—</text> 
<paragraph id="H01F7F07D94654ECEA0598850F7E0EAB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>non-diplomatic officials of the Government of Iran in the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC87A9A31B1A42D1B55CC147980C0C3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">non-diplomatic officials of the Government of Iran in any other country if the government of such country provides authority in advance to the United States to take such actions to detain such officials in such country.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A4115AF9C984C28BDF15F96F3FD5B80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority of subsection (a) shall expire on the date on which the United States citizens described in section 1 have been released and returned to the United States or the date on which the Government of Iran provides to the United States Government a full accounting of the whereabouts of Robert Levinson, whichever occurs later.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

