<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE9564D75C09F464BAC05F7B453BBE7B7" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4093 IH: Library of Congress Administrative Reform Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4093</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151119">November 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To revise certain administrative and management authorities of the Librarian of Congress, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCA3005BA22FA43AE99DED43FC394D87C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8A32DA0347F74516A1A4F3AF566FE1D3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Library of Congress Administrative Reform Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF9F0383862004D57B5EEA9EE5427EB63"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorizing National Library Service for the Blind and Physically Handicapped to provide playback equipment in all formats</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The first sentence of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide books for the adult blind</quote>, approved March 3, 1931 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/135a">2 U.S.C. 135a</external-xref>), is amended by striking <quote>and for purchase, maintenance, and replacement of reproducers for such sound-reproduction recordings</quote> and inserting <quote>and for purchase, maintenance, and replacement of reproducers for any such forms</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H3424B6F2679C4DD3B9DBD33D22924DB6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Library of Congress National Collection Stewardship Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H30D71EAF80D84767B01E92ACD4803CC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States, as an account for the Librarian of Congress, the <quote>Library of Congress National Collection Stewardship Fund</quote> (hereafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA7559FD49EDD435DAE798FBA22EF9029"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of Fund</header><text>The Fund shall consist of the following amounts:</text> <paragraph id="H2F13C0AC305F404F86BCFED0123394BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Such amounts as may be transferred by the Librarian from amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the Library of Congress under the heading <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09BF8025FC1B4791B3155B72FC94FC6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such amounts as may be transferred by the Architect of the Capitol from amounts appropriated for any fiscal year for the Architect of the Capitol under the heading <quote>Library of Congress Buildings and Grounds</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0D8D204AA5B4854BFEA5C3AE4837EFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such amounts as may be appropriated to the Fund under law.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD9D7454098E48D8ABD5EA408A3D2DE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Fund may be used by the Librarian as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H06423A65A5FB4DD58650010FB8364FFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Librarian may use amounts directly for the purpose of preparing collection materials of the Library of Congress for long-term storage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E2B07FDBA1B40CE840296FA227568F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Librarian may transfer amounts to the Architect of the Capitol for the purpose of designing, constructing, altering, upgrading, and equipping collections preservation and storage facilities for the Library of Congress, or for the purpose of acquiring real property by lease for the preservation and storage of Library of Congress collections in accordance with section 1102 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1823a">2 U.S.C. 1823a</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BD4CE06C5554EF4BC0F6E4ED09AF06E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continuing Availability of Funds</header><text>Any amounts in the Fund shall remain available until expended.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H0182B92490994CC9A28D094CA1B047D5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Librarian and the Architect of the Capitol shall submit a joint report on the Fund to the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9D3857C136A74D068090B9757922FAA7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Initial 5-Year Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Librarian shall submit to the Joint Committee on the Library and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report providing a plan for expenditures from the Fund for the first 5 fiscal years of the Fund’s operation.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB925901BE4FC43A0AAC49608C88CA816"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expanding uses of certain revolving funds</header>
 <subsection id="HD508574BDE75430883C7F11BB31577DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Audiovisual Conservation Center Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101 of the Library of Congress Fiscal Operations Improvement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/182a">2 U.S.C. 182a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H344EAE666BFE4DECAF290FBE5ACBF21B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">duplication</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF15F5565D2584A45931DC1905DDAD35F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA8431DBD081B4EFF9049241FE44B84D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>duplication and delivery services provided by the Librarian</quote> and inserting <quote>the following programs and activities of the Librarian</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8639D20E27574B1AB82425043A1CA01F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting a colon; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB2D0EF563224230A84C20BD34904AC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD5F58C499544015B7ADB50812A31C9F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H1242361286CF4734A927316443E2C922"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Services related to the duplication and preservation of audiovisual materials and associated collections.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BC417C63896448D82DB112722DC466B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Storage, inspection, and delivery of audiovisual materials and associated collections.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA92288A7B38440209FE35FAC74DDE353"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revolving Fund for Gift Shop and Related Services</header><text>Section 102 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/182b">2 U.S.C. 182b</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEA824B94EACC43C6A5598C6CD1A03B71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">gift shop</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">sales and other services</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H635A3B6FC64949A4B7979B448853D1FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9369376BCD3E4874B71B546EC8314E41" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H9CCA4172EC3744499DD2331710CE3348"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Traveling exhibitions and exhibition materials.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD623173C029C425280415A4D16ACDE9A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Training.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H180DA94AF72D4B64A133634C6F8C3B3B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of Tribal Governments in FEDLINK Program</header><text>Section 103(f)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/182c">2 U.S.C. 182c(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>Federal Government,</quote> the following: <quote>tribal governments (as defined in section 502(c)(3)(B) of title 40, United States Code),</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H93D4757DC5B545E7BF9E7C571A324AFA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to accept gifts and bequests</header> <subsection id="H374C2D2AF1C04A78940C2C32496BB87E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expanding types of gifts that may be accepted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first undesignated paragraph of section 4 of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to create a Library of Congress Trust Fund Board, and for other purposes</quote>, approved March 3, 1925 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/160">2 U.S.C. 160</external-xref>), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H83FA30E3779148F9810F87D95113D747"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>in the name of the United States</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>in the name of the United States and in the interest of the Library, its collections, or its service gifts or bequests of personal property, nonpersonal services, voluntary and uncompensated personal services, or money for immediate disbursement.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0465CE77AC654777985D07E89590D07E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>of money</quote> after <quote>bequests</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H468F9B7CCAA44D349724801EDB78B058"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by striking <quote>enter them</quote> and inserting <quote>enter the gift, bequest, or proceeds</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD79AEC5B08A94A008AE8E6EAA55DE543"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of gifts of securities</header><text>The first undesignated paragraph of section 4 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/160">2 U.S.C. 160</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the first sentence the following new sentence: <quote>In the case of a gift of securities, the Librarian shall sell the gift and provide the donor with a receipt from the proceeds of the sale.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9B6906581C9F4535852DF396229A2294"><enum>6.</enum><header>Continuation of service of returning members of Joint Committee on the Library at beginning of
			 Congress</header>
			<subsection id="HAA9719F1DBE24C028B737C4A7C0E1EB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Continuation of Service</header>
 <paragraph id="H527C83AAA54A43369E2A77CC3495CD74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on the first day of a Congress and ending on the date described in paragraph (2), any Member of Congress who served as a member of the Joint Committee on the Library during the previous Congress shall continue to serve as a member of the Joint Committee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF45C628520E48C1B3A8C36D748C3D1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date described</header><text>The date described in this paragraph is, with respect to a Congress—</text> <subparagraph id="H15DF112DAB9C477A844403636F3AEDF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a Member of Congress who is a Member of the House of Representatives, the date on which Members of the House are appointed to serve on the Joint Committee for the Congress; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27576ADD1B82430580B3C5A50454AF15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a Member of Congress who is a Senator, the date on which Senators are appointed to serve on the Joint Committee for the Congress.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21F79ACD8E9B4465A493EDB70F6BB159"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming Amendment</header><text>The final undesignated paragraph under the heading <quote>Senate.</quote> in section 2 of the Act of March 3, 1883 (chapter 141; 22 Stat. 592) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/133">2 U.S.C. 133</external-xref>), is hereby repealed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0BB4FFD4E8B44108E19C73ABE9A02F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>This section and the amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to the One Hundred Fifteenth Congress and each succeeding Congress.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HB7647F2DCC8848A3AE408D45DC2BCE88"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2016 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


