<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB40B205200948DB82C3B6F15A34DF96" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3185 IH: Equality Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3185</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000373">Mr. Ashford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000287">Mr. Becerra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O’Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000197">Ms. Pelosi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000030">Ms. Loretta Sanchez of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000473">Mr. Takai</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000622">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit discrimination on the basis of sex, gender identity, and sexual orientation, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H736E390D2B2244D3834E068A48FE542D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7B96CC4921A94559B38EEBACD5589BF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equality Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD3B9F4D62FA0462D82B460456D96EE98"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H672D669140064A5387929A27E5E2E03D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Discrimination can occur on the basis of the sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition of an individual, as well as because of sex-based stereotypes. Each of these factors alone can serve as the basis for discrimination, and each is a form of sex discrimination.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9017969A854948C494AED5D20091A285"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A single instance of discrimination may have more than 1 basis. For example, discrimination against a married same-sex couple could be based on the sex stereotype that marriage should only be between heterosexual couples, the sexual orientation of the 2 individuals in the couple, or both. Discrimination against a pregnant lesbian could be based on her sex, her sexual orientation, her pregnancy, or on the basis of multiple factors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E81A3ED065C4B6ABD80D176651BE736"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (referred to as <quote>LGBT</quote>) people commonly experience discrimination in securing access to public accommodations—including restaurants, stores, places of or establishments that provide entertainment, and transportation. Forms of discrimination include the exclusion and denial of entry, unequal or unfair treatment, harassment, and violence. This discrimination prevents the full participation of LGBT people in society and disrupts the free flow of commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD90EDFCAB87049C3BC9BD792EEEB5D51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Women also face discrimination, in establishments such as stores and restaurants, and places or establishments that provide other goods or services, such as entertainment or transportation, including sexual harassment, differential pricing, and denial of services because they are pregnant or breastfeeding.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2011BFD8BCFD40C3913F6B802CCEDA2E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Regular and ongoing discrimination against LGBT people, as well as women, in accessing public accommodations contributes to negative social and economic outcomes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H265039E6BDD040359E58CE10B4923111"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Both LGBT people and women face widespread discrimination in employment and various services, including by entities that receive Federal financial assistance. Such discrimination—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1D41C401657E4180BC60B69D897EED45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is particularly troubling and inappropriate for programs and services funded wholly or in part by the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26F5464E16B2446DB348844CC876C8CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>undermines national progress toward equal treatment regardless of sex, sexual orientation, or gender identity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D0FD85C4E8746A6B2F759025754C908"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is inconsistent with the constitutional principle of equal protection under the Fourteenth Amendment of the Constitution of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H380898428B5C4783892F68657AE977EB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Workers who are LGBT, or are perceived to be LGBT, have been subjected to a history and pattern of persistent, widespread, and pervasive discrimination on the bases of sexual orientation and gender identity by private sector employers and Federal, State, and local government employers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD01A489EB48F4065A4703FCAE8DB6BB9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Numerous provisions of Federal law expressly prohibit discrimination on the basis of sex, and Federal agencies and courts have correctly interpreted these prohibitions on sex discrimination to include discrimination based on sexual orientation, gender identity, and sex stereotypes. In particular, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission has explicitly interpreted sex discrimination to include sexual orientation and gender identity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4294F98B981B457AA7FCA752A221A39A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The absence of explicit prohibitions of discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity under Federal statutory law, as well as some conflicting case law on how broadly sex discrimination provisions apply, has created uncertainty for employers and other entities covered by these laws. This lack of clear coverage also causes unnecessary hardships for LGBT people.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AA188C65B9C4B79AE593AC2454C0E2C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>LGBT people often face discrimination when seeking to rent or purchase housing, as well as in every other aspect of obtaining and maintaining housing. LGBT people in same-sex relationships are often discriminated against when 2 names associated with 1 gender appear on a housing application, and transgender people often encounter discrimination when credit checks or inquiries reveal a former name.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE4B9A69F9DF4D49B05BCDB98BEA5F15"><enum>(11)</enum><text>National surveys, including a study commissioned by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, show that housing discrimination against LGBT people is very prevalent. For instance, when same-sex couples inquire about housing that is available for rent, they are less likely to receive positive responses from landlords. According to other studies, transgender people have half the homeownership rate of non-transgender people and about 1 in 5 transgender people experience homelessness.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03EE58B963CA419AB33E5F05999995FC"><enum>(12)</enum><text>As a result of the absence of explicit prohibitions against discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity, credit applicants who are LGBT, or perceived to be LGBT, have unequal opportunities to establish credit. LGBT people can experience being denied a mortgage, credit card, student loan, or many other types of credit simply because of their sexual orientation or gender identity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC02B51DE906249748043C2B9794EE00E"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Numerous studies demonstrate that LGBT people, especially transgender people and women, are economically disadvantaged and at a higher risk for poverty compared with other groups of people.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BCC635732F34098848EFE6B75127E5E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The right to an impartial jury of one’s peers and the reciprocal right to jury service are fundamental to the free and democratic system of justice in the United States and are based in the Bill of Rights. There is, however, an unfortunate and long-documented history in the United States of attorneys discriminating against LGBT individuals, or those perceived to be LGBT, in jury selection. Failure to bar peremptory challenges based on the actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity of an individual not only erodes a fundamental right, duty, and obligation of being a citizen of the United States, but also unfairly creates a second class of citizenship for LGBT victims, witnesses, plaintiffs, and defendants.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB9E2691BA34C40B1B3D0524A3ABD9053"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public accommodations</header> <subsection id="H1CBE3228C2B84AB88FE4C5A878A0B8ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on discrimination or segregation in public accommodations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA804557AE9DB4FFE8DAFE7AC98151EB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B6F3C7F13FD4725B87898464EF52F94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA193931B33BC4CB1B50C5285989BB51E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>stadium</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>stadium or other place of or establishment that provides exhibition, entertainment, recreation, exercise, amusement, gathering, or display;</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3ADF0290995C45828827E9459620851C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (6); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC95D6CC7E9F4DA3A8DCC8D63D088A48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE87AA8D8D0324BB5BD6B2F469CAEEEE8" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H11CB11871C3043FD9B1DAA9BE7B0B9A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any establishment that provides a good, service, or program, including a store, shopping center, online retailer or service provider, salon, bank, gas station, food bank, service or care center, shelter, travel agency, or funeral parlor, or establishment that provides health care, accounting, or legal services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3CCFFFDC93A40B886E04A2580CF87B7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any train service, bus service, car service, taxi service, airline service, station, depot, or other place of or establishment that provides transportation service; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCCE24C64F3845C587CE46A556E45BC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on discrimination or segregation under law</header><text>Section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a-1">42 U.S.C. 2000a–1</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA3AA3C4E25604486A145F69B267181C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Title II of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9423FD8FAB5D406980492E386EDE96CD" style="OLC"> <section id="HCA75F0D995454D9F9F809069524FB0D2"><enum>208.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A reference in this title to an establishment—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H3E0004DB6DC04AEF9D0B2E9C3ABA6DF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be construed to include an individual whose operations affect commerce and who is a provider of a good, service, or program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H87B02D06F75D4FFDBBF02FBFCC01275E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be construed to be limited to a physical facility or place.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H81EEC2015EF94AFDAC300A7FD0D8AE03"><enum>4.</enum><header>Desegregation of public facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 301(a) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000b">42 U.S.C. 2000b(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H78D0E47121C64EADB27D53ACB8B639F8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Desegregation of public education</header> <subsection id="HD563057449AA404EA951F135EE1ED049"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 401(b) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000c">42 U.S.C. 2000c(b)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4EEEF3CD8BFB4632869F22A6CFA1088A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil actions by the Attorney General</header><text>Section 407 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000c-6">42 U.S.C. 2000c–6</external-xref>) is amended, in subsection (a)(2), by inserting <quote>, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H913B8C7C063E4F24AD688CA151726370"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Classification and assignment</header><text>Section 410 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000c-9">42 U.S.C. 2000c–9</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCA7FA8FA72244D0C814B58FA1AB4B075"><enum>6.</enum><header>Federal funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 601 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin,</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3B2D7426ED7D4CF58BD8EE8DD20BCF1F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Employment</header> <subsection id="H3E2002E66A1B4CF4BBD1A265EF1736E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 is amended by inserting after section 701 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB874E41D16254EFEAED938286EA5CFFD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9989E9DBBF8C4264ABFCDB87A774BA21"><enum>701A.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1106 shall apply to this title except that for purposes of that application, a reference in that section to an <quote>unlawful practice</quote> shall be considered to be a reference to an <quote>unlawful employment practice</quote>.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD4854B1F4C1D48A4B25BA7F5F0B24E87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unlawful employment practices</header><text>Section 703 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-2">42 U.S.C. 2000e–2</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H448D3DA62F2341F5A25F2D5209EA5947"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section header, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="traditional">sex,</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="traditional">sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H906AB241DC54480796FC1DD03DB09B56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>except in subsection (e), by striking <quote>sex,</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7089ADCEE9854CB2A24759F3A6547D2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by striking <quote>enterprise,</quote> and inserting <quote>enterprise, if, in a situation in which sex is a bona fide occupational qualification, individuals are recognized as qualified in accordance with their gender identity,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BE6B05EC5C24358A2AB42A650BB44C7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by striking <quote>sex</quote> the second place it appears and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3AA6B6B7B84C4DEF8FD01911122BEEC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other unlawful employment practices</header><text>Section 704(b) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-3">42 U.S.C. 2000e–3(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6BF5E6CB8B3E432E9D68231B733A570A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>sex,</quote> the first place it appears and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C6FF5F9539E494EAF00CAA362EB7371"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>employment.</quote> and inserting <quote>employment, if, in a situation in which sex is a bona fide occupational qualification, individuals are recognized as qualified in accordance with their gender identity.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB6C7C16E69214A6380CC71521FC60352"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 706(g)(2)(A) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (2000e–5(g)(2)(A)) is amended by striking <quote>sex,</quote> and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98E95D32E26B443282DA2F3B6507048D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Employment by Federal Government</header><text>Section 717 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-16">42 U.S.C. 2000e–16</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9B4245404A5E4BA5971683D1F8ADEBD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>sex,</quote> and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H910EF1D37F9E47579C624F034847EC13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>sex</quote> and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5E3AE8D72FB445F4928EF3660C0E8B4E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Government Employee Rights Act of 1991</header><text>The Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16a et seq.) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H62B413613B1B4B009AF60FBC2E12B421"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 301(b), by striking <quote>sex,</quote> and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27DE3F481C434EBBB870B9B390ABDC80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 302(a)(1), by striking <quote>sex,</quote> and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09F1289BDE474E9393DC68BEDCB0267C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5538D587EAF4BD89FA6D43226A6D3BC" style="OLC"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6764CA0FB6D4321AB974D2F35518CE9"><enum>305.</enum><header>Rules of construction and claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 1101(b), 1106, and 1107 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall apply to this title except that for purposes of that application, a reference in that section 1106 to <quote>race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or national origin</quote> shall be considered to be a reference to <quote>race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, national origin, age, or disability</quote>.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7369C7A2AAC446D8A181004502E99B08"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Congressional Accountability Act of 1995</header><text>The Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD913BA28CC8B47B98FF0F87811573FF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 201(a)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1311">2 U.S.C. 1311(a)(1)</external-xref>) by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECCCFC68B1FB46E0927D4788A009F4A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end of title II (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1311">42 U.S.C. 1311 et seq.</external-xref>) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11DB21D2FD0F4B2AAC2C4F4A36BC59CE" style="OLC"> <section id="HC885034766C64410A6A6F86099426B48"><enum>208.</enum><header>Rules of construction and claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 1101(b), 1106, and 1107 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall apply to section 201 (and remedial provisions of this Act related to section 201) except that for purposes of that application, a reference in that section 1106 to <quote>race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or national origin</quote> shall be considered to be a reference to <quote>race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, national origin, age, or disability</quote>.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6AC1E7B0084644BD9459C4B808BD64B3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Civil Service Reform Act of 1978</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/23">Chapter 23</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H699B5FEAF5554BEB83ED266CF96E3117"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2301(b)(2), by striking <quote>sex,</quote> and inserting <quote>sex, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote>; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93B3C2FC5C9A4291B05BAD38C84E2A7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2302—</text> <subparagraph id="HE2EFC9B4017F48D4AA31D063EAF4F4B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(A), by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA75A1523980F4C72B9CAB7373A93F963"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin;</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE34BCBBEEAE4F89984B51917E60F73D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF25CEA2E3384938A04BC8AC892583AE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H44E3A0960683499C8AF9F07C8C95D512"><enum>2307.</enum><header>Rules of Construction and claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 1101(b), 1106, and 1107 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall apply to this chapter (and remedial provisions of this title related to this chapter) except that for purposes of that application, a reference in that section 1106 to <quote>race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or national origin</quote> shall be considered to be a reference to <quote>race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, national origin, age, a handicapping condition, marital status, or political affiliation</quote>.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7A77A2F2441E48438821A9B88D5A150E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Intervention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 902 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000h-2">42 U.S.C. 2000h–2</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> before <quote>or national origin,</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD7E07DCB172D4E2DA0A3867C36E43FC3"><enum>9.</enum><header>Miscellaneous</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8DC356E5C9E94D249683E4AEA77494B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating sections 1101 through 1104 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000h">42 U.S.C. 2000h et seq.</external-xref>) and sections 1105 and 1106 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000h-5">42 U.S.C. 2000h–5</external-xref>, 2000h–6) as sections 1102 through 1105 and sections 1108 and 1109, respectively;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77B22D2D5F2E41649071656CB6241C15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the title heading the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D9D524B2BD843B9BEC268D33EB4B159" style="OLC"> <section id="HA237B92E5CF44648B2507784D60F28B7"><enum>1101.</enum><header>Definitions and Rules</header> <subsection id="H49071B7A3D2E4F40A85A702230ED62C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In titles II, III, IV, VI, VII, and IX (referred to individually in sections 1106 and 1107 as a <quote>covered title</quote>):</text> 
<paragraph id="HEB220D241BE5446A9C13C95D0706645E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Race; color; religion; sex; sexual orientation; gender identity; national origin</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>race</term>, <term>color</term>, <term>religion</term>, <term>sex</term>, <term>sexual orientation</term>, <term>gender identity</term>, or <term>national origin</term>, used with respect to an individual, includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H3819FAA269844585B8C4D95E347AE2E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or national origin, respectively, of another person with whom the individual is associated or has been associated; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D6E60A709144D7680C0FAC47632CB58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a perception or belief, even if inaccurate, concerning the race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or national origin, respectively, of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C8EE8321D99415D81EEB057519CF259"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gender identity</header><text>The term <term>gender identity</term> means the gender-related identity, appearance, mannerisms, or other gender-related characteristics of an individual, regardless of the individual’s designated sex at birth.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E36D1B801424990B7CD2C0311913E66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Including</header><text>The term <term>including</term> means including, but not limited to, consistent with the term's standard meaning in Federal law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46545007A9084ECD8E67D8670AF31235"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>The term <term>sex</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4A42D9FBD37C4A309115955072712BD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a sex stereotype;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B48CFB1784C41AFB075460A1417B736"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5AC5E8BD4CE40F3A36C31AE41DB02FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sexual orientation or gender identity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2218A662E51F4C5FB632AC51744A43F0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sexual orientation</header><text>The term <term>sexual orientation</term> means homosexuality, heterosexuality, or bisexuality.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD066AAB771B34454AE2806B8CD1F7E3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>In a covered title referred to in subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H6B64F53A73D14E588F09514809CE61EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>(with respect to sex) pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition shall not receive less favorable treatment than other physical conditions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4EC71517DE2477DB4687090169D5A58"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">(with respect to gender identity) an individual shall not be denied access to a shared facility, including a restroom, a locker room, and a dressing room, that is in accordance with the individual's gender identity.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2985A7516744EDAADF4A0AC00055F8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 1105 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20CD88CCAF0F44029B864E81FFAC3B09" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H27B6E099E49B46C3B77BEB6F0A1463E3"><enum>1106.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> 
<subsection id="H11DC828262D040338726281BFE358472"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>Nothing in section 1101 or the provisions of a covered title incorporating a term defined or a rule specified in that section shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H0F12B0B1D2DC477586CB540EE55C58F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to limit the protection against an unlawful practice on the basis of pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition provided by section 701(k); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54168F1272E84FD6930818D0CE1AE5C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to limit the protection against an unlawful practice on the basis of sex available under any provision of Federal law other than that covered title, prohibiting a practice on the basis of sex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC69B9E7C00AB4121A1F615594458AF33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Claims and remedies not precluded</header><text>Nothing in section 1101 or a covered title shall be construed to limit the claims or remedies available to any individual for an unlawful practice on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or national origin including claims brought pursuant to section 1979 or 1980 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1983">42 U.S.C. 1983</external-xref>, 1985) or any other law, including a Federal law amended by the Equality Act, regulation, or policy.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3501A6814EA24246A9F33666497A8377"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No negative inference</header><text>Nothing in section 1101 or a covered title shall be construed to support any inference that any Federal law prohibiting a practice on the basis of sex does not prohibit discrimination on the basis of pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition, sexual orientation, gender identity, or a sex stereotype.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB84D0EB490A84DB9BDB40AE3475CDBAA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>1107.</enum><header>Claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000bb">42 U.S.C. 2000bb et seq.</external-xref>) shall not provide a claim concerning, or a defense to a claim under, a covered title, or provide a basis for challenging the application or enforcement of a covered title.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H29D46E5AFA3E47C097EF774B581CE85C"><enum>10.</enum><header>Housing</header> 
<subsection id="H5906FDAF2386428FA15F0AA5B5B162BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fair Housing Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Fair Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H47F451B0E6FC414EBDC60F5862DCF8CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 802, by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0FD8D82D46140CAB7CFA36D8E92DC00" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H521F50877C294351B465B02A482E0C18"><enum>(p)</enum><text><term>Gender identity</term>, <term>sex</term>, and <term>sexual orientation</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1101(a) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5D8251B7C3894F4290A0AA05B9CCB3F9"><enum>(q)</enum><text><term>Race</term>, <term>color</term>, <term>religion</term>, <term>sex</term>, <term>sexual orientation</term>, <term>gender identity</term>, <term>handicap</term>, <term>familial status</term>, or <term>national origin</term>, used with respect to an individual, includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9F637D6658244EF387076160F1C412CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, handicap, familial status, or national origin, respectively, of another person with whom the individual is associated or has been associated; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE249CAAA8CE24996837AB167CDA6826A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a perception or belief, even if inaccurate, concerning the race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, handicap, familial status, or national origin, respectively, of the individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7403DCBFA28048B680088187326E30E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 804, by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote> each place that term appears;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BA85F4819FF4E10A1CF250F12A633DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 805, by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote> each place that term appears;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F6319F8262443A98514BC22A57A688B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 806, by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DC3F42CE9EA46F48B6A3EC9CE5923BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 808(e)(6), by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD939F5F4C0342C1BB76C4B16F191538"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB4F68CD9F3548A391044A50F7946A98" style="OLC"> <section id="HC6702FA9ADE74854ADC7817BCAECC216"><enum>821.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 1101(b) and 1106 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall apply to this title and section 901, except that for purposes of that application, a reference in that section 1101(b) or 1106 to a <quote>covered title</quote> shall be considered a reference to <quote>this title and section 901</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H59218301D6C34612940AD5D4C2F23867"><enum>822.</enum><header>Claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1107 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall apply to this title and section 901, except that for purposes of that application, a reference in that section 1107 to a <quote>covered title</quote> shall be considered a reference to <quote>this title and section 901</quote>.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H10E6EE269D8A49C19587BCA20721E6A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prevention of intimidation in fair housing cases</header><text>Section 901 of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3631">42 U.S.C. 3631</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>sexual orientation (as such term is defined in section 802 of this Act), gender identity (as such term is defined in section 802 of this Act),</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote> each place that term appears.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF818E648449E4ACBAF42CBD972481601"><enum>11.</enum><header>Equal credit opportunity</header> 
<subsection id="H61A076F08D78463E96423EA7873181F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited discrimination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 701(a)(1) of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1691">15 U.S.C. 1691(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> after <quote>status,</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8BE41A397A8B47589D898B07F7823EFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 702 of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1691a">15 U.S.C. 1691a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H47C227A74B1148488AF3DCBAD5B7584F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (f) and (g) as subsections (h) and (i), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF02395B38B3942F0B4DE27B659A1FDD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F5EC6369F1A4D25AC15A03A4F2D4343" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H961765B23D644A348DC802F8A59D3C2F"><enum>(f)</enum><text>The terms <term>gender identity</term>, <term>sex</term>, and <term>sexual orientation</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1101(a) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF2FF25DA80A74848AE53D067446CEB29"><enum>(g)</enum><text>The term <term>race</term>, <term>color</term>, <term>religion</term>, <term>national origin</term>, <term>sex</term>, <term>sexual orientation</term>, <term>gender identity</term>, <term>marital status</term>, or <term>age</term>, used with respect to an individual, includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB86F5BFABD994F6DAB4AE62F80491481"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the race, color, religion, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, marital status, or age, respectively, of another person with whom the individual is associated or has been associated; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F1E27BA5FEC46E3AF72723E13CF72D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a perception or belief, even if inaccurate, concerning the race, color, religion, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, marital status, or age, respectively, of the individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC66C5EEA7D254EFEBD200B4848357E1A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H246054ACF5EE46B289D224EA43FD8952" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H510D12E8B2F945589E6F5999621058F1"><enum>(j)</enum><text>Sections 1101(b) and 1106 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall apply to this title, except that for purposes of that application—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFE7BEC2A13564989ACBE46A60C55D655"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a reference in those sections to a <quote>covered title</quote> shall be considered a reference to <quote>this title</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74325FA68B2F43298C862FCA35929A64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>paragraph (1) of such section 1101(b) shall apply with respect to all aspects of a credit transaction.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDDB2E925DB3A47BDA41CC16DB54A747D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relation to State laws</header><text>Section 705(a) of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1691d">15 U.S.C. 1691d(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> after <quote>sex</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF0F32BC681D841CD894AB1B156C84DBB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil liability</header><text>Section 706 of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1691e">15 U.S.C. 1691e</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCC29B02BC0341BF91C6EB276F92784A" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H65FB3AB24133420B98F6097846A9F10D"><enum>(l)</enum><text>Section 1107 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall apply to this title, except that for purposes of that application, a reference in that section to a <quote>covered title</quote> shall be considered a reference to <quote>this title</quote>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HC9C5984CEE11462BABF6754737F7C8A7"><enum>12.</enum><header>Juries</header> <subsection id="H01FAD925150A4CF6B0483DE5243768F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/121">Chapter 121</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEBED7CF124C242AFA565C407E3AFE3AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1862, by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H694B706A1FA04E7DA63A302F6B0B6899"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1867(e), in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>sexual orientation, gender identity,</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E7F93454BA648878489543DB90C6180"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 1869—</text> <subparagraph id="HD5A9E542DBAE4DD8B1337D0F886D4D08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2264A6C8835543179777B9C8ECD38D81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (k), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B58614BACBB4705AF3F19B8A1A5C964"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAD80C4C9C5C409293FC9F1805204982" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HCBB123FCEF98433692FC6A7C60A81F05"><enum>(l)</enum><text><term>gender identity</term>, <term>sex</term>, and <term>sexual orientation</term> have the meanings given such terms under section 1101(a) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964; and</text></subsection> <subsection id="H54A2A81B482740D7A0C7253882637A2E"><enum>(m)</enum><text><term>race</term>, <term>color</term>, <term>religion</term>, <term>sex</term>, <term>sexual orientation</term>, <term>gender identity</term>, <term>economic status</term>, or <term>national origin</term>, used with respect to an individual, includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD0057BEDE637434F82ADCAF689D79C91"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, economic status, or national origin, respectively, of another person with whom the individual is associated or has been associated; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H507B2F67D3D6440DA2C5BC37AB9E78C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a perception or belief, even if inaccurate, concerning the race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, economic status, or national origin, respectively, of the individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43F1ACD06DF647889BCBE318E4FEF9FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38B8CBE4CAFF4BC6838A0106B3BFAF3F" style="USC"> <section id="H9D60F0DAF6194390ABCF75BDCA35C269"><enum>1879.</enum><header>Rules of construction and claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 1101(b), 1106, and 1107 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall apply to this chapter, except that for purposes of that application, a reference in those sections to a <quote>covered title</quote> shall be considered a reference to <quote>this chapter</quote>.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H197C5DE955C247A3ACC05325BD3CE6F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/121">chapter 121</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H685072B9CF344F49A017C5A9D8EAFC7D" style="USC"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section">1879. Rules of construction and claims.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

