<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFA70AB203DB949038321E9C58549752A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3172 IH: Wild Horse Oversight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3172</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150722">July 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act to provide for State and tribal management and
			 protection of wild free-roaming horses and burros, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HEF2CF0947A58486B86A418F9BA8AAD67" style="OLC">
 <section id="H66F415E879B447E1995CAEA2AED4AFCD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wild Horse Oversight Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6E25094B07BB4EFCBB6208895223B007"><enum>2.</enum><header>State and tribal management and protection of wild free-roaming horses and burros</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Public Law 92–195 (commonly known as the <quote>Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act</quote>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1016562AADA740A6BECCC50363053CCC" style="OLC">
				<section id="HC38E734C3AD946438267EDA68E677BB8"><enum>12.</enum><header>State and tribal management and protection</header>
 <subsection id="H43DF5FBC96FD40178A68AAF071DCB303"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by subsection (b), at the request of the legislature or Governor of a State or the governing body of a federally recognized Indian tribe, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall allow the State or federally recognized Indian tribe to assume all management and protection functions under this Act regarding wild free-roaming horses and burros on land within the boundaries of the State or federally recognized Indian tribe. After a State or federally recognized Indian tribe assumes such functions, wild free-roaming horses and burros shall be managed by the State or federally recognized Indian tribe in accordance with this Act and in the same manner as any other non-federally regulated species regarding functions not specified in this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H86BFD6ECE03D4050A8C248D13EE3FC46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inventory</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall continue to maintain the inventory required by section 3(b)(1).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

