<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H637ABA37732D40F394B2A5DBD9E3F4AE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1734 IH: Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1734</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150413">April 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000413">Mr. Whitfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000364">Mr. Shimkus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to encourage recovery and beneficial use of
			 coal combustion residuals and establish requirements for the proper
			 management and disposal of coal combustion residuals that are protective
			 of human health and the environment.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HCE28FAB1FE144AC48731F190C1E035B6" style="OLC">
		<section id="H15031E698A5F4354951C2CA5203E0126" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H7B9889E93DD24B3CB51B6726CF18672D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8CD706BACAF64F0885EA74A3A06EEC8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H15031E698A5F4354951C2CA5203E0126" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1550DBC37839485897AA79601E0C88B3" level="section">Sec. 2. Management and disposal of coal combustion residuals.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC80847688FEF431A81930A38F7529415" level="section">Sec. 3. 2000 regulatory determination.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H183D7D42E4D64EE38617D442C787C5C9" level="section">Sec. 4. Technical assistance.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8757BF800EC84D458601CDFF1EDD2734" level="section">Sec. 5. Federal Power Act.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1550DBC37839485897AA79601E0C88B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Management and disposal of coal combustion residuals</header>
 <subsection id="H97EECF0DC883479F9663E95028DED1ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6941">42 U.S.C. 6941 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H6E767F47DA9147FEA148F38C92E2F8F9" style="OLC">
					<section id="H39BD3A047CCB4DCFB4A6D63AEC6C11D1"><enum>4011.</enum><header>Management and disposal of coal combustion residuals</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H9659341E9E104FD9A4A2E6A422CF2E0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State permit programs for coal combustion residuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State may adopt, implement, and enforce a coal combustion residuals permit program in accordance with this section.</text>
						</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0D9B8FDA97ED4C199E381E220E4BFC64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State actions</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H589ECAC3FA7D408393898C5550B4EEE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section (except as provided by the deadline identified under subsection (d)(3)(B)), the Governor of each State shall notify the Administrator, in writing, whether such State will adopt and implement a coal combustion residuals permit program.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA87C8A319F9149F0B6B952B78CE874B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H679714777D4E49E0A1E84E5B36FC20A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this section (except as provided in subparagraph (B) and subsection (f)(1)(A)), in the case of a State that has notified the Administrator that it will implement a coal combustion residuals permit program, the head of the lead State implementing agency shall submit to the Administrator a certification that such coal combustion residuals permit program meets the requirements described in subsection (c).</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD9D17ABEE005433A9BC4DF67985CA790"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="HF643760B7B5549E8ABA1399A1B3DEB24"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Administrator may extend the deadline for submission of a certification for a State under subparagraph (A) for a period of 12 months if the State submits to the Administrator a request for such an extension that—</text>
 <subclause id="H1EB262A239284BCF82073380CD8D5FE2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>describes the efforts of the State to meet such deadline;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H8F1A15BFA88C490B8F9B03E5F2171D34"><enum>(II)</enum><text>demonstrates that the legislative or rulemaking procedures of such State render the State unable meet such deadline; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HCFA8F2AF2A0B471C9D6D35A319F3D80A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provides the Administrator with a detailed schedule for completion and submission of the certification.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HDE92A7DDD34D4DF2A52A328FE64451CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>If the Administrator does not approve or deny a request submitted under clause (i) by the date that is 30 days after such submission, the request shall be deemed approved.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2FEA7EB8D37A410FB2BAFBAC04427542"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A certification submitted under this paragraph shall include—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H6D40631821DA44B7B932DC9F679E133A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a letter identifying the lead State implementing agency, signed by the head of such agency;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H02367C8697C64FD795476BED8051ABC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identification of any other State agencies involved with the implementation of the coal combustion residuals permit program;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H409E91110ABD452DB0D2A121C47A6713"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an explanation of how the State coal combustion residuals permit program meets the requirements of this section, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H6A149E94D54B4694A9688585FDF7A2BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a description of the State’s—</text> <item commented="no" id="HC9AFA1F0BD09400589C7469EE1243E24"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>process to inspect or otherwise determine compliance with such permit program;</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H626608311A0A4CDE88171711CD7DD146"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>process to enforce the requirements of such permit program;</text> </item><item commented="no" id="H5B4F0A8898044EBFA45925E8A361D531"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>public participation process for the promulgation, amendment, or repeal of regulations for, and the issuance of permits under, such permit program; and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="HAF3CFA0C19444056B8457E339B12B9B9"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">statutes, regulations, or policies pertaining to public access to information, including information on groundwater monitoring data, structural stability assessments, emergency action plans, fugitive dust control plans, notifications of closure (including any certification of closure by a qualified professional engineer), and corrective action remedies; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC887E468D1644E91A785290BB74BB2C8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identification of any changes to the definitions under section 257.53 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, for purposes of the State coal combustion residuals permit program, including a reasonable basis for such changes, as required under subsection (l)(5);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H612AF01C2F124E129A5482DBBA73B63D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a statement that the State has in effect, at the time of certification, statutes or regulations necessary to implement a coal combustion residuals permit program that meets the requirements described in subsection (c);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5C80E41668204A319683C053769FD519"><enum>(v)</enum><text>copies of State statutes and regulations described in clause (iv);</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD74DFF6941BA4E7CAC5EE8E484D8E27C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for a response by the State to a release at a structure or inactive surface impoundment that has the potential for impact beyond the site on which the structure or inactive surface impoundment is located; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H52F9874236214AC49C5EA9DF0F985B7C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a plan for coordination among States in the event of a release that crosses State lines.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC873525801AD4E79B18229A168F53E3C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>A State may update the certification as needed to reflect changes to the coal combustion residuals permit program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB176399ACC6A49769236F5E3D584F460"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maintenance of <enum-in-header>4005(c)</enum-in-header> or <enum-in-header>3006</enum-in-header> program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to adopt or implement a coal combustion residuals permit program under this section (including pursuant to subsection (f)), the lead State implementing agency shall maintain an approved permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions under section 4005(c) or an authorized program under section 3006.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD6EBFD5336034CF688DAA5F0C8007BF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for a coal combustion residuals permit program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A coal combustion residuals permit program shall consist of the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H69058270F347426F847F5E3574E322F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General requirements</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2974BF3176834F3DA067455DCD52071F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Permits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementing agency shall require that owners or operators of structures apply for and obtain permits incorporating the applicable requirements of the coal combustion residuals permit program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E082F403C324F8891A6DBCC258A6EAE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability of information</header><text>Except for information with respect to which disclosure is prohibited under section 1905 of title 18, United States Code, the implementing agency shall ensure that—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H41A5AA02EA054C2D828E7479EC7E47B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>documents for permit determinations are made publicly available for review and comment under the public participation process of the coal combustion residuals permit program;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8BAF9A2D7A004165BC256DCB7DC6FC77"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">final determinations on permit applications are made publicly available;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1D125E32A146486CA143F4F0A6653FD7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on groundwater monitoring data, structural stability assessments, emergency action plans, fugitive dust control plans, notifications of closure (including any certification of closure by a qualified professional engineer), and corrective action remedies required pursuant to paragraph (2), collected in a manner determined appropriate by the implementing agency, is publicly available, including on an Internet website; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD12D3AA4479647B8A1B82F692070A942"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding the exercise by the implementing agency of any discretionary authority granted under this section and not provided for in the rule described in subsection (l)(1) is made publicly available.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6D1C75064ECA40EFAA96568D19C3CBEE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Agency authority</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H7FF91B3489C842C9AAB20CB6C715DB94"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The implementing agency shall—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H1DD5B5E9875C440C97E96D9E5077FA73"><enum>(I)</enum><text>obtain information necessary to determine whether the owner or operator of a structure is in compliance with the requirements of the coal combustion residuals permit program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HA6BA2F3B4F56480D9A5EE69E2422D016"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct or require monitoring or testing to ensure that structures are in compliance with the requirements of the coal combustion residuals permit program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H6829F8B59CF64D818C6CEFC23BFCB111"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter any site or premise at which a structure or inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment is located for the purpose of inspecting such structure or surface impoundment and reviewing relevant records.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H9E1D5250271C404CAF135131124F22D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Monitoring and testing</header><text>If monitoring or testing is conducted under clause (i)(II) by or for the implementing agency, the implementing agency shall, if requested, provide to the owner or operator—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HC1F362CA9A1F445A8DD8E9EF0D4F6055"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a written description of the monitoring or testing completed;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC8D4944542BF423F8531E0EEA729FA16"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at the time of sampling, a portion of each sample equal in volume or weight to the portion retained by or for the implementing agency; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H718394B02F3B4911B57EAFF078E71E6E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a copy of the results of any analysis of samples collected by or for the implementing agency.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0EE3F8B5720341F2B504B4BA2337356A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The implementing agency shall apply the following criteria with respect to structures:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEF6ABD2AEFDE4525BEC9C48E455B98DE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Design requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For new structures, including lateral expansions of existing structures, the criteria regarding design requirements described in sections 257.70 and 257.72 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, as applicable.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE00BE5E7C715404CAAAC5C21D2959755"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Groundwater monitoring and corrective action</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H68984005CF944E25BA2503A1BBBDC0D5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), for all structures, the criteria regarding groundwater monitoring and corrective action requirements described in sections 257.90 through 257.98 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, including—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H95C7006F193E4AB8871766F13B175728"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purposes of detection monitoring, the constituents described in appendix III to part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD635B81AB96147DB916D74AE68D6C590"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purposes of assessment monitoring, establishing a groundwater protection standard, and assessment of corrective measures, the constituents described in appendix IV to part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
										</subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H2F32E51952A442A4802CDDD7BF7F20AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions and additional authority</header>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H0303DD88773145F7B9417C444FBBEB9C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Alternative point of compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 257.91(a)(2) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, the implementing agency may establish the relevant point of compliance for the down-gradient monitoring system as provided in section 258.51(a)(2) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.<italic></italic></text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HDE7D61AD279F4E70A3B43E1E9EC242E1"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Alternative groundwater protection standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 257.95(h) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, the implementing agency may establish an alternative groundwater protection standard as provided in section 258.55(i) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.<italic></italic></text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD557203F7CA147B7A711718CC8CA1AAD"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Ability to determine that corrective action is not necessary or technically feasible</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 257.97 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, the implementing agency may determine that remediation of a release from a structure is not necessary as provided in section 258.57(e) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H1DE832968D1D4831AB1DC21E0D810198"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Authority relating to releases, other than releases to groundwater</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 257.90(d) and 257.96(a) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, the implementing agency may, with respect to a release from a structure, other than a release to groundwater, authorize, for purposes of complying with this section, remediation of such release in accordance with other applicable Federal or State requirements if compliance with such requirements will result in the same level of protection as compliance with the criteria described in sections 257.96 through 257.98 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, taking into consideration the nature of the release.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H270C804E06A84F7DB3A9CB780300D073"><enum>(V)</enum><header>General authority relating to groundwater monitoring and corrective action</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 257.90 through 257.98 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, the implementing agency may authorize alternative groundwater monitoring and corrective action requirements provided that such requirements are no less stringent than the alternative requirements authorized to be established under subpart E of part 258 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H9353129E5D52482DA3579851D1F7D0DF"><enum>(VI)</enum><header>Opportunity for corrective action for unlined surface impoundments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 257.101(a)(1) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, the implementing agency may allow the owner or operator of an existing structure that is an unlined surface impoundment—</text>
 <item commented="no" id="H44DE7E9D1F8E4B59BE3973F65F94ABFC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to continue to operate, pursuant to sections 257.96 through 257.98 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, until the date that is 102 months after the date of enactment of this section; and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H7CCD4F349C3F495DA5F33046E5CA2ACB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to continue to operate after such date as long as such unlined surface impoundment meets the groundwater protection standard established pursuant to this subparagraph and any other applicable requirement established pursuant to this section.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H76E4413864D843819220A94C8498963F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Closure</header><text>For all structures, the criteria for closure described in sections 257.101, 257.102, and 257.103 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, except—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H526CF91C1224440F8DB6B1BC199963B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the criteria described in section 257.101(a)(1) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, shall apply to an existing structure that is an unlined surface impoundment only if—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H2A138195A4EF47F786B485BFE5438998"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the unlined surface impoundment is not allowed to continue operation pursuant to subparagraph (B)(ii)(VI)(aa); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HE5D0569239CF4CCCB7B6873663E7E4C5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an unlined surface impoundment that is allowed to continue operation pursuant to subparagraph (B)(ii)(VI)(aa), the date described in such subparagraph has passed and the unlined surface impoundment does not meet the requirements described in subparagraph (B)(ii)(VI)(bb);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HFD372C1F6DDE4735B9F0892AE2D9429B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the criteria described in section 257.101(b)(1) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, shall not apply to existing structures, except as provided in subparagraphs (E)(i)(II) and (E)(ii); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H23058235E4C84C04B7BDFC06FD3898AE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if an implementing agency has set a deadline under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (L), the criteria described in section 257.101(b)(2) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, shall apply to structures that are surface impoundments only after such deadline.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAB8C7347DAD9450EAA9E4D5C56C8E38B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Post-closure</header><text>For all structures, the criteria for post-closure care described in section 257.104 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8189ABF3C2D1403B8C0699C61D74CC1C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Location restrictions</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="HF224C43450AB4CAE974407C033578D0D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The criteria for location restrictions described in—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H74179BF6D4D446BD8169B34228E91183"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for new structures, including lateral expansions of existing structures, sections 257.60 through 257.64 and 257.3–1 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD5690EC61D624D38A4EAEE4D0D19EA81"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for existing structures, sections 257.64 and 257.3–1 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H50135F2111BA435D8844A3F4A28E8E97"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementing agency may apply the criteria described in sections 257.60 through 257.63 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, to existing structures that are surface impoundments.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0D2A8E59AF21433FB153298E98CC8747"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Air criteria</header><text>For all structures, the criteria for air quality described in section 257.80 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H15553F39F8774B05BEC3FF5280F8D4D3"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Financial assurance</header><text>For all structures, the criteria for financial assurance described in subpart G of part 258 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H96FAC55C18554685AEE8C94AFBFA2DBD"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Surface water</header><text>For all structures, the criteria for surface water described in section 257.3–3 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAE0493D3C0CB482FA5B1A5569724C4A7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text>For all structures, the criteria for recordkeeping described in section 257.105 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA84FC8A3FF7F42068E940A72592A55EC"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Run-on and run-off controls</header><text>For all structures that are landfills, sand or gravel pits, or quarries, the criteria for run-on and run-off control described in section 257.81 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAF2F947B32AC419D89967819FD6665FD"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Hydrologic and hydraulic capacity requirements</header><text>For all structures that are surface impoundments, the criteria for inflow design flood control systems described in section 257.82 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB4650DFE278745F49BB72154F50B11C8"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Structural integrity</header><text>For structures that are surface impoundments, the criteria for structural integrity described in sections 257.73 and 257.74 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, except that, notwithstanding section 257.73(f)(4) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, the implementing agency may provide for—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HF921159AF5AD48A79F79E1B934761643"><enum>(i)</enum><text>up to 30 days for an owner or operator to complete a safety factor assessment when an owner or operator has failed to meet an applicable periodic assessment deadline provided in section 257.73(f) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H429CE86BC5E447ADAA7938B107A01B69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">up to 12 months for an owner or operator to meet the safety factor assessment criteria provided in section 257.73(e)(1) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, if the implementing agency determines, through the initial safety factor assessment, that the structure does not meet such safety factor assessment criteria and that the structure does not pose an immediate threat of release.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H33BBE340EA9A40778AF515A65C65619A"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Inspections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For all structures, the criteria described in sections 257.83 and 257.84 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE7A47D7D5EC94BB791CD00A2A446DA22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permit program implementation for existing structures</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD2BBFD48A1F04AEE96DA62A6BA2B7AF5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date on which a State submits a certification under subsection (b)(2), not later than 18 months after the Administrator receives notice under subsection (e)(1)(A), or not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this section with respect to a coal combustion residuals permit program that is being implemented by the Administrator under subsection (e)(3), as applicable, the implementing agency shall notify owners or operators of existing structures of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HF25292BA9BC14FC995428B104AF6584C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the obligation to apply for and obtain a permit under subparagraph (C); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8A9223F234384E1F86B67F57451C6689"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the requirements referred to in subparagraph (B)(ii).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3AB25CD3B92044E89B7416F0E37E6A01"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance with certain requirements</header>
 <clause id="HD6832EB544574D71BBCB2C652C65A4FF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial deadline for certain requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 8 months after the date of enactment of this section, the implementing agency shall require owners or operators of existing structures to comply with—</text>
 <subclause id="H2D1F2D6976624D9BA786E8E7E6A0A3B8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the requirements under paragraphs (2)(F), (2)(H), (2)(I), and (2)(M); and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H135889A279F24EB49CE0520D40D4B5A5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirement for a permanent identification marker under the criteria described in paragraph (2)(L).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA112223BD0A243EDB25618FFF20625BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent deadline for certain other requirements</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date on which a State submits a certification under subsection (b)(2), not later than 30 months after the Administrator receives notice under subsection (e)(1)(A), or not later than 36 months after the date of enactment of this section with respect to a coal combustion residuals permit program that is being implemented by the Administrator under subsection (e)(3), as applicable, the implementing agency shall require owners or operators of existing structures to comply with—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HC09B1013E5814227A4AEC07C6A8252BC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirements under paragraphs (2)(B), (2)(G), (2)(J), (2)(K), and (2)(L); and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H325B924A4F584943AA0C1913532B6D28"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the requirement for a written closure plan under the criteria described in paragraph (2)(C).</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD5CBE835B6C34F5BA73A806129428702"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Permits</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="HFB76EE9359E54D02911BC3D39EEE264E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Permit deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 months after the date on which a State submits a certification under subsection (b)(2), not later than 66 months after the Administrator receives notice under subsection (e)(1)(A), or not later than 72 months after the date of enactment of this section with respect to a coal combustion residuals permit program that is being implemented by the Administrator under subsection (e)(3), as applicable, the implementing agency shall issue, with respect to an existing structure, a final permit incorporating the applicable requirements of the coal combustion residuals permit program, or a final denial of an application submitted requesting such a permit.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H40108C7C07264FEDBAB2F9E9E778C8B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Application deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementing agency shall identify, in collaboration with the owner or operator of an existing structure, a reasonable deadline by which the owner or operator shall submit a permit application under clause (i).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H44F2FD8931BF488FA6F54F50CA7C2323"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Interim operation</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H97DA4D350ADC4835B8A537FD573191D9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prior to deadlines</header><text>Unless the implementing agency determines that the structure should close in accordance with the criteria described in paragraph (2)(C), with respect to any period of time on or after the date of enactment of this section but prior to the applicable deadline in subparagraph (B), the owner or operator of an existing structure may continue to operate such structure until such applicable deadline under any applicable regulations in effect during such period.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H51AA4EF66A8340C88D2E1B6A5E278C17"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prior to permit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless the implementing agency determines that the structure should close in accordance with the criteria described in paragraph (2)(C), if the owner or operator of an existing structure meets the requirements referred to in subparagraph (B) by the applicable deadline in such subparagraph, the owner or operator may operate the structure until such time as the implementing agency issues, under subparagraph (C), a final permit incorporating the requirements of the coal combustion residuals permit program, or a final denial of an application submitted requesting such a permit.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8F771D147D2A4A23A4ED0AB8317818FA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements for inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundments</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0AB1AEC97F7B4967AF7384A2CD5969F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 2 months after the date of enactment of this section, each owner or operator of an inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment shall submit to the Administrator and the State in which such inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment is located a notice stating whether such inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment will—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H37F286824AF444B7BE00E92660FE9CC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, complete closure in accordance with section 257.100 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HBE08297BDFD3430189C70DC3DF742235"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comply with the requirements of the coal combustion residuals permit program applicable to existing structures that are surface impoundments (except as provided in subparagraph (D)(ii)).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA3F5B45E4EEF44BEA18AD92BC472169F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment for which the owner or operator submits a notice described in subparagraph (A)(i), the implementing agency may extend the closure deadline provided in such subparagraph by a period of not more than 2 years if the owner or operator of such inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H7AE68B4F46D840CCA31FA61866E790DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates to the satisfaction of the implementing agency that it is not feasible to complete closure of the inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment in accordance with section 257.100 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, by the deadline provided in subparagraph (A)(i)—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HF25D9C95042A4CE49F8524445B24746E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>because of complications stemming from the climate or weather, such as unusual amounts of precipitation or a significantly shortened construction season;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H383E8243D78E4730B414DFF7AE32ABB1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">because additional time is required to remove the liquid from the inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment due to the volume of coal combustion residuals contained in the surface impoundment or the characteristics of the coal combustion residuals in such surface impoundment;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H447A6FC3E3A54BA6B55C3FBEEB3AB218"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">because the geology and terrain surrounding the inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment will affect the amount of material needed to close the inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H7FC3C5D5793849A2825D4A61D6FCD127"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>because additional time is required to coordinate with and obtain necessary approvals and permits; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H17C9DE266A38445CA0BACD8F05417743"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates to the satisfaction of the implementing agency that the inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment does not pose an immediate threat of release.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2F709D432D794745B6E55975DFAA5443"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Financial assurance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementing agency shall require the owner or operator of an inactive surface impoundment that has closed pursuant to this paragraph to perform post-closure care in accordance with the criteria described in section 257.104(b)(1) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, and to provide financial assurance for such post-closure care in accordance with the criteria described in section 258.72 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D07CC30C0894B2092A3975B5BF6C6CD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment as structure</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H749C8EDACB484143B32C6DDBCC7B4DF9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment shall be treated as an existing structure that is a surface impoundment for the purposes of this section, including with respect to the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2), if—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H75D57EB8BBCC496C84E39D185E43972A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the owner or operator does not submit a notice in accordance with subparagraph (A); or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H1FAAF2FBD92B4FB7A219C5AB921A5C18"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the owner or operator submits a notice described in subparagraph (A)(ii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0DCA5DF602754FEE9B92CE568AB0E205"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundments that fail to close</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment for which the owner or operator submits a notice described in subparagraph (A)(i) that does not close by the deadline provided under subparagraph (A)(i) or subparagraph (B), as applicable—</text>
 <subclause id="HB89D34BE9EC64188B95BA213C0D7EBEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be treated as an existing structure for purposes of this section beginning on the date that is the day after such applicable deadline, including by—</text>
 <item id="H08CDEE440E964ABCA0F03D9DD4E9D878"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>being required to comply with the requirements of paragraph (1), as applicable; and</text> </item><item id="HEA8D840762024FCBBA5337655ACDF7D5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>being required to comply, beginning on such date, with each requirement of paragraph (2); but</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HCDBBE29193834715A7736AA9ACA08D8E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall not be required to comply with paragraph (3).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8225848EA22405DBDB7C1D0FEF79B99"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal review of State permit programs</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H05B51D8AA4BB4EF298CE09239EF4A18C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall provide to a State written notice and an opportunity to remedy deficiencies in accordance with paragraph (3) if at any time the State—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCA4332BB5AA9436B847110C88E49569C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not satisfy the notification requirement under subsection (b)(1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA1A16616DF654815B9671693AA062244"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not submitted a certification as required under subsection (b)(2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFC6A5A0608DA4903B88F3737B8795DB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not satisfy the maintenance requirement under subsection (b)(3);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB207BAE69DC846D79ABD612C91978933"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not implementing a coal combustion residuals permit program, with respect to which the State has submitted a certification under subsection (b)(2), that meets the requirements described in subsection (c);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E1C105A0FD44B33BF3137F88C309E6C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not implementing a coal combustion residuals permit program, with respect to which the State has submitted a certification under subsection (b)(2)—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H12CD4D21831D447BBD47FA7C1859D035"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is consistent with such certification; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H2AD50546B6B148F2B8D4A5731FEFA58E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which the State continues to have in effect statutes or regulations necessary to implement such program; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF3945B0710C447B3943D3D68022D7A5C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not make available to the Administrator, within 90 days of a written request, specific information necessary for the Administrator to ascertain whether the State has satisfied the requirements described in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD66F58846A1E4F6CAF3F371F95C0DC62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Request</header><text>If a request described in paragraph (1)(F) is proposed pursuant to a petition to the Administrator, the Administrator shall make the request only if the Administrator does not possess the information necessary to ascertain whether the State has satisfied the requirements described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA492C807FA64793B466F67C528007B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of notice; deadline for response</header><text>A notice provided under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H381241F02FBC40C59C3E493CB32C87EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include findings of the Administrator detailing any applicable deficiencies described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6BE5D211E7FF4DD6BA69EEE4E8161B19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify, in collaboration with the State, a reasonable deadline by which the State shall remedy such applicable deficiencies, which shall be—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H946D784CB64A42F2A9FADEBA6183F122"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a deficiency described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1), not earlier than 180 days after the date on which the State receives the notice; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H40C683D7F591439A93EA57FD817729D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a deficiency described in paragraph (1)(F), not later than 90 days after the date on which the State receives the notice.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA997E9302AE9493BA7B9982711DF7108"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Considerations for determining deficiency of State permit program</header><text>In making a determination whether a State has failed to satisfy the requirements described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (1), or a determination under subsection (e)(1)(B), the Administrator shall consider, as appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD6085B7690AF44D78A521538D13ED105"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the State’s statutes or regulations to implement a coal combustion residuals permit program are not sufficient to meet the requirements described in subsection (c) because of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H1F2298C1986442D2B139E125036A77FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>failure of the State to promulgate or enact new statutes or regulations when necessary; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HDDFAB92D1F6049BEB7EE58D6D7A1E9C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>action by a State legislature or court striking down or limiting such State statutes or regulations;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDEA0B8F3AE6046A6B79A5DF51FE10B64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the operation of the State coal combustion residuals permit program fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (c) because of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HA3F88D9A2F4E468F8BCD8CA26B6FF1A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>failure of the State to issue permits as required in subsection (c)(1)(A);</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H2679EF0E273540B6B546157F23411130"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>repeated issuance by the State of permits that do not meet the requirements of subsection (c);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H66515A1CEC2E4332B16F9056718BD3B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>failure of the State to comply with the public participation requirements of this section; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H084339E5E80940A19C97B86F727CDE5A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>failure of the State to implement corrective action requirements required under subsection (c)(2)(B); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1974857B59B444B2BC3BD171A4C2035A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the enforcement of a State coal combustion residuals permit program fails to comply with the requirements of this section because of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H8F95EA56BBF7433892F0F08BC923FA05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>failure to act on violations of permits, as identified by the State; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HDF389BB5343D4D43A6E5F6272A422029"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>repeated failure by the State to inspect or otherwise determine compliance pursuant to the process identified under subsection (b)(2)(C)(iii)(I).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63485FE404E54E218410218B8866D24D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation by Administrator</header>
 <paragraph id="HE571884119BE4DD58255330385F9611A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal backstop authority</header><text>The Administrator shall implement a coal combustion residuals permit program for a State if—</text> <subparagraph id="H2486E7487A474BB1A43DB65D02E9FC9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Governor of the State notifies the Administrator under subsection (b)(1) that the State will not adopt and implement a permit program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF85ECCC598DD4A04BE0085F66AD7C96F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State has received a notice under subsection (d) and the Administrator determines, after providing a 30-day period for notice and public comment, that the State has failed, by the deadline identified in the notice under subsection (d)(3)(B), to remedy the deficiencies detailed in the notice pursuant to subsection (d)(3)(A); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E080F73F75C4147B073A83110528591"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State informs the Administrator, in writing, that such State will no longer implement such a permit program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1BC636417B14F33A46EF1EAAC914073"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>A State may obtain a review of a determination by the Administrator under this subsection as if the determination was a final regulation for purposes of section 7006.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CFAA8FE1952442190708BA2E3CAC8BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other structures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For structures and inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundments located on property within the exterior boundaries of a State that the State does not have authority or jurisdiction to regulate, the Administrator shall implement a coal combustion residuals permit program only for those structures and inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9321C3FF83D9428396C53308C47575F5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>If the Administrator implements a coal combustion residuals permit program under paragraph (1) or (3), the permit program shall consist of the requirements described in subsection (c).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HBF9E0EE703A2417191C325A95E5E9993"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5EE7009721BB42C89D18BC71DB210C21"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Administrator implements a coal combustion residuals permit program for a State under paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="H831387A2CA0547E7845501FB89A7B057"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the authorities referred to in section 4005(c)(2)(A) shall apply with respect to coal combustion residuals, structures, and inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundments for which the Administrator is implementing the coal combustion residuals permit program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB24AF2265AE4444D824A36D129485C51"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator may use those authorities to inspect, gather information, and enforce the requirements of this section in the State.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1E01566AB5D481982003EA414A7C940"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other structures</header><text>If the Administrator implements a coal combustion residuals permit program under paragraph (3)—</text> <clause id="H172AABB6FCB647F4BD6BF4AD2095D599"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the authorities referred to in section 4005(c)(2)(A) shall apply with respect to coal combustion residuals, structures, and inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundments for which the Administrator is implementing the coal combustion residuals permit program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H09F36F2A3BD847B4A4B2D1D216AA5709"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator may use those authorities to inspect, gather information, and enforce the requirements of this section for the structures and inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundments for which the Administrator is implementing the coal combustion residuals permit program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD26CB8FAE3D6473689B990761CF26FCA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public participation process</header><text>If the Administrator implements a coal combustion residuals permit program under this subsection, the Administrator shall provide a 30-day period for the public participation process required under subsection (c)(1)(B)(i).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2323F8F4CD6A499FA1211A70C43272B3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>State control after implementation by Administrator</header>
							<paragraph id="H81C3AC13B46645638562538855650B7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State control</header>
 <subparagraph id="H72739E48E19947E99232B8001B70B4FE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>New adoption, or resumption of, and implementation by State</header><text>For a State for which the Administrator is implementing a coal combustion residuals permit program under subsection (e)(1)(A) or subsection (e)(1)(C), the State may adopt and implement such a permit program by—</text>
 <clause id="H4EA95D81E1424346BC1932E44ADFE3C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notifying the Administrator that the State will adopt and implement such a permit program;</text> </clause><clause id="H1DE690B1D26847DF991E6FDF24807C33"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after the date of such notification, submitting to the Administrator a certification under subsection (b)(2); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0CF139EE96A9434D91EC06C5255B157C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>receiving from the Administrator—</text> <subclause id="H4EEE67955E4E49E2B8511D051ED26506"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a determination, after the Administrator provides for a 30-day period for notice and public comment, that the State coal combustion residuals permit program meets the requirements described in subsection (c); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5A501A30F93F450094EE39D73D0AC6A6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a timeline for transition to the State coal combustion residuals permit program.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DF00CEB7ED1467CA66C38786E8E2AB1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Remedying deficient permit program</header><text>For a State for which the Administrator is implementing a coal combustion residuals permit program under subsection (e)(1)(B), the State may adopt and implement such a permit program by—</text>
 <clause id="HBD938948F0514B139DDF31B2E20170BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>remedying only the deficiencies detailed in the notice pursuant to subsection (d)(3)(A); and</text> </clause><clause id="HBBE2DE9C244D491BA4F1ECEDB4B95851"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receiving from the Administrator—</text>
 <subclause id="HE0EE2A26525D43579EE8DE5D8A16AD42"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a determination, after the Administrator provides for a 30-day period for notice and public comment, that the deficiencies detailed in such notice have been remedied; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB32DB75987BE42B089D2B835F79EA875"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a timeline for transition to the State coal combustion residuals permit program.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H244659974A8C4735BEAEFBEC6BE8554A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of determination</header> <subparagraph id="HEDD9D37CA6954E79901BB02E72F936E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text>The Administrator shall make a determination under paragraph (1) not later than 90 days after the date on which the State submits a certification under paragraph (1)(A)(ii), or notifies the Administrator that the deficiencies have been remedied pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(i), as applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB1EB933056E46C3A1452FE883521E34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text>A State may obtain a review of a determination by the Administrator under paragraph (1) as if such determination was a final regulation for purposes of section 7006.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H65079712E9044199B1DEC53D15F83565"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Implementation during transition</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8A3E6868FB614530A936C0CC5124C694"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effect on actions and orders</header><text>Program requirements of, and actions taken or orders issued pursuant to, a coal combustion residuals permit program shall remain in effect if—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7EA2765012CC463087185858238A69A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State takes control of its coal combustion residuals permit program from the Administrator under subsection (f)(1); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6CECF97B0BDD466F85F4F2F7F65257B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator takes control of a coal combustion residuals permit program from a State under subsection (e).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE06D259760CE4E73BA739DC74923FE2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Change in requirements</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall apply to such program requirements, actions, and orders until such time as—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B30E626B0A24020AAAE8405E1C78A34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the implementing agency that took control of the coal combustion residuals permit program changes the requirements of the coal combustion residuals permit program with respect to the basis for the action or order; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0A220B68A2C64B919965A11780F61DA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to an ongoing corrective action, the State or the Administrator, whichever took the action or issued the order, certifies the completion of the corrective action that is the subject of the action or order.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6D69EB7BFB2A42E5A053F3FA012266BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Single permit program</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD476A7D2B0C44648ADCC8ECB98BB70D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if a State adopts and implements a coal combustion residuals permit program under subsection (f), the Administrator shall cease to implement the coal combustion residuals permit program implemented under subsection (e) for such State; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H74CE2CFD0B244ED28681DAB8E460A995"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Administrator implements a coal combustion residuals permit program for a State under subsection (e)(1), the State shall cease to implement its coal combustion residuals permit program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB49D80DEF264C9B8642CD58FBC34FA3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effect on determination under 4005<enum-in-header>(c)</enum-in-header> or 3006</header><text>The Administrator shall not consider the implementation of a coal combustion residuals permit program by the Administrator under subsection (e) in making a determination of approval for a permit program or other system of prior approval and conditions under section 4005(c) or of authorization for a program under section 3006.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H7CF26320694E4ACBAA681853A97B4A72"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authority</header>
 <paragraph id="HABE2C819688C4D35975A4914CF8F862B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall preclude or deny any right of any State to adopt or enforce any regulation or requirement respecting coal combustion residuals that is more stringent or broader in scope than a regulation or requirement under this section.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HF8D51C2F30904407BBB473D8E4C1FF8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority of the Administrator</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC5917EA0070C42CF8D9FE164A4ACCCD8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsections (d), (e), and (g) of this section and section 6005, the Administrator shall, with respect to the regulation of coal combustion residuals under this Act, defer to the States pursuant to this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H132A034B520D470C90D8BA45AE5C77A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Imminent hazard</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Administrator under section 7003 with respect to coal combustion residuals.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DF2E644EFED4AED88B3049363575649"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Enforcement assistance only upon request</header><text>Upon request from the head of a lead State implementing agency, the Administrator may provide to such State agency only the enforcement assistance requested.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H78CAF04B758046D484548C050B955530"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Concurrent enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C) of this paragraph and subsection (g), the Administrator shall not have concurrent enforcement authority when a State is implementing a coal combustion residuals permit program, including during any period of interim operation described in subsection (c)(3)(D).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H903C1037384141118B2C94FA00C4E300"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Citizen suits</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the authority of a person to commence a civil action in accordance with section 7002.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74253F4E3D1E4173867431DF7BD284E2"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Mine reclamation activities</header><text>A coal combustion residuals permit program implemented by the Administrator under subsection (e) shall not apply to the utilization, placement, and storage of coal combustion residuals at surface or underground coal mining and reclamation operations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5B99DB136DEA48C59F59E80AB0A23F69"><enum>(k)</enum><header> Use of coal combustion residuals</header><text>Use of coal combustion residuals in any of the following ways shall not be considered to be receipt of coal combustion residuals for the purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC4DA8479CF2E45C1996843CF86F16383"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Use as—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9EFFFFDBE1DD4FBB94CF5B4D5A59F503"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engineered structural fill constructed in accordance with—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H69A126510423431E85E132F1F5073589"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ASTM E2277 entitled <quote>Standard Guide for Design and Construction of Coal Ash Structural Fills</quote>, including any amendment or revision to that guidance;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H81CA641A910445DFA0778AD70DE99FFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other published national standard determined appropriate by the implementing agency; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H110C5CDE87BB47069377DA797E34CE42"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a State standard or program relating to—</text> <subclause id="HA6E1C34376CE4DBE9A3F79080C17BA37"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fill operations for coal combustion residuals; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7FE61C4B509E4B89B5A437B9E6EC0297"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the management of coal combustion residuals for beneficial use; or</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCC8FB8295BBB43A6A44E2172790394FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engineered structural fill for—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HF1DF06E95F31488DB0F21E416C85D65B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a building site or foundation;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H44AF01AB628C4B9C8733CEFE3ED81D5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a base or embankment for a bridge, roadway, runway, or railroad; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA90F07B66C4F4428AB449F0B7C270D6B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a dike, levee, berm, or dam that is not part of a structure.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2C2CB80936674A7D998D9DDDD0CF89B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Storage in a manner that is consistent with the management of raw materials, if the coal combustion residuals being stored are intended to be used in a product or as a raw material.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5945A0BBEC2344C188051053E8FCD71E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Beneficial use—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE28CD7EF787C4387ABD4FE7543BD8610"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that provides a functional benefit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6526C3036FD2449091EC6E9FA0B96B2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is a substitute for the use of a virgin material;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H662C6E54F410464BB1BD75BA629F1286"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that meets relevant product specifications and regulatory or design standards; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE8B55682B40A43DAA7BB52AAEDAF07FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such use involves placement on the land of coal combustion residuals in non-roadway applications, in an amount equal to or greater than the amount described in the definition of beneficial use in section 257.53 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, for which the person using the coal combustion residuals demonstrates, and keeps records showing, that such use does not result in environmental releases to groundwater, surface water, soil, or air that—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H0F5BCD5273244419AC62273598BA3B10"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are greater than those from a material or product that would be used instead of the coal combustion residuals; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H6D8F2EA7D6DD4617A0D7BC52F9E0C151"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exceed relevant regulatory and health-based benchmarks for human and ecological receptors.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H83DCBDA018B4449D9ABC50B8D3E291B5"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Effect of rule</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H20ECBC4EAA81466C9E59A8F98D218305"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to the final rule entitled <quote>Hazardous and Solid Waste Management System; Disposal of Coal Combustion Residuals from Electric Utilities</quote> signed by the Administrator on December 19, 2014—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1C8E2528F51B4832810435995C43AD70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such rule shall be implemented only through a coal combustion residuals permit program under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H486BA084A2C948C3BFB31A70A527350D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent that any provision or requirement of such rule conflicts, or is inconsistent, with a provision or requirement of this section, the provision or requirement of this section shall control.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB6B6B172ECD6436C86CF2EBC586EF70E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References to the Code of Federal Regulations</header><text>For purposes of this section, any reference to a provision of the Code of Federal Regulations added by the rule described in paragraph (1) shall be considered to be a reference to such provision as it is contained in such rule.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H15B212D52C214D76AC6AC0EF5A773581"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>For purposes of this section, any reference in part 257 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, to the effective date contained in section 257.51 of such part shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this section, except that, in the case of any deadline established by such a reference that is in conflict with a deadline established by this section, the deadline established by this section shall control.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H22E05985F1444D53AF97D7DE3135C379"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability of other regulations</header><text>The application of section 257.52 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, is not affected by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF033FD124EBB4D7FAAA8DFBE8D609A42"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The definitions under section 257.53 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, shall apply with respect to any criteria described in subsection (c) the requirements of which are incorporated into a coal combustion residuals permit program under this section, except—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H78D3C46EFB704C9CA668D623656199AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as provided in paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9C6C3862A2F54CEAAE6E5A352FAA8493"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a lead State implementing agency may make changes to such definitions if the lead State implementing agency—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H862B25516A094030BE898713581862A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifies the changes in the explanation included with the certification submitted under subsection (b)(2)(C)(iii); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD6BA904053BD4B558D96BC9516A36A95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides in such explanation a reasonable basis for the changes.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H510645745E454506BC2383691161EFA8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Other criteria</header><text>The criteria described in sections 257.106 and 257.107 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, may be incorporated into a coal combustion residuals permit program at the discretion of the implementing agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEEBBE37C7294DA38AE2756A4F69ED18"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA0459042D8984299AF352B0CC662D2B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coal combustion residuals</header><text>The term <term>coal combustion residuals</term> means the following wastes generated by electric utilities and independent power producers:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H71B076E40F8F45D6A0FA6401CC56676A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The solid wastes listed in section 3001(b)(3)(A)(i) that are generated primarily from the combustion of coal, including recoverable materials from such wastes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6682BDAFA87044AF9D50B0C3A621E867"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Coal combustion wastes that are co-managed with wastes produced in conjunction with the combustion of coal, provided that such wastes are not segregated and disposed of separately from the coal combustion wastes and comprise a relatively small proportion of the total wastes being disposed in the structure.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H833E1334D24347C0B01C1DEEE6D4ED60"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Fluidized bed combustion wastes that are generated primarily from the combustion of coal.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFC92285529FA4D2690682FF01231C671"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Wastes from the co-burning of coal with non-hazardous secondary materials, provided that coal makes up at least 50 percent of the total fuel burned.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF49066E0FBBE45769142AEC495E90A02"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Wastes from the co-burning of coal with materials described in subparagraph (A) that are recovered from monofills.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H703E5D6D6327429AB2A2B760B4607421"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coal combustion residuals permit program</header><text>The term <term>coal combustion residuals permit program</term> means all of the authorities, activities, and procedures that comprise a system of prior approval and conditions implemented under this section to regulate the management and disposal of coal combustion residuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H965C68C3315C4AA98C6F7330CDAFE219"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electric utility; independent power producer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>electric utility</term> and <term>independent power producer</term> include only electric utilities and independent power producers that produce electricity on or after the date of enactment of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D01F5D3B4B347CCBB2C0D6C18C18CCE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Existing structure</header><text>The term <term>existing structure</term> means a structure the construction of which commenced before the date of enactment of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA94E72019F68431CACB29CCAD6E52519"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Implementing agency</header><text>The term <term>implementing agency</term> means the agency responsible for implementing a coal combustion residuals permit program, which shall either be the lead State implementing agency identified under subsection (b)(2)(C)(i) or the Administrator pursuant to subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4CB564BDECB40D68DC14736771E2BFA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment</header><text>The term <term>inactive coal combustion residuals surface impoundment</term> means a surface impoundment, located at an electric utility or independent power producer, that, as of the date of enactment of this section—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H63D26AE23D604798A95FD709E1840DA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>does not receive coal combustion residuals;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H45BA40A5422749E1A54AA5F203744CBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contains coal combustion residuals; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H99F3A76CDCAD4A33AFBEC9F42AA0EC92"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains liquid.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39E4914E457345458BE59A98E339F66B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Structure</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6CF1F0D56F824C50ABD771BB2FC30153"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>structure</term> means a landfill, surface impoundment, sand or gravel pit, or quarry that receives coal combustion residuals on or after the date of enactment of this section.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3244F31D19014F1D877E3617399B15F2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <clause id="HE95DB54FB4034E6A879ABB97B24D3C8F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Municipal solid waste landfills</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>structure</term> does not include a municipal solid waste landfill.</text> </clause><clause id="H8F42404CDD8B41C68B6D0C99AA10FACD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>De minimis receipt</header><text>The term <term>structure</term> does not include any landfill or surface impoundment that receives only de minimis quantities of coal combustion residuals if the presence of coal combustion residuals is incidental to the material managed in the landfill or surface impoundment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDE4E12645F8B46EB9296A3C124BA674D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Unlined surface impoundment</header><text>The term <term>unlined surface impoundment</term> means a surface impoundment that does not have a liner system described in section 257.71 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD70838E390A144768984A4729AC111E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of contents contained in section 1001 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4010 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H9FA846C235EE4D6B8F0BA54E8361C955" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4011. Management and disposal of coal combustion residuals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC80847688FEF431A81930A38F7529415"><enum>3.</enum><header>2000 regulatory determination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to alter in any manner the Environmental Protection Agency’s regulatory determination entitled <term>Notice of Regulatory Determination on Wastes From the Combustion of Fossil Fuels</term>, published at 65 Fed. Reg. 32214 (May 22, 2000), that the fossil fuel combustion wastes addressed in that determination do not warrant regulation under subtitle C of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6921">42 U.S.C. 6921 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="H183D7D42E4D64EE38617D442C787C5C9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to affect the authority of a State to request, or the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide, technical assistance under the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6901">42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="H8757BF800EC84D458601CDFF1EDD2734"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal Power Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to affect the obligations of an owner or operator of a structure (as such term is defined in section 4011 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act, as added by this Act) under section 215(b)(1) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824o">16 U.S.C. 824o(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


