<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3C326B33A86248709D77B391B5439B19" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3294 IH: Sanctuary Regulatory Fairness Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3294</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To establish a program to assist in the importation and care of abused, injured, or abandoned nonhuman primates.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC74111DD8721467F9DFA1991DB9ABBE3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6711B413A3B74ACEB5665A1CD7B4FA1E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sanctuary Regulatory Fairness Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H258D9EA25D804BEDA6EE73EA9A7F996C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1549E819E75B43959A675DF609C59252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nonhuman primates, such as chimpanzees, gorillas, orangutans, macaques, and numerous other species, often face abusive and cruel captive conditions in other countries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6462D02AC2C4C3BAF0DDC1D93661B52"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is growing evidence that, absent a suitable humane alternative, these primates will remain or be placed in other cruel captive conditions and face inhumane deaths in areas outside the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FE2D6E9969E41AFB5AD96D4081FB916"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention allow importation of nonhuman primates only for scientific, educational, or exhibition purposes and not for humane lifetime shelter and care in appropriate primate sanctuaries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CFC0FED23A84DABB14A59854327E0B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Many of these animals could be obtained by certified primate sanctuaries in the United States and provided with shelter and care for the remainder of their natural lives in a species-appropriate, humane environment if allowed by law to be imported for such purpose.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFAA33B01C8C1405190E37029F7A0CCDB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H451423450C684914923B6B7E57380845"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>certified primate sanctuary</term> means a primate sanctuary that has been certified by the Secretary pursuant to section 4.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EF00DFCF25A4E53AD3D6974878AAE66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>nonhuman primates</term> means the species included in the biological order Primates, except Homo sapiens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF8E47B62E2F4BBE81DC4A2857880708"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>primate sanctuary</term> means a facility that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H55A886B93EC944EDB83D36111966C4A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rescues and provides lifetime shelter and care for animals that have been abused, injured, or abandoned, or are otherwise in need;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08A555075FDD4A6C962537A8017E895C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FC5019337A541E0AA9CA5A6F480AA81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not commercially trade in any animals, including animal parts, animal byproducts, and animal offspring;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4771010C72F24C6AA09CC5A4594E2E81"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not intentionally breed or propagate nonhuman primates;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8A4F1794F374950A2D19590A96CF56C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>does not allow direct contact between the public and nonhuman primates;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7BBAEA8825942DCAC449D2C4F527962"><enum>(F)</enum><text>does not allow unescorted public visitation at the facility, except for discrete, nonintrusive observation by individuals approved by the sanctuary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9E4E1E4B938449C805DF7844837912E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>does not allow animals to be removed from the facility, or from the animals’ enclosures, for exhibition or education; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62452B6F11864CBA9E7EC679D236759B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>does not conduct research on animals, except where the facility determines that—</text> 
<clause id="H69D609C1653A4B5AA8867E67DF0C1464"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the health and welfare of the animal involved is best served by participating in a treatment study; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8C70427450A14AA4831C3FB54DD8696D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the facility reasonably believes that the outcome of the study will provide a tangible benefit to the animal involved.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F3A0E551FD54DE39FDC1AE5CA8E5D7E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA845A7BDAB4A4B64A05A74F4FC1F7F11"><enum>4.</enum><header>Importation of nonhuman primates</header> <subsection id="H13B0E18D17AF41C78291F548A791E81C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, consistent with section 361 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/264">42 U.S.C. 264</external-xref>; relating to control of communicable diseases), shall promulgate a final rule revising section 71.53(c) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, to expand the categories of uses for which nonhuman primates may be imported and distributed to include live nonhuman primates imported into the United States by a certified primate sanctuary for purposes of providing lifetime shelter and care.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H874468022FFE4296B166B09A18D3573F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification process</header> 
<paragraph id="HAAFB3ABB2B5841F591042DBEEFDA1505"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The rule required by subsection (a) shall establish a process under which the Secretary certifies facilities as primate sanctuaries for purposes of the importation, shelter, and care of nonhuman primates, as described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD41E5ED3DA6842C7A013F6FE7D6F889E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall require, as a condition of such certification, that a facility—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H16666D5011AC47198325C265D845CB62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a primate sanctuary, as defined in section 3; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63797340A99346AA960583C696E52F74"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">satisfies any other criteria that—</text> 
<clause id="H4C9155EEBC164E6B838B1F615A084A65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are determined to be appropriate by the Secretary; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1BFD515AFA0044C495FEE67311047B7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are consistent with the criteria specified in the definition of a primate sanctuary in section 3.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H937BAAE306A142258C4C64F656A57BFE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To seek certification under this Act, a primate sanctuary shall submit an application in such form, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Any information in an application for certification under this Act shall be protected from disclosure as provided in section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

