<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3D5719BAB9C94354B4E6BE51C0645DF0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3585 IH: Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3585</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150922">September 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize surface transportation research and development programs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H36C469D5A5114D40952E018917C26AC4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H14365185A9A64FB087384B511A814E6F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H05FD625162DB4DCC97FCD0D6F3350093"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the followings findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC21BB090F4A940BC978ACCF96653F4B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal transportation research and development planning and coordination—</text> <subparagraph id="H712BA705DD074757A5BE1B56827E42FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>should occur within the Office of the Secretary of Transportation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H555852A66CAD46E0AA996BCE1A5A6423"><enum>(B)</enum><text>should be, to the extent practicable, multimodal and not occur solely within the subagencies of the Department of Transportation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45BDEF1671C948F4B420FBF8FD4349BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Managing a multimodal research and development portfolio within the Office of the Secretary will—</text> <subparagraph id="H5040CB9D2F78493896C7F572FEE863FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>help identify opportunities where research could be applied across modes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2007F2A71C314A7EBD07990C672B1F6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevent duplication of efforts and waste of limited Federal resources.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA0B310BDE9044618840B53184E3F5CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Increasing transparency of transportation research and development efforts will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC6FE4F63FC944C5C9000C5929E4B50DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>build stakeholder confidence in the final product; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2B0952291F64AA78624D566D9E85108"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lead to the improved implementation of research and development findings.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H937CBF129189440AA80FC8225784DA69"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transportation research and development 5-year strategic plan</header>
 <subsection id="H174A85F38FF34DF9BC2477CB839C3F4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall develop a 5-year transportation research and development strategic plan for fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to guide future Federal transportation research and development activities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCF27CA4E63C7497B873689E6A45FCB93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consistency</header><text>The strategic plan developed under subsection (a) shall be consistent with—</text> <paragraph id="H0111098D259F4F15BC36EBE619C23EAD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 306 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2FCD1FA0C8F4240AFD9A9462F4140E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sections 1115 and 1116 of title 31, United States Code; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A336114237D435487E4F7FF06EDF96A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other research and development plan within the Department of Transportation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7934381CABA34C828A02BE54D69FC868"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The strategic plan developed under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HCC56731F49684531AFE4385E440B84D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describe the primary purposes of the transportation research and development program, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9FD1A8CD12BF4EEF967C8809AE4ADDEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving mobility of people and goods;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90FE60263D184DCFA28F5F680D1F9D1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reducing congestion;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H986ADC7342A04B7787613D56588B4022"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promoting safety; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48258B2C551D4A9F98BD8D876B670DD1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improving the durability and extending the life of transportation infrastructure;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29A7B03081FB4EAFB2261B95D4BBDEB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each of the purposes referred to in paragraph (1), list the proposed research and development activities that the Department of Transportation intends to pursue to accomplish that purpose, which may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAD3F672EC82B4ED3BD4F5412F48030E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fundamental research pertaining to the applied physical and natural sciences;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H390596B4216C4CE390C3C80B3EC6A86C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applied science and research;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED94AD9250424DCE9ED01E894300AFF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technology development research; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FF3E03177B7497A89FF429A89DB411D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>social science research; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB8AE807A2A74644A0363FD79D4BE6D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for each research and development activity—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA51CB698DD14B0091D28046A7310426"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify the anticipated annual funding levels for the period covered by the strategic plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37A7276EE63847BC92C85949548C9914"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the research findings the Department of Transportation expects to discover at the end of the period covered by the strategic plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA3267561F9D433994C6B4256B70B473"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the strategic plan developed under this section—</text> <paragraph id="H733AA57DA9D1489B89C92DD3AC6D9EBF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reflects input from external stakeholders;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H753D573709F146C38AE31112E7F81B22"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes and integrates the research and development programs of all of the Department of Transportation’s modal administrations and joint programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7C295AB1BA544FD9CE024301FD3D351"><enum>(3)</enum><text>takes into account research and development by other Federal, State, local, private sector, and nonprofit institutions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE787DDD31004605823C0CB2065206F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is published on a public website by December 31, 2016.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H522901088F78445C9F30C5FF2C2E1E7C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H689CE9CB241642D79CAC3758166968E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National Research Council review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the National Research Council for a review and analysis of the Department’s 5-year research and development strategic plan described in this section. By March 31, 2017, the Secretary shall publish on a public website the National Research Council’s analysis of the Department’s plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC4F9B05AA843D785324A1849D387BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By June 30, 2019, the Secretary shall publish on a public website an interim report that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCB7A98114F7A4FDC92DA575A75B81809"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides an assessment of the Department’s 5-year research and development strategic plan described in this section that includes a description of the extent to which the research and development is or is not successfully meeting the purposes described under subsection (c)(1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H470B553400554696923CAB27347C7BB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>addresses any concerns and identifies any gaps that may have been raised by the National Research Council analysis under paragraph (1), including how the plan is or is not responsive to the National Research Council review.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75E928EDA2F24CB5807DAF411EB0C2B6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H91CFF12AF0E245DB8F19BB39EE3CA68C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chapter 5 of title 23</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/5">Chapter 5</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H392251D83E32436AA6C322CC79DCBEA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking section 508;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92FB514CCC9D46A4A59C1E4EA5C8F9E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the table of contents, by striking the item relating to section 508;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H063A7FAE88D143339E4321F8292B478D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 502—</text>
 <clause id="H9B478E52A32A4D2BAE92751FBD95FA80"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(9), by striking <quote>transportation research and technology development strategic plan developed under section 508</quote> and inserting <quote>transportation research and development strategic plan under section 3 of the <short-title>Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2015</short-title></quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD4583F2BF1274D42980CA729F7407EC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(4), by striking <quote>transportation research and development strategic plan of the Secretary developed under section 508</quote> and inserting <quote>transportation research and development strategic plan under section 3 of the <short-title>Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2015</short-title></quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60F28B1127C04FF896402E99085C1428"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in section 512(b), by striking <quote>as part of the transportation research and development strategic plan developed under section 508</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C94D62835B3478397DB86DF11D41E2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intelligent transportation systems</header><text>The Intelligent Transportation Systems Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/502">23 U.S.C. 502</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC1062B281B4648B0B70D6C950554B070"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 5205(b), by striking <quote>as part of the Surface Transportation Research and Development Strategic Plan developed under section 508 of title 23, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>as part of the transportation research and development strategic plan under section 3 of the <short-title>Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2015</short-title></quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51C3F9BAB3104A9C95CF87490911CAC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 5206(e)(2)(A), by striking <quote>or the Surface Transportation Research and Development Strategic Plan developed under section 508 of title 23, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>or the transportation research and development strategic plan under section 3 of the <short-title>Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H322CF848D6C14D4194DACE80A55DAAF1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intelligent transportation system research</header><text>Subtitle C of title V of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/512">23 U.S.C. 512</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H467AB79A18AF4AC79D599E4FA9EE37A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 5305(h)(3)(A), by striking <quote>the strategic plan under section 508 of title 23, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>the 5-year transportation research and development strategic plan under section 3 of the <short-title>Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2015</short-title></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58D5FA76387F420AB766855EC009AD31"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 5307(c)(2)(A), by striking <quote>or the surface transportation research and development strategic plan developed under section 508 of title 23, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>or the 5-year transportation research and development strategic plan under section 3 of the <short-title>Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE0B1A14629F6453F89FE68DC0ABB5521"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual research plans and research abstract database</header>
 <subsection id="H47039529B8004900957F98088824F23A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than May 1 of each year, the head of each modal administration and joint program office of the Department of Transportation shall submit a comprehensive annual research plan for the fiscal year following the upcoming fiscal year to the Assistant Secretary for Research and Technology of the Department of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>). Each plan submitted under this subsection, after 2016, shall be consistent with the strategic plan developed under section 3.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD53E5A8C463E4AB79277D890E0A92A81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header>
 <paragraph id="HC81C88C3A8634FCAB751F1E11EBEC3C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than September 1 of each year, the Assistant Secretary, for each plan submitted pursuant to subsection (a), shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H66DF18BE68BA4C4297DF34F6A424025A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the scope of the research; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H334453A1B0284606A930A016C0DB2A1F"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H77CB93D11D544125B334F8519B04C5D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve the plan; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFA30B352DBD94C38BCAC7FEADD31C80B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>request that the plan be revised and resubmitted for approval.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5315BD9CDAD74D34B92F2C6C3DDA64C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publications</header><text>Not later than January 30 of each year, the Assistant Secretary shall publish on a public website each plan that has been approved under paragraph (1)(B)(i).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H439694AC3FDC476CB41AC1A19A13D9BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rejection of duplicative research efforts</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may not approve any plan submitted by the head of a modal administration or joint program office pursuant to subsection (a) if such plan duplicates significant aspects of research projects of any other modal administration.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86093746ED53481793F724B3DB93A606"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding limitations</header><text>No funds may be expended by the Department of Transportation on research that has not previously been approved as part of a research plan approved by the Assistant Secretary unless—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDBC65704014E44C8BF7837D27B700FB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such research is required by an Act of Congress;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF67D19F7CD3426293B83611A1E29B5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such research was part of a contract that was funded before the date of enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE013B61484CF42E287F7DB59DCA75232"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Transportation certifies to Congress that such research is necessary and provides justification for the certification.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3A6278B46FA4BC89AE5E73F1F404586"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duplicative research</header>
 <paragraph id="HABECA680A40E49BAB62E0E0E6A2540AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), no funds may be expended by the Department of Transportation on more than one research project that the Assistant Secretary identifies as duplicative under subsection (b)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB5B27A26A1F4474999AA2B5EA7185EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text> <subparagraph id="H992EBC78C8364CB5BADD5FF28515BAB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research commissioned before the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8A5C273298F45BC878973A63ABB872E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>updates to previously commissioned research, including replication studies; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EE850AF654D48DFB6C6F0DF46FB286B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>research specifically required by law.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF247D4A08AF2466289AAB81F359F71DE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Research abstract database</header>
 <paragraph id="HE24FECFD04B64CCB836D7618AFC2F9C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall annually publish on a public website a comprehensive database of all research projects conducted by the Department of Transportation, including, to the extent practicable, research funded through University Transportation Centers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F988C1128C449748A43F318EDE7E00D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The database published under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9DFFA7383A064DDEB8C9106531CDF2D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the research plans approved under subsection (b)(1)(B)(i);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFA60FBBA0134CE09D337A78721E8284"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the research objectives, progress, findings, and allocated funds for each research project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67414B32C2994AB6AEFC18B4ABA05A93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify research projects with multimodal applications;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4A33DCF64644540902702E128282759"><enum>(D)</enum><text>specify how relevant modal administrations have assisted, will contribute to, or plan to use the findings from the research projects identified under paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BEBEA06B69148FE973DA95507895CB5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identify areas in which more than 1 modal administration is conducting research on a similar subject or a subject which has a bearing on more than 1 mode;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF32944CA251244FD925EA2E390884634"><enum>(F)</enum><text>describe the interagency and cross-modal communication and coordination that has occurred to develop the research plans approved under subsection (b)(1)(B)(i), and to prevent duplication of research projects within the Department of Transportation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEDA2908A33E4269902E4B7ED12097C4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>indicate how the findings of research are being disseminated to improve the efficiency, effectiveness, and safety of transportation systems; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AC193A9A8174924A12DDF1196A6414C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>describe the specific content and sources of public and stakeholder input to the research plans approved under subsection (b)(1)(B)(i).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A9CA83A88AD419693846DABA331719C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding report</header><text>In conjunction with each of the President’s annual budget requests under section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to Congress and annually publish on a public website a report that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4670415C12934B629B8A933697239A7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount spent in the last completed fiscal year on each transportation research and development project; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F0F917D94434C2F870AC415C8548608"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount that the Secretary plans or estimates the Department will spend during the current fiscal year on each transportation research and development project.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1EC2A275B8A3491AA007040FF928C818" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Traffic congestion</header>
 <subsection id="H8E66F17BB3794202BC2B72EC26EE212F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Working group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall establish a working group consisting of appropriate representatives from the different modal administrations of the Department of Transportation, chaired by the Assistant Secretary of Transportation for Research and Technology, to design, develop, and propose a program of research on the reduction of traffic congestion.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E96CEF0F6684EF4BB78DDD2BA8B88D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The working group established under subsection (a), shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF96E67518B244A199C57F117DC8BB977"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish goals and objectives for the program under this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5199FC2E99144E5AA3790889A0CAC3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend research to accelerate the adoption of transportation management systems that allow traffic to flow in the safest and most efficient manner possible while alleviating current and future traffic congestion challenges;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7C0F7CA0083438F85F53AB4DF25B9B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess and analyze traffic, transit, and freight data from various sources relevant to efforts to reduce traffic congestion so as to maximize mobility, efficiency, and capacity while decreasing congestion and travel times;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85F5F0F176FE4645B10BCAF0D1C3582F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the use and integration of multiple data types from multiple sources and technologies, including road weather data, private vehicle (including Global Positioning System) data, arterial and highway traffic conditions, transit vehicle arrival and departure times, real time navigation routing, construction zone information, and reports of incidents, to suggest improvements in effective communication of such data and information in real time;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD6F124838EB4D20A81FEA1B5C370F68"><enum>(5)</enum><text>study and propose solutions to the traffic congestion issues on high-traffic roads in the Washington, DC, area to alleviate and prevent gridlock in and around the Nation’s Capital, reflecting its significance as the seat of the Federal Government and headquarters for several critical national security agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98035C42D0D148A0BC09D7FB5D5D00D9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop and disseminate suggested strategies and solutions to reduce congestion for high-density traffic regions nationwide; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA96C4FB00844461A46A7D568CE53DD5"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate with other relevant Federal agencies, State and local agencies, industry and industry associations, and university research centers to fulfill its goals and objectives.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8609D3AA052E4297A0F91BD23C00305A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identifying information</header><text>The working group shall ensure that information used pursuant to this section does not contain identifying information of any individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA6A2312847A4D979D86937FE0739DEF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>The working group shall keep the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate apprised of the activities and progress of the working group at least once every 6 months.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC4694FC91EC40979EE8B469F5D8ACD6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the working group shall transmit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report on its activities under this section, including a transportation strategy that enables our transportation system in and around Washington, DC, to provide mobility in the event of an emergency or natural disaster.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H697FE60AE8274FAA8D4BA01E85CD98A8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Highway efficiency</header>
			<subsection id="H222F0FB3F35C4B439E82043BED0A847C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header>
 <paragraph id="HDF28303C5B684F48BC3DED9509F13AAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary of Transportation for Research and Technology shall examine the impact of pavement durability and sustainability on vehicle fuel consumption, vehicle wear and tear, road conditions, and road repairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H392D15E6A5434A53B548A97575373502"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the study, the Assistant Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H950D19B3B9F647769E6FB6411DAD1E75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a thorough review of relevant peer-reviewed research published during at least the past 5 years;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H300E35BCBFB5410A89E23D11C8919A82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>analyze impacts of different types of pavement on all motor vehicle types, including commercial vehicles;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CB5D43A821A409DA36C32AD34F7C33A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>specifically examine the impact of pavement deformation and deflection; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28600C6B2C734BE7BB6B80C29FCF32C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze impacts of different types of pavement on road conditions and road repairs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2CB49A1A4F34EB191822210F7CAD6CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the study, the Assistant Secretary shall consult with—</text> <subparagraph id="HBFCA122A6CE74A44AD5669120FB10FD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>experts from the different modal administrations of the Department of Transportation and from other Federal agencies, including the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3406A4ABB2C48C681386632B564ED65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State departments of transportation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9799A5D6B394F4E96C2CC94D73BD170"><enum>(C)</enum><text>local government engineers and public works professionals;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H909150093206416D9A3A6B6960403042"><enum>(D)</enum><text>industry stakeholders; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H534F1DC9F3DC4AAA82BE3ABE165382ED"><enum>(E)</enum><text>appropriate academic experts active in the field.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EB32B1C84654ABBA9D56B7005462BC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H4556A85A85144CC4B2C6B16CD7E6F96D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall publish on a public website the results of the study.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C274A755A3B47CCA26896E27098B7DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H4202BAA1A6624D1984868311B7DB50C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the different types of pavements analyzed in the study and the impacts of pavement durability and sustainability on vehicle fuel consumption, vehicle wear and tear, road conditions, and road repairs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA36998BED59741EC894957F17C7A9AEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for State and local governments on best practice methods for improving pavement durability and sustainability to maximize vehicle fuel economy, ride quality, and road conditions and to minimize the need for road and vehicle repairs.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0FBF4721047A41FBB31D5A04E8201709"><enum>7.</enum><header>Intelligent transportation technologies</header>
 <subsection id="HBBAA0E168503427199794A1DB9AD342D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary of Transportation for Research and Technology, as part of the Intelligent Transportation Systems research program, with the goal of reducing traffic congestion and vehicle crashes and accelerating testing and research on the introduction of safe, connected, and automated vehicle technology systems, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEC539F8A86ED43F1BDFC416D29481328"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to identify and understand—</text> <subparagraph id="H0DBA1667F4C04E36BACD2ADF22D876C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>new and innovative vehicle technologies, including active safety technologies, and their safe application in vehicles; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2EC51EB5ED7464DBBC341CF2A46ACC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emerging vehicle technologies and advanced communications and sensing techniques that may require additional exploration and understanding by the Department of Transportation of how such technologies work alone and in conjunction with other vehicle and relevant nonvehicle technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A313A789B584541AEA19611B9953BDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess wireless technologies’ capabilities to achieve a deployable system in which vehicles of all types (including automobiles, trucks, motor coaches, transit vehicles, and other fleets), traffic signals, other infrastructure systems, pedestrians, motorcyclists, bicyclists, and mobile devices can interact with and among each other through secure communications, including by conducting rigorous, real-world testing, in cooperation with representatives of the Federal Communications Commission, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the automotive, Wi-Fi, cellular, and Intelligent Transportation Systems communities, of viable spectrum sharing technologies that could enable the safe operation of unlicensed devices, including Wi-Fi, in the 5.9 GHz band without interfering with connected and automated vehicle communications; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA9BBD23542145ED886DE8CC9645EC99"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist in the development of cybersecurity standards in cooperation with relevant modal administrations of the Department of Transportation and other Federal agencies, including the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to help prevent hacking, spoofing, and disruption of connected and automated transportation applications among surface transportation vehicles of all types.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF160318D6FE42D9AEB2B40A770855D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Upon completion of the testing described in subsection (a)(2), the Secretary of Transportation shall send to Congress and the Federal Communications Commission, and publish on a public website, a report identifying any potential signal interference risks to connected and automated vehicle communications that may exist due to unlicensed devices, including Wi-Fi, operating in the 5.9 GHz band, including a determination of whether such devices can safely operate in the 5.9 GHz band without creating signal interference that could jeopardize or delay the deployment of an effective connected and automated vehicle communications system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H894987FF0FF348D1853FC9E7BC6F904A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Assistant Secretary of Transportation for Research and Technology shall document and analyze the technologies described in subsection (a), and share results of the analysis with the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration annually.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9101AA741945462FAD24CE098C869D19"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary and the Assistant Secretary shall ensure the privacy of individuals.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF4003C09F906482BB91FCEA4B6A65A1A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>active safety technologies</quote> means technologies which actively assist drivers or vehicles in preventing or mitigating a crash.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H0E9A0E28DCAC46A6B6F29E3F22EFA257"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rail safety</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of Transportation for Research and Technology shall transmit to Congress a report containing—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7FA1F59C63DD4F959394DD0F8ECB2DC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of a study to examine the state of rail safety technologies and an analysis of whether the passenger, commuter, and transit rail transportation industries are keeping up with innovations in technologies to make rail cars safer for passengers and transport of commerce;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H636112037A3641E8883092FF33DD6C88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a determination of how much additional time and public and private resources will be required for railroad carriers to meet the positive train control system implementation requirements under section 20157 of title 49, United States Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81A7FA4B6D44431EABC88BE1E77F7705"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of technologies that in whole or in part achieve the safety goals of the positive train control implementation requirements under section 20157 that could be implemented sooner than positive train control systems, along with an analysis of the advantages and disadvantages, including costs, of incorporating those alternative technologies to supplement or substitute for positive train control systems.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1AFAE0D1FA55451FABF6FA4231813D34" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>9.</enum><header>University Transportation Centers program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5505 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF4573CB391BC4C839FE16061479203D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(B) by inserting <quote>multimodal</quote> before <quote>transportation knowledge</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H468CE218C96C4AB5A6BCD3D1A7A24BE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B2A21FA801E4A4E86CD1A8BB730E934"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23FFC9133DB746F3BDD2DD446CE78603" style="USC">
						<paragraph commented="no" id="H6625A6FD410D44FF8D77F15C1234F6DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restrictions</header>
							<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1EFF3F08F2D4475CAA94A3C8AA2BE7A9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation on applications</header>
 <clause id="H2144381D274C446D87955180E449E0A1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit institution of higher education may only submit 1 grant application described in clause (ii) per fiscal year for each of the transportation centers described under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (c).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HADDB3B3E7EB94FA98B8B282975035AA6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applications referred to in clause (i) are applications submitted by a nonprofit institution of higher education—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H4186030EA2D944C1A5027674CC9D2BCF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an individual capacity, not through participation in a consortium of nonprofit institutions of higher education; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H8D5C7AD2797845D3B21530C697B380A6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as the lead institution of a consortium of nonprofit institutions of higher education.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EFBB88C2A1A4E22BAA4E00A880B9884"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit institution of higher education may not receive in any fiscal year more than 1 grant under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (c) based on applications described in subparagraph (A)(ii) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6F058D5FB3B4E6EAEB39A6D0C2341E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(B)(iii) by inserting <quote>multimodal</quote> before <quote>transportation problems</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95C30167FCAC437DBBD8AE96CE22FC03"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4)(B)(v)(II) by inserting <quote>, including women and underrepresented populations</quote> after <quote>field</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91AE96A82DE24DFF8F01D1B6E3851059"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H420F877335A542988F37C37B1AE32BCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>1 year after the date of enactment of the Transportation Research and Innovative Technology Act of 2012</quote> and inserting <quote>June 1, 2017</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BFE2BBCCEA84D0CAB0B9F9CE5C06424"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3)(E) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HB3E2353DE9064DA5ACF2C07D4C69D565" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H7831F1E04A79443685804C66EE91E2F5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Focused research</header> <clause id="H46738F3DB74A4E5D95E58144414024C0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Comprehensive transportation safety</header><text>The Secretary shall make a grant to 1 of the 10 regional university transportation centers established under this paragraph for the purpose of furthering the objectives described in subsection (a)(2) in the field of comprehensive transportation safety.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4D49351FB3B7451DB0C770B8ACAB06CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Traffic congestion</header><text>The Secretary shall make a separate grant to 1 of the 10 regional university transportation centers established under this paragraph for the purpose of furthering the objectives described in subsection (a)(2) in the field of traffic congestion.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D0192EF8B78453B8789BDC7E0A5E86B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <clause id="HABF308B2C8FF410590072FD6625E78E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H061705E5AD0248E3B487C03A317E593D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (C) and (D) as subparagraphs (B) and (C), respectively; and</text> </clause><clause id="HB5DF2950F46543F88025DB0D2918C031"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C), as so redesignated by clause (ii) of this subparagraph, by striking <quote>paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>section</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H651A37214AD44F7497C556459D691011" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>10.</enum><header>Prize competitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 502(b)(7) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H98FEAD145C354EEF8ED186BDBCA163A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9FE698F3692E496BBCA5080DB710EA55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(such as www.challenge.gov)</quote> after <quote>public website</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H571C71DC1609432AA08847C87E948C6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (iii) and (iv) as clauses (iv) and (v), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56CF3521916548C789733809B1C65C3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ii) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H942C2F3262A648929F3033414BD68DE2" style="USC"> <clause id="H3CF67D80DE114446ACD7FF8D5DC3BD0A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the process for participants to register for the competition;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H521EF02C09FE44DE84CD947F9D62144B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in clause (iv) (as redesignated by subparagraph (B) of this paragraph), by striking <quote>prize</quote> and inserting <quote>cash prize purse</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H215748E4644E426381C8128391EB086E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>prize</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>cash prize purse</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0141A3270B046FAB5815FFC059B3E3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (F) through (K) as subparagraphs (G) through (L), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9481E35EFFB244F58404A2D7CC6E8242"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1D9EF5CD7AB42089D9DA8877DD39B9B" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H0D88FCB8D7564E9F8AF12F7F64161E88"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Use of Federal facilities; consultation with Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual or entity is not ineligible to receive a cash prize purse under this paragraph as a result of the individual or entity using a Federal facility or consulting with a Federal employee related to the individual or entity’s participation in a prize competition under this paragraph if the same facility or employee is made available to all individuals and entities participating in the prize competition on an equitable basis.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDEA85F74CA04A589C460AF37AC9A986"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G) (as redesignated by paragraph (3) of this section)—</text> <subparagraph id="H703F503060CD458385BCAF5F7A06320C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i)(I), by striking <quote>competition</quote> and inserting <quote>prize competition under this paragraph</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC4AF370F967467CB09F0AFBAC8DE232"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii)(I)—</text> <clause id="HC3770060C81F4CCAB305FD3C006CFB3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>participation in a competition</quote> and inserting <quote>participation in a prize competition under this paragraph</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA4399DF340DF4CEF9594785F929A85E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>competition activities</quote> and inserting <quote>prize competition activities</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C72B439123A4A45815441BE8C65A65A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EC2A54DCF1143FBB7A1343DB93928AC" style="USC">
						<clause id="H911FFFE431E9477E96C940739C6662FE"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Intellectual property</header>
 <subclause id="H1757D69B1F6449A5A7EE8281AD04A3F8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Prohibition on requiring waiver</header><text>The Secretary may not require a participant to waive claims against the Department arising out of the unauthorized use or disclosure by the Department of the intellectual property, trade secrets, or confidential business information of the participant.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H16E02E1C05A64AC4897F8C6CBD446C13"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Prohibition on government acquisition of intellectual property rights</header><text>The Federal Government may not gain an interest in intellectual property developed by a participant for a prize competition under this paragraph without the written consent of the participant.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6E809CC3BCA14EF3B52A8954ECCFB137"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Licenses</header><text>The Federal Government may negotiate a license for the use of intellectual property developed by a participant for a prize competition under this paragraph.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H202426D0A8DE4FA89C6F615727019956"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (H)(i) (as redesignated by paragraph (3) of this section), by striking <quote>subparagraph (H)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (I)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H40B02C1B0F95436EB01157823C4CC48F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (I) (as redesignated by paragraph (3) of this section), by striking <quote>an agreement with a private, nonprofit entity</quote> and inserting <quote>a grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or other agreement with a private sector for-profit or nonprofit entity</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CB912B21F7340FBBC3D5AE34DAA1D65"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (J) (as redesignated by paragraph (3) of this section)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF128A4D881BC40E1B6B5A32CC3A09B77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text>
 <clause id="H401ED4EBD1A44327AF9C6E4696821377"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>the private sector</quote> and inserting <quote>private sector for-profit and nonprofit entities, to be available to the extent provided by appropriations Acts</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD4A95DD4EA2040E786FE78CB2BFC23A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>and metropolitan planning organizations</quote> and inserting <quote>metropolitan planning organizations, and private sector for-profit and nonprofit entities</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H996C8E221E0E44D09BABCCC7BE08A244"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subclause (III), by inserting <quote>for-profit or nonprofit</quote> after <quote>private sector</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADC1BC0C63BE4D2490C6DD40807A1590"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>prize awards</quote> and inserting <quote>cash prize purses</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4B8FD60D1394B12B5D487E103A47750"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (iv)—</text>
 <clause id="H72149C69A548479AB1164B69E88955C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>competition</quote> after <quote>A prize</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5C9A496D889F43B6AF22D36689AF2193"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the prize</quote> and inserting <quote>the cash prize purse</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57FE62A8F9024E71B8880907DD6FC851"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in clause (v)—</text> <clause id="HF4F1B4631893460480A512FEF30738BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>amount of a prize</quote> and inserting <quote>amount of a cash prize purse</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H44668384763340A3939CB10BBFCCCC85"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>competition</quote> after <quote>announcement of the prize</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H135704B72DB14FDCAD86E74F8DDA4BEF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by inserting <quote>competition</quote> after <quote>prize</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA54F71BC25BF471AB62AD1515D6B73DC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in clause (vi), by striking <quote>offer a prize</quote> and inserting <quote>offer a cash prize purse</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AAEFB74B7764790ADE99A5A7B3D34FE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by striking <quote>cash prizes</quote> and inserting <quote>cash prize purses</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E7941384C764CED9C64D0C18779FC34"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (K) (as redesignated by paragraph (3) of this section), by striking <quote>or providing a prize</quote> and inserting <quote>a prize competition or providing a cash prize purse</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEC924C20B6742B2B79C2F7FBF74151E"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (L)(ii) (as redesignated by paragraph (3) of this section)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H25478767CFAD4B77A03DD0F872ACF496"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H638657056F1E4E8CB25436AD47A578C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (II)—</text>
 <clause id="HDCBEDD69F9544F60AFB6D834692AB837"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in item (cc), by striking <quote>cash prizes</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>cash prize purses</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H602579B8606346CBB56E50753E8E48A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in item (ee), by striking <quote>agency</quote> and inserting <quote>Department</quote>.</text>
					</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H63EE3402C0C14992BC095E65DFE4048A"><enum>11.</enum><header>Motorcycle safety</header>
 <subsection id="HA80E457B486049F0995F861055EAD804"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Research and Technology of the Department of Transportation shall enter into an agreement, within 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study on the most effective means of preventing motorcycle crashes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB53E92A2923449D8AD8FAAD56F46EFFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Department of Transportation may not provide a grant or any funds to a State, county, town, township, Indian tribe, municipal, or other local government to be used for any program to check helmet usage or create checkpoints for an operator of a motorcycle or passenger on a motorcycle until the Assistant Secretary submits to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the study required under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DEDC6A478C449C68BBD3B2C0F7A6379"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submittal to congressional committees</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall submit the report to the committees as described in subsection (b) within 30 days after receiving the results of the study from the National Academy of Sciences.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H06D0520BCFC54F9ABB6B974225901D89"><enum>12.</enum><header>Prohibition of lobbying activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds appropriated to the Secretary of Transportation shall be available for any activity whose purpose is to influence any pending Federal, State, or local legislation, except that this section shall not prevent officers or employees of the United States or of its departments or agencies from communicating to Members of Congress on the request of any Member or to Congress, through the proper channels, requests for legislation or appropriations which they deem necessary for the efficient conduct of the public business. Nothing in this section shall prohibit officers or employees of the United States or its departments or agencies from testifying before any Federal, State, or local legislative body upon the invitation of such legislative body.</text>
		</section><section id="H04D7BA98E4E043E0A69184D25F6567E5"><enum>13.</enum><header>Bridge safety</header>
 <subsection id="H2A925E9BF4EC4B359743426645A0D448"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Highway and bridge infrastructure research and development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 503(b)(3)(A)(i) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, including through corrosion prevention measures for structural integrity of bridges</quote> before the semicolon.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H2B4D26DE5E2D4072956E8B43AC1EB3F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research, development, testing, and training for railroad safety</header><text>Section 20108(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, including corrosion prevention measures and structural integrity of rail bridges</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0DE60E35B158493FB342884828797DAF"><enum>14.</enum><header>Hazardous materials research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5118 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H59D0ECA3EA7E4256AB838C122D596815"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3A656B955FE8474BAD6B27383A95D18D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7052D4E0B094C5E8604CA271C461CB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote> ; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1273946F5EB4D9DB5ACC1B89FA7228A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E0D85D83977489BA3530FAD51805756" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="HB1FB01867E574925B467AB5BC997E246"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate, as appropriate, with other Federal agencies, including the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of Energy.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF30039AD4291402EA6D6D3AD3C287817"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6747B9393F824D3E8227FB5802A9A5D2" style="USC"> <subsection id="HF311C4CDAA8E43DE8941749802ECC193"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cooperative research</header> <paragraph id="HF935490FFEEA4D27877FF5E64D8A2641"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the program established in subsection (a), the Secretary may carry out cooperative research on hazardous materials transport.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF66A84ECD1C948C5967C2F0A28B0EAB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Academies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may enter into an agreement with the National Academies to support such research.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1A1DA840CB14C4BADB2D731188ED54F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Research</header><text>Research conducted under this subsection may include activities related to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2F99CA290F1E4ADDB3D7CC4BF4CEC35D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emergency planning and response, including information and programs that can be readily assessed and implemented in local jurisdictions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC79EC4FEB0C4DF88042A27A4F7BF008"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">risk analysis and perception and data assessment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7F55B53CD5A4910AEBDDBC8FE557F57"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commodity flow data, including voluntary collaboration between shippers and first responders for secure data exchange of critical information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9638230B9CDF450B93FA8F34D7EDB753"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integration of safety and security;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F9AAC99BF15477890517A22FA57CA7B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cargo packaging and handling;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD4E135A47B148719FF41A84EE486BA3"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hazmat release consequences; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09702AF2EEA94E499B96EABB9ED98E38"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">materials and equipment testing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF2ECF418F28A4255AEDA2597CADF37BC"><enum>15.</enum><header>Web-based training for emergency responders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5115(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, including online curriculum as appropriate,</quote> after <quote>a current curriculum of courses</quote>.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

