<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBECDB2C6912240F4B336762C72D7FFDE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 280 IH: To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to recoup bonuses and awards paid to employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 280</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150112">January 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to recoup bonuses and awards paid to employees of
			 the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H31C58A3885F04176B35175CDD82B42C0" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9A6FB84A21B24F4D881E7B4843B81D40" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authority to recoup bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="HF4753943ADBA40069ECDAA67B2B85AC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7843C319B39147E9A08ABEAD59CC7634" style="USC">
					<section id="HD8CB63C4CBB84CF1B2B74B988588E773"><enum>715.</enum><header>Recoupment of bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department</header>
 <subsection id="HE50B6410660048CFB395C71A3A512FF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recoupment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may issue an order directing an employee of the Department to repay the amount, or a portion of the amount, of any award or bonus paid to the employee under title 5, including under chapters 45 or 53 of such title, or this title if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H13F849393F4B4C8EB56E8726B94315F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines such repayment appropriate pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary to carry out this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0072C6322B14777AA3B475C705AE5DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>before a repayment, the employee is afforded notice and an opportunity for a hearing conducted by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H415169FB9271472FA0D0A4844A7AF059"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The decision of the Secretary regarding a repayment by an employee pursuant to subsection (a) is final and may not be reviewed by any other agency or any court.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7160A7AC67A0407391654257FCB2EC40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is further amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FB30AE7D82541FE9AFC9F1928AB4BEA" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">715. Recoupment of bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEA40276D3A73445C91B734F2871583BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 715 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to an award or bonus paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDF79921B0AAB4CC08DBFDC1BCB58BDC9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act may be construed to modify the certification issued by the Office of Personnel Management and the Office of Management and Budget regarding the performance appraisal system of the Senior Executive Service of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


