<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H22871E54D2314D17ACE45761CDE263DD" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3102 RH: Airport Access Control Security Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 215</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3102</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 114–283]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150716">July 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HHM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151006">October 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>October 6, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 16, 2015</action-instruction></action><action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reform programs of the Transportation Security
			 Administration, streamline transportation security regulations, and for
			 other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9E40257828B1489A94B86801CB3183D4" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H178A33D5E6534B0D9088C857EAC37A8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Airport Access Control Security Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H270C7BA7D14C4D22BA8F69CE6AB346C4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Aviation security</header> <subsection id="H73EEA8CCC3BB476E9EEE0CABCB9D2EE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle A of title XVI of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F6712AA840E44D9948D89D26D3B9AAE" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<section id="H52B0B31ED80343FCBF5E556377181D3D"><enum>1602.</enum><header>Risk-based screening of employees at airports</header>
						<subsection id="HF657D2C5C6CB496EA03652C76605DEA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Screening model</header>
 <paragraph id="H364BBDFBCF8C44C49BEBC487C7067655"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish a risk-based, intelligence-driven model for the screening of employees at airports based on level of access and employment positions at domestic airports. Such screening model shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H89CBF34679354B239ACAD8064448715C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that only those individuals authorized to have access to the secure areas of a domestic airport are permitted such access;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD501730974E34FD2885589663E5CC541"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that an individual is immediately denied entry to a secure area when such individual’s access authorization for such secure area is withdrawn; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H870201DAEA74421FA0C98230204A1068"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide a means to differentiate between individuals authorized to have access to an entire secure area and individuals authorized access to only a particular portion of a secure area.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DFD2DFD88374F5ABBC352EA4D20F398"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>The Administrator shall consider the following factors when establishing the screening model described in paragraph (1):</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7DAEB077BE634DA989A8CFCFDCA778CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whether and how often employees at airports require employment-related access to Secure Identification Display Areas, Airport Operations Areas, or secure areas.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBA95390DB94342B0A92C872FA323F410"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The ability of each airport operator to reduce employee entry and exit points to a mutually agreed upon minimum number of such entry and exit points necessary to maintain airport operations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC0F7044425BE44A7BAC3E2B453F931E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In consultation with airport operators, the ability of the Administration to create a randomization plan for screening at the defined operational minimum entry and exit points at airports which maximizes the deterrent effect of screening efforts.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBED0A555B254BEE83A4143A25DDCE91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disqualifying offenses</header>
 <paragraph id="H4D8F9683914940CDBCEB9CB6C8D92C2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, labor organizations representing aviation, ground, and cabin crew workers, and the Aviation Security Advisory Committee, shall conduct an aviation security risk-based review of the disqualifying criminal offenses codified in sections 1542.209 and 1544.229 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to determine the appropriateness of such offenses as a basis for denying to an employee a credential that allows unescorted access to Secure Identification Display Areas of airports. Such review shall consider the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF2D9B1D726364D9FAED451E4F7E7B01C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The adequacy of codified disqualifying offenses to address the current aviation security threat environment, particularly the terrorism insider threat.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0296B746FB61473180621E00695B7E22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If such codified disqualifying offenses should be tailored to address the current aviation security threat environment, particularly the terrorism insider threat, by excluding or including other offenses.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6173305399EF43BA8EE0A7D5BD3B7655"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The potential security benefits, drawbacks, and challenges associated with identifying patterns of misdemeanors or of other non-disqualifying offenses that could jeopardize aviation security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59F009A6AA344ACFB640F1DEB7053DDE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The feasibility of integrating similar departmental eligibility requirements for access to Secure Identification Display Areas of airports.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD032D50E03D64B7582E3258E3D0D2168"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the ten year look-back period for disqualifying offenses is appropriate, in light of the current aviation security threat environment, particularly the terrorism insider threat.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A43126D5EBC4CE8ACF6602242C2F955"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall provide an adequate redress process for an employee who is subject to an adverse employment decision, including removal or suspension of such employee, due to a disqualifying offense referred to in paragraph (1), that is consistent with the appeals and waiver process established for applicants for commercial motor vehicle hazardous materials endorsements and transportation workers at ports under section 70105(c) of title 46, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4E8138E48C44D6B85A749BC7B8E33B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any changes to the Secure Identification Display area badge program, such as changes considered pursuant to subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (E) of paragraph (1) shall be subject to notice of proposed rulemaking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8ECE70A85A58471699EF545B73D9C363"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Briefing to Congress</header><text>Upon completion of the aviation security risk-based review required under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the results of such review.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCD72298852964E28B76DF0D3F8E4F24F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credentialing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator, in consultation with the Aviation Security Advisory Committee, shall review the auditing procedures for all airport-issued identification media. Such review shall determine the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC818F5B071244775A283FA92FFC19737"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The efficacy of the auditing program requirements at domestic airports to ensure the integrity, accountability, and control of airport-issued identification media.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82991F5E63744F07ACD5DC13F8A68FC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The feasibility of including biometrics standards for all airport-issued identification media used for identity verification and badge verification.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C534EDB201A41498905122C7757CE43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The feasibility of integrating other departmental programs’ eligibility requirements for access to secure areas of airports.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1E7B581CEA9422A802848722BB8A111"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Vetting</header>
 <paragraph id="HE86EEEDB05574B6FBA5C26F3FBA440E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE85AEA2EFCE348A9A121F4D7DEC5DC31"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a program to allow airport badging offices to utilize the employment eligibility confirmation system established under section 404 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note; commonly referred to as <quote>E-Verify</quote>) to determine the eligibility to work in the United States of all applicants seeking access to secure areas of airports;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H52C1718CB379407EA7076F091DC5BCD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a process to transmit applicants’ biometric fingerprint data to the Office of Biometric Identity Management’s (OBIM’s) Automated Biometrics Identification System (IDENT) for vetting; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE8C2DEED5034CB4B7BDC121F139C787"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct a data quality assessment to ensure that credential application data elements received by the Administration are complete and match the data submitted by the airport operators.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9026479E4DC746CBABC23585A8B3FC3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing to Congress</header><text>Upon completion of the responsibilities specified in paragraph (1), the Administrator shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the results of such completion.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H286B1FBE76CF4B3CAFC502C20FE918E6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting of violations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish a nationwide program for the anonymous reporting of violations of airport security.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H68F96CCD53654C04A14B722100CFF8E1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Centralized database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator, in consultation with the Aviation Security Advisory Committee, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0F09A24FF27E4392A658763FC67BE7FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a national database of employees who have had either their airport or aircraft operator-issued badge revoked for failure to comply with aviation security requirements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83382E6636FD4C4693CAEBEF8A03AAC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the appropriate reporting mechanisms for airports and airlines to submit data regarding employees described in paragraph (1) and to access the database established pursuant to such paragraph; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H716DA1A88AD644F3A38A3FF387488F43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish a process that allows individuals whose names were mistakenly entered into such database to have their names removed and have their credentialing restored.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H24CED44A92C742AB94F90C3F51B17FCE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Updated review</header><text>Not later than April 8, 2016, the Administrator, in consultation with the Aviation Security Advisory Committee, shall conduct an updated and thorough review of airport access controls.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H1136C799860647A18F947EFB59F4D470"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Employee screening study</header>
 <paragraph id="H3F64172D196D4DBA8C6683E3927EDB8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator, in consultation with the Aviation Security Advisory Committee, shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Comptroller General of the United States a cost and feasibility study of a statistically significant number of Category I, II, and X airports, that ensures that all employee entry and exit points that lead to secure areas of such airports are comprised of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H994F4FD931284DF7A2DF62455BBDDC14"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A secure door utilizing card and pin entry or biometric technology.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4FF921AE6574782883E87D83DD02032"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Surveillance video recording, capable of storing video data for at least 30 days.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H122E4CB587474CEB82749D310B88DC93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Advanced screening technologies, including at least one of the following:</text> <clause id="H3D5F304256BC4F499E7D23F17DAA786F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Magnetometer (walk-through or hand-held).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H68F0CF6D4B6E403F9F1780E4BE52C5AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Explosives detection canines.</text> </clause><clause id="H8B51F22782264F7E8622D2A2FE3EF2BF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Explosives trace detection swabbing.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB80FFC4E195E41028A7252171C22BD76"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Advanced imaging technology.</text> </clause><clause id="HCDBD17CC78F048BF83FA725DC468EC5B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>X-ray bag screening technology.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB42514633A15472BB8347BE992172014"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study required under paragraph (1) shall include information related to the employee screening costs of those airports which have already implemented practices of screening one-hundred percent of employees entering secure areas of airports, including the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5EAF84F1F3754079BCD49CDE7B2F9101"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs associated with establishing an operational minimum number of employee entry and exit points.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A992DD029594E18BB02FC49B5B15E1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of costs associated with implementing the requirements specified in paragraph (1), based on whether such implementation was carried out by the Administration or airports.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58E57E416CA64B35B01FA9A6A84A8AB0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Comptroller General assessment</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2E3AB1686D2440C6AE7F715BF5E7717F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of the study required under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall review such study to assess the quality and reliability of such study.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BE36B778B4B4567ADD28D4CDF228047"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the receipt of the study required under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the results of the review required under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBF8B0918391D48BC8692247F884F2845"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1601 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22F33B971526444F952BED6BB52A85CE" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<toc changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1602. Risk-based screening of employees at airports.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date date="20151006">October 6, 2015</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


