<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H85155061E79B435987118B38C446A2A2" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1144 IH: To amend title 18, United States Code, to prevent discriminatory misconduct against taxpayers by Federal officers and employees, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1144</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150226">February 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to prevent discriminatory misconduct against taxpayers by
			 Federal officers and employees, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H93EFFA3F6E3F4270BCA5EE36C98AC646" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1896CA5565E244DC84F40A45501CA6AE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taxpayer Nondiscrimination &amp; Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE3BCC0CD86F548C4A7689C893F67EDDB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Misconduct against taxpayers by Internal Revenue Service employees</header> <subsection id="H55429109C2074140A5CC95B022311866"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criminal liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">Chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77DED3518CCC4E1F80D5028096C995BC" style="USC">
 <section id="H099926A0A74C4D34BB744A7CE288BCD0"><enum>250.</enum><header>Misconduct against taxpayers by Internal Revenue Service employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Whoever being an employee of the Internal Revenue Service, engages, during the performance of that employee’s official duties, in an act or omission described in section 1203(b) of the Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998 shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H554D3B65902E48D6AD6C1302D2376A8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of acts and omission constituting misconduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1203 of the Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998 and section 250 of title 18, United States Code (as added by this section) the protections and guarantees afforded under the First Amendment of the Constitution of the United States to political speech and political expression shall not fail to be treated as rights under the Constitution of the United States referred to in section 1203(b) of the Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCBF50AD505E741A584C1FC320F71B851"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 249 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9351B0FA26094426AF5C86B094FEB7C0" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">250. Discriminatory misconduct against taxpayers by Federal officers and employees.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


