<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD8637021FD3D4805BE2D88B3334AD231" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3992 IH: Students Before Profits Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3992</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve the determination of cohort default rates and
			 provide for enhanced civil penalties, to ensure personal liability of
			 owners, officers, and executives of institutions of higher education, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H98ED54BFB2804C89B38891B68E359745" style="OLC">
 <section id="H23B17ED4BCF64BF3BAFA412F3366948D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Students Before Profits Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2778E4DD71E546839EE78DBA03DFCD6B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improved determination of cohort default rates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 435 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE57B06E44C4D4664B901A0FE12974F56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF91B5009E14D4104ADFF99C1242335AC" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H7A9AA22B344E49A88A641D0752D18947" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBA791DE87EF6494BBC60098237C4D28F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In any case where the Secretary has determined that the institution has engaged in default manipulation, the Secretary—</text>
 <subclause id="HA06B6ED429DF40B3B2DE304823A521AC" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall recalculate the cohort default rate for the institution under this section using corrected data and information, for all fiscal years for which the default manipulation has occurred; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBFDE72E5E9B04B3D87E08C11A4F98D75" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>using the recalculated cohort default rate, shall redetermine whether the institution is ineligible to participate in a program under this title.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA2181ECEBBDB4CF08AC984B68517FB16" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In this section, the term <term>default manipulation</term> means engaging in a device or practice, such as branching, consolidation of campuses, consolidation or manipulation of the identification codes used by the Office of Postsecondary Education to designate campuses and institutions, change of ownership or control, serial forbearance, or any similar device or practice (as determined by the Secretary) when, but for the device or practice, one or more campuses of an institution of higher education would be at risk of cohort default rate sanctions under this section or student default risk sanctions under section 489A.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H830B019E0BE64BFCB170EBC4AB282366"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (m)(3), by striking <quote>through the use of</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>through default manipulation.</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA28F140623C747508A05C96AE7918022"><enum>3.</enum><header>Civil penalties</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE8883F595E049C48A7764129B5129C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part G of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 489 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EC697AB2193462B983A78487C9C3481" style="OLC">
					<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E1DB50143104F0C8DE578152D41E40A"><enum>489A.</enum><header>Civil penalties and other remedies</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FA63801A23A4809A6971DE29FB7412E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4837331BF9D84D2D9840D1C138C02934"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Officer of an institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>officer of an institution of higher education</term> includes the president, chief executive officer, and chief financial officer of an institution of higher education or their equivalents.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1487E7D4F0F848BCA708E69FFFBDFDB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student default risk</header><text>The term <term>student default risk</term> means a risk that is reflected as a percentage that is calculated by taking an institution's 3-year cohort default rate, as defined in section 435(m), for the most recent fiscal year available, and multiplying it by the percentage of students enrolled at such institution receiving a Federal student loan authorized under this title during the previous academic year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD53DDC4999064E69B537C45B1C4CF0C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Substantial misrepresentation or other serious violation</header><text>The term <quote>substantial misrepresentation or other serious violation</quote> means either of the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EEB7072512843509362FA5333B69413"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A substantial misrepresentation regarding—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D9BCEECF83F408E88FB7DA697E57AF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the nature of the educational program of an institution of higher education;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC006118713984470875FFCDF007F180F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the financial charges of the institution;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H201E83E6BFCD4C3DB3BF6943C5C92D47"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the space availability in a program of the institution for which a student is considering enrollment;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB38D19954B094DA4A6379EB98DDA35FF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the admission requirements of the institution;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5562B049F96C4C15A7D90EDA24E04A33"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the transferability of credits from the institution;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7BBC908662B4B70A33B1B37C2EDDACF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>whether a program of the institution meets the necessary standards to qualify students to sit for licensing examinations, or obtain certification required as a precondition for employment, in the State in which the students reside;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H963A5A25524140109B2CF102BD05983A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the passage rates of students at the institution in obtaining certification requirements;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H293FBA98B9CA4AEFA77E5794BFF6665A"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the passage rates of students who sit for licensing examinations; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99AA769AF47E4C4CB2D112567F85A5D1"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the employability of the graduates of the institution.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51C901F746374DCBAF7107578355C410"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A violation as follows that is determined to constitute an unfair, deceptive, or abusive act or practice:</text>
 <clause id="HC697340A231E4C979AF56A8F2447A1D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A violation of section 487(a)(20).</text> </clause><clause id="HD93F22139CAD42069ED813ED5F805424"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A violation of the default manipulation regulations promulgated by the Secretary under section 435(m)(3).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4F524FBD25054E94BE7096AE7FB01C11"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Failure to comply with the program review process described in section 498A.</text> </clause><clause id="H663EBC5C9C2443B892EBB119605FCF85"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A violation of the program integrity regulations promulgated by the Secretary under this Act.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DC32E0C1007462CB99B6DD55F453F5E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A violation of this Act that the Secretary has determined, by regulation, to be a serious violation for purposes of this section.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FE6E7C3F13F465394A3287331BFF339"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions for substantial misrepresentations or serious violations</header>
							<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90CF9D223C4040ECAB6D232E69E08326"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A9152018BB04BBC9E51B6C78AF71CDD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may impose a civil penalty upon an eligible institution upon making a determination, after reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing, that an eligible institution has engaged in a substantial misrepresentation or other serious violation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F98F71DA3BE46AEA35B0C56110369FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount of civil penalties</header><text>A civil penalty imposed for a violation under subparagraph (A) shall be not less than $100,000 or—</text> <clause id="H220C4D137EAD45B3A12E443D386EBB1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a first violation, an amount equal to the product of $1,000,000 multiplied by the institution’s student default risk, whichever is larger;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA9366174135145598BE25F252F578085"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a second violation, an amount equal to the product of $2,000,000 multiplied by the institution’s student default risk, whichever is larger; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD8F88E4B48DE49FE941F71D6D7EA49BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a third or subsequent violation, an amount equal to the product of $3,000,000 multiplied by the institution’s student default risk, whichever is larger.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H85F393EAA8894573A7751507E9401AC5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of multiple institutions</header><text>For the purpose of determining the number of violations under subparagraph (B), any violation by a particular institution will accrue against all identification codes used by the Office of Postsecondary Education to designate campuses and institutions affiliated with the institution, and within the period of participation for the institution, as defined in section 668.13(b) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47376D718A4C4DB780203D46063476C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions for other violations of this title</header><text>Upon determination, after reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing, that an eligible institution has engaged in a violation of any other provision of this title, including the failure to carry out any provision of this title, that is not a significant misrepresentation or other serious violation, the Secretary may impose a civil penalty upon such institution of not more than $100,000 (subject to such adjustments for inflation as may be prescribed in regulation) for each such violation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H97F86AFE5F754818BF3BEBFDB1731C66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil penalties and sanctions for officers of institutions</header><text>Upon determination, after reasonable notice and an opportunity for a hearing, that an officer of an institution of higher education that participates in a program under this title has knowingly and willfully, or with gross negligence, violated a provision of this title, the Secretary may sanction the officer. Such sanctions may include the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB823765AB556454CB332018E0B8245A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Prohibiting the institution of higher education that has employed the officer of an institution of higher education and that participates in a program under this title, or any other institution of higher education that participates in a program under this title, from employing the officer, except that any such prohibition under this subsection shall not be for a period of more than 5 years from the date of the determination of the violation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H454B4A0CAC0A4D1E898E45E7751DEAB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assessing a civil penalty against an officer of an institution of higher education who has knowingly and willfully, or with gross negligence, violated a provision of this title, except that any such civil penalty under this subsection shall not be greater than the amount of the officer’s compensation for each year for which the violations are determined to have occurred. For purposes of this paragraph, an officer's compensation shall include proceeds of any sales of stock and any incentive-based compensation (including stock options awarded as compensation) based on information required to be reported to the Secretary or any other Federal agency during the period in which the violations are determined to have occurred.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDD4C083F6D6A45E5A574D9526803EA33"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation, suspension, or termination of eligibility status</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HBB1E422F74964CF0821844A0583ECA81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon determination, after reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing, that an eligible institution has engaged in a violation of any provision of this title (including the failure to carry out any provision of this title or any regulation prescribed under such provision) or a violation of any applicable special arrangement, agreement, or limitation, the Secretary may limit, suspend, or terminate the participation in any program under this title of an eligible institution, subject to the requirements of paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73C0B5AD7EAC4795979AF486B9D3CD71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Suspension procedures</header><text>No period of suspension under this section shall exceed 60 days unless the institution and the Secretary agree to an extension or unless limitation or termination proceedings are initiated by the Secretary within that period of time.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDCB5B97D2E44723A2717DE245D49B99"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Emergency action</header>
 <paragraph id="HDE913FFF3A224D799DB0ECE6303D896C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take an emergency action against an institution, under which the Secretary shall, effective on the date on which a notice and statement of the basis of the action is mailed to the institution (by registered mail, return receipt requested), withhold funds from the institution or its students and withdraw the institution's authority to obligate funds under any program under this title, if the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9645F7B3BCE9446BBBA66EE62CE45C9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receives information, determined by the Secretary to be reliable, that the institution is violating any provision of this title, any regulation prescribed under this title, or any applicable special arrangement, agreement, or limitation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCD90E5E52E14402866CAEEBA04EED4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determines that immediate action is necessary to prevent misuse of Federal funds; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47FAEC3647FB4A4D9C55256260ED9F3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determines that the likelihood of loss outweighs the importance of the procedures prescribed in subsection (e) for limitation, suspension, or termination.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7EE2B3E850464CBA983262C04F896D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time limitation</header><text>An emergency action described in paragraph (1) shall not exceed 30 days unless limitation, suspension, or termination proceedings are initiated by the Secretary against the institution within that period of time.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA936AE62F48642679486BB7FE1754DA4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Opportunity to show cause</header><text>The Secretary shall provide an institution that is the subject of an emergency action under this subsection an opportunity to show cause, if the institution so requests, that the emergency action is unwarranted and should be lifted.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D9D4D67AAFC4C6F8B3EEC82FFA967BD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Lifting of sanctions</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, an institution of higher education that has been sanctioned by the Secretary under this section or any other provision of this title may not have such sanctions lifted until the Secretary has conducted a subsequent program review under section 498A and has found the institution to be in compliance with this title.</text>
						</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2212FC4789742399D0B1DE87575214B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Single course of conduct; compromise authority</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1BD3C8571724975A6361B56662FAAE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Same course of conduct</header><text>For purposes of this section, acts and omissions relating to a single course of conduct shall be treated as a single violation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB820A146CFE8443DAB72A5A8DA1F3C97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compromise authority</header><text>Any civil penalty under this section may be compromised by the Secretary. In determining the amount of such penalty, or the amount agreed upon in compromise, the Secretary shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50EE277EEC1A4634AC4E29B0D24E5411"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appropriateness of the penalty to the size of the institution of higher education subject to the determination; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BB5D31A9EC94E4A80432A00782B2D7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the gravity of the violation, failure, or misrepresentation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H845A4B92DAB649DE879DE88A79F9A781"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Collection of penalty</header><text>The amount of any penalty under this section may be deducted from any sums owing by the United States to the institution charged.</text>
						</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC18F64199F1B4C4B842647F9C4008DDD"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Disposition of amounts recovered</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H4B63A9E3119042D4B6B51C1851DE950F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use for student relief fund</header><text>For each fiscal year, an amount equal to 100 percent of the amounts recovered or collected under this section shall be deposited into the Student Relief Fund established under subsection (k).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D062382B5CB4A48BD7B0F8C163FCF88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall regularly publish, on the website of the Department, a detailed description that includes the amount of funds that were used for the Student Relief Fund under paragraph (1).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C8140D07EEB4D55B87C3F9A51B6CB3A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Student relief fund</header>
 <paragraph id="H99ACBA3C5E2641EC9A1FB0030CCBEA96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a Student Relief Fund (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Fund</quote>) that shall be used, subject to the availability of funds, to provide financial relief to any student enrolled in an institution of higher education that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H867AC5D7AEB144149A2098805BCB8A65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has failed to comply with an eligibility requirement under section 101 or 102 or an obligation incurred under the terms of the program participation agreement under section 487; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H518AADBDF75142289E21510C2234C13A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been sanctioned under subsection (b) or (c).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2719BC1D7D394D99A22E3AEADFA5DBEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment and availability of funds</header> <subparagraph id="HE6DA1BE78DE54BD7B5137E9C90094CED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Funds that are not government funds</header><text>Funds obtained by or transferred to the Fund shall not be construed to be Government funds or appropriated monies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E0389296DDE4790B55F850BB1967E4E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amounts not subject to apportionment</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts in the Fund shall not be subject to apportionment for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/15">chapter 15</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, or under any other authority.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H923286FDE371450198A56F047E357C04"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No fiscal year limitation</header><text>Sums deposited in the Fund shall remain in the Fund and be available for expenditure under this subsection without fiscal year limitation.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF980ADD854F2446C8772DE0FE22221C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H856D93ED460B4193882A95D2B5BAB959"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amounts in fund may be invested</header><text>The Secretary of Education may request the Secretary of the Treasury to invest the portion of the Fund that is not, in the discretion of the Secretary of Education, required to meet the current needs of the Fund.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06C7405A35AD484CA727443C5DC13839"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible investments</header><text>Investments shall be made by the Secretary of the Treasury in obligations of the United States or obligations that are guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States, with maturities suitable to the needs of the Fund as determined by the Secretary on the record.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B63A73127A147938DCFDAB6520438E5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interest and proceeds credited</header><text>The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to the Fund.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9C97991F3584C77B70B0A630E571CD4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to implement the requirements of this section within 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Students Before Profits Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0654C264D7FC4B468EAF38C899C5157E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to funds derived from financial penalties assessed pursuant to subsection (j), there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection for fiscal year 2015 and each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF4D9443C5D5445AB7CD913ABC4A3B38"><enum>(l)</enum><header>State enforcement</header>
 <paragraph id="H8E7562AC920A46C1BA35C288F8BF5BBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any violation of subsection (b), including the regulations promulgated under such subsection, shall be a cause of action enforceable by the State, through the attorney general (or the equivalent thereof) of the State, in any district court of the United States in that State or in a State court that is located in that State and that has jurisdiction over the defendant. The State may seek any relief provided under paragraph (4)(B) for such violation, or any remedies otherwise provided under law.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H340B0A0E5C6F4C1CAEB3605DD7489AE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice required</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDB754316585749559DC5EA4BBF12EB45"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before initiating any action in a court or other administrative or regulatory proceeding against any institution of higher education as authorized by paragraph (1) to enforce any provision of this subsection, including any regulation promulgated by the Secretary under this subsection, a State attorney general shall timely provide a copy of the complete complaint to be filed and written notice describing such action or proceeding to the Secretary, except as provided in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H320A310A1B9E43E8A8F918D265D1D0D1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Emergency action</header><text>If prior notice is not practicable, the State attorney general shall provide a copy of the complete complaint and the notice to the Secretary immediately upon instituting the action or proceeding.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCFB7FCD8152C4658A834295192098711"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The notification required under this paragraph shall, at a minimum, describe—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H3969BE4B97E4405BA4EF8B680D2E2BAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the identity of the parties;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HC425ED52779C4E54A1953EA4691DF980"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alleged facts underlying the proceeding; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HFF07C2A44F2844C9A98CE583B6D93E09"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether there may be a need to coordinate the prosecution of the proceeding so as not to interfere with any action, including any rulemaking, undertaken by the Secretary or another Federal agency.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C0E04FD9C3844A2BE54F49F90BA1A9D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to implement the requirements of this subsection and periodically provide guidance in order to further coordinate actions with the State attorneys general.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H21B128FA555E482B9B0D980B24208AE7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preservation of state authority</header>
 <subparagraph id="H971DADD69283449A87C8A10149F1CFFF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State claims</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as altering, limiting, or affecting the authority of a State attorney general or any other regulatory or enforcement agency or authority to bring an action or other regulatory proceeding arising solely under the law in effect in that State.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1437ADECE8B4434F8DCDEC63C0982ECE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header>
 <clause id="HB9EA59E46276428DA7CEBA1DA30C91AE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Relief under this subsection may include, without limitation—</text> <subclause id="H648477D18C3746308DC68A035256B524"><enum>(I)</enum><text>rescission or reformation of contracts;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB70904DFD6794EAF93CD428E7445745F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>refund of moneys or return of real property;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H92B7548BC5504DAB98310CB42E155C16"><enum>(III)</enum><text>restitution;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEE3A55E964BE44A6977BD204033BF302"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>disgorgement or compensation for unjust enrichment;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H6EE6907823A74EA29005A6590C15CAC5"><enum>(V)</enum><text>payment of damages or other monetary relief;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2DBD19892680472FB293E4D2ECB99137"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>public notification regarding the violation, including the costs of notification; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC46AD18B32864667A232EE8E6AFE42B6"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>limits on the activities or functions of the person.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HB7EC8B563E9741DB89E29E1157AC8072"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Relief under this subsection shall not include the ability to suspend or terminate the eligibility status of an institution of higher education for programs under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC798D2543A834506A044452BF5F64CDF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program review and data</header><text>Section 498A(b)(8) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099c-1">20 U.S.C. 1099c–1(b)(8)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and to the applicable State attorney general if the institution is found to have not complied with the program review process under this section</quote> after <quote>under review</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H224F6B91B14E4949B6CC291564615ED5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Personal liability for officers of institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 498(e) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099c">20 U.S.C. 1099c(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3AEDE0BAD84140ADA3A3EBCE41BEB87A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (7), the Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B2725F80E104DA89EBE96EB3BE945CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F6C380EE4AE4580ADB1904C519D32F9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HABD3E1A0885844AAB04E2A56AF514E6B" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (4), if the Secretary has taken an enforcement action against a proprietary institution of higher education (as defined in section 102(b)), (which may include heightened oversight activities such as heightened cash monitoring, provisional certification, or requirements to obtain approval for new educational programs and locations), the Secretary may hold an executive officer of the institution personally liable for financial losses related to such action to the Federal Government, student assistance recipients, and other program participants for funds under this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C3347D225A94FBC8962DD52571C4F62"><enum>5.</enum><header>Government claims for discharge</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE48D672B3B874EEB9F914311776E9CC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>FFEL and Direct loan programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 437(c)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087">20 U.S.C. 1087(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended in the first sentence by striking <quote>against the institution and its affiliates and principals</quote> and inserting <quote>against the institution, its affiliates and principals, and any executive officer or board member of the institution</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H588F5D5385E149EA8F6105B357E95DD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Perkins loans</header><text>Section 464(g)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087dd">20 U.S.C. 1087dd(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>against the institution and the institution's affiliates and principals</quote> and inserting <quote>against the institution, the institution's affiliates and principals, and any executive officer or board member of the institution</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H680982FA18AB4DC1AB1780EDBC875859"><enum>6.</enum><header>Program participation agreement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6836662295E54DDE8022F53BAA84F586" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFFB6B8D0DCD451F9E146B3A64D96555"><enum>(30)</enum><text>In the case of a proprietary institution of higher education (as defined in section 102(b)), such institution will prohibit any individual who has been found guilty of defrauding students from being a member of the board of directors, the chief executive officer, or other executive officer of the institution.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


