<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7D9E97FFD48D4EAA9AE0D7E73AA827D6" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3746 IH: State Marihuana And Regulatory Tolerance Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3746</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151009">October 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To make the Controlled Substances Act inapplicable with respect to marihuana in States that have
			 legalized marijuana and have in effect a statewide regulatory regime to
			 protect certain Federal interests, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFE93D78D7EE8491684B08392732398D2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H59B9FFB2578C44EFA2DBE563E8742BAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Marihuana And Regulatory Tolerance Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD00D1D5F4FE4407EB6DF89BAB9073920"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inapplicability of Controlled Substances Act to marihuana in certain States</header> <subsection id="H2106473BD38C4A7AA2817EC777C3088D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part E of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/871">21 U.S.C. 871 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H1CD9457380F840B58B3572D17054F414" style="OLC">
					<section id="H9FD708C982414A60B994774D64A0685E"><enum>521.</enum><header>Inapplicability to marihuana in certain States</header>
 <subsection id="H8EA4AF3592DC4AD3A251BA73BC102779"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the period described in subsection (c), this title shall not apply with respect to the production, manufacture, distribution, prescribing, dispensing, possession, and use of marihuana in a State if each of the following conditions is met:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8DB0701BDD0449FA9B96685D07CA4BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The State submits a request to the Attorney General certifying that the State has legalized marihuana for recreational or medical use.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3AFDA892B0045109824A0365B7561D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The request demonstrates, as determined by the Attorney General, that the State has, or will have, in effect a statewide regulatory regime for marihuana that is sufficient to protect Federal interests, including each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF47C72F2DE184252B1609B05CF9EA4DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Preventing the distribution of marihuana to minors.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45A878BBC80F48688687D1DD90ED953F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Preventing revenue from the sale of marihuana from going to criminal enterprises, gangs, and cartels.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1B3FC2E8C774F9B8E174E4A0066B877"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Preventing the diversion of marihuana from States where the manufacture, distribution, dispensing, and possession of marihuana is legal to other States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D47DF9C29EF45E08E64257C931AD7E2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Preventing State-authorized marihuana activity from being used as a cover or pretext for the trafficking of other illegal drugs or other illegal activity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8CE90BAD15E47C0B947D166788E46C6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Preventing violence and the use of firearms in the cultivation and distribution of marihuana.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00B02CF7176A4E0DBDB362687F1570BF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Preventing drugged driving and the exacerbation of other adverse public health consequences associated with marihuana use.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD6E396723294AC38805F05D36D0FF98"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Preventing the growing of marihuana on public lands and the attendant public safety and environmental dangers posed by marihuana production on public lands.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46459E0075A2430981371AD71FEDB924"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Preventing marihuana possession or use on Federal property.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H028BA14441B84E4E8C932F309F5D3E36"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Preventing distribution of tainted marihuana.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D218B56A7024C34AC2E6948205433B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The State agrees to study and report annually to the Attorney General regarding outcomes of legalizing marihuana in the State on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7ACA14ECA4D34AB499E52719E9798A00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Youth marihuana use.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBE1EB5CA47045DBBA4DCA0DE749D3ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Rates of driving while intoxicated.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56AE7F64C991445BA3E77A4B874F3D5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Diversion to other States.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43C5A466D51B4D22886CDEB279D9C91C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Prevalence of drug-related organized crime activity.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E0639AD1F624684A50F41D808B45386"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Finding by Attorney General</header>
 <paragraph id="HEA82C192387D4228A8F3B4D969CCF458"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after receipt of a request under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HAB799721777545568502AC236F11D8FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a finding on whether the conditions listed in subsection (a) are met; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F66F3FB54EB48B3A6535BB160F54ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Attorney General finds that such conditions are not met, include an explanation of the reasons why such conditions are not met.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5F16A7B5FED487BB4B3CB7C7A4537BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure To issue a finding</header><text>If the Attorney General fails to issue such a finding by the deadline specified in paragraph (1), the Attorney General is deemed to have found that the conditions listed in subsection (a) for the State involved are met, subject to the Attorney General’s authority to revoke such a finding under subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H422F128FA96D4FCB8A38C2027D236D9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration of period</header><text>The period described in this subsection is, with respect to a State, the period of 3 years beginning on the effective date of the Attorney General’s finding that the conditions listed in subsection (a) are met. A State may submit requests under subsection (a)(1) for subsequent, consecutive 3-year periods.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAC22BAAA37684F74A7C7F9E298E2C83F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effective date of a finding under subsection (b)(1) that the conditions listed in subsection (a) are met with respect to a State shall be not sooner than the effective date of the State’s regulatory regime required by subsection (a)(2).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HA448A001AB4D4E7CAE845FBDC0B064FF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Loss of waiver</header>
 <paragraph id="H8F4E4473CF4741999529292D2E995865"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may—</text> <subparagraph id="H81654FD0197D4BAF9C086F2844B72E3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continually review the production, manufacture, distribution, prescribing, dispensing, possession, and use of marihuana in a State with respect to which the Attorney General finds the conditions listed in subsection (a) are met; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE332174972E4BA4A7D93887DCCA8414"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after providing notice and an opportunity to correct any failure to meet such conditions in accordance with paragraph (2), revoke such finding if the Attorney General finds that the conditions listed in subsection (a) are no longer met.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C8CBC5154FB4A409FB241B1013D1168"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice; opportunity To correct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Attorney General finds that the conditions listed in subsection (a) are no longer met, the Attorney General shall give the State involved—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9AEA5CAEBA2340E392CA430247EA9621"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of such finding; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2110052A59674906A03CE6240BA9634E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a period of not less than 180 days to correct any failure to meet the conditions listed in subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H376C8AF5D83045DCBB7213E42E96E07C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Federal Government from providing assistance to a State (under Federal law other than this title) in the implementation or enforcement of State law relating to the production, manufacture, distribution, prescribing, dispensing, possession, or use of marihuana.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0AAAD9FB3450436883C0B5F6E1FDEFA7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>tainted</term> means containing microbes, pesticides, or controlled substances other than marihuana.</text> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD3BE511251BE41E68F22CC2BE8402DA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents at the beginning of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/513">Public Law 91–513</external-xref>) is amended by inserting at the end of the items relating to part E of title II the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HA6D785879DEC46BEA8017E105E2E4736" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 521. Inapplicability to marihuana in certain States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


