<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDEAA7AA281C24F0D846891D48EC2A57C" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1886 IH: To amend section 1341 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to repeal the funding mechanism for the transitional reinsurance program in the individual market, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1886</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend section 1341 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to repeal the funding
			 mechanism for the transitional reinsurance program in the individual
			 market, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H5683F6FC48E947BD9595DA87A71144BF" style="OLC">
		<section id="H61564BE2FC68467DB383CEA9078F33E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header>
 <subsection id="H5274354F1E804A62962DD61FF75AC90D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H2E6B6084D0EA45AA897B7D86CB742A05"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the most recent United States Census, employer-based health insurance is the largest source of health insurance coverage in the United States. Of those employed, 70 percent receive employment-based health insurance. Of unemployed Americans, 30 percent receive employer-sponsored health insurance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2E05A876E4C4E69B5DC4D4CB5988841"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Despite the large percentages of coverage, as health care costs climb, the percentage of Americans who receive health insurance through employers has fallen significantly over the last decade—from 70 percent nationwide in 2000 to 60 percent in 2011, according to a report by the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD71B995CBC48A2930F3C903F610B5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to recent surveys done by the National Business Group on Health and the Kaiser Family Foundation, most companies continue to provide health insurance for employees and wish to continue doing so into the future.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A1C6A6532CE491998B5BC98B60149EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Employers who offer insurance will not contribute additional risk to the health insurance exchanges established in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (in this Act referred to as <term>PPACA</term>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC80C63555E584BC391E09A70262C0027"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The transitional reinsurance program, established in section 1341 of PPACA, is intended to stabilize risk in the individual health insurance market during the first three years of the health insurance exchanges, as established by that Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE727D8086784CF99D7A07B0905FA6E8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>PPACA also requires that the Treasury collect a fee for each employer-sponsored covered life in order to pay for the transitional reinsurance program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48CB856AD20248338AA4F9027AACDD30"><enum>(7)</enum><text>This fee is a disincentive for employers to continue offering coverage to all employees, and does not give employers any benefits of the transitional reinsurance program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9556D45406545AEB8577E941582220C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to remove the current funding mechanism for the transitional reinsurance program. Employer-sponsored insurance should be supported so that Americans can sustain quality health coverage.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3F671BA1CDEA44AD9BF00A72D2E2673A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Changes in funding for transitional reinsurance program in the individual market</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1341(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18061">42 U.S.C. 18061(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFEADD81B0A64477299DEDD655FBC76B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>3-year period</quote> and inserting <quote>1-year period</quote> each place it appears;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H715C7F3AB3B445C385AFD3FAAEA8656F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), by striking <quote>36-month period</quote> and inserting <quote>12-month period</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD478B1EDFE774FA08C97C820384E2F12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B)(iii), by striking <quote>, $6,000,000,000 for plan years beginning 2015, and $4,000,000,000 for plan years beginning in 2016</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE64329B93E64E8C840BF72261747A1E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B)(iv), by striking <quote>, an additional $2,000,000,000 for 2015, and an additional $1,000,000,000 for 2016</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29B8EBEF058D4090A60CC672CD1AB34E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4)(A), by striking <quote>used in any of the three calendar years for which amounts are collected based on the reinsurance needs of a particular period or to reflect experience in a prior period</quote> and inserting <quote>only used with respect to the calendar year for which amounts are collected based on the reinsurance needs for that year, as determined by the Secretary</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F51CD2AD0084C63B982055C06FEF208"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FFBCDC756DB4601A067CFC998218FEC" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H7ADCC08447A54C758DF1454995A3C377"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts remaining unexpended as of December, 31, 2015, shall be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury of the United States.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AD2890486404FB2A6839776FABCDDA0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9884808F16F44DA81DD7201A6D96199" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE98B0168A7D44D1EBBD8CD413CA809D9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Availability of funding for States for 2015 and 2016</header> <subparagraph id="H2F0720610B3640B59671C69FBFFA5E8B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations; payment formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated, based on the best estimates of the NAIC, $6,000,000,000 for plan years beginning in 2015 and $4,000,000,000 for plan years beginning in 2016 to make reinsurance payments to health insurance issuers that cover high-risk individuals in the individual market (excluding grandfathered health plans) that insure high-risk individuals consistent with this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB3A5521F411499D9E4336C37A6F60B7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fund availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts appropriated under subparagraph (A) for plans years beginning in a calendar year shall be allocated among States and only used with respect to the calendar year for which amounts are collected based on the reinsurance needs for that particular year, as determined by the Secretary and the amounts remaining unexpended as of December 31 of the following year shall be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17809EE939A34A299821AAA079916684"><enum>(6)</enum><header>GAO audit of use of 2014 funds</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall provide for an audit of expenditures made under this subsection with respect plans years beginning during 2014. Such audit shall include a determination of the number of claims submitted by health insurance issuers, the amount of such claims, a comparison of the amount of such claims and the amounts collected to cover such claims, and the amount of reinsurance payments made under this section to health insurance issuers. The Comptroller General shall submit a report on such audit to Congress not later than 3 months after the last date that such reinsurance payments are made, but not later than July 1, 2016.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


