<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H238A11FF937642D5BDF34ED4C9773EBA" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3617 IH: Improving All Government Efficiency Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3617</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150925">September 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve efficiency by consolidating some duplicative and overlapping Government programs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H15A27EC8D5E44F08BEB2F52C1698DFC1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1D7EDA7B3F7D4ADEB51BFAED75558503" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving All Government Efficiency Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IMAGE Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3F0B2151691D4DFA9254DFBAD04EFBF2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consolidating unnecessary duplicative and overlapping Government programs</header> <subsection id="H6320392174FF48BCB293BAA654342098"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall coordinate with the heads of the relevant departments or agencies to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H85B2760B2E0741A8B4F31CBA7F06B90E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use available administrative authority to eliminate, consolidate, or streamline Government programs and agencies with duplicative and overlapping missions identified in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE395AC67651A4E909928958E63E34E68"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the March 2015 Government Accountability Office report to Congress, titled <quote>Government Efficiency and Effectiveness: Opportunities to Reduce Fragmentation, Overlap, Duplication, and Improper Payments and Achieve Other Financial Benefits</quote> (GAO–15–440T);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H482E104D32A04A9891E3871FA14441AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the April 2014 Government Accountability Office report to Congress, titled <quote>Government Efficiency and Effectiveness: Opportunities to Reduce Fragmentation, Overlap, Duplication, and Improper Payments and Achieve Other Financial Benefits</quote> (GAO–14–478T); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCA572E09823456F9153D57E06A7BF41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the April 2013 Government Accountability Office report to Congress, titled <quote>Actions Needed to Reduce Fragmentation, Overlap, and Duplication and Achieve Other Financial Benefits</quote> (GAO–13–279SP);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H730B6F76202147CCBAC76CC904B418C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify and report to Congress any legislative changes required to further eliminate, consolidate, or streamline Government programs and agencies with duplicative and overlapping missions identified in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE1C187406A214176AA39014026E9E471"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the March 2015 Government Accountability Office report referred to in paragraph (1)(A);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36456187E61244C78D04DBA0BE627EDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the April 2014 Government Accountability Office report referred to in paragraph (1)(B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94880C1EF1234773A4B5616C0D8D4099"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the April 2013 Government Accountability Office report referred to in paragraph (1)(C);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B112790AF564F7194E3BFCFA9FB7D53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>estimate the total cost savings expected to result to each department or agency from the actions described in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2B25C3725D4F86BC78C1FE7D739039"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rescind from the amounts made available to such departments or agencies the total amount of cost savings estimated by paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE5478972855468EA0EB4B17F4DF0E38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of rescission</header><text>The rescission required under subsection (a)(4) shall only apply to amounts made available for Government programs that are eliminated, consolidated, or streamlined under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H703BF3C0B7D04A76B96FD61B66C5C5B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2015, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit a report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate listing the accounts reduced by the rescission in subsection (a)(4) and the amounts rescinded from each such account.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4E92F2305CE446E6874253F6D0B5C694"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rescission for noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a department or agency that does not meet the requirements of subsection (a) before September 30, 2015, there is rescinded from the funds made available to such department or agency in fiscal year 2015 an amount equal to 1 percent of such funds.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


