<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBD1CEDFE13BB4771BBD4F6C27D301F5F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 815 IH: Access to Professional Health Insurance Advisors Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 815</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150209">February 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000796">Mr. Westmoreland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to preserve consumer and employer access to
			 licensed independent insurance producers.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6FA4D5D79AFC43658B7BE56FD3E0FC09" style="OLC">
 <section id="H45F243C96EF24A7CB47810F7B0CA62CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Professional Health Insurance Advisors Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4CF4D3E9B7D84AFD99DD21A650DECFCD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H08869446EDD54AE7948854E0D0A6D43A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Licensed independent insurance producers (agents and brokers) provide a wide range of services for both individual consumers and the business community. Producers interface with insurers, acquire quotes, analyze plan options, and consult clients through the purchase of health insurance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEBD48ECDE03400387234AEF54145234"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Licensed independent insurance producers provide guidance regarding benefit and contribution arrangements to ensure compliance with applicable State and Federal laws and regulations; assist with establishing section 125 plan tax savings under the Internal Revenue Code, health reimbursement arrangements, flexible spending arrangements, and other programs to maximize tax advantages and ensure compliance with applicable Internal Revenue Service guidelines; create educational materials and provide on-site assistance to aid in employee benefit communication; assist in managing eligibility for new hires and terminated employees; provide advocacy for employees through the health insurance claim process; and advocate for employers with insurers in developing proposals, renewals, and for service issues throughout the year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38AEF9BA640649819C046A882AFC27A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In order to meet these responsibilities, licensed independent insurance producers are required to complete continuing education on an ongoing basis in order to maintain appropriate licenses. This requirement to maintain educational standards helps assure the insured public that producers remain current with the ever-evolving insurance market.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC78575258B034FD0BC00A96DDEEE9213"><enum>(4)</enum><text>It is essential that licensed independent insurance producers continue to perform these duties, and others, as the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act has made significant changes to the regulatory environment for health plans. To understand these changes, employers and consumers will need professional guidance even more in the future. This service is especially important for small businesses, as such producers often fill the role of a human resources department as well as professional consultant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C4917CDE5DC428AB3DF4C18E91BF565"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The National Association of Insurance Commissioners—whose core mission is to protect consumers in all aspects of the business of insurance—strongly advocates for the continuing role of licensed independent insurance producers in health insurance, and has expressed that the ability of insurance agents and brokers to continue assisting health insurance consumers at a time of rapid insurance market changes is more essential than ever.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA6EF280AFC542D8A5299D98ED4B9845"><enum>(6)</enum><text>It is critical that the indispensable role played by licensed independent insurance producers is recognized and protected.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HDF675664ABE44DB18A5A736DFDD825CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protecting the ability of licensed independent insurance producers to continue to serve the public</header>
 <subsection id="H0D050053922A4AB8920B9FC5CDA8FCAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2718 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg et seq.</external-xref>), as inserted by section 1001 and amended by section 10101(f) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H579E12A99FDB4940A252B2C888AAD76D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3), by inserting <quote>, remuneration paid for licensed independent insurance producers,</quote> after <quote>State taxes</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAE7790A7C994F3C842C941B011FD9A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9497A4FB73D9461AB701A888F7EA17A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>, remuneration paid for licensed independent insurance producers,</quote> after <quote>State taxes</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67C6F5BB15E54FBAA86290E2A18B0875"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>or small group market</quote> before <quote>in such State</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F977C13EEDB4FFDBF867250B790D1ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(B), by inserting <quote>, remuneration paid for licensed independent insurance producers,</quote> after <quote>State taxes</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA55AA73CEA2C421A80CF2D532FF8F64C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting <quote>or small group market</quote> after <quote>individual market</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C75252E525445DEBCCF7B93B506C009"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H1494C631A5CE47C18A5E841F6708A2A5" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H5ABAB41CB06B4578A8E9D3D7BF7EE1CB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Independent insurance producer remuneration definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7E9B1BB543BC4078A30A9C8113832883"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>independent insurance producer</term> means an insurance agent or broker, insurance consultant, benefit specialist, limited insurance representative, and any other person required to be licensed under the laws of the particular State to sell, solicit, negotiate, service, effect, procure, renew or bind policies of insurance coverage or offer advice, counsel, opinions, or services related to insurance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6640244264524363BEE96B680E871063"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>remuneration</term> means compensation earned from an insurance issuer for services rendered under contractual agreement which may include commissions or any other thing of value but which shall not include production bonuses.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8BA5FCD4DD34526A49EEDCB0FB0F86A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, shall amend any applicable regulations so as to take the amendments made by subsection (a) into account.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


