<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCC6C62A1C7A14D7C90F2894C1D8F1D9E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2441 IH: AVG Flying Tigers Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2441</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150519">May 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To award a Congressional gold medal, collectively, to the 1st American Volunteer Group of the
			 Chinese Air Force, also known as the AVG Flying Tigers, in recognition of
			 their service to the nation.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA647BD9CC9824CE79F5DB6D3E5FD6C51" style="OLC">
 <section id="H27D96569612F46419D6D6CC5C26D811C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AVG Flying Tigers Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H43D205A36CF24C5F8A1876CD7AB72E41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H05E600C1318E42F4B21581C6202784C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In April 1937, Claire L. Chennault, a retired Army Air Corps Captain was working as a military advisor to Chinese General Chiang Kai-shek during the Sino-Japanese War.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD88E964BEFEE482D82304BEAC76371D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After President Roosevelt approved of Chennault’s request for a special air unit, Chennault spent the winter of 1940–41 overseeing the purchase of P–40 fighters and the recruitment of pilots and ground crew that would constitute the 1st American Volunteer Group of the Chinese Air Force, also known as the AVG Flying Tigers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E0EE35823C6480EBD8FFF4DCACF6E4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Of these pilots, 60 came from the Navy and Marine Corps, and 40 from the Army, and they were discharged from the armed services to be trained and instructed for the mission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2142C4A8464645E9AFC677B7AC149B4A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By 1942, after being organized and in part directed out of the White House, the AVG Flying Tigers had effectively been brought into the U.S. Army chain of command.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0F2F6383A4E4DBFA7B3380CBA28335A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The AVG Flying Tigers successfully kept the port of Rangoon and the Burma Road open for a crucial stretch of time to allow Allied forces to reinforce the Pacific theater, which was dominated by the Imperial Japanese Army Air Force.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H230FB0C2E2F34DF1A5A4E9B2FFFD6739"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The AVG Flying Tigers’ kill ratio was far superior to that of Allied air groups in the Pacific theater.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H346DC15B59384F8D9EB323D51D89CA3E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The AVG Flying Tigers’ success is remarkable considering they were far outnumbered by Japanese fighters in almost all their engagements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A57D4896A2346888B46BA797EBD9674"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During their service, 33 AVG Flying Tigers pilots and three ground crew received the Order of the Cloud and Banner.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFC5CB4C21644948B4F36BB0318AA8F3"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many AVG Flying Tigers pilots received the Chinese Air Force Medal.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H896FA42E921348E3960A2E0FD35D3B73"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each AVG Flying Tigers ace and double ace was awarded the Five Star or Ten Star Wing Medal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8B4902C3CDE4BEDB1E6C9747E1F9211"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President Franklin D. Roosevelt stated that the AVG Flying Tigers’ <quote>outstanding gallantry and conspicuous daring … is a source of tremendous pride throughout the whole of America</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDECA61407810470887B795926B59AC71"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The AVG Flying Tigers were disbanded on July 4, 1942.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H782F98CA00A846F6964A6481F9F12658"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> <subsection id="H92022CE4BDF44F1599D98C8084ECE727"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of the Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design to the 1st American Volunteer Group of the Chinese Air Force, also known as the AVG Flying Tigers, collectively in recognition of their service to the nation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB9238C31AAC24B0EAE066115D1BFFE6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike the gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCC13BF5D6E4D41DA9D336939C2427B8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian institution</header>
 <paragraph id="H1923ADD9F86849FC8A3F55903F131596"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal in honor of the AVG Flying Tigers under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution, where it will be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H236DD0D363BF442C8975DE5F22420ABC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated with the AVG Flying Tigers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDAB0558472AE4E2389E6D670EBABFB18"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the medals, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text>
		</section><section id="H2F86AAD060564D7EA13FD87BA25AA3C1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header>
 <subsection id="H7CFE3D347D824540A6812C15A4018D55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDBA35501564945C1A933EAEBA62EAAFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of section 5134 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


