<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H069B7062E3A744FC910C5FF7CF003910" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4309 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reimburse each possession of the United States for the cost of the earned income tax credit.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 4309</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000596">Mr. Pierluisi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reimburse each possession of the United States for the cost of the earned income tax credit.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HBEFD07807CFB49B382D21DE1AD4CCC86" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H61C4788DB9BD489485F3273728769033" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Reimbursement of possessions for cost of earned income tax credit</header> 
<subsection id="H0CFDAEF0F1704DF5998D51443368A71C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32">Section 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H446C9487444E4F11AA4502E4BAC0AEB5" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H8B91C83847CD42CEAF5699449E53D97C"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Treatment of possessions</header> <paragraph id="H0E62DAA49D664C278EB082A34C57F4F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments to possessions</header> <subparagraph id="HC984FAE5227A4F2F888B45BFEE46F066"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mirror code possession</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall periodically (but not less frequently than annually) pay to each possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system amounts equal to the loss to that possession by reason of the application of this section (determined without regard to paragraph (2)) with respect to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015. Such amounts shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F8CF4E331A447BEADC5955CD7DCBBEE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other possessions</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall periodically (but no less frequently than annually) pay to each possession of the United States which does not have a mirror code tax system amounts estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the aggregate benefits that would have been provided to residents of such possession by reason of the application of this section for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015, if a mirror code tax system had been in effect in such possession. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to any possession of the United States unless such possession has a plan, which has been approved by the Secretary of the Treasury, under which such possession will promptly distribute such payments to the residents of such possession.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H551E578689E74D43A841634F56D6437F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against United States income taxes</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any taxable year to any person—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAC0513DD255740C8902BABB68AF1D377"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to whom a credit is allowed against taxes imposed by the possession by reason of this section (determined without regard to this paragraph) for such taxable year, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22C281E501BC46DABD55C36338C2047C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is eligible for a payment under a plan described in paragraph (1)(B) with respect to such taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEBBB697607C4F5A925C0032E9AACBF2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0F205890E203417E92712B6B1F6EBAE9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Possession of the United States</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>possession of the United States</quote> includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9DD2E50B042B4D648A671946BD2103E9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mirror code tax system</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>mirror code tax system</quote> means, with respect to any possession of the United States, the income tax system of such possession if the income tax liability of the residents of such possession under such system is determined by reference to the income tax laws of the United States as if such possession were the United States, and such system includes a tax credit substantially identical to the credit allowed under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6BD2D8EEA6046AAB426AE967CC3E299"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text>For purposes of section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, or any similar rule of law, any payment made under this subsection shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from the credit allowed under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD5C22663B0694A12A39BC726E5A3F9DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


