<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE273A33DCFC54B0C9723CC758C32FE75" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3521 IH: Gulf Red Snapper Data Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3521</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150916">September 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize grants for data collection for use in stock assessments of red snapper and other reef
			 fish species in the Gulf of Mexico, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD760A7089A75494F9AF12EFA2E58E949" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAC754C8CD285416E9878E1548130C4A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gulf Red Snapper Data Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC60A1105F606497497071C1BC794F7C4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Gulf of Mexico red snapper and other reef fish species data collection grants</header> <subsection id="H448B3B8139334D98965B12102EC4B57D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the National Marine Fisheries Service Southeast Regional Office, shall award competitive grants for fishery-dependent and fishery-independent data collection for use in stock assessments for red snapper and other reef fish species in the Gulf of Mexico.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2A51E82846FD4DDCA6354C3961632CFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Innovative approaches</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall seek to improve red snapper and other reef fish species stock assessments through innovative approaches to data collection that incorporates data from cooperative peer-reviewed research involving academia, fishermen, and other fisheries sources.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDB6531D6143E4D08BFB2CD68777B92ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>Grants under this section may be for one or more fiscal years.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H950F5613AAB34D35A1EDA29C000294E6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Communication with stakeholders</header> <subsection id="H1C071FED78CD41F5B9C107289B8950B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce shall seek to improve communications by the National Marine Fisheries Service with stakeholders regarding the Gulf of Mexico red snapper and other reef fish species stock assessment processes and outcomes of such processes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF88E7C12C61C462689F38E5DFAFBE6E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HCF5B7A7C2E6B4FE2B0F9622134A7E88C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, report to Congress on actions taken under this section and the results of such actions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32A241C377174C7FBFFBA5D8093B159C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update such report every 180 days thereafter.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCCF6C01EEBEC4DFC92073B0261BE7178"><enum>4.</enum><header>Process for using Gulf of Mexico red snapper and other reef fish species cooperative research data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6AA06C9BAB204AF3A61711A0161BE358"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, develop and report to the Congress on a process for using data collected through cooperative research activities for Gulf of Mexico red snapper and other reef fish species stock assessments; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BDA73046FC64DEA83F54E58A22C06E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update such report every 180 days thereafter.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H5AEDB31A256843DA88B129927D622407"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce $10,000,000 for grants, personnel, operations, and data collection under this Act to improve Gulf of Mexico red snapper and other reef fish species stock assessments.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


