<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCBBB4CF172FA4F31BDB93B96865D7C2B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 564 IH: Endangered Salmon and Fisheries Predation Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 564</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to reduce predation on endangered Columbia River
			 salmon and other nonlisted species, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H32AA808FB8B740D581D55684D7801580" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H753B95DC02E346A88908C29E2E330B44" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Endangered Salmon and Fisheries Predation Prevention Act</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="H7462C521B00C478EA9F426DA98B7C544"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA346E3EF49D54CE88CF3526BAD7A8F61"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are 13 groups of salmon and steelhead that are listed as threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 that migrate through the lower Columbia River.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H044FC8B9FE8A49AEA80AF93CFC8BB644"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The people of the Northwest United States are united in their desire to restore healthy salmon and steelhead runs, as they are integral to the region’s culture and economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AEE0D133A0A4EBC9AAED71327FA5038"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Columbia River treaty tribes retain important rights with respect to salmon and steelhead.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C62FD3CAAC7412F8AF2494D52C6527C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Federal, State, and tribal governments have spent billions of dollars to assist the recovery of Columbia River salmon and steelhead populations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD80112B9683F474EAF2C2B0CB2DAD387"><enum>(5)</enum><text>One of the factors impacting salmonid populations is increased predation by marine mammals, including California sea lions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF416DE9673E42BAA2436C773663D48D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The population of California sea lions has increased 6-fold over the last 3 decades, and is currently greater than 250,000 animals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7E0D6318C784911AD1D54E8529DF7A2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In recent years, more than 1,000 California sea lions have been foraging in the lower 145 miles of the Columbia River up to Bonneville Dam during the peak spring salmonid run before returning to the California coast to mate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3076326EE9444C8A44DB302ED573035"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The percentage of the spring salmonid run that has been eaten or killed by California sea lions at Bonneville Dam has increased 7-fold since 2002.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FEFA555B6EE448599E975AE873AE6D6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In recent years, California sea lions have with greater frequency congregated near Bonneville Dam and have entered the fish ladders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H735692E4A7ED4415A8EA6037FB1E858E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>These California sea lions have not been responsive to extensive hazing methods employed near Bonneville Dam to discourage this behavior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43CBCF18529F47E7A4A79EA8CDB38656"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process established under the 1994 amendment to the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to address aggressive sea lion behavior is protracted and will not work in a timely enough manner to protect threatened and endangered salmonids in the near term.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05BA83F147A643BCB9657DE1E08071B8"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the interest of protecting Columbia River threatened and endangered salmonids, a temporary expedited procedure is urgently needed to allow removal of the minimum number of California sea lions as is necessary to protect the passage of threatened and endangered salmonids in the Columbia River and its tributaries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53BE4859A91C4DCF84A090F144F1B879"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On December 21, 2010, the independent Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force recommended lethally removing more of the California sea lions in 2011.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H231683F603894A71877F8BC6ED1AF823"><enum>(14)</enum><text>On August 18, 2011, the States of Washington, Oregon, and Idaho applied to the National Marine Fisheries Service, under section 120(b)(1)(A) of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1389">16 U.S.C. 1389(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>), for the lethal removal of sea lions that the States determined are having a <quote>significant negative impact</quote> on the recovery of Columbia River and Snake River salmon and steelhead.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2DE6A0DE109403EB4B08C4A5B03FBB4"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 12, 2011, the National Marine Fisheries Service announced it was accepting the States’ application for lethal removal of sea lions and that it would reconvene the Pinniped-Fishery Interaction Task Force to consider the States’ application. This Act will ensure the necessary authority for permits under the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to be issued in a timely fashion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7378AAB4DF94D0F9E3F2C214F298E27"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a June 14, 2011, hearing, the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives received testimony from State and tribal witnesses expressing concern that significant pinniped predation of important Northwest fish resources other than salmonids is severely impacting fish stocks determined by both Federal and State fishery management agencies to be at low levels of abundance, and that this cannot be addressed by section 120 of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1389">16 U.S.C. 1389</external-xref>), which as in effect before the enactment of this Act restricted control of predatory pinnipeds’ impact only with respect to endangered salmonids.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7B9B1F59B0DA43E58AB63C21AE29D594"><enum>3.</enum><header>Taking of sea lions on the Columbia River and its tributaries to protect endangered and threatened
 species of salmon and other nonlisted fish species</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 120 of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1389">16 U.S.C. 1389</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (f) and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HA8CD0E76A00D430F8FF9D8787489AD4B" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HE70B17349B2D4BDDAB6805707EBADEB4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Temporary marine mammal removal authority on the waters of the Columbia River or its tributaries</header>
 <paragraph id="HBCA81586B8A34E38AD2A1B0B17673F3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Removal authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary may issue a permit to an eligible entity authorizing the intentional lethal taking on the waters of the Columbia River and its tributaries of sea lions that are part of a healthy population that is not listed as an endangered species or threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), to protect endangered and threatened species of salmon and other nonlisted fish species.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HBB89E0DE2A904F3DAA19B13B6A0CF5B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permit process</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE920D060FA8C4542BC0C884160CAE70C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity may apply to the Secretary for a permit under this subsection.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB84E2D224584FB2A793E00F92856C7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline for consideration of application</header><text>The Secretary shall approve or deny an application for a permit under this subsection by not later than 30 days after receiving the application.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H982CBF83D4B4407DB3BA39DAB86B01FB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration of permit</header><text>A permit under this subsection shall be effective for no more than one year after the date it is issued, but may be renewed by the Secretary.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H318A8EAA08E74888A4D82ECBC19185C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC7C1994ECBAC40B2B4C9B5DCD99FE3E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation on permit authority</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), a permit issued under this subsection shall not authorize the lethal taking of more than 10 sea lions during the duration of the permit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A148E74F29D44C3979660A024B3ECD5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on annual takings</header><text>The cumulative number of sea lions authorized to be taken each year under all permits in effect under this subsection shall not exceed one percent of the annual potential biological removal level.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF911DDE7AC054B4B8C13E11351954E77"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Delegation of permit authority</header><text>Any eligible entity may delegate to any other eligible entity the authority to administer its permit authority under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEB528C295494D22984D588E4CDF9A99"><enum>(5)</enum><header>NEPA</header><text>Section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>) shall not apply with respect to this subsection and the issuance of any permit under this subsection during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF39D7595E0A49B4AD1777AF32417E5B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Suspension of permitting authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, 5 years after enactment, the Secretary, after consulting with State and tribal fishery managers, determines that lethal removal authority is no longer necessary to protect salmonid and other fish species from sea lion predation, may suspend the issuance of permits under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7FEFC22145E40DBAEA434A073614F41"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means each of the State of Washington, the State of Oregon, the State of Idaho, the Nez Perce Tribe, the Confederated Tribes of the Umatilla Indian Reservation, the Confederated Tribes of the Warm Springs Reservation of Oregon, the Confederated Tribes and Bands of the Yakama Nation, and the Columbia River Inter-Tribal Fish Commission</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HCC8623BD7046499EB986A157713599DE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HDD325266C65041798BD3C12B4C826355"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preventing predation by sea lions, recovery of listed salmonid stocks, and preventing future listings of fish stocks in the Columbia River is a vital priority;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7323E53AECD243E5A4D3DB219079E657"><enum>(2)</enum><text>permit holders exercising lethal removal authority pursuant to the amendment made by this Act should be trained in wildlife management; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08F448BDD1CD4724B8320D11AF5C9871"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal Government should continue to fund lethal and nonlethal removal measures for preventing such predation.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HE0CE215AE92741E3ACA9304EACCEE4D3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treaty rights of federally recognized Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendment made by this Act shall be construed to affect or modify any treaty or other right of any federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


