<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H14561D4F26864608BEB327D3D11D8CD6" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2443 IH: To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to CLIA waiver study design guidance for in vitro diagnostics.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2443</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150519">May 19, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to CLIA waiver study design guidance for in vitro diagnostics.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H082A42A6D68743C5865C9F5FA2929703" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2B722C9C2E6E487F9FBA0BE41221BC0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>CLIA waiver study design guidance for in vitro diagnostics</header> 
<subsection id="H1258967E6A7F477D8D5B5BEAA1AC84B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Draft revised guidance</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall publish a draft guidance that— </text> <paragraph id="H92C7A01F4240403496C2403B39944FDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revises section V <quote>Demonstrating Insignificant Risk of an Erroneous Result—<quote>Accuracy</quote></quote> of the guidance entitled <quote>Recommendations for Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments of 1988 (CLIA) Waiver Applications for Manufacturers of In Vitro Diagnostic Devices</quote> and dated January 30, 2008; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8C34715AD93448E89D98B57328AB10F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes guidance on the appropriate use of comparable performance between a waived user and a moderately complex laboratory user to demonstrate accuracy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H99D0432EDCC64E5EA9E6E2077776154F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final revised guidance</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall finalize the draft guidance published under subsection (a) not later than 12 months after the comment period for such draft guidance closes. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

