<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H35C63273805840C6A72E391373440406" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1360 IH: America’s Fund for Future Opportunities and Outcomes in the United States Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1360</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150313">March 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the Secretary of the Treasury to use revenue generated by certain fines, penalties, and settlements that are not designated for restitution or any other purpose to fund evidence-based youth mentoring projects, justice reinvestment efforts, and innovations in medical research and development.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE64F8FB8635040E0BDDD9ACCCDB70436" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H970B6BBD57E849E7B40232F447BA8463" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>America’s Fund for Future Opportunities and Outcomes in the United States Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>America’s FOCUS Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFFCA97E2154F40EDB96C390C924DB9C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H04312AF102A54B75988D65A1CD5EBAB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States faces increasing competition from countries with populations of a billion or more inhabitants, who contribute to the human capital of these countries and improve their performance in the global economy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B05395A08B74E068D619AF9BA3B7A17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To ensure that the United States retains its leadership position in the global economy, the United States should maximize the opportunities and outcomes of its citizenry.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F50B74E3929469CB2FAD1BB79B4F444"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States can achieve this goal by investing in STEM education and character development for youth, justice reinvestment efforts, and innovations in medical research and development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38B60C196E814DF0BAD5A9CCC49B3689"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To fund these investments in the public interest, the United States should use revenue generated by acts perpetrated against the public interest.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4686672A38EA440DBC5B3DC62E2209C3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As corporate and financial wrongdoing touches the lives of all Americans, revenue generated by such acts should serve as the basis for these investments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89282452F94449A58A33451D89E44B25"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This revenue should be used to assist programs and organizations seeking to better the Nation through their work in the youth mentoring, justice reinvestment, and medical research fields.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H715F4CA1B5884059AA9482A615A56BB4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 1956 and 1958, Congress issued Federal charters to the Boys and Girls Clubs of America and Big Brothers Big Sisters of America in recognition of their work helping children reach their full potential and succeed in American public life. Youth mentoring organizations still carry out this work and are putting children on the path to self-sufficiency. These organizations include—</text> <subparagraph id="H6A468298673C4FA2A42472AC1FAD983A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Boys and Girls Clubs of America;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB4D092AD4B244B87A28C39779ECDEC0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Big Brothers Big Sisters of America;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33D789BBCEED431FA1C5018C18C9C1C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Boy Scouts of America;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0244B12995CD4C519BD341BFFF0102A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Girl Scouts of the USA;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29B8FD0E57D14C1AAD5FFFC3E57FD57A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>MENTOR: the National Mentoring Partnership;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEEB5578398E14D969883F6F5D7A21C00"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the United Way;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E4B7D9A70E149A0B6FD96FC4F4A1601"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Girls Inc.;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B63891179534F9499CC09363177B000"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Amachi;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H558292F4FA274E96A578E66256DC67BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Y.M.C.A.;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45E5515F4D4F4605A647DBED28A43D83"><enum>(J)</enum><text>FIRST Robotics;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A6D76A3445144169591FF117D6A645D"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the United States D.R.E.A.M. Academy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD46B933762F48D99B82FC08937B1258"><enum>(L)</enum><text>GEAR UP;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2E2AE277CB04692A057CBFD76F0EB5B"><enum>(M)</enum><text>4–H;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8CDAE950679C43EB9E80C809FB7FCE15"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the National Urban League;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB88235EC8C004289B81592CA1AC1B934"><enum>(O)</enum><text>the First Tee;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27F65954E95F4141A55573D6B0A5E67E"><enum>(P)</enum><text>the Civil Air Patrol;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38451C94A8D74C78AFD4D6B1723F9EAD"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>the National Pan-Hellenic Council;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C3192F2EC924197AB982812C3070CCB"><enum>(R)</enum><text>the National CARES Mentoring Movement;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H165911A63D664DECB2F8C8AD5F342F01"><enum>(S)</enum><text>the National Alliance of Faith and Justice; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7950A1956DA4228984AC5E37F4AA24B"><enum>(T)</enum><text>the National Council of Youth Sports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE36C18DBD334204AC756588909FD734"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Innovations in medical research and development significantly benefit the American people. For example, through innovations in the diagnosis and treatment of life-threatening diseases, Americans are now living longer and more productive lives, contributing to the economic growth of the United States. Additional investments in medical research and development will contribute to overall public health and productivity in America.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5ECAE515FF6042C498AC12F85D6AF942"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through participation in the Justice Reinvestment Initiative, States have implemented evidence-based criminal justice reforms. These reforms are cost effective, redirecting revenue to better serve the public safety needs of local communities. In addition, these reforms have decreased risks of recidivism and instituted alternatives to incarceration for non-violent offenders. According to a July 2013 report from the Urban Institute, States participating in the Justice Reinvestment Initiative may achieve $3.3 billion in savings over the next 10 years. Additional funding to the Initiative would better enable States and local governments to carry out this work and achieve these savings.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD3BCF096BA7B458392DFEB941336118C"><enum>3.</enum><header>America’s Focus Fund</header> <subsection id="HCB8F18B195D04A02B1A47A9A7EB89C56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury a separate account to be known as the America’s FOCUS Fund (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H13D421847558474ABA2D0AB3C63AC6DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revenue deposited in Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit in the Fund—</text> <paragraph id="HE46C561DE08345EAB6EC487145E29546"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all revenue generated by civil and criminal fines and penalties for the violation or alleged violation of Federal law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22F5D7718B7849FBBD8B5E325612230F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all revenue generated by legal settlements reached between corporations and the Federal Government for the violation or alleged violation of Federal law; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9665AFBE157248BDA4E320E6F0617B67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any gift, bequest, or donation to the Fund from a private entity or individual, if such gift, bequest, or donation does not attach any condition inconsistent with Federal law or regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H576FED981EA14639AD9FF859CAC33081"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not deposit in the Fund—</text> <paragraph id="H4F56688E2FFF4FBBAC3CD9BBB68B03D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revenue designated for deposit in the Crime Victims Fund established by section 1402 of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10601">42 U.S.C. 10601</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A7EFE517FFE4B74BFA62239827986E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>revenue that has been designated by Federal law or court order for deposit in a fund other than the General Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H33C21A75F22B47CA952408A998E659E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="HEA131FF443D94D6FA4F0E31C5AC6D58D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Revenue in the Fund shall be used for the following purposes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDE7FCADEB27B4A6A8B8CD681B7FBB91F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Youth Mentoring Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 33 percent of the total revenue in the Fund as calculated on a quarterly basis shall be used to award grants for evidence-based youth mentoring and STEM education, in the manner provided in section 4.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6121E695EA64DB0B0E1C688F0A3A658"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Justice Reinvestment Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 33 percent of the total revenue in the Fund as calculated on a quarterly basis shall be used to award grants for evidence-based justice reinvestment, in the manner provided in section 5.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8758751865E49E695731A3CD4595C94"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Medical Innovation Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 33 percent of the total revenue in the Fund as calculated on a quarterly basis shall be used to award grants and prizes for innovations in medical research and development, in the manner provided in section 6.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48D92E9897954DA798A5FFEDE7851428"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reducing the Federal Debt</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use the remaining revenue for Federal budget deficit reduction or, if there is no Federal budget deficit for the fiscal year, for reducing the Federal debt in such manner as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEED824029FFF446585685F0799CEF286"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement to supplement, not supplant other funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds awarded under this Act shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, and local funds designated to carry out the activities funded by the grants.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8C372A8FC48449CBBC4E7515B8CFBC00"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Retention of sums in Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sums deposited in the Fund shall remain in the Fund and be available for expenditure for grants under this Act without fiscal year limitation.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4D7059962A864301BE93CE05B03AEEF9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Youth Mentoring Grants</header> 
<subsection id="H4DEB20777B4045C0AD23965F94F0BFB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header> 
<paragraph id="H7DFE901077114875B441D8AA75E3979C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Youth mentoring grants</header><text>The Secretary of Education, in cooperation with the Federal Mentoring Council, shall award grants to eligible entities that provide evidence-based youth mentoring programs, using the revenue designated for such purpose in subparagraph (A) of section 3(d)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AE73515094F4241B686C930DDF8A025"><enum>(2)</enum><header>STEM education grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Associate Administrator for Education for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall award grants to eligible entities that offer STEM education to individuals under the age of 21, using the revenue designated for such purpose in subparagraph (A) of section 3(d)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A8BDB69F3034A7E8AABFA3113543892"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity is eligible for a grant under this section if it is—</text> <paragraph id="H5DC136B4D12D44E7A7932E1AD2126669"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a national non-profit, community-based organization with at least 2 years of experience in administering STEM education programs or youth mentoring programs; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA56F0A4EBBA4BDEB34C2DA6B97B57B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a State or local government.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5068AF42F43D4AD4934C6A9E77E4C253"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An entity seeking to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application at such time and in such form as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H808AA81D07D6401BA8AF5553D8119564"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds available under this section, 25 percent shall be allocated for the award of grants to State and local governments.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H17A6C5873C784A818FA2B7FD34ED638A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="H6F859B9B8CCE43C896CDDA9BA090B177"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State and local governments</header> <subparagraph id="H8BA2FD852DF1484FB605BB64D9D2B06C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>A State or local government that receives a grant under this section shall distribute the grant funds to non-profit, community-based organizations and local educational agencies within the jurisdiction of such government that provide evidence-based mentoring or STEM education to individuals under the age of 21.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8F99803B07A4DB7BF7CD92CB7F87984"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funds reserved for vulnerable youth</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local government that receives grant funds under this section shall allocate not less than 50 percent of such funds for distribution to organizations described in subparagraph (A) that provide evidence-based mentoring or STEM education to vulnerable youth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF714DF3FC3E0423A8949097CBF70A99B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other entities</header> <subparagraph id="HB0E7319AB23E4693BC011ADF7DB7745A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>An organization other than a State or local government that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to establish or expand one or more programs that provide evidence-based mentoring or STEM education to individuals under the age of 21.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53FA702A3F2A44979D6BE82BE69DC393"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funds reserved for persistent poverty counties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An organization other than a State or local government that receives grant funds under this section shall allocate not less than 10 percent of such funds for programs that provide evidence-based mentoring or STEM education in persistent poverty counties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0D243BF06FCB48A19460DF945E9CED96"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual award of grants</header><text>To the extent funds are available, the grants under this section shall be awarded at least once during each fiscal year, with the first grants to be awarded within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC98186E7CAF94840A3FDDC3C7BE26DE9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7CFCA72740514A46ABA76804D69B6165"><enum>(1)</enum><header>STEM education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>STEM education program</quote> means a program to educate students in one or more of the following disciplines: science, technology, engineering, or mathematics.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE41F39981A194A6DB0B3F65372900745"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Persistent poverty counties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>persistent poverty counties</quote> means any county that has had 20 percent or more of its population living in poverty over the past 30 years, as measured by the 1990, 2000, and 2010 decennial censuses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D183BACD6BF46B29D502EB0F443F87A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vulnerable youth</header><text>The term <quote>vulnerable youth</quote> includes individuals under the age of 21—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0C63DE231B174B3DB6CCAA5537C09E03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who experience emotional and adjustment problems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2E20F65B43440FD9522DDAB2D49D82B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who have left or are at risk of leaving secondary school without a diploma;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD17F2E475EE0473EA43CDA3ACAB7AD43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who lack the skills to succeed in the workforce after graduation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77EB32699BF94899A718C213646F1A9B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>who live in an unstable family or community environment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3CC7D08539594B6EB84299C3AC01B867"><enum>(E)</enum><text>who are involved in the juvenile justice system;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59D041DA39B5434C942DE5176D13123B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>who are homeless or live in foster care;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19FAA50B84364084AA8E0F59D78AB56A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>who have physical or mental disabilities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6D04B5ACE5D45EBB5D62D65BDB14AF6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>who receive special education;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAFBF636CBEB4DFFAB83AC0D9EC3255D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>who are or have been victims of human trafficking; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF13095EA48F14492BEB50D6760369BD8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>who live in neighborhoods with high rates of illegal drug use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC4760AB706954888BA127F3FF15E9768"><enum>5.</enum><header>Justice Reinvestment Grants</header> 
<subsection id="H68EEE60730CE465799EAC49F65F495B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall use the revenue designated for justice reinvestment grants in subparagraph (B) of section 3(d)(1) to fund evidence-based justice reinvestment projects as part of the Justice Reinvestment Initiative and programs established under the Second Chance Act within the Department of Justice.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0DD043EC7B604897AC11E149054B2E2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="H74C3C94C442944EEB1E2FDCED70FEC27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State and local governments</header> <subparagraph id="H8CD525C81C6B4063AEA0A9A808328990"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), 50 percent of the funds under this section shall be used to award grants to State and local governments for evidence-based justice reinvestment projects.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E014E20FE8D40CEBBD4D7DF64F50026"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funds reserved for persistent poverty counties</header><text>The Attorney General shall allocate not less than 10 percent of such funds for projects that support persistent poverty counties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C0CAE78AD19464E99B0B48C886FCB3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal Government</header><text>The Attorney General may use not more than 25 percent of the funds under this section to support Federal justice reinvestment projects.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95FECF5ACD2B40BC9E5427911D6A23BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Second Chance Act Programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall allocate not more than 25 percent of the funds in this section to grant programs established under the Second Chance Act within the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H81D39A62185047BE868CA91A85A8397A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity seeking to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application at such time and in such form as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC209C3121D1499484125E8E1E9E9862"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual award of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent funds are available, the Attorney General shall award grants under this section at least once during each fiscal year, with the first grants to be awarded within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8C121B66402E4092AB4397CCE851B9AB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Persistent poverty counties defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>persistent poverty counties</quote> means any county that has had 20 percent or more of its population living in poverty over the past 30 years, as measured by the 1990, 2000, and 2010 decennial censuses.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6856A37F4C454810AB69E1AF706B2BE6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Medical Innovation Grants</header> 
<subsection id="H5BB1B391E9594E4EA340513558FFBB5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall use the revenue designated for medical innovation in subparagraph (C) of section 3(d)(1) to fund entities that conduct innovative medical research and development.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9F57EF17A648477F9D1DFCD6EEB56A59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="H4150A294D5894BC8BEB00F8D828AAAA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants</header> <subparagraph id="H128C9FE939054BF9B861A2BD0724FFA9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the funds available under this section shall be used to award grants to entities that conduct innovative medical research and development to provide faster cures for medical ailments and diseases.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6290740E6D36495DBC811002F4D5AB86"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An entity seeking to receive a grant under this paragraph shall submit an application at such time and in such form as the Director may reasonably require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E3A15A9DDD348A686104C54FCE520F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prizes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may use not more than 15 percent of the funds available under this section to award monetary prizes to entities that have used their own funding and research facilities to produce innovative results in medical research and development.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48A050FB104A423983F47D486763EE7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual award of grants and prizes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent funds are available, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall award the grants and prizes under this section at least once during each fiscal year, with the first grants and prizes to be awarded within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

