<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H926FB9A43EC3424F9C7D52A813D39B2D" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2679 IH: Tibetan Refugee Assistance Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2679</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150604">June 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the admission to the United States of certain Tibetans.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF56171EA3E1A48F899C7A91A13CA0731" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0B1981465607416DAA1D9260366F9DE2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tibetan Refugee Assistance Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1ABFE95471374E06A63EBA7940C98793" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transition for displaced Tibetans</header> <subsection id="HD452B745C50644D884FBB3234E8BAD21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the numerical limitations specified in sections 201 and 202 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1151 and 1152), there shall be made available to qualified displaced Tibetans described in subsection (b) of this section 3,000 immigrant visas in the 3-fiscal-year period beginning with fiscal year 2016.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3737B4FD7D5D44EEB039ECE1F3710D33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified displaced Tibetan described</header>
 <paragraph id="H1753DDE4851C43A5BF466C6203EEDD44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual is a qualified displaced Tibetan if such individual is an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="H6898A1529B934302838CA2689FD83D2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a native of Tibet; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF385797DA2B04E39BA150BBBDF633FF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>since before the date of the enactment of this Act, has been continuously residing in India or Nepal.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF41127F2EE14CC29DEDC9189E137636"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Native of Tibet described</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), an individual shall be considered to be a native of Tibet if such individual was born in Tibet or is the son, daughter, grandson, or granddaughter of an individual born in Tibet.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A8EAE24F85248928598716A4988D762"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution of visa numbers</header><text>The Secretary of State shall ensure that immigrant visas provided under subsection (a) are made available to qualified displaced Tibetans described in subsection (b) (or described in subsection (d) as the spouse or child of such a qualified displaced Tibetan) in an equitable manner, giving preference to those qualified displaced Tibetans who are not resettled in India or Nepal or who are most likely to be resettled successfully in the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB39D63D291F34447A94316617424A59D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Derivative status for spouses and children</header><text>A spouse or child (as defined in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) of section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</external-xref>)) shall, if not otherwise entitled to an immigrant status and the immediate issuance of a visa under this section, be entitled to the same status, and the same order of consideration, provided under this section, if accompanying, or following to join, the spouse or parent of such spouse or child.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


