<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H81F4FF79FD964D7AA2962569F287749F" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1484 IH: Honor the Nevada Enabling Act of 1864 Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1484</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150319">March 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal
			 lands to the State of Nevada in fulfillment of the Nevada Statehood
			 Enabling Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H997992B93AED4BF9A8B0801B44EC0D9F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEA092706BD98439B8878A40F8C71767E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Honor the Nevada Enabling Act of 1864 Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H04EB4B5AEE6B4F1B91235519A7097094"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1F212675A7A947C2B2393B43E231508B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Government controls over 80 percent of all of the land within the State of Nevada, which is a greater percentage than any other State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC07604A916D64859B107442837689E7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The paucity of State land and privately controlled land in Nevada severely constrains the size and diversity of Nevada’s economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6546AB6BDA364A018613FC96098DAC71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Government promised all new States, in their statehood enabling Act contracts, that it would dispose of federally controlled public lands within the borders of those States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4C2E042B0E640B783ADCC2610D2062D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Federal Government has honored this promise with 38 States.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4E3F0DF5FF024057A9C6BC1CB906A9A1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government has failed to honor this promise with, and continues to control significant percentages of the land within, the States of Alaska, Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, Utah, and Washington.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E00A7CE2D564D848CADB5581C84F2D8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States Supreme Court has declared that statehood enabling Act contracts are <quote>solemn compacts</quote> with enforceable rights and obligations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE10F8E84BC4500B53C9B6B80257C37"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Nevada could generate significant net revenue for the benefit of its lands and people if it were afforded the opportunity to manage an expanded State-controlled land portfolio.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H661E6D4A513C4D6493D574C631130CAB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A transfer of federally administered land to Nevada can be accomplished in phases.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HAC0D0DD460634039A5633AFBBFEA3436"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions in this Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6AD01FE62FD34858AC7E1940951D7E9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>identified Federal lands</quote> means all lands within the State of Nevada that are owned, managed, or controlled by the Federal Government acting through the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, excluding the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H63C2C5CE7B1F483781E99FD02CC42844"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, National Park System, and National Wildlife Refuge System.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H553B697FFBBD4F7ABB7ADAE50D489362"><enum>(B)</enum><text>National Conservation Areas.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9750B4899594E19A20EDDD21FD973C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>National Monuments designated pursuant to the Act of June 6, 1908 (commonly known as the Antiquities Act of 1906).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB60B244280F64E238DB1FFE691A603DE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Lands designated as Areas of Critical Environmental Concern for Protection of Desert Tortoise by the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47CA186A539C446A87A7584A33802E01"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Lands allocated as Herd Management Areas for Wild Horses and Burros.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AAA1DCD55EC4B5CA5F22F1D68A61684"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Lands withdrawn and reserved for use by the Department of Defense or the Department of Energy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AF079234F8940CA9E67E840A85D70F9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Federally recognized Indian reservations and lands administered or held in trust by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB10EFF21F94A42D2A0A37DB5D286ABF2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Bureau of Reclamation lands not identified as surplus.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF968D7165218463880D880108B5F4048"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>Secretary concerned</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDA55BEE2D83647A1B677DAE982C09BCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to identified Federal lands administered by that Secretary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82A021A676E541F7928FCB5EB1725C4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to identified Federal lands administered by that Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC938DCBE8014B32B0490DF012E093FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>select beneficiaries</quote> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAC3ADE8C6133431A80CAA70C7D8DE1D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Public elementary and secondary education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77459332E9004E74AB54FCDBA36F7EB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Public higher education.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E7743439947466EBDF0A0E4416D1AAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Public specialized education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F2F2CCB24414282994E13A16EC7B9D6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Public mental and medical health services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H141A434932024152A8596C25D252478D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Social, senior, and veterans services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36052A5E38694DB9824766F0A79E4CC4"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public programs for recovery plan development and implementation for candidate and threatened or endangered species.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6B0F39B32DC4E348A1C458224AC44BC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Political subdivisions of the State of Nevada, but only with respect to payment for services and infrastructure on conveyed identified Federal lands that would otherwise be financed through property taxes or other revenues available to a political subdivision of the State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9644B85BE0814F439887D675F44A4668"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the State of Nevada.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HBBC503504C8943A9B9F9A309AAE223F6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Conveyance of identified Federal lands to the State of Nevada</header> <subsection id="HE875CE3751594027B4FDDC74FD9CE952"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance required</header><text>As provided in this Act, the Secretary concerned shall convey, in phases and without consideration, to the State of Nevada all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to identified Federal lands for the purpose of permitting the State to use the conveyed lands to support select beneficiaries.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF5739C3BB59F4D8D974A25774AC7C256"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Condition of conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All conveyances under this Act shall be subject to the condition that the State hold the identified Federal lands in trust for the select beneficiaries, except the State may sell, lease, or securitize lands acquired under this Act to cover the cost of management of the newly acquired lands.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H48D867E60CAE4F21AEF546A6D7D968C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of lands for conveyance</header><text>The State is authorized to select the identified Federal lands to be conveyed under this Act.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HB55DA8521B8F48C1ADE436B5D03E3D4F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Valid existing rights and uses</header><text>All conveyances under this Act shall be subject to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4C6A7D01BBED4DF099277A1C03748092"><enum>(1)</enum><text>valid existing rights; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CD152BA08E146B2A1A62AB24DBC3FB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">valid existing uses on, permits for, and public access to the conveyed lands, as in effect at the time of conveyance, subject to State law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H360FB2723BCF4CBE9146CBADA51E053D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conveyance of entire interest</header><text>For identified Federal lands conveyed under this Act, title to and ownership of both federally held surface and subsurface estate, and appurtenant federally held water rights, shall pass to the State.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HFB0F3436A3D443BBB42C29D3F57432B4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Initial conveyance phase</header>
 <subsection id="HFF034CFCCAA54F88BDD704DF6F63F5F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after selection by the State, the Secretary concerned shall convey to the State pursuant to section 3 identified Federal lands selected by the State from the following categories of identified Federal lands:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCA8F79629624479DAA4CED831EFB3FE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Lands identified as suitable for disposal in the report to Congress submitted by the Secretary of Agriculture on May 27, 1997, pursuant to section 390(g) of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/127">Public Law 104–127</external-xref>; 110 Stat. 1024).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAECEEF20EAB349119DE4F7BF4FD17104"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Lands identified as suitable for disposal in any Federal land use plan developed and approved pursuant to section 202 the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>) or section 6 of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1604">16 U.S.C. 1604</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D46D9B69ABB4291B01AF497C98ACA24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management pursuant to the Act of June 14, 1926 (commonly known as the Recreation and Public Purposes Act; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/869">43 U.S.C. 869 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE1039D5D3ED4C0E954DF6710E8CF695"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Lands allocated by the Secretary concerned as Solar Energy Zones.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7FB0EA7C4FC45609803541AF0EF0314"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Lands leased pursuant to the mineral and geothermal leasing laws under the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C93357CE6564CAFB40C153437BCCB3F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management as linear and nonlinear rights-of-way granted to the State and political subdivisions of the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE853E3A9AC814D69920F8CEA66781168"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Split estate lands, where the surface is privately held and the Bureau of Land Management administers the subsurface mineral estate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F568380FD5402A8DDC92531E03452D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Lands in the State designated for disposal by any other Act of Congress.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H863B7688CDD843CC8227A49D29B864B5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management remaining within the original Central Pacific Railroad corridor along Interstate Highway 80 in Northern Nevada, also known as the <quote>checkerboard</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2759C11E4C064CF9B9FB6DA745713789"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized acreage</header><text>The State is authorized to select no less than 7,200,000 acres from the categories of identified Federal lands described in subsection (a) during the initial conveyance phase.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H386DE7018B6E45D399C433A17C75E81D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Subsequent conveyance phases</header>
 <subsection id="H2191FE522992488BA7B2680E6FFE3267"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance process</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall establish a process to convey to the State the remaining identified Federal lands not conveyed in the initial conveyance phase under section 5.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H929766227848433D87872BA62A479B91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requests for conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 10-year period beginning upon the completion of the initial conveyance phase under section 5, the Secretary concerned shall convey to the State pursuant to section 3, upon the request of the State or a political subdivision of the State and consistent with the process established under this section, identified Federal lands remaining under the control of the Secretary concerned.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF442B9BA3F444D71980DE9FD96D4C035"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management of lands conveyed in subsequent conveyance phases</header><text>The State shall manage identified Federal lands conveyed under this section for ongoing net-revenue generation and environmental health, function, productivity, and sustainability.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0BDDB876D27A4F6381055B0CB4CF7D3C"><enum>7.</enum><header>State payments to political subdivisions of the State</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">As an additional condition on conveyances under this Act, the State shall agree to make payments to political subdivisions of the State, using gross revenues derived from management of identified Federal lands conveyed under this Act, to replace—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC1505F9E72B94CB786B82837872AC407"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revenues lost through reduced Federal payments under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/69">chapter 69</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, on account of the conveyance of the lands; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H676FA633DE1E4B58B6674DE100A1C2CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revenues that would otherwise have been shared with the political subdivisions by the Department of the Interior Office of Natural Resources Revenue from royalties, rents, and bonuses generated through energy and mineral leases on identified Federal lands had the lands remained in Federal ownership.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


