<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD7B9EF5A22543BD8D151910E105BBE5" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2801 IH: No Office Space for Executive Amnesty Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2801</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150617">June 17, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit the Administrator of General Services from leasing space for certain purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0774CAF8DD864492AF94232E27A4199F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1184257D4F864B2DBB619B9D47253EC8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Office Space for Executive Amnesty Act of 2015</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HBAA6BAE9D9CE4A03A71C422D88F2F549"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on GSA leasing authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds may be obligated or expended by the Administrator of General Services to lease any space for purposes of carrying out the policies set forth in the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4577F375BD8341B6B4E23BC16E055681"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Southern Border and Approaches Campaign</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H339636A7FF174820A28047C403979E41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Policies for the Apprehension, Detention and Removal of Undocumented Immigrants</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20D1DC88F0014C78B2D6D491AD85D10D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Secure Communities</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23E1BB8B94894AD8B5497BD7801157A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Exercising Prosecutorial Discretion with Respect to Individuals Who Came to the United States as Children and with Respect to Certain Individuals Who Are the Parents of U.S. Citizens or Permanent Residents</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11D65404A24648D6A6082EEFAF822DD4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Expansion of the Provisional Waiver Program</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A8778B0F93047BBAF09CC3745CDEED8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Policies Supporting U.S. High-Skilled Businesses and Workers</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07B16A5CCE7240D49E809748BC93D78C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Families of U.S. Armed Forces Members and Enlistees</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H494583A15E4744ED8FB37D8EA457984E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Directive to Provide Consistency Regarding Advance Parole</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A444855ECD04B2BB2742285E27877FC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Policies to Promote and Increase Access to U.S. Citizenship</quote> dated November 20, 2014.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H945F2BEB3DC2417795FB181140EB4973"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The memoranda issued by the President on November 21, 2014, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB4FC1F2ACD664ADA98C5A2A21CA2A395"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the memorandum entitled <quote>Creating Welcoming Communities and Fully Integrating Immigrants and Refugees</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CB6EB4680324D72B9F7631AC57039FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the memorandum entitled <quote>Modernizing and Streamlining the U.S. Immigrant Visa System for the 21st Century</quote>.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D6093E03C6B46D3A6EC1CCD8C55BC71"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Any similar memorandum issued after November 21, 2014.</text></paragraph> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

