<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A632F870C47429D8DF2008689BE7147" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1301 IH: Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1301</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150304">March 4, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000372">Mr. Frelinghuysen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000449">Mr. Fortenberry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Federal Communications Commission to extend to private land use restrictions its rule relating to reasonable accommodation of amateur service communications.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HEB776A14C6204651A23491681E4155E5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H817A7C17C3E34799A3232B73E2CCCD5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7FA1F8E6FF3F420A9A935C1777DB31EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF7471F1B26204E67A16504CFFEED2E42"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">More than 700,000 radio amateurs in the United States are licensed by the Federal Communications Commission in the amateur radio service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3C18D6822064E2F870C1C2425346286"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amateur radio, at no cost to taxpayers, provides a fertile ground for technical self-training in modern telecommunications, electronics technology, and emergency communications techniques and protocols.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA263BE2040774223A090A402C7758BBD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a strong Federal interest in the effective performance of amateur radio stations established at the residences of licensees. Such stations have been shown to be frequently and increasingly precluded by unreasonable private land use restrictions, including restrictive covenants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DBF762414104BE5A87C2EB13D1A7C75"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Communications Commission regulations have for three decades prohibited the application to amateur radio stations of State and local regulations that preclude or fail to reasonably accommodate amateur service communications, or that do not constitute the minimum practicable regulation to accomplish a legitimate State or local purpose. Commission policy has been and is to permit erection of a station antenna structure at heights and dimensions sufficient to accommodate amateur service communications.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2DD30DADF6B44A5930C32FFDC187384"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Communications Commission has sought guidance and direction from Congress with respect to the application of the Commission’s limited preemption policy regarding amateur radio communications to private land use restrictions, including restrictive covenants.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H1946BB3588504D37B0903FBA5EFB65D5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Accommodation of amateur service communications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall amend section 97.15(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, so that such section prohibits application to amateur service communications of any private land use restriction, including a restrictive covenant, that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD7E336718C534AEE98906FA14C363DC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>precludes such communications;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13005770982A4DD99EE7AC0FBFB6D9D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fails to reasonably accommodate such communications; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02954BABDCE245A3AA7907E81C115730"><enum>(3)</enum><text>does not constitute the minimum practicable restriction on such communications to accomplish the legitimate purpose of the private entity seeking to enforce such restriction.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

