<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1CADE6D93D314864BA8708969E293381" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1765 IH: To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to submit a report regarding certain plans regarding assistance to applicants and grantees during the response to an emergency or disaster.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1765</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150414">April 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to submit a report regarding certain plans regarding assistance to applicants and grantees during the response to an emergency or disaster.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H792BF49958344B2AA89229BF667E0707" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H96D267A537234E8CA1AB02E15F3E91E6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Action plan to improve field transition</header> 
<subsection id="HD935CD241CDB4A7CAF8648D5256962B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate regarding the plans the agency will undertake to provide the following:</text> <paragraph id="H445C3FE7FD06474986C79216C94F43F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Consistent guidance to applicants on FEMA disaster funding procedures during the response to an emergency or disaster.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80754EB062164B188A562EE6E22C89D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Appropriate record maintenance and transfer of documents to new teams during staff transitions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8657787E5D7F4428843A616CE24F470F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Accurate assistance to applicants and grantees to ease the administrative burden throughout the process of obtaining and monitoring assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F09A23B0D4C4FBABEC9DE7B097F41BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maintaining records</header><text>The report shall also include a plan for implementing operating procedures and document retention requirements to ensure the maintenance of appropriate records throughout the lifecycle of the disaster an emergency or disaster.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H96C58332B5524314B1972FC48E2EF1DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>New technologies</header><text>Finally, the report shall identify new technologies that further aid the disaster workforce in partnering with State, local, and tribal governments and private nonprofits in the wake of a disaster or emergency to educate, assist, and inform applicants on the status of their emergency or disaster assistance applications and projects.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

