<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H491EA189E857473A96D36C51D797C1DF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3852 IH: To direct the Secretary of Energy to conduct a study on the benefits of solar net energy metering, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3852</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151028">October 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Energy to conduct a study on the benefits of solar net energy metering,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H59A762F1F3B24D62B0958F28D168D4B1" style="OLC">
		<section id="H470A66DFA4204A0EB79794C69184FB08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Study and report on benefits of solar net energy metering</header>
			<subsection id="HACE771239F2543EEBE1FCD35F9BC051F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study and report</header>
 <paragraph id="H71C288E8AD284D09B18B6BFB40E07411"><enum>(1)</enum><header>in general</header><text>The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a study on solar net energy metering. The study shall include an analysis of any benefits that may result from implementing solar net energy metering, including any resulting—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB45EC26C00EE483AA282C1ED9BAC449E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduction in demand on the grid during peak hours;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAB8D296B65E40549A48BB559D114CD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increased grid security through localized grid support;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3BD00C8F04B4F1D80FBA46FE5EE7265"><enum>(C)</enum><text>creation of jobs related to solar energy, including jobs in production, construction, and installation, increasing the tax base for State and local governments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB87044D2D60B4FD593F35B383D1364DE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>avoidance of energy-related expenditures by electric consumers that enables such electric consumers to increase discretionary spending and stimulate local economies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3358CF1778934D22B0DACB7F53D5396F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reduction in air pollution and associated health risks;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DAD70EEE3B249FDB7C4740E30AB3B9B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>reduction in greenhouse gas emissions and associated climate change impacts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21076E9FE3CB40BF8F81F0D33999CB3F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>assistance to electric utilities in meeting applicable renewable portfolio standards;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB42ADC407EE40A986D68AE500B66189"><enum>(H)</enum><text>reduction in water usage as compared to the amount of water used in fossil-fuel-based electricity production;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63F5F660EC764EF694EFB377075AFFFE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reduction in electricity cost for electric consumers as a result of reduced demand for centrally supplied electricity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5E97FBBB44444C6BFDB48855FDE589C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>avoided cost in energy generation, deferred capacity, and grid support services to electric utilities by or on behalf of an electric consumer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD75E230B5E8043B4959BD9833E99BEFC"><enum>(K)</enum><text>avoided cost to electric utilities for fuel price hedging otherwise needed to guarantee that a portion of electricity supply costs are fixed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3BA8F1FC2AC4103A37E1548F89364C2"><enum>(L)</enum><text>increase in the availability of private capital to individuals generating electricity through use of solar power based on the stable assumptions solar net energy metering provides for financial institutions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF73DA6277E794A218FF1FFCF14A72A00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study required to be conducted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0547D0CA1A164266BD01F3E273BD6019"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H4A647CF93BC4499CA39F85FB8238B90A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible solar generating facility</header><text>The term <term>eligible solar generating facility</term> means a facility that produces electric energy solely by the use, as a primary energy source, of solar energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDA21995CBCB4FE0B2957878DA777BA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Primary energy source</header><text>The term <term>primary energy source</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/796">16 U.S.C. 796</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6911C3D8FB2645BEB19F5AA52ACF2F72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Solar net energy metering</header><text>The term <term>solar net energy metering</term> means service to an electric consumer under which electric energy generated by such electric consumer from an on-site eligible solar generating facility and delivered to local distribution facilities may be used to offset electric energy provided by an electric utility to the electric consumer during the applicable billing period.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F7ECFFE4109420A8F6FD98D5C20DC9E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Electric utility; electric consumer</header><text>The terms <term>electric utility</term> and <term>electric consumer</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2602">16 U.S.C. 2602</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


