<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1C63643F466B47B2BB1883E13A2EE633" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 849 IH: To grant a Federal charter to the National Academy of Inventors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 849</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To grant a Federal charter to the National Academy of Inventors.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H22E742EB0E234F4EBC0685E584B0F2F6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB5C4FC9D2E25495B8BD904CDB68A2068" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Grant of Federal charter to the National Academy of Inventors</header>
<subsection id="H8FCC0DCA33F54B51AC7E7738AE02C448"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant of charter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part B of subtitle II of title 36, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 1503 the following new chapter:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC41E5F52E55D4A049D1C9D109CE4F1FA" style="USC"> <chapter id="H8B0FD71CE9C5472C9EABF3CAD876517E"><enum>1504</enum><header>National Academy of Inventors</header> <section id="H9175A713914D497BA9FC1308E4046E16"><enum>150401.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HE9CB1395FA2743F2900E873A03736C47"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The majority of our Nation’s basic research is done at our colleges and universities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A6AF03E9A4641E3AC8BD316AA9BB937"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The National Academy of Inventors recognizes and encourages inventors who have a patent issued from the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0C259C7C51A945CEAA58C758FD450829"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The National Academy of Inventors enhances the visibility of university and non-profit research institute technology and academic innovation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00BB61C8E5FE4F8392BAD207A2125ECD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The National Academy of Inventors encourages the disclosure of intellectual property.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H915F052646FA4FDAADBC67C537EF071D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The National Academy of Inventors educates and mentors innovative students.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20E5A038FE50434EB85D488360FBB166"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The systematic application of organized knowledge and information can generate technology and produce creative solutions to existing problems.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H561D8BF739E544E0B3B71C732782D521"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Innovation, based on new inventions and technologies, has proven to be a key factor in the industrial and economic development of the world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1862C45B10694ADB8F1E2DA36DA0FC56"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The National Academy of Inventors serves a valuable role in the translation of science and technology within the university and non-profit research institute community, and for the benefit of society.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8F52C39611074FD69779EE3BF3436D33"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Congress supports the mission of the National Academy of Inventors to encourage the translation of the inventions of its members to benefit society.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HAA4F6759448A4BB5B7213F958640E501"><enum>150402.</enum><header>Organization</header> <subsection id="H96EF90255D1544AB93137E6720F1E3A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal charter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Academy of Inventors, a not for profit organization that meets the requirements under section 501(c)(3) of the internal revenue code, and is organized under the laws of the State of Florida, is a federally chartered organization.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4FCF8FAE3B064D8080CC015BDB5BC0AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expiration of Charter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the organization does not comply with the provisions of this chapter, the charter granted shall expire.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD6AD88AF394B4939B860E33455BBE525"><enum>150403.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of the organization are as provided in its bylaws and articles of incorporation.</text></section>
<section id="H4089BE6EE91C448FB00D86754157FB7E"><enum>150404.</enum><header>Governing body</header>
<subsection id="H324F76EC9EB74F89AE620138236650BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of Directors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The composition of the board of directors for the organization, and the responsibilities of the board are as provided in the articles of incorporation and bylaws of the organization.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD5347609A0CD4E4E95EED05DFC86924F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Officers</header><text>The positions of officers/executive committee members of the organization, and the election of the officers and executive committee members, are as provided in the articles of incorporation and bylaws.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H73BC3C6B11C14BD7BD930D23CF526079"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Executive Committee</header><text>The positions of executive committee members of the organization, and the election of executive committee members, are as provided in the articles of incorporation and bylaws.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H16D4E2B1B0BB4E87A00D1BCDC8426CD9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Executive Advisory Board</header><text>The composition of the executive advisory board for the organization, and the responsibilities of the executive advisory board are as provided in the articles of incorporation and bylaws of the organization.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HB3EE701BBF754D77B323F98BC20F2776"><enum>150405.</enum><header>Powers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The corporation has only those powers provided in its bylaws and articles of incorporation filed in each State in which it is incorporated.</text></section> <section id="HE5528521C6DD4BE2A99E744E5E326CB5"><enum>150406.</enum><header>Restrictions</header> <subsection id="H81FEF67B0F7C4639ABBB62B127D835A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Stock and Dividends</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFB0C2EE2437B47ACB7C9BA7EF9FAE46F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution of Income or Assets</header><text>No part of the income or assets of this Corporation will be distributed, to its Directors or Officers. However, the corporation may contract in due course of business with its Officers or Directors for services rendered to the extent permissible under the articles of incorporation, under law and under section 501(c)(3) of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H13A3031361BE4B589F858F15B798C7CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loans</header><text>The organization may not loan money to any of its directors or officers.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H71998F3AB5AF43FCA21086F86154D0B7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Corporate Status</header><text>The organization shall maintain its status as a corporation incorporated under the laws of the State of Florida.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB91A4FCFCA9D4A98AD3CDA47BDF8373B"><enum>150407.</enum><header>Tax-exempt status required as a condition of charter</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the corporation fails to maintain its status as an organization exempt from taxation under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the charter granted under this chapter shall terminate.</text></section>
<section id="HF9E17668E6D64A7685A786D67347ECF2"><enum>150408.</enum><header>Records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The organization shall keep—</text> <paragraph id="H36A1A0C7E540436B91746ADA0F0BF43E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>correct and complete records of account;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H442D4B6D4F2C4184A0A7D0DE4600A590"><enum>(2)</enum><text>minutes of the proceedings of the members, board of directors, and committees of the corporation having any of the authority of the board of directors of the corporation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66EB1BE54ED9403B99C3471A5B9B1B32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>at the principal office of the corporation, a record of the names and addresses of the members of the corporation entitled to vote on matters relating to the corporation.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H741056779B974B6A8333BF5A1D2EEF13"><enum>150409.</enum><header>Liability for acts of officers and agents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The organization is liable for any act of any officer or agent of the corporation acting within the scope of the authority of the corporation.</text></section> <section id="H450C38C750784DC2AEC2954789815163"><enum>150410.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The corporation shall transmit to Congress an annual report on the activities of the corporation during the preceding fiscal year. The report shall be submitted at the same time as the report of the audit required. The report may not be printed as a public document.</text></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HC427044FB4774CE6A6284272FF383C17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of chapters at the beginning of subtitle II of title 36, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 1503 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68F45CF873CC4D128DB764A799DCD1EE" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="chapter">1504. National Academy of Inventors..............................150401</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

