<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF450DB85E02B4C5EA271C5E2217157AF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3094 IH: Gulf States Red Snapper Management Authority Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3094</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150716">July 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000796">Mr. Westmoreland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to transfer to States the
			 authority to manage red snapper fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0A8D28F37E17413787A27C908AC7F7BB" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE4D64C010E7347D98564399D429A1DE9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gulf States Red Snapper Management Authority Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6F5B860685F74154BED66EA181B53BCA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transfer to States of management of red snapper fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico</header> <subsection id="H08F28EFDD9BA4EDC98F58DB0800CA3EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC882EE058E7E4897A5A2C879B01E04A8" style="OLC">
					<title id="H260CBCBB79254545BC358A2D4F6B7200"><enum>V</enum><header>Transfer to States of Management of Red Snapper Fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico</header>
 <section id="HBE913252F7104CDDB73A5375CAC5E716"><enum>501.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HF88320C66448447FB8264B1DB6118E2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coastal waters</header><text>The term <quote>coastal waters</quote> means all waters of the Gulf of Mexico—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6AE3B97F23CC43A79F57170D5B9226BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shoreward of the baseline from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56CBE26B045E4976BF5E6014457013CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seaward from the baseline described in subparagraph (A) to the outer boundary of the exclusive economic zone.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE02BBABF96954586BD443541B520CD81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gulf coastal State</header><text>The term <quote>Gulf coastal State</quote> means each of the following States:</text> <subparagraph id="HE5861FA8CB7D4A8CB1C3C27E11068D80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Alabama.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C22812D9D5940A08C86EEC5DB28C9A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Florida.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F8B9E3E33A45CD86004DA8AF3E9E7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Louisiana.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0732243499C54A85874C7E5ECE40B79E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Mississippi.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA3CA071AF974D29BF33BF8342C24452"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Texas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DE5A70D391A45EB802E8911CBD0AA8F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council</header><text>The term <quote>Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council</quote> means the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council established under section 302(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1833F79D079D4D989A29DE5A8DA2A7BE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gulf of Mexico red snapper</header><text>The term <quote>Gulf of Mexico red snapper</quote> means members of stocks or populations of the species Lutjanus campechanus, which ordinarily are found within the waters of the exclusive economic zone and adjacent territorial waters of the Gulf of Mexico.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD293C7D0BA54475AB92CC521B759FD09"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gulf States Red Snapper Management Authority</header><text>The term <quote>Gulf States Red Snapper Management Authority</quote> and <quote>GSRSMA</quote>, means the Gulf States Red Snapper Management Authority established under section 502(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H698FCDAFCFCF4746B4F1A1D6E898FFBF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Red snapper fishery management plan</header><text>The term <quote>red snapper fishery management plan</quote> means a plan created by one or more Gulf coastal States to manage Gulf of Mexico red snapper in the coastal waters adjacent to such State or States, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H737AC2A7F6AD4E4CB131B1F995B87DA7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reef Fish Federal fishery management plan</header><text>The term <quote>Reef Fish Federal fishery management plan</quote> means the Fishery Management Plan for the Reef Fish Resources of the Gulf of Mexico, as amended, prepared by the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council pursuant to title III and implemented under part 622 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or similar successor regulation).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE3BE2660BB447DF96CCADA52365FDDC"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State territorial waters</header><text>The term <quote>State territorial waters</quote>, with respect to a Gulf coastal State, means the waters adjacent to such State seaward to the line three marine leagues seaward from the baseline from which of the territorial sea of the United States is measured.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="H6EA1EF3F67C846A081A78BAA3CB425F4"><enum>502.</enum><header>Management of Gulf of Mexico red snapper</header>
							<subsection id="HC6D5433EF4C344EABD047F8221D5D97A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gulf States Red Snapper Management Authority</header>
 <paragraph id="H6E9730355F17497F95F0CB0602FE83F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to establish</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this title, the Secretary shall establish a Gulf States Red Snapper Management Authority that consists of the principal fisheries manager of each of the Gulf coastal States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDF0097C4B444248855855A948CA6180"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the GSRSMA are as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H79106A179ECB49309A0D4022FC62157B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To review and approve red snapper fishery management plans, as set out in the Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F513E37E2DB412F9914F1B61BD11E15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To provide standards for each Gulf coastal State to use in developing fishery management measures to sustainably manage Gulf of Mexico red snapper in the coastal waters adjacent to such State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BAE072D9B784CFFA89EADC660571938"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To the maximum extent practicable, make scientific data, stock assessments and other scientific information upon which fishery management plans are based available to the public for inspection prior to meetings described in paragraph (c)(2).</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4A8775492AA408583E3FD273616EA7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for plans</header>
 <paragraph id="HCA054F490B6A4D11B3B859024D20EC50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline for submission of plans</header><text>The GSRSMA shall establish a deadline for each Gulf coastal State to submit to the GSRSMA a red snapper fishery management plan for such State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C2981195E0E49B8BC5EA100EA4DFC38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consistency with Federal fishery management plans</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Gulf Coastal States fishery management plans shall be consistent with the requirements in section 303(a) of the Fishery Conservation and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1853">16 U.S.C. 1853(a)</external-xref>).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E24A23703D74754839E0D9FD96C2661"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review and approval of plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H3FAEBDE0D9184F1DAE38E66FC3486471"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this title and not more than 60 days after one or more Gulf coastal States submits a red snapper fishery management plan and annually thereafter, the GSRSMA shall review and approve by majority vote the red snapper fishery management plan if such plan meets the requirements of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF6461FDBB2B4A4A987A6FF75F972D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text>Prior to approving a red snapper fishery management plan submitted by one or more Gulf coastal States, the GSRSMA shall provide an adequate opportunity for public participation, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA76B4C4B50BF433CACAC0D7FAA845F92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least 1 public hearing held in each respective Gulf coastal State; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC34123397A084BA8BC5B3D83FA205D57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>procedures for submitting written comments to GSRSMA on the fishery management plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD96D3E2E1B64058AD7F0F13700202CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Plan requirements</header><text>A red snapper fishery management plan submitted by one or more Gulf coastal States shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H49174BE8FC964C91BBE935CD4083F2D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contain standards and procedures for the long-term sustainability of Gulf of Mexico red snapper based on the best available science;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A6EE83EF3EA4D439ECF2B8884734A33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comply with the standards described in subsection (a)(2)(B); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F6E125808724882A934447BA7883B28"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determine quotas for the red snapper fishery in the coastal waters adjacent to such Gulf coastal State or States, respectively, based on stock assessments, and—</text>
 <clause id="H4E834F24CAD44B509C316B07EC92B60F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any recommendation by the GSRSMA to reduce quota apportioned to the commercial sector by more than 10 percent shall be reviewed and approved by the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA919849F649B4A839D97DE3D42B1A2F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during the 3-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this title and consistent with subsection (d), the GSRSMA shall not determine a quota apportioned to the commercial sector; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3D9503706BA24F9EA674344550514F71"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>nothing in this Act shall be construed to change the individual quota shares currently in place in the commercial sector of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85B2B9E9A8324F359A36D303F17905E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Review and approval</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date the GSRSMA receives a red snapper fishery management plan from one or more Gulf coastal State or States, the GSRSMA shall review and approve such plan if such plan satisfies the requirements of subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCD92D5038768419CAF5D763F67513656"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continued management by the Secretary</header><text>During the 3-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this title, the Secretary, in coordination with the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council, shall continue to manage the commercial sector of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H7EBB2BFD2E484F0EBE9A4DFCFAFAE831"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H850D18181E3F4D7CA8E5F2C68F1FC427"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports by Gulf coastal States</header><text>Each Gulf coastal State shall submit to the GSRSMA an annual report on the status of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery in coastal waters adjacent to such State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4CF16677AAD48C885E57FBECFC3CDBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report by the GSRSMA</header><text>Not less often than once every 5 years, the GSRSMA shall use the information submitted in the annual reports required by paragraph (1) to prepare and submit to the Secretary a report on the status of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35B05E8CA5154E56ACBFDA08F1357A3B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report by national oceanic and atmospheric administration</header><text>The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall submit to Congress an annual report on the implementation of this title.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1B73E4BF1C0040FC821B72C879468CA1"><enum>503.</enum><header>State implementation of the red snapper fishery management plans</header>
							<subsection id="HA5BCC4D76274454682C2DF4B6E033349"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allocation of management to the Gulf States</header>
 <paragraph id="H2B52CA883CC94D12B9F9267FF86E1D1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification of approved plans</header><text>The GSRSMA shall certify to the Secretary that a red snapper fishery management plan is approved under section 502 for each of the Gulf coastal States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB03C008D359841049C603C01DED0680F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer of management</header><text>Upon receipt of the certification described in paragraph (1) and subject to section 502(d), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9E08555482804FB795E073585129DE35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish a notice in the Federal Register revoking the regulations and portions of the Reef Fish Federal fishery management plan that are in conflict with any red snapper fishery management plan approved by the GSRSMA; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42CFFBF02CCF4872AEC1335C910A0C4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transfer management of Gulf of Mexico red snapper to the GSRSMA.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H783FBB59A2FE4057B9FE6C149DAF5B3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header> <paragraph id="H0D64A7C42B6D481F98AB3BAACFE111CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon the transfer of management described in subsection (a)(2)(B) and subject to section 502(d), each Gulf coastal State shall implement and enforce the red snapper fishery management plans approved under section 502 for the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery in the coastal waters adjacent to each Gulf coastal State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CFD59B1EA1A4456A1D373D9A0BCC042"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to transfer management</header><text>If the certification described in subsection (a)(1) is not made the transfer of management described in subsection (a)(2)(B) may not be accomplished and the Secretary shall remain responsible for management of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0B8C0A5449FE4E89AE536EF709D82B48"><enum>504.</enum><header>Oversight of Gulf of Mexico red snapper management</header>
 <subsection id="H3B59335F47A34AC186297574C265C917"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation and enforcement of fishery management plans</header><text>Not later than December 1 of the year following the transfer of management described in section 503(a)(2), and at any other time the GSRSMA considers appropriate after that date, the GSRSMA shall determine if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3F5762DCAE554190BA44552CD31568B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each Gulf coastal State has fully adopted and implemented the red snapper fishery management plan approved under section 502 for such State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H290D0449E64F4286887B4F3D5B9E96D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each such plan continues to be in compliance with the standards for sustainability provided by the GSRSMA pursuant to section 502(a)(2); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34ACDA44869744EF96191CAA214B8211"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the enforcement of the plan by each Gulf coastal State is satisfactory to maintain the long-term sustainability and abundance of Gulf of Mexico red snapper.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D259267CE094B07A6C9189E2F9A94BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Overfishing and rebuilding plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H2A87025C858C4E1B9977535073D03070"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>If the Gulf of Mexico red snapper in the coastal waters adjacent to a Gulf coastal State is experiencing overfishing or is subject to a rebuilding plan, such Gulf coastal State shall submit a certification to the GSRSMA showing that such State—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD21DC2E791D2495CB8A0B097EA1F8A5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has implemented the necessary measures to end overfishing or rebuild the fishery; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39DD1F4EF973477BB56C408F4482F1C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in consultation with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, has implemented a program to provide for data collection adequate to monitor the harvest of Gulf of Mexico red snapper by such State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE894AC59F6534202B68C4F6C7059C543"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification to Secretary</header><text>If, after such time as determined by the GSRSMA, a Gulf coastal State that submitted a certification under paragraph (1) has not implemented the measures and requirements described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such paragraph, the GSRSMA shall vote on whether to notify the Secretary of a recommendation of closure of the red snapper fishery in the waters adjacent to the State territorial waters of the Gulf coastal State.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF240B27611944EB79F3BF9C4C9C0AB5F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Closure of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery</header>
 <paragraph id="H04E5FEDEADEC4AF4A8C26784C813E676"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conditions for closure</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the receipt of a notice under subsection (b)(2) for a Gulf coastal State, the Secretary may declare a closure of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery within the waters adjacent to the State territorial waters of the Gulf coastal State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00E1B747BE6E45078F391E7DFFA16539"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>Prior to making a declaration under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall consider the comments of such Gulf coastal State and the GSRSMA.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D84034A430443F5A6D241746825A695"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Actions prohibited during closure</header><text>During a closure of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery under paragraph (1), it is unlawful for any person—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBBDD73DDF6774057A5EB76C533D7906A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to engage in fishing for Gulf of Mexico red snapper within the waters adjacent to the State territorial waters of the Gulf coastal State covered by the closure;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7309B006A33E40F6A308AB5C4DAD2046"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to land, or attempt to land, the Gulf of Mexico red snapper in the area of the closure; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C13BCFE068D4261B604C8C38C52256B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to fail to return to the water any Gulf of Mexico red snapper caught in the area of the closure that are incidental to commercial harvest or in the recreational fisheries.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD1F8ECBE4D247158315F94B13A652B3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to allow the Secretary to close the red snapper fishery in the State territorial waters of a Gulf coastal State.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF1359C1A74D84BAEAB60196C1DB669F8"><enum>505.</enum><header>Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H692D2B8596614FC0AF7FE0873240A4E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding to the Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission</header><text>The Secretary shall provide all Federal funding to the Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission for all necessary stock assessments, research, and management for the red snapper fishery.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2A3A15C387B548BD882087AA3B9C9F52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding to the Gulf coastal states</header><text>The Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission shall be responsible for administering the Federal funds referred to in paragraph (1) to each of the Gulf coastal States for proper management of the red snapper fishery.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCA04CDAFD6F1425AA1C83BE87F641091"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No additional appropriations authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to increase the amount of Federal funds authorized to be appropriated for Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery management.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HF56FA1FFD20E4238A21B505E318D50B1"><enum>506.</enum><header>No effect on management of shrimp fisheries in Federal waters</header>
 <subsection id="H9F27D42398FB42DEB24E9C1FAE5B50D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bycatch reduction devices</header><text>Nothing in this title may be construed to effect any requirement related to the use of Gulf of Mexico red snapper bycatch reduction devices in the course of shrimp trawl fishing activity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1999CC6CFD514D2996FDB78EBAF51D76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bycatch of red snapper</header><text>Nothing in this title shall be construed to apply to or affect in any manner the Federal management of commercial shrimp fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico, including any incidental catch of red snapper</text></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H37A4C7905F53481F8CE653642CCB1A2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H1ED6F06A8AC642DDAEF49008356E36AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>Section 401(g)(3)(C) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1881">16 U.S.C. 1881(g)(3)(G)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end of clause (iv), by striking the period at the end of clause (v) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H04DA36CBC1E745A2858ED4DFDDDCD392" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H36131FC1E21948F18551DE00C7B90C0E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>in the case of each fishery in the Gulf of Mexico, taking into consideration all data collection activities related to fishery effort that are undertaken by the marine resources division of each relevant State of the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAE248CBFFB64BA98C374E68C12F8F1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gulf State territorial waters</header><text>Section 306(b) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1856">16 U.S.C. 1856(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H6ACB7C0D5667452C92A3F7C99D4585FD" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HF5F2591A82864F81A35A23D8D30CE0A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 3(11) and subsection (a) of this section, for purposes of managing fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico, the seaward boundary of a coastal State in the Gulf of Mexico is a line three marine leagues seaward from the baseline from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B1025D5F7C4469791EA408B9E6E2084"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in the first section of such Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6377C2A858744ECB41246531AFA7E62" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HC882EE058E7E4897A5A2C879B01E04A8" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H260CBCBB79254545BC358A2D4F6B7200" level="title">Title V—Transfer to States of Management of Red Snapper Fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HBE913252F7104CDDB73A5375CAC5E716" level="section">Sec. 501. Definitions.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H6EA1EF3F67C846A081A78BAA3CB425F4" level="section">Sec. 502. Management of Gulf of Mexico red snapper.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H1B73E4BF1C0040FC821B72C879468CA1" level="section">Sec. 503. State implementation of the red snapper fishery management plans.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="H0B8C0A5449FE4E89AE536EF709D82B48" level="section">Sec. 504. Oversight of Gulf of Mexico red snapper management.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HF1359C1A74D84BAEAB60196C1DB669F8" level="section">Sec. 505. Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="HF56FA1FFD20E4238A21B505E318D50B1" level="section">Sec. 506. No effect on management of shrimp fisheries in Federal waters.</toc-entry>
					</toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


