<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEA90981C89B8464B8A6019DF9A5C2AA0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2009 IH: Pascua Yaqui Tribe Land Conveyance Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2009</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150423">April 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the conveyance of certain land inholdings owned by the United States to the Tucson
			 Unified School District and to the Pascua Yaqui Tribe of Arizona.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3C661724674C49A68790A8FF7EFBC457" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0CABAACE1051485696B65BA1C9DF8572" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pascua Yaqui Tribe Land Conveyance Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H75D70E0CD0D54ED8826C8AD2362EEE27"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act, the following definitions apply:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE65A1C0BDD504B62BCA338556DEEF638"><enum>(1)</enum><header>District</header><text>The term <term>District</term> means the Tucson Unified School District No. 1, a school district recognized as such under the laws of the State of Arizona.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF091F5242FBE48DA819FA3B03D76BA33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map titled <quote>PYT Land Department/2015/BLM Congressional Bill</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA01F67CC2473436195528CDA163EC950"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recreation and Public Purposes Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Recreation and Public Purposes Act</term> means the Act of June 14, 1926 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/869">43 U.S.C. 869 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA491E5124B04AFBAA65B4A605E07FAE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9004007BF02742378F8BE0BC6940DC17"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Pascua Yaqui Tribe of Arizona, a federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H711C4CC7B9CE48B9BD99088FA017014F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Lands to be conveyed or held in trust</header>
 <subsection id="H3BB9C475F08B4489AD5C8981143E482F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Parcel A</header><text>In the event that the District conveys all of its existing right, title, and interest in and to the approximately 39.65 acres of land depicted on the Map as Parcel A, to which the United States holds a reversionary interest under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act, to the United States, Parcel A shall be accepted by the United States and held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Tribe as part of the Pascua Yaqui Tribal Reservation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H37F013D677FB4085ADFA6F40140706BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Parcel B</header><text>Subject to subsection (a) and valid and existing rights, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the approximately 13.24 acres of Federal lands generally depicted on the Map as Parcel B shall be conveyed to the District by patent without reservation of rights by the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3AA19C7C3C754C6BAE6BA53EA20E3359"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Parcel C</header><text>Subject to valid and existing rights, the United States hereby waives and gives up, all reversionary interest otherwise retained under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act in and to the approximately 27.50 acres of the land generally depicted on the Map as Parcel C and said lands shall thereafter be deemed held by the District free and clear of any claims of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H76617166BE764F7FAC2935B1C66DDDEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a) and (b) shall take effect on the day after the District conveys all right, title, and interest of the District in and to the approximately 39.65 acres of land depicted on the Map as Parcel A to the United States.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H26AD4583B88B47B0BCCBFC5575D0D4F2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Gaming prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Tribe may not conduct gaming activities on lands taken into trust pursuant to this Act, either as a matter of claimed inherent authority, under the authority of any Federal law, including the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>), or under regulations promulgated by the Secretary or the National Indian Gaming Commission.</text>
		</section><section id="H68461AF0BF9241788AD11C10F41E8297"><enum>5.</enum><header>Water rights</header>
 <subsection id="HC266A443C40B43C481D3328F3DC6FD21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be no Federal reserved right to surface water or groundwater for any land taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Tribe under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB6376D8220B3459A91BB1C73BF192F66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State water rights</header><text>The Tribe retains any right or claim to water under State law for any land taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Tribe under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEE9994596D42496FB216B4BCFC44BB21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Forfeiture or abandonment</header><text>Any water rights that are appurtenant to land taken into trust by the United States for the benefit of the Tribe under this Act may not be forfeited or abandoned.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9A6C647AAD224407BFE1529A90F8787B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects or modifies any right of the Tribe or any obligation of the United States under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/375">Public Law 95–375</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1300f">25 U.S.C. 1300f et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


