<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H03DC9769A8334C3BA4A1B92125552DB1" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1206 IH: No Hires for the Delinquent IRS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1206</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150302">March 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit the hiring of additional Internal Revenue Service employees until the Secretary of the Treasury certifies that no employee of the Internal Revenue Service has a seriously delinquent tax debt.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HBAD43717AC7248F5A41E8196E11CD28B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF2BF8CE74C4C4CDC8B7C163827D29A52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Hires for the Delinquent IRS Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H35B4D74B75D944138E7820AD160D8D03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on IRS hiring of new employees until certification that no IRS employee has a seriously delinquent tax debt</header> <subsection id="H2AAD7B27C45045478C65A032858DDF73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No officer or employee of the United States may extend an offer of employment in the Internal Revenue Service to any individual until after the date on which the Secretary of the Treasury publicly issues a written certification that the Internal Revenue Service does not employ any individual who has a seriously delinquent tax debt.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1BBFB4961A74349A80E0169B432A700"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Seriously delinquent tax debt</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>seriously delinquent tax debt</quote> means an outstanding debt under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for which a notice of lien has been filed in public records pursuant to section 6323 of such Code, except that such term does not include—</text> <paragraph id="HE50B0732135247FD9493D676FCCFB162"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a debt that is being paid in a timely manner pursuant to an agreement under section 6159 or section 7122 of such Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3A10307417F450EA5C92C479A7637D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a debt with respect to which a collection due process hearing under section 6330 of such Code, or relief under subsection (a), (b), or (f) of section 6015 of such Code, is requested or pending;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H036B48D4B3D341268B6A098F4EA1E571"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a debt with respect to which a levy has been issued under section 6331 of such Code (or a debt with respect to which the applicant for employment agrees to be subject to a levy issued under such section); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CCD453AFB4C4DC39F53B136D2F3F1C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a debt with respect to which relief under section 6343(a)(1)(D) of such Code is granted.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

