<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6D5DE7E1F19644C1B0574077CEC7078B" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3229 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the non-application of Medicare competitive acquisition rates to complex rehabilitative wheelchairs and accessories.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3229</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150727">July 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the non-application of Medicare
			 competitive acquisition rates to complex rehabilitative wheelchairs and
			 accessories.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0D67D8093149432EBC28118621A8AF02" style="OLC">
		<section id="H303BA66FB7864222A36034688F879660" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Clarifying non-application of Medicare competitive acquisition rates to complex rehabilitative
 wheelchairs and accessories</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(a)(1)(F) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(a)(1)(F)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H773EF0558EBF435A9EA7B138E25EB01B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking at the end <quote>and</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9154950225084FF882650E8D90508CB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking at the end the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H04EB24112020452EBC1A88D546BA10CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3852515BC50D4E08A9822D162D1818DA" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HBEE30ECE897E4A58988C529CA0AE3EEF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of covered items furnished on or after January 1, 2016, the Secretary shall not apply this subparagraph or any other provision of this title to use information from the competitive acquisition program to determine payment amounts for items excluded from such competitive acquisition program, including all complex rehabilitative manual and power wheelchairs classified by the Secretary as of January 1, 2015, and, without limitation, any wheelchair accessory, cushion, or back when furnished in connection with a complex rehabilitative manual or power wheelchair.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


