<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1A7BD1FA0FAC4B669221B2F56A36A3A7" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2203 IH: To remove the Kosovo Liberation Army from treatment as a terrorist organization, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2203</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150501">May 1, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To remove the Kosovo Liberation Army from treatment as a terrorist organization, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H4129AEFDB35D486A8D2CD65662D85734" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H60BFE77628284BB1BAF070782798A618" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Treatment of the Kosovo Liberation Army under the Immigration and Nationality Act</header> 
<subsection id="H4E8F17BFA057409BAB2DB5581A121603"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Removal of the Kosovo Liberation Army From treatment as a terrorist organization</header> 
<paragraph id="H6FA32F155808426EAB066603F63A3CE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Kosovo Liberation Army shall not be considered to be a terrorist organization (as such term is defined in section 212(a)(3)(B)(vi)(III) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(vi)(III)</external-xref>)) for purposes of inadmissibility under section 212(a)(3)(B) of such Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA398CE531EF84C67A8EA94A804EABA1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, after consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General, or the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, may suspend the application of paragraph (1) in such Secretary’s sole and unreviewable discretion.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA8C201AACA1C430A88FE2B801597B4B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relief regarding admissibility of nonimmigrant aliens associated with the Kosovo Liberation Army</header> 
<paragraph id="H8EE34FAD628B40E4BC668DF13223015D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), section 212(a)(3)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>) shall not apply to an alien in connection with the alien’s activities undertaken in association with the Kosovo Liberation Army—</text> <subparagraph id="H3917150F6EE4427A828DCE0E9B6375C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case in which the alien is applying for a nonimmigrant visa, unless the consular officer—</text> 
<clause id="HE62DE0891B5848F6A6966733069CB880"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knows, or has reasonable grounds to believe, that the alien poses a threat to the safety and security of the United States; or</text></clause> <clause id="HBB826DC2033D4F55B8DFC08CB65ED409"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise believes, in the discretion of the consular officer and based on the totality of the circumstances, that the visa should not be issued; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85494B6A8A554ABCB2F06AF72D81ABF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a case in which the alien presents himself or herself for inspection and admission as a nonimmigrant to an immigration officer at a port of entry or is applying in the United States for nonimmigrant status, unless the Secretary of Homeland Security—</text> <clause id="HC62F897E521C45B087248EB4911BD9F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>knows, or has reasonable grounds to believe, that the alien poses a threat to the safety and security of the United States; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H47C86A1152644199AA4B61F4A6F53E31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise believes, in the discretion of the Secretary and based on the totality of the circumstances, that the alien should not be admitted to the United States or granted nonimmigrant status.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H24F9FA70A2BE4EA7B32F5D38C0021996"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary of State, after consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General, or the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, may suspend the application of paragraph (1) on a case-by-case basis in such Secretary’s sole and unreviewable discretion.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H343E7DB33E8D433A8A2E0A67EE081B2E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation requirement</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall implement this subsection in consultation with the Attorney General.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8005A98429D741418BD8AC3DC675D494"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to alter an alien’s burden of demonstrating admissibility under the immigration laws of the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

