<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H191EBADE49664401B788F67385C90608" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1864 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to designate a single senior official of the Department of Defense to procure wideband satellite communications necessary to meet the requirements of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1864</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Defense to designate a single senior official of the Department of
			 Defense to procure wideband satellite communications necessary to meet the
			 requirements of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBB5D167198844F43925082424899CBFE" style="OLC">
		<section id="HF6D69EEC38DA4189BF0A926895EEF4C7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Procurement of wideband satellite communications</header>
 <subsection id="H43B3F32111174E489335CE2FE1E3EB35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acquisition agent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by subsection (b)(1), not later than September 30, 2016, the Secretary of Defense shall designate a single senior official of the Department of Defense to procure wideband satellite communications necessary to meet the requirements of the Department of Defense for such communications, including with respect to military and commercial satellite communications.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3A35941531024C88AB9C70861225D292"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header>
 <paragraph id="HC1D35D6048B64CF286D40C3624E2006A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), an official described in paragraph (2) may carry out the procurement of commercial wideband satellite communications if the official determines that such procurement is required to meet an urgent need.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8A5AD6F750E489F9A62CC3F9BE693AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Official described</header><text>An official described in this paragraph is any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H76768199713F4B5CBFE84CBE5671457C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A Secretary of a military department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB822C0E292AC4516B448F6F7A59976AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C2C1027ECDB4006A92B962A44959BBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D61CD2A6A284A83BD21175CC3AE63B1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A commander of a combatant command.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50E31952F2B24EE1A7FCFB60F87C49D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than March 1, 2017, and each year thereafter through 2021, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code) a report on procurement carried out under paragraph (1) during the year prior to the submission of the report, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H780288D788874FBF88086B55F003C503"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a brief description of the urgent need fulfilled by each such procurement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8432D289B134E58BA6D60E714DE2660"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date and length of the contract of each such procurement; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5D85A6CFE3F4D48889403F5596530A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the value of each such contract.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H46D4A99123964FA0A42E57D81D14B29A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan for the Secretary to meet the requirements of the Department of Defense for satellite communications, including with respect to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H76C39719BF3E4520AC00D5004C87CBC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the roles and responsibilities of officials of the Department; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H22F3E588C56147898768B9B0C6601333"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carrying out subsections (a) and (b).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


