<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H15E92FDAE803458F853FBEA1173D3787" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4240 IH: No Fly for Foreign Fighters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4240</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151211">December 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require an independent review of the operation and administration of the Terrorist Screening
			 Database (TSDB) maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and
			 subsets of the TSDB, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H04E93032CD9347F8B553F48E6D3C6A4E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6E19FAA32B87406B80BA2F81C23F2DC9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Fly for Foreign Fighters Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBCA1C65A420343718C95F751B871F6EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study on the Terrorist Screening Database</header> <subsection id="H8CF380D984B1499088289B61AF93CA17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and submit, to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, a report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6674749E202B4CD7B3E9DCD8F9FBC95F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether past weaknesses in the operation and administration of the Terrorist Screening Database (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>TSDB</quote>) and subsets of the TSDB have been addressed; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B274AB7859C40F6AFC070018C207626"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which existing vulnerabilities to the United States may be addressed or mitigated through additional changes to the TSDB and subsets of the TSDB, thereby enhancing America’s security and defenses.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD16D85ED88E54DA99CD88A5DE416A03D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study and report under subsection (a) shall include information on the extent to which—</text> <paragraph id="H4864F25D5C104FCBBC887D18626E9407"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information is being integrated into the TSDB from all relevant sources across the government in a timely manner;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94C007BDF3774A12A867678CD366A0CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agencies are able to comply with increased demands for information to improve the TSDB;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF839CEB611264A7C8916F13D2A71C9FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the TSDB, and relevant subsets of the TSDB, are accessible to agencies, authorities, and other entities, as appropriate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB662B1634E24F86A58049B81E35EFDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the TSDB is capable of enabling users to identify known or suspected terrorists in the most timely and comprehensive manner possible.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


