<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD85BA02822140F597EF9874DB141245" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3566 IH: To prohibit an alien who is not in a lawful immigration status in the United States from being eligible for postsecondary education benefits that are not available to all citizens and nationals of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3566</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150918">September 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit an alien who is not in a lawful immigration status in the United States from being
			 eligible for postsecondary education benefits that are not available to
			 all citizens and nationals of the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD2F3BC3BE3874266985330EEFB1C9673" style="OLC">
		<section id="H547235C89EA648AE91E5C3A179AA1FEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition of preferential treatment for illegal aliens</header>
 <subsection id="H1C50A98DC5CF4AE29B872B801EC5E288"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1623">8 U.S.C. 1623</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60EEE7F602794C69B87D5318E0B1B535" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD9A8419FD1EE47628E71DDFE103A66D9"><enum>505.</enum><header>Ineligibility for aliens not in lawful immigration status in the United States to receive
			 preferential postsecondary education benefits</header>
 <subsection id="H675E02EBE6224855A91664A7E685D1F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien who is not in a lawful immigration status in the United States shall not be eligible for any postsecondary education benefit unless every citizen and national of the United States is eligible to receive such a benefit (in no less an amount, duration, and scope).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H8717543FA6E247D6B5A6E71C066EA589"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement through civil action</header>
 <paragraph id="H78A4D58666904F108248C65A4AB08450"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any citizen or national of the United States who is enrolled at a postsecondary educational institution in the United States that is alleged to have violated subsection (a) may petition the district court of the United States in which such institution is located to enforce the restriction described in such subsection by commencing a civil action, on his or her own behalf, in such court against any State official that oversees such institution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED8DDBB8382244AEA366AD0E2C52B734"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>If the plaintiff in a civil action commenced under paragraph (1) proves by a preponderance of the evidence that the postsecondary educational institution in which the plaintiff was enrolled violated subsection (a), the court shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC9AFB939875C4F04998D44C9BC85F7B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide all appropriate relief to the plaintiff, including damages equal to the monetary value of any benefit provided to an alien who is not in a lawful immigration status in the United States that was denied to the plaintiff; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7FBBA095CFC4AEE94490E871F76D444"><enum>(B)</enum><text>award attorneys' fees and court costs to the plaintiff.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H36C8D91809E847F4A3F0C703B234D2A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(d) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (110 Stat. 3009–546) is amended by striking the item relating to section 505 and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H93949F45A7B0498AB91B0AF2545D8D4E" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="HD9A8419FD1EE47628E71DDFE103A66D9" level="section">Sec. 505. Ineligibility for aliens not in lawful immigration status in the United States to receive
			 preferential postsecondary education benefits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


