<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD2718D1CF7074C4A80DC754E4762B331" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4074 IH: To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to collect data regarding foreign travel, or repatriation, to the country of nationality or last habitual residence by an alien admitted to the United States as a refugee, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4074</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151118">November 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to collect data regarding foreign travel, or
			 repatriation, to the country of nationality or last habitual residence by
			 an alien admitted to the United States as a refugee, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0416238C31A44F6CBE2F82BCE93B1FB5" style="OLC">
		<section id="H02F7517D6DE241ADB8E62C19824E4805" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Data collection regarding refugee returns to country of nationality</header>
 <subsection id="HFCCB850DB46F4EBFBEBF9984E25BA093"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each alien admitted to the United States under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) as a refugee (as defined in section 101(a)(42) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(42)</external-xref>)), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall collect data regarding any instance in which the alien returns temporarily or permanently—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1453F407482C4F85AFF966181533DDDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the country of the alien’s nationality at the time of such admission; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FB395D04BB647A0B31EF79057A5E51C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an alien having no nationality at the time of such admission, the country in which the alien last habitually resided prior to such admission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD50C9468A1604DAF96377E07125E83EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security annually shall submit a report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate containing the data collected under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H04F9E834248D478F8EC09338DC2E207B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cessation of refugee admissions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security may not admit into the United States an alien under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) until such time as Congress passes a joint resolution giving the Secretary authority to resume admitting aliens under such section.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


