<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7E0360879CB4671AC53BE0404A35DC3" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1220 IH: Removing Barriers to Colorectal Cancer Screening Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1220</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150303">March 3, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to waive coinsurance under Medicare for colorectal cancer screening tests, regardless of whether therapeutic intervention is required during the screening.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H610EC4FB2B374163AEF3A7DF1757E8C1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H19B00B79E41844478128A35765A16CE8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Removing Barriers to Colorectal Cancer Screening Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H20DFEC84994A43FD82A760527BA6D428"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF0D5E2D759B74F54A8B5609805F32A1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Colorectal cancer is the second leading cause of cancer death among men and women combined in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8104A35C5BD4EFDAE42E7E3056525C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2015, more than 130,000 Americans will be diagnosed with colorectal cancer and approximately 50,000 Americans will die from it.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEAE15A8952E46A389E0D479BB024516"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 60 percent of colorectal cancer cases and 70 percent of deaths occur in those aged 65 and older.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07986EE8164140349C316515DFE9BEF9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Colorectal cancer screening colonoscopy allows for the detection and removal of polyps, or abnormal growths, that could become cancerous, as well as for the early detection of colorectal cancer when treatment can be most effective.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE127BA4977A4E5192BBAD6957555132"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Although colorectal cancer is largely preventable, one in three adults between the ages of 50 and 75 are not up to date with recommended colorectal cancer screening.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9665D3ACE7E04D019579C96805F36612"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Over 200 organizations have committed to eliminating colorectal cancer as a major public health problem and are working toward the shared goal of reaching 80 percent screened for colorectal cancer by 2018.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H982F9FC1CBDF4C43B2CE0E44C73AC3B5"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Colorectal cancer screening colonoscopy is a highly effective preventive service, and removing financial barriers can help to increase screening rates.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA8C9A93D7AE54508A108C0E1632EDB28"><enum>3.</enum><header>Waiving Medicare coinsurance for colorectal cancer screening tests</header> <subsection id="H81B3DE7A057F4B6BA1279138B3292E23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1833(a)(1)(Y) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)(Y)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including a colorectal cancer screening test (regardless of the code that is billed for the establishment of a diagnosis as a result of the test, or for the removal of tissue or other procedure that is furnished in connection with, as a result of, and in the same clinical encounter as the screening test),</quote> after <quote>section 1861(ddd)(3)</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4F99118E6CCB4E2D8981263181CF5C5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to items and services furnished after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

