<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB890B11C30CC4C768F8B1F980C218EE0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3224 IH: Gun Look-Alike Case Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3224</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150727">July 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To regulate the sale of cases and covers that resemble firearms, to amend the Consumer Product
			 Safety Improvement Act of 2008 with respect to the regulation of toy,
			 look-alike, and imitation firearms, and to provide penalties for a
			 violation of such regulations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA1ED3A93459F4F6AAD569DC97EAD3129" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2ADA8F00003445ACB5846290DC0C71D7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gun Look-Alike Case Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB6DACE450C8F4CB59DDD32F622BFCAB3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on toy, look-alike, and imitation firearms</header> <subsection id="HD94E14E7D93C4779BCED28BB26C991EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Consumer Product Safety Improvement Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1278a">15 U.S.C. 1278a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB795ABE527BB42D99183A1C2F0AE784C" style="OLC">
					<section id="H3B86788131B344809EC2BC7D4F11D70B"><enum>109.</enum><header>Prohibition on toy, look-alike, and imitation firearms</header>
 <subsection id="H20E8E3B800DB4BC295CAD559D1308F5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acts prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture, enter into commerce, ship, transport, or receive any toy, look-alike, or imitation firearm unless such firearm contains, or has affixed to it, a marking approved by the Commission, as provided subsection (b).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H9E8FED0FF39D4741B7F3DFAAA72E4DAA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distinctive marking or device; exception; waiver; adjustments and changes</header>
 <paragraph id="H0952ED890F014F6190652BEC0932725B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) or (3), each toy, look-alike, or imitation firearm shall have as an integral part, permanently affixed, a blaze orange plug inserted in the barrel of such toy, look-alike, or imitation firearm. Such plug shall be recessed no more than 6 millimeters from the muzzle end of the barrel of such firearm.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A9D82C1003541E0B89D8404C4483757"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative markings</header><text>The Commission may issue regulations to provide for an alternate marking or device for any toy, look-alike, or imitation firearm not capable of being marked as provided in paragraph (1) and may waive the requirement of any such marking or device for any toy, look-alike, or imitation firearm that will only be used in the theatrical, movie, or television industry. The Commission is authorized to make adjustments and changes in the marking system provided for by this section, after consulting with interested persons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7B3139D3CEB48589D3D3293BE0F846D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability of former regulations</header><text>Unless and until the Commission issues regulations approving other markings or providing an alternate marking or device under this subsection, part 1150 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, shall apply as if promulgated by the Commission. Markings approved under section 1150.3 of such part shall be considered markings approved by the Commission for purposes of subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD42DCC4B791740ED807612531A9F1980"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Look-Alike Firearm Defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>look-alike firearm</term> means any imitation of any original firearm which was manufactured, designed, and produced since 1898, including and limited to toy guns, water guns, replica nonguns, air-soft guns firing nonmetallic projectiles, and cases and covers for products where such case or cover has the appearance, shape, or configuration of a firearm. Such term does not include any look-alike, nonfiring, collector replica of an antique firearm developed prior to 1898, or traditional B–B, paint-ball, or pellet-firing air guns that expel a projectile through the force of air pressure.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB5B3A815730B40ED9644A4C552EA40BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of Violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as a violation of section 19(a)(1) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2068">15 U.S.C. 2068(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD84225D88A534FAB98C002B6BE0C1FAE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment as Consumer Product Safety Standards; Effect on State Laws</header><text>Subsections (a) and (b) shall be considered consumer product safety standards under the Consumer Product Safety Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3830BD9292B14CCC915131787C4F26FC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preemption of State or local laws or ordinances; exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this section shall supersede any provision of State or local laws or ordinances which provide for markings or identification inconsistent with provisions of this section provided that no State shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB4BBF9E70C3A40269BA3507A4D4C39AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibit the sale or manufacture of any look-alike, nonfiring, collector replica of an antique firearm developed prior to 1898; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF39EE0F29DE403BAACCF2853C8EE206"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit the sale (other than prohibiting the sale to minors) of traditional B–B, paint ball, or pellet-firing air guns that expel a projectile through the force of air pressure.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAA7E75B7731B46F78182D361B9863A30"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Federal Energy Management Improvement Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/5001">15 U.S.C. 5001</external-xref>) is repealed.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

