<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7BFC9FA3B59C46C4A693089807E6CE79" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 906 IH: To modify the efficiency standards for grid-enabled water heaters.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 906</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150211">February 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000413">Mr. Whitfield</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To modify the efficiency standards for grid-enabled water heaters.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF1EFC757B754428B8D05B407FC2FAB9B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H009526A96D474B5790387D5651880839" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Grid-enabled water heaters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6291">42 U.S.C. 6291 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA598BE34BE4F4DE3A4A707742CB1035F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 325(e) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(e)</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF093D765BB63485DA669E7C4E6EBC219" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HAA66708C315B49218E94AD190F08478C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Additional standards for grid-enabled water heaters</header>
 <subparagraph id="H515D0CAF4BA849AC8272730FEA6B5B1E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H297D499F37DE4049B23E7A0B193F7C65"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Activation lock</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>activation lock</term> means a control mechanism (either a physical device directly on the water heater or a control system integrated into the water heater) that is locked by default and contains a physical, software, or digital communication that must be activated with an activation key to enable the product to operate at its designed specifications and capabilities and without which activation the product will provide not greater than 50 percent of the rated first hour delivery of hot water certified by the manufacturer.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H39CAD6540F284E5193C78375039AFBD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Grid-enabled water heater</header><text>The term <term>grid-enabled water heater</term> means an electric resistance water heater that—</text> <subclause id="H0193AD8BEE85425381E51702F2A6F1F8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has a rated storage tank volume of more than 75 gallons;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9B2DE6CF1F384571B83F59F0526F3EE3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is manufactured on or after April 16, 2016;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H25134497E30742BEADF9897AED9FC279"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has—</text>
 <item id="H67925A69593B4C5C868A74533F3BE652"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an energy factor of not less than 1.061 minus the product obtained by multiplying—</text> <subitem id="HDF72C0FD597347DE98A57F01D65004BD"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the rated storage volume of the tank, expressed in gallons; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H6E2D11219F7F4D6598C4B646AC2F08DA"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>0.00168; or</text> </subitem></item><item id="HC76478337A3640C89A662CD2F320B0F9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an equivalent alternative standard prescribed by the Secretary and developed pursuant to paragraph (5)(E);</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H32C70F3CC6374DE0A14C4D5FFEB5EC13"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>is equipped at the point of manufacture with an activation lock; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA1477B6A41C74846BB779496F37F500F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>bears a permanent label applied by the manufacturer that—</text>
 <item id="H66C4DB8D7A41467ABD01D29E75A7FA70"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is made of material not adversely affected by water;</text> </item><item id="HAA95FCAA652742B793857665A7D2F6FE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is attached by means of non-water-soluble adhesive; and</text>
 </item><item id="H2D4D2ABD18FE47E4AB949190C10F760B"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>advises purchasers and end-users of the intended and appropriate use of the product with the following notice printed in 16.5 point Arial Narrow Bold font:</text><non-statutory-material><para><quote>IMPORTANT INFORMATION: This water heater is intended only for use as part of an electric thermal
			 storage or demand response program. It will not provide adequate hot water
			 unless enrolled in such a program and activated by your utility company or
			 another program operator. Confirm the availability of a program in your
			 local area before purchasing or installing this product.</quote>. </para></non-statutory-material>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC52571AEEE0042B685D9A3F32518BCA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The manufacturer or private labeler shall provide the activation key for a grid-enabled water heater only to a utility or other company that operates an electric thermal storage or demand response program that uses such a grid-enabled water heater.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6A08C02B6FF41FAAF31E38862000FE8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <clause id="H776560C7BD7847F0AE64A6DEC229E6F5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Manufacturers</header><text>The Secretary shall require each manufacturer of grid-enabled water heaters to report to the Secretary annually the quantity of grid-enabled water heaters that the manufacturer ships each year.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB7A29CE9DB404D9DB1989373F00B60DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Operators</header><text>The Secretary shall require utilities and other demand response and thermal storage program operators to report annually the quantity of grid-enabled water heaters activated for their programs using forms of the Energy Information Agency or using such other mechanism that the Secretary determines appropriate after an opportunity for notice and comment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H42EB12EB689E4D9997DE9176D0393518"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Confidentiality requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall treat shipment data reported by manufacturers as confidential business information.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A4386017DE7479BBFB2F809CA4DF4D2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Publication of information</header>
 <clause id="HF9ABE268F1744F298695B71021FDF98A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In 2017 and 2019, the Secretary shall publish an analysis of the data collected under subparagraph (C) to assess the extent to which shipped products are put into use in demand response and thermal storage programs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0448D6751B5348C89F28A630179FBDDE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prevention of product diversion</header><text>If the Secretary determines that sales of grid-enabled water heaters exceed by 15 percent or greater the quantity of such products activated for use in demand response and thermal storage programs annually, the Secretary shall, after opportunity for notice and comment, establish procedures to prevent product diversion for non-program purposes.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H689729871FF347C4877BE806CEC9AB44"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Compliance</header>
 <clause id="H042C6B81DE59480C94205505CDF43248"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraphs (A) through (D) shall remain in effect until the Secretary determines under this section that—</text>
 <subclause id="H332971E068F448F7AAEB1C5FED65C27A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>grid-enabled water heaters do not require a separate efficiency requirement; or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H633C39C08DE14071AB94AA1A584FD480"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sales of grid-enabled water heaters exceed by 15 percent or greater the quantity of such products activated for use in demand response and thermal storage programs annually and procedures to prevent product diversion for non-program purposes would not be adequate to prevent such product diversion.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H111189272BDC42B2828F5EBA1CFEEE62"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>If the Secretary exercises the authority described in clause (i) or amends the efficiency requirement for grid-enabled water heaters, that action will take effect on the date described in subsection (m)(4)(A)(ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HACDAEA2FA76C4B5498629196E8A9D09D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In carrying out this section with respect to electric water heaters, the Secretary shall consider the impact on thermal storage and demand response programs, including any impact on energy savings, electric bills, peak load reduction, electric reliability, integration of renewable resources, and the environment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7C1EADD8BA584FA1AB71D9E4D392BAEA"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary shall require that grid-enabled water heaters be equipped with communication capability to enable the grid-enabled water heaters to participate in ancillary services programs if the Secretary determines that the technology is available, practical, and cost-effective.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E1C85BC82E549D1ACC54169A02EB83D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 332(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6302">42 U.S.C. 6302(a)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1787103FF8FF405994C1FDB398500F7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD89B0CF231AF48F7B4FE8EFC543B42CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the first paragraph (6), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CE7BEA327C443CBADC225AB1D0D7C1E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating the second paragraph (6) as paragraph (7);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C5BA32483894166B52968032F8BE620"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (7) (as so redesignated), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2F30DD19E6C4AB6BB7865A9D799F59A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56A69C0E3FE643948A7E51D9AAC2A2E8" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H54E0E2913F814E97953DB8D1E6B85BEC"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any person to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H02C60D62DC144F76A1F83358D8A072E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>activate an activation lock for a grid-enabled water heater with knowledge that such water heater is not used as part of an electric thermal storage or demand response program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9571DA89AC3847CD8919EB5EAA40ADD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distribute an activation key for a grid-enabled water heater with knowledge that such activation key will be used to activate a grid-enabled water heater that is not used as part of an electric thermal storage or demand response program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7752C105DD3C475F9936D7094BC5AD09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise enable a grid-enabled water heater to operate at its designed specification and capabilities with knowledge that such water heater is not used as part of an electric thermal storage or demand response program; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA43E588CD1C448B9994D8765F24B39B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>knowingly remove or render illegible the label of a grid-enabled water heater described in section 325(e)(6)(A)(ii)(V).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3DBA497DF78B4BE59CFFF6CE815B89D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 333(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6303">42 U.S.C. 6303(a)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H794546A3EF784C65B3CA5CEA9CFB3C81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 332(a)(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (5), (6), (7), or (8) of section 332(a)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H958C2D5B52364ACCAB65140A6BB9F143"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>paragraph (1), (2), or (5) of section 332(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1), (2), (5), (6), (7), or (8) of section 332(a)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7AD8D65C46CA4E47B33A094AD156DFD8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 334 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6304">42 U.S.C. 6304</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C050E4F99044639BD3D4DA2D99F71F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 332(a)(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (5), (6), (7), or (8) of section 332(a)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDC003B0A24D64068B387CB1ED9063ECF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 332(a)(6)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 332(a)(7)</quote>.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


