<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81A1CE26786345608AC50E8083DE63B4" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2567 IH: To posthumously award the Congressional Gold Medal to each of Glen Doherty, Tyrone Woods, J. Christopher Stevens, and Sean Smith in recognition of their contributions to the Nation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2567</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001283">Mr. Bridenstine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000413">Mr. Whitfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001055">Mr. Heck of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To posthumously award the Congressional Gold Medal to each of Glen Doherty, Tyrone Woods, J. Christopher Stevens, and Sean Smith in recognition of their contributions to the Nation.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H44262408EA4E42558389E801DF8D38AE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H445CF33D392D45E69BFD57E6BABA1C23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H7535839863284921A28C628FCDF6547E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On September 11, 2012, the United States consulate, and its personnel in Benghazi, Libya, were attacked by militants.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF1771BE5A0F49B4A5B5B651E0E42639"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Four Americans were killed in the attack, including Ambassador J. Christopher Stevens, Sean Smith, Glen Doherty, and Tyrone Woods.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCCAA304D6644E74B7004FC49E3F0617"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Glen Doherty and Tyrone Woods were former Navy SEALs who served as security personnel in Libya. As the attack unfolded, they bravely attempted to defend American property and protect United States diplomatic personnel. In so doing, they selflessly sacrificed their own lives.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96BFF6755FAA468C9EEA4DF0A053D214"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Glen Doherty was a Navy SEAL for 12 years and served in Iraq and Afghanistan. He attained the rank of Petty Officer First Class and earned the Navy and Marine Corps Commendation Medal. After leaving the Navy, Glen Doherty worked with the Department of State to protect American diplomats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73BE9A2B046B4029B8C620E0B36CBAE1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Tyrone Woods served for 20 years as a Navy SEAL including tours in Iraq and Afghanistan. In Iraq he led multiple raids and reconnaissance missions and earned the Bronze Star. After retiring from the Navy as a Senior Chief Petty Officer, Tyrone Woods worked with the Department of State to protect American diplomats.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96DDE77C5BC14C198C84D189E8E8AC46"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">J. Christopher Stevens served for 21 years in the U.S. Foreign Service. He was serving as U.S. Ambassador to Libya and previously served twice in the country, as both Special Representative to the Libyan Transitional National Council and as the Deputy Chief of Mission. Earlier in his life, he also served as a Peace Corps volunteer teaching English in Morocco.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B0B89024ACA45E0A814FBD13C31CD83"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Sean Smith served for 6 years in the U.S. Air Force. He attained the rank of Staff Sergeant and was awarded the Air Force Commendation Medal. After leaving the Air Force, Sean Smith served for 10 years in the State Department on various assignments, which took him to places such as Baghdad, Brussels, Pretoria, and The Hague.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F20C669DC294E47BD6CFC544C08CFA9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As their careers attest, all four men served their country honorably.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H30EFB55CEF974EBCBCEC01DB6543F5D7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional Gold Medal</header> <subsection id="H1CA1E1580C88456C8DF457BBF7621A49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award Authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous award, on behalf of the Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration of Glen Doherty, Tyrone Woods, J. Christopher Stevens, and Sean Smith in recognition of their contributions to the Nation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H63BA5BD205EA4398BAD6ECF90E62BFB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and Striking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of the awards referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall strike the gold medals with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7CD67A8F7ECC44C28D6485EED6E1DB29"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medals struck under section 2, at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the medals, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses, and the cost of the gold medals.</text></section> 
<section id="H46E5C5861A2F4038BDD3477A1DAB0C88"><enum>4.</enum><header>National medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Medals struck pursuant to this Act are National medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></section> <section id="H8F569FB612ED4FE9935EF43619BCCBDF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations; proceeds of sale</header> <subsection id="H703FBE70271648559A802B34AFF2718D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund, such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the cost of the medals struck pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D8B0B820E8545AAA157277DD362870D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of Sale</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals under section 3 shall be deposited in the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

