<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E2129BAB9084198B8875D1EABD884DA" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 805 IH: Domain Openness Through Continued Oversight Matters Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 805</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150205">February 5, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000364">Mr. Shimkus</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000213">Mr. Barton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000363">Mr. Kline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit the National Telecommunications and Information Administration from relinquishing responsibility over the Internet domain name system until the Comptroller General of the United States submits to Congress a report on the role of the NTIA with respect to such system.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0E45F1EDB8CA41D2BD2F7404FAB7F231" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H74DC7D54156540808651BD493CF0BC23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Domain Openness Through Continued Oversight Matters Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DOTCOM Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9B9B9647BDB84DD79DC0E4CF66B17775"><enum>2.</enum><header>NTIA retention of DNS responsibilities pending GAO report</header> <subsection id="HD73998FEBB1645509A9C8CB5D76718AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Retention of responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Until the Comptroller General of the United States submits the report required by subsection (b), the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information may not relinquish or agree to any proposal relating to the relinquishment of the responsibility of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>NTIA</quote>) over Internet domain name system functions, including responsibility with respect to the authoritative root zone file, the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority functions, and related root zone management functions.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7E1D4B044EF0451DA3D87C2D01793D50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the NTIA receives a proposal relating to the relinquishment of the responsibility of the NTIA over Internet domain name system functions that was developed in a process convened by the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers at the request of the NTIA, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the role of the NTIA with respect to the Internet domain name system. Such report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HAB8CF866656040378FEEC8C45136A6B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a discussion and analysis of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4D92DCE95EB34BA28DB9B5EFDC24C8B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the advantages and disadvantages of relinquishment of the responsibility of the NTIA over Internet domain name system functions, including responsibility with respect to the authoritative root zone file, the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority functions, and related root zone management functions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H797360BE2B3246B8BDEB991B53BAEB5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any principles or criteria that the NTIA sets for proposals for such relinquishment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD72D1A8311254F9C91E89F1417B6053E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each proposal received by the NTIA for such relinquishment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A8ED079EA6747248E9C5BE4E388A043"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the processes used by the NTIA and any other Federal agencies for evaluating such proposals;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H816336D9B34E4B7BA0928D38FC9783D6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any national security concerns raised by such relinquishment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5B25D6940F54FA58BA66CA1440DA5F8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any concerns raised by such relinquishment with respect to the security of the Internet domain name system or the security of other information networks and systems; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38323CCC409F4136B4C66575B4F5F703"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a definition of the term <quote>multistakeholder model</quote>, as used by the NTIA with respect to Internet policymaking and governance, and definitions of any other terms necessary to understand the matters covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

