<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H60CB82B45C914AED80EB6313A39D99FC" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2306 IH: Obamacare Marriage Penalty Elimination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2306</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150513">May 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to eliminate the marriage penalty in, and reduce the eligibility limitation on, the tax credit for health insurance premiums.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA31B7B68E01E448E86136F906844AA7B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4758341A84804EDCB123A601A0DB023C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Obamacare Marriage Penalty Elimination Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HF7BF087AACBF4767A2C1A666ABCC746B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elimination of marriage penalty in health insurance premium tax credit</header> <subsection id="HDFBE6184E34842E18DF03AC1EEBE8C1D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF3E27C04F5654801B8943A67948B5B4A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H04EE25D1CF9F4B4087E3537D1FD71A6C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Elimination of marriage penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a joint return—</text> <subparagraph id="H1DF3FF72F96240D9A4C8387EF225C0E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Credit determined separately with respect to each spouse</header><text>The credit allowed under this section shall be sum of the two credits determined under this section separately with respect to each spouse (as provided under this subparagraph).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF935D5BED034DB3A7FE29F460EDDD9D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of income of spouses</header> 
<clause id="H5A22A0773BBE4DB492388ACA94038E0A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), each spouse shall take into account the income of such spouse for purposes of this section.</text></clause> <clause id="H1D878054102A453291EF71E703EB9AEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Income split not to result in ineligibility for credit for either spouse</header><text>If—</text> 
<subclause id="H1FCA95743714403C855902FBE64D8C46"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the poverty line with respect to a spouse (determined after application of this paragraph but without regard to this clause) exceeds the income taken into account by such spouse for purposes of this section (as so determined), and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H68C1F201A6B54AFD945094A4D863D577"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the income taken into account by the other spouse for purposes of this section (as so determined) exceeds the sum of the poverty line with respect to such other spouse (as so determined) plus the excess described in subclause (I), </text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">the excess described in subclause (I) shall be taken into account as income of the spouse referred to in subclause (I) and not as income of the spouse referred to in subclause (II).</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H401CD31D0F114727B94D897BDA591B9C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of dependents</header> 
<clause id="HF84556B9F8504399AD4FBF0230E3CC62"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), dependents of the taxpayer shall be allocated between the two spouses at the election of the taxpayer. For purposes of determining the family size involved and household income with respect to each spouse, only such spouse and the dependents allocated to such spouse under this subparagraph shall be taken into account</text></clause> <clause id="HD5E3EE15F49049159FA448282D493F76"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on taxpayer allocation</header><text>The number of dependents allocated to a spouse under clause (i) cannot exceed the number of dependents allocated to the other spouse by more than 1 dependent.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8FE4393E0E84468A6DABA0A3D90336A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of premiums</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that the amount of any monthly premium is determined separately with respect to either spouse or any dependent of the taxpayer, such premium shall be taken into account by such spouse or the spouse to which such dependent is allocated under subparagraph (C). In the case of any monthly premium which is not so separately determined, such premium may be allocated between the two spouses at the election of the taxpayer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H2E60EB6A49A2450BAF4E0EE83FDC8550"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6C488052B02A4732B46E1CD7735C7F19"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reduction in poverty line eligibility limitation for health insurance premium tax credit</header> 
<subsection id="H1E340A690A16469F8099557CECECDD3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</header> 
<paragraph id="HEE0A8588EDD14E1DAFC0443EFAE00C5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B(c)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>400 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>the applicable percentage</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5D37A4171DA4FC497CAD7A46E1EC3B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>Section 36B(c)(1) of such Code is amended by redesignating subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) as subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E), respectively, and by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE299857CD8944F07AD1279059A3E4A0B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H5F32B70B88B04A1CAA3F6A9575DA2B54"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>applicable percentage</quote> means such percentage as the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, determines will result in a combination of increased Federal revenues and reduced Federal outlays which is equal to the combination of reduced Federal revenues and increased Federal outlays as a result of the amendments made by section 2 of the <short-title>Obamacare Marriage Penalty Elimination Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52F8FC4856E84081966473E32DCD4F5E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subparagraph id="H06D8F18724B94DAA926520A6184AC018"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 36B(b)(3)(A)(i) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>and subsection (c)(1)(A)</quote> after <quote>Except as provided in clause (ii)</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE46A6B32BE9A47BA8EE47E48D81633ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 36B(f)(2)(B)(i) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>400 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>the applicable percentage (as defined in subsection (c)(1)(B))</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28613E84FF7C46D7B184DA096A08CBEA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A60F3B32D3848EDBFF63A460732E056"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act</header> 
<paragraph id="H3974FE1E6AE045C79884B3DEADD5CC81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1402(b)(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act is amended by striking <quote>400 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>the applicable percentage (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(c)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986)</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H716D24BEA8A3485FB302D89499C150DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subparagraph id="HFB0B2FB7E15C47C3A2C06D5D2C865DBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 1402(c)(1)(A) of such Act is amended by striking <quote>The reduction</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (b)(2), the reduction</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23D401D1A65B4B2D84FAB1DD5A59E521"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1402(c)(1)(B)(i) of such Act is amended by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (b)(2), the Secretary</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B16B78E58434E44814992AD3F1B8698"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to months beginning after December 31, 2015.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

