<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A249B4F36D84178A01E5EB90EA42C89" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3187 IH: PRIME Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3187</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act to exempt from inspection the slaughter of animals and the preparation of carcasses conducted at a custom slaughter facility, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2BAC1B8972034E88AB04C52317E6202C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H10D3337404D541F1A13CC09791BB978E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Processing Revival and Intrastate Meat Exemption Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>PRIME Act</quote>. </text></section> <section id="HE06719516CE942209E6DB58EDDCDB424"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption for slaughter and preparation occurring at custom slaughter facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 23 of the Federal Meat Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/623">21 U.S.C. 623</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2AFE09761BB341478DBF3C3717357306"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (b), (c), and (d) as paragraphs (c), (d), and (e), respectively; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEAF4F3245FA4D17B4160EC98FF32D61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (a) the following new paragraph: </text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="H69B0C72FBDEC4597B31FBDE5B503E038" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H63CE5BC886C746E383A2608FEA5E6CD8"><enum>(b)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H132022F32B384B9BAFEB6DBF888C9BA2" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The provisions of this title requiring inspection of the slaughter of animals and the preparation of the carcasses, parts thereof, meat and meat food products at establishments conducting such operations for commerce shall not apply to the slaughtering by any person of animals at a custom slaughter facility, and the preparation at such custom slaughter facility and transportation in commerce of the carcasses, parts thereof, meat and meat food products of such animals if—</text> <subparagraph id="H9ADE11032F594F3AA0BD5924A6C21F0A" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the slaughtering and preparation carried out at such custom slaughter facility is carried out in accordance with the law of the State in which the custom slaughter facility is located; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H20592B9BF2314DA0BB42FAC56B9298D6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the animals are so slaughtered and the carcasses, parts thereof, meat and meat food products of such animals are so prepared exclusively for distribution to—</text> <clause id="H0B40BB27481A48E6AC262709CE585B0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>household consumers within the State; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H97AD3D3F3A9942F584DA92D345730E6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>restaurants, hotels, boarding houses, grocery stores, or other establishments located in such State that—</text> <subclause id="HE5A358DFD0FF46F885D326F9B2ACE78C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are involved in the preparation of meals served directly to consumers; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBD06BE01C1A94FD3AE6E969AA0A5DF87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>offer meat and meat food products for sale directly to consumers in the State.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4779D9939F094B109E38AACB392DFF64" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (1), the term <quote>State</quote> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and each territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H122F362D218A4D58B7742B61C865F5EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (c) (as redesignated by paragraph (1)), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>paragraph (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (c)</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HAFE6488006224CAD86ED2D0E9390E7CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>No preemption of State law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by section 1 shall not be construed as preempting any State law that concerns the slaughter of animals or the preparation of carcasses, parts thereof, meat and meat food products at a custom slaughter facility, or the sale of meat or meat food products.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


