<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0C331C1418D34AA982782A3DF78A0AD9" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 595 IH: Amy and Vicky Child Pornography Victim Restitution Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 595</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150128">January 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000566">Mr. Gowdy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend section 2259 of title 18, United States Code, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H62E514B96D774863B07144E822FA9F58" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA01BD014FAAB42D4B26AA0E8C03E80A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Amy and Vicky Child Pornography Victim Restitution Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9C436A8BE42B4A1C8C5808E94A08DA99"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H485E89F04B5A494BBD4F892B246F52B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The demand for child pornography harms children because it drives production, which involves severe and often irreparable child sexual abuse and exploitation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6495F099E96B4E65B295E45686C16FDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The harms caused by child pornography are more extensive than the harms caused by child sex abuse alone because child pornography is a permanent record of the abuse of the depicted child, and the harm to the child is exacerbated by its circulation. Every viewing of child pornography is a repetition of the victim's original childhood sexual abuse.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D682ACC978A4A3EB9620015735E70EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Victims suffer continuing and grievous harm as a result of knowing that a large, indeterminate number of individuals have viewed and will in the future view images of their childhood sexual abuse. Harms of this sort are a major reason that child pornography is outlawed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69ADC47E7567401EAB119AD00F6CD5F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The unlawful collective conduct of every individual who reproduces, distributes, or possesses the images of a victim’s childhood sexual abuse plays a part in sustaining and aggravating the harms to that individual victim. Multiple actors independently commit intentional crimes that combine to produce an indivisible injury to a victim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B53CD3C805B48B48C0D51B61F88C224"><enum>(5)</enum><text>It is the intent of Congress that victims of child pornography be fully compensated for all the harms resulting from each and every perpetrator who contributes to their anguish.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H853A51CAF48B4D788AFE60A6EEA2B146"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Congress intends to adopt and hereby adopts an aggregate causation standard to address the unique crime of child pornography and the unique harms caused by child pornography.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61A60EA68EA44546AB69EE76452E0B7A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Victims should not be limited to receiving restitution from defendants only for losses caused by each defendant’s own offense of conviction. Courts must apply a less restrictive aggregate causation standard in child pornography cases, while also recognizing appropriate constitutional limits and protections for defendants.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H11B1ABA2CD354772911B6542C825BFED"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mandatory restitution</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2259 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE4900182DB3E4F9C8A3B3EEABAA57736"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A0F7C9FDC5E4F999DF8130BC8D7A9F7" style="USC">
					<paragraph id="HA491D12B087840048C0B8756D5F2E73A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC55D4160760C4ACBA5887903B79C92D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>full amount of the victim's losses</term> includes any costs incurred by the victim for—</text> <clause id="H525481D29BA142E79EA2EC5E02A4CA6E" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lifetime medical services relating to physical, psychiatric, or psychological care;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H462C1E9F6AB74850B0151BD842F1E42A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lifetime physical and occupational therapy or rehabilitation;</text> </clause><clause id="H11F99DAFCFF94C5E89A0C5D35D094367" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>necessary transportation, temporary housing, and child care expenses;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFC6C0A481DFE43F3AC1AC918AA632F1C" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>lifetime lost income; and</text> </clause><clause id="H9D4966F374B14467B6CD494021713A7F" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>attorneys’ fees, as well as other costs incurred.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA8D2B9A25CE40F4AE82EDF2151FC475" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>full amount of the victim's losses</term> also includes any other losses suffered by the victim, in addition to the costs listed in subparagraph (A), if those losses are a proximate result of the offense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA13B746367349F9BA9FE4C62A88DA39" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>full amount of the victim's losses</term> also includes any losses suffered by the victim from any sexual act or sexual conduct (as those terms are defined in section 2246) in preparation for or during the production of child pornography depicting the victim involved in the offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEDFAA6F50A544AEB04ED383D4F1B631"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2D628005ADA4DC89060FFAAB627F952"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2D66B6120BF4403873F3D8F7B688AD0" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H4BF11DFCC86642DDBC099D9B92D3017D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determining restitution</header>
 <paragraph id="H68E012FA5640493988155C34355B8390"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Harmed by one defendant</header><text>If the victim was harmed as a result of the commission of an offense under section 2251, 2251A, 2252, 2252A, or 2260 by 1 defendant, the court shall determine the full amount of the victim's losses caused by the defendant and enter an order of restitution for an amount that is not less than the full amount of the victim's losses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD889B9593F564F76A668DE41B2FF85D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Harmed by more than one defendant</header><text>If the victim was harmed as a result of offenses under section 2251, 2251A, 2252, 2252A, or 2260 by more than 1 person, regardless of whether the persons have been charged, prosecuted, or convicted in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction within the United States, the court shall determine the full amount of the victim’s losses caused by all such persons, or reasonably expected to be caused by such persons, and enter an order of restitution against the defendant in favor of the victim for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1D939C2AA54440AC957DFA2174E359B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the full amount of the victim's losses; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC10D3422110F4B7E86F76C68477E371D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an amount that is not more than the amount described in subparagraph (A) and not less than—</text>
 <clause id="H7244C40394D14E738FAF7FA2C4EA03AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$250,000 for any offense or offenses under section 2251(a), 2251(b), 2251(c), 2251A, 2252A(g), or 2260(a);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H53CE30A98ACE4CB8B7F3ABD09DF76382"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$150,000 for any offense or offenses under section 2251(d), 2252(a)(1), 2252(a)(2), 2252(a)(3), 2252A(a)(1), 2252A(a)(2), 2252A(a)(3), 2252A(a)(4), 2252A(a)(6), 2252A(a)(7), or 2260(b); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H57EF4F35BB4E49B988B71EA3082D7000"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>$25,000 for any offense or offenses under section 2252(a)(4) or 2252A(a)(5).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00C020C3878245E29068A56E2C490262"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maximum amount of restitution</header><text>No order of restitution issued under this section may exceed the full amount of the victim's losses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5E3B7AF4F2B414AA04BF8403F320201"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Joint and several liability</header><text>Each defendant against whom an order of restitution is issued under paragraph (2)(A) shall be jointly and severally liable to the victim with all other defendants against whom an order of restitution is issued under paragraph (2)(A) in favor of such victim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FE1FA148DD74F8BB824BBA20B1D11A8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Contribution</header><text>Each defendant who is ordered to pay restitution under paragraph (2)(A), and has made full payment to the victim equal to or exceeding the statutory minimum amount described in paragraph (2)(B), may recover contribution from any defendant who is also ordered to pay restitution under paragraph (2)(A). Such claims shall be brought in accordance with this section and the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. In resolving contribution claims, the court may allocate payments among liable parties using such equitable factors as the court determines are appropriate so long as no payments to victims are reduced or delayed. No action for contribution may be commenced more than 5 years after the date on which the defendant seeking contribution was ordered to pay restitution under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0B3C5CBE94B48049C7FF89807DCCF30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as redesignated, by striking <quote>a commission of a crime under this chapter,</quote> and inserting <quote>or by the commission of (i) an offense under this chapter or (ii) a series of offenses under this chapter committed by the defendant and other persons causing aggregated losses,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2010517C0AEF412684CB0F79BB79BD89"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H332EE38B8A644EFCB73C8E2956FA6594" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H4FD4C97F8AA64631AF7ED583D135F271"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Amy and Vicky Child Pornography Victim Restitution Improvement Act of 2015</short-title>, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the progress, if any, of the Department of Justice in obtaining restitution for victims of any offense under section 2251, 2251A, 2252, 2252A, or 2260.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


