<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H412A1C3097EB4BC1B133DF99722979EE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 521 IH: To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation located in Bethel, Alaska.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 521</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation located
			 in Bethel, Alaska.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H49B0A8A6BC394468B8AEE719A15EBD79" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9F9A4AE5C8E24C309DCEEDF179DC8DA5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Conveyance of property</header>
 <subsection id="H005497504B3242B6B8A4F94B5E52A4CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, but not later than 180 days after such date, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall convey to the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation located in Bethel, Alaska, all the right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property described in section 2 for use in connection with health and social services programs. The Secretary’s conveyance of title by warranty deed under this section shall, on its effective date, supersede and render of no future effect any quitclaim deed to the property described in section 2 executed by the Secretary and the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7AD340A0BB66471DAD42686E71794363"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The conveyance of the property under this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H8C39DD9AE8444F2B8A91E53B7FAED0FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be made by warranty deed;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD44C75EC65C84E23941771ADA1562D7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not require any consideration from the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation for the property;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0024007A436642A0998F1D6F37A12441"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall not impose any obligation, term, or condition on the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A193D03AF348459EC4825C5A9A8445"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall not allow for any reversionary interest of the United States in the property.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC93000095C27433BB558CE5226B5527D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Property described</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The property, including all land and appurtenances, described in this section is that property included in U.S. Survey No. 4000, Lot 2, township 8N, Range 71W, Seward Meridian, containing 22.98 acres.</text>
		</section><section id="HA1FAFA0EF1F145F4B4FDA6FA2E9CB78B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Environmental liability</header>
 <subsection id="HD4E892673D5A4B7CA291A45EF1EB9D3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation shall not be liable for any soil, surface water, groundwater, or other contamination resulting from the disposal, release, or presence of any environmental contamination, including any oil or petroleum products, or any hazardous substances, hazardous materials, hazardous waste, pollutants, toxic substances, solid waste, or any other environmental contamination or hazard as defined in any Federal or State of Alaska law, on any of the property described in section 2.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0315FE81293D4140B825663950DE9098"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Easement</header><text>The Secretary shall be accorded any easement or access to the property conveyed under this Act as may be reasonably necessary to satisfy any retained obligation or liability of the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBD4ED80B49FD44328C1A91DA5409EF2C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of hazardous substance activity and warranty</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary shall comply with section 120(h)(3) (A) and (B) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)(3)(A)</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


