<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3A0B6C068EA24134A51D87C4B60F0E71" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2148 IH: Ensuring Quality in the Unemployment Insurance Program (EQUIP) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2148</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title III of the Social Security Act to require a substance abuse risk assessment and targeted drug testing as a condition for the receipt of unemployment benefits, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H532BF31C09BC4252944B12F2BF9A369E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEC063567FCB044C182C476FF8306D7E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Quality in the Unemployment Insurance Program (EQUIP) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDCA432B3E66B452C8620DF544D6429F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Drug screening made a condition of benefit receipt</header> <subsection id="H5EA209E73FD446A69FAFB1F315C2B8B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 303(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/503">42 U.S.C. 503(l)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HEF015E55247841B6AA84C16150EC05BC" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HA5DA734807214A8395A4293E984F6E6D"><enum>(l)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H3ACDE36060A744D1A6C6B0E15E5DBED9" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the State law (as defined in section 205 of the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3304">26 U.S.C. 3304</external-xref> note)) of a State shall provide the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HE87351B733CB4FED9BAB64E387DB0BB8" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No regular compensation may be paid to an applicant for such compensation with respect to a benefit year unless, before the receipt of any such compensation—</text> 
<clause id="HE7E54D155AA94959948421A0C41F6AC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicant has completed a substance abuse risk assessment for such benefit year; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7E99DB9B5E7A4F7C984F67F837584C2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (B), if the State determines based on the results of such assessment that the applicant is a high-risk applicant, not later than 1 week after the results of the assessment are determined, the applicant tests negative for controlled substances.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE02635FF52347AC8666748979E1FCCA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a high-risk applicant tests positive for any controlled substance—</text> <clause id="H1FB21D133B4D4045B39A8C620EEFDE1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if such test result is the first positive test result for such applicant in the benefit year—</text> 
<subclause id="H9A4D08FAA5AB4CD8BF3EADCA67483307"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no regular compensation may be paid to such applicant for a period of 30 days beginning on the date that such test result is determined; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEC8360E52DE24633A673F3D28D1A1ECD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>no regular compensation may be paid to such applicant during the remainder of such benefit year unless the applicant tests negative for controlled substances at the end of such period;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1D3208EFFC9845FBA0425AEE28B7A225"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such test result is not the first positive test result for such applicant in the benefit year, no regular compensation may be paid to such applicant during the remainder of such benefit year.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DD0E3A781A74ABDAAD2EFF44523EF73" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A high-risk applicant receiving benefits with respect to a benefit year shall be subject to testing for controlled substances by the State at any time during the benefit year, with limited notice provided to the applicant of such testing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD542F1C46F2F486486B17EFBB014DCE2" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A high-risk applicant who is tested for controlled substances under—</text> <clause id="H09F8A4F0B28A42778E11C4C7B50473DC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subparagraph (A) or (C) shall be responsible for the cost of such test if the individual tests positive for any such substance; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD1B239A0529B45E4B1D4B84814D8A172" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraph (B)(i)(II) shall be responsible for the cost of such test.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02391ED703E84A658693758B8A43BCE5" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDF5F678ACB2A4C63B552C77641B95DFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>benefit year</quote> means the benefit year as defined in the applicable State law;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H421376D734C9482CBA9E45334037BD9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>controlled substance</quote>—</text> 
<clause id="HDD09FD736D5B4E229E594626E635FD41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a drug or other substance selected by the State to be included in drug testing under this subsection; and</text></clause> <clause id="H646392179BE34564AFE02B5886814F2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include any drug or other substance used by the applicant pursuant to a valid prescription or as otherwise authorized by law;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC0ADB97777CA4AA4BA97BA08E5FD9857"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <quote>high-risk applicant</quote>, with respect to a benefit year, means an individual who is determined by the State to have a high risk of substance abuse based on the results of a substance abuse risk assessment administered under paragraph (1)(A)(i); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDF39828756C475D9AD618A129AF6AF7" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <quote>substance abuse risk assessment</quote> means a screening instrument, approved by the Director of the National Institutes of Health, designed to determine whether an individual has a high risk of substance abuse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H22F30023B19E40B5A48F701154054EFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No merit staffing requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 303(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/503">42 U.S.C. 503(a)(1)</external-xref>) shall not be construed in such a manner as to apply the merit staffing requirements in section 900.603 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on October 1, 2011, to the implementation of section 303(l) of such Act (as amended by subsection (a)).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8BBB2552AE5F4D1EADE28344492915AB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding for substance abuse testing</header> <paragraph id="H62912B24B6D64E468FFBF39B63E6B20E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Funding from IPAB</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1899A(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395kkk">42 U.S.C. 1395kkk(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D9A2B5A54BE49E8B61493BE1BCD8399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>to the Board to carry</quote> and inserting <quote>for the purposes of carrying out section 303(l), and, if any funds remain in the fiscal year involved, for the Board for the purpose of carrying</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H335BF68107B84971BCD21FBB72649B10"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03DED3922DCB48119848D841830852EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding from the CO-OP program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1322(g) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18042">42 U.S.C. 18042(g)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>to carry out this section</quote> and inserting <quote>to carry out section 303(l) of the Social Security Act, to the extent funds are necessary to carry out such section after the application of section 1899A(m)(1) of such Act</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H72D97C5CD2824089BDF18D962AAB1EA6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H43841CEC22444AB897B2CF80E1EFFFA0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5235C6768DF4EF1A43A9D5AEF492884"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay permitted if legislation pending</header><text>If a State applies to the Secretary of Labor to delay implementation of the requirements of section 303(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/503">42 U.S.C. 503(l)</external-xref>) on the grounds that legislation to implement such requirements is pending in the State legislature on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall not refuse certification for payment to the State under section 302 of such Act solely on the basis of the failure of the State to implement such requirements before such date.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

