<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD2D8B59F25E743DDA5DB25058F735397" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3381 IH: Childhood Cancer Survivorship, Treatment, Access, and Research Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3381</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To maximize discovery, and accelerate development and availability, of promising childhood cancer
			 treatments, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H773D2D7B28FB47DDB5C510E4054E5856" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0013A7109D8F4A0C8C43C43093CF83D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H198B8BB20E9A4681A143D72BB32FC911"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Childhood Cancer Survivorship, Treatment, Access, and Research Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Childhood Cancer STAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H1D312EEF07114DBAA32EC0D2B4212508"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="H0013A7109D8F4A0C8C43C43093CF83D6" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC3D9CDF6CF8D49C79E9D82786FFCDF04" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6C7924CBDB3F495FB059301331B3ACA1" level="title">TITLE I—MAXIMIZING RESEARCH THROUGH DISCOVERY</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBE2CF910525A426D9E458941DF852962" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Caroline Pryce Walker Conquer Childhood Cancer Reauthorization Act</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1A4CCFEC8A3642029099EB8C90B052FA" level="section">Sec. 101. Comprehensive children’s cancer biorepositories.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H177BD312BF7F4F46AF9779A6A60C734F" level="section">Sec. 102. Improving Childhood Cancer Surveillance.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6D4AD4133797475C914DFB185C3BE7D6" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Pediatric Expertise at NIH</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4891A2EEDF924B279841C073CADC2D26" level="section">Sec. 111. Inclusion of at least one pediatric oncologist on the National Cancer Advisory Board.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBD5B52E126ED4A3D8714D79F07186B16" level="section">Sec. 112. Sense of Congress regarding pediatric expertise at the National Cancer Institute.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCF9435135B384CFF966993368C384B11" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—NIH Report on Childhood Cancer Activities</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE8F59259F3BA4C23AC2C7C88DA683B86" level="section">Sec. 121. Reporting on childhood malignancy projects.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H35AC03EBB9A94F35BDB62C0C1C14E625" level="title">TITLE II—AVAILABILITY OF PROMISING TREATMENTS</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7C4057DABE814C219EA84A4974E9FCBB" level="section">Sec. 201. Expanded access policy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDA3ABCC8BB4B42F1A54E04973D2FA41A" level="section">Sec. 202. Finalizing draft guidance on expanded access.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2AAD9B5AAD62497C86BE9B69BD9FA04F" level="title">TITLE III—MAXIMIZING DELIVERY: CARE, QUALITY OF LIFE, SURVIVORSHIP, AND CAREGIVER SUPPORT</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0BD9D9EDFD684F249607D149EBA73F8E" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Childhood Cancer Survivors’ Quality of Life Act</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEC9DC37DD4B24DE08DFB30D68685F820" level="section">Sec. 301. Cancer survivorship programs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBCE374AB51C24953AFFF7C1F1C9D8037" level="section">Sec. 302. Grants to improve care for pediatric cancer survivors.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9E2B23D0B34F4843AD540D4187A6569D" level="section">Sec. 303. Comprehensive long-term follow-up services for pediatric cancer survivors.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBFB7A109C4DC40B5B4ADD64A08301911" level="section">Sec. 304. Survivorship demonstration project.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H164940A8FE1E44DE9FE4D8B063A625DF" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Coverage and Payment of High Quality Care</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBB830FFE3F2D40CBB21C1445F86803E9" level="section">Sec. 311. Report by the Comptroller General.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC3D9CDF6CF8D49C79E9D82786FFCDF04"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H19B33CACD0AE4E1B87BA0513EEDEB04F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each year in the United States there are an estimated 15,780 children between birth and the age of 19 diagnosed with cancer. Approximately 1 in 285 children in the United States will be diagnosed with cancer before their 20th birthday.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA424831F94904804B55A05E6F1C1B217"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 1960, only 4 percent of children with cancer survived more than 5 years, but today, cure rates have increased to over 80 percent for children and adolescents under age 20.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0867F6C97DEB4C1E9933EB5D5931D592"><enum>(3)</enum><text>While the cure rates for some childhood cancers are now over 80 percent, the survival rates for many types of cancers in children remain extremely low.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0ECDF9BFD7604674B2F03F08486F7D6A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, cancer continues to be the leading cause of death by disease in children and adolescents under the age of 14.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1375FC20463F41608085769B1B39438C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>By 2020, the population of childhood cancers survivors is expected to be 500,000 individuals.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H228CC9F04D4D41079E4C135B500F4D1A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>As many as two-thirds of childhood cancer survivors are likely to experience at least one late effect of treatment, with as many as one-fourth experiencing a late effect that is serious or life-threatening. Common late effects of childhood cancer are neurocognitive, psychological, cardiopulmonary, endocrine, and musculoskeletal effects, secondary malignancies, and early death.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5FDB3EC83AF43E19751FAE9B17A5A45"><enum>(7)</enum><text>As a result of disparities in the delivery of cancer care, minority, low-income, and other medically underserved children are more likely to be diagnosed with late stage disease, experience poorer treatment outcomes, have shorter survival time with less quality of life, and experience a substantially greater likelihood of cancer death.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC7F37314F6540CFA981FDD101DF6237"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Collection of biospecimens, along with clinical and outcome data, on the maximum possible number of children with cancer in the United States is necessary to improve childhood cancer treatments and cures. Currently biospecimens, and clinical and outcome data, are collected for less than half of children in the United States with cancer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1902BA22E85401AB6CE169E365C8BC5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Despite the significant unmet medical need, pharmaceutical companies have been reluctant to develop drugs appropriate for children with cancer because it requires making an investment in products that are unlikely to cover the high costs associated with their research, development, marketing, and distribution. Only 3 drugs have been approved by the Food and Drug Administration to treat any type of pediatric cancer since the 1980s, including Unituxin, the first-ever drug approved for high-risk neuroblastoma, for which the sponsor of the drug was rewarded under the Food and Drug Administration's priority review program to encourage treatments for rare pediatric diseases.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73B487D974164213AA8CDDAEC79538FF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The late effects of cancer treatment may change as therapies evolve, which means that the monitoring and care of cancer survivors may need to be modified on a routine basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3286D27596F4D94A7CF6E80B2264E6D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Despite the intense stress caused by childhood cancer, there is a lack of standardized and coordinated psychosocial care for the children and their families, from the date of diagnosis through treatment and survivorship.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA598958AEAF4CAEA737794983568A39"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Institute of Medicine, in its report on cancer survivorship entitled <quote>Childhood Cancer Survivorship: Improving Care and Quality of Life</quote>, states that an organized system of care and a method of care for pediatric cancer survivors is needed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D36ED9DC21F4CD5A524684C6931CD99"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Focused and well-designed research and pilot health delivery programs can answer questions about the optimal ways to provide health care, follow-up monitoring services, and survivorship care to those diagnosed with childhood cancer and contribute to improvements in the quality of care and quality of life of those individuals through adulthood.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H537A9BD749054C5AA83A35A2547CAB65"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The National Institutes of Health, including the National Cancer Institute, invest approximately half of their annual appropriations to support basic research that serves as the foundation for translational and clinical research for all diseases and conditions, with the potential to lead to breakthroughs for children with cancer. Virtually all progress against cancer—in both children and adults—has been founded in basic research, often in areas not directly related to the disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6737CFF3E584758BF21E52824DCF67D"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The National Cancer Institute supports a number of key research programs specifically to advance childhood cancer care, including precision medicine clinical trials for children with cancer, including the Children’s Oncology Group (part of the National Clinical Trials Network of the National Cancer Institute), the Pediatric Preclinical Testing Program, the Pediatric Brain Tumor Consortium, the Childhood Cancer Survivor Study, the Therapeutically Applicable Research to Generate Effective Treatments program and related pediatric cancer genomics research, and the Pediatric Oncology Branch (part of the intramural program of the National Cancer Institute, whose mission is to develop new treatments for pediatric cancer).</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="H6C7924CBDB3F495FB059301331B3ACA1"><enum>I</enum><header>MAXIMIZING RESEARCH THROUGH DISCOVERY</header>
			<subtitle id="HBE2CF910525A426D9E458941DF852962"><enum>A</enum><header>Caroline Pryce Walker Conquer Childhood Cancer Reauthorization Act</header>
 <section id="H1A4CCFEC8A3642029099EB8C90B052FA"><enum>101.</enum><header>Comprehensive children’s cancer biorepositories</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 417E of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285a-11">42 U.S.C. 285a–11</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE95B6D29CDA948FDA40F2C1D6214F479"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF229C23750744F63B38C61FAFDEBC506" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="H1B529AE68608493F9B1CF3A94604EEE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Comprehensive children's cancer biorepositories</header>
 <paragraph id="H112641E525B8418EB457A23A2F92CD55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Award</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, may make an award for a duration of at least 5 years to an entity or entities described in paragraph (4) to build upon existing initiatives to collect biospecimens and clinical and demographic information for at least 90 percent of all children, adolescents, and young adults with cancer in 1 or more Comprehensive Children's Cancer Biorepositories to achieve a better understanding of the cause of such cancers and the effects of treatments for such cancers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F212B445C4C4E4E8741F10CC073C91D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts received under the award under paragraph (1) may be used to carry out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H7CFCD41348034DDD833623743B906BA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Prospectively acquire, preserve, and store high-quality, donated biospecimens and associated clinical and demographic information on children, adolescents, and young adults diagnosed with cancer in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F83EBC601D24EA0B0C99CA6614E4268"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Maintain a secure searchable database on stored biospecimens and associated clinical and demographic data from children, adolescents, and young adults with cancer for the conduct of research by scientists and qualified health care professionals.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC7EC89440EB4B3A9E97F6F47E2119BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Establish procedures for evaluating applications for access to such biospecimens and clinical and demographic data from researchers and other qualified health care professionals.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0955B5E64F2A4C5EBC5453D71E32894C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Make available and distribute biospecimens and clinical and demographic data from children, adolescents, and young adults with cancer to researchers and qualified health care professionals for peer-reviewed research at a minimal cost.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD60773D77DC64B39843941019A42FB9F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No requirement</header><text>No child, adolescent, or young adult with cancer shall be required under this subsection to contribute a specimen to a Biorepository or share clinical or demographic data.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HCACE692BD9D140FDB52F38CB224A24BB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application; considerations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H51BD27D6981B414C841A8B29D6ED8E4B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under paragraph (1) an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such a time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H171AAA62197E4F00A52CD7FA86F0073A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In evaluating the applications in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider the existing infrastructure of the entity that would allow for the timely capture of biospecimens and related clinical and demographic information for children, adolescents, and young adults with cancer.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF1A66DC1AAA43AF8CAB478D6CF3DB8E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Privacy protections; consent</header>
 <subparagraph id="H029D042DFBC442E8BA1D28B34EA79B47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may not make an award under paragraph (1) to an entity unless the Secretary ensures that such entity—</text>
 <clause id="H78FB854603504350B6FFE2DF9DDFDDBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collects biospecimens and associated clinical and demographic information from children with appropriate permission from parents or legal guardians in accordance with Federal and State law; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCF494DA1CFAE495A8279B83D48A0BB47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adheres to strict confidentiality to protect the identity and privacy of patients in accordance with Federal and State law.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA36FC4D8FF97406888338A47C8EE4FFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consent</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an appropriate process for achieving consent from the patient, parent, or legal guardian.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09228E008BDA49ABA145F307319DC8FA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Single point of access; standard data; guidelines and oversight</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFD1C15F692BE45E0967F9A592A08D39F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Single point of access</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each Biorepository supported under paragraph (1) has electronically searchable data for use by researchers and other qualified health care professionals in the manner and to the extent defined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H888D477C0EF1496B868CDE76EBEE5F22"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Standard data</header><text>The Secretary shall require all recipients of an award under this section to make available a standard dataset for the purposes of subparagraph (A) in a standard electronic format that enables researchers and qualified health care professionals to search.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DD038662CD04DD2B7932FF28C2AC2A6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Guidelines and oversight</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and disseminate appropriate guidelines for the development and maintenance of the biorepositories supported under this section, including appropriate oversight.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA70F68216D34AD1895673FAE46AA5FF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that clinical and demographic information collected in accordance with this section is collected in coordination with the information collected under section 399E–1.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA33FD6C6D8064FC5911E5671B157A330"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds</header><text>Funds made available to carry out this subsection shall not be used to acquire, preserve, or maintain a biospecimen collected from a patient if such activity is already covered by funds available from the National Cancer Institute for such purpose.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBF2A74FD540467E865FACA74B212B03"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Childhood Cancer Survivorship, Treatment, Access, and Research Act of 2015</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="H093EDD0609B244879696A882C1E5AD1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of biospecimens and corresponding clinical demographic data collected through the Comprehensive Children’s Cancer Biorepositories supported under paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA9CBB950B4D4C6CB9FAE7858CAA62FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of biospecimens and corresponding clinical demographic data requested for use by researchers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08AEAFB92E3B45E08284ABDE03FEDBEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any barriers to the collection of biospecimens and corresponding clinical demographic data;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5991558ABEFA4E92BED2D99293805E27"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any barriers experienced by researchers or health care professionals in accessing the biospecimens and corresponding clinical demographic data necessary for use in research; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D6D6CAB1EF342138D41B955D201CFC0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any recommendations with respect to improving the Comprehensive Children’s Cancer Biorepository program under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4C9F4FFD3EE4BABBD0D7245760651A0"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HAA5EA161AB0D44E1AF6E55C047F5F133"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Award</header><text>The term <term>award</term> includes a grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or other mechanism determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H833D571212F448A7BD5DD135DF89B752"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Biospecimen</header><text>The term <term>biospecimen</term> includes—</text> <clause id="HCEB3DB6A834B4FA1804972A90CE984B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>solid tumor tissue or bone marrow;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3E49FEA58D6644EAA40C9BFF7512B424"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>normal or control tissue;</text> </clause><clause id="H8935E6AF695A48C18774F82A2332F486"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>blood and plasma;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C726E6D2998409A80E0D6EC16ACB118"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>DNA and RNA extractions;</text> </clause><clause id="HC67A4A563A284245B567B8992CBB4FCB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>familial DNA; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDB514C5855504F71A82DD51B8C9F6D90"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other sample required by the Secretary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E477D5D6F144784A7F630B83B85F92E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Clinical and demographic information</header><text>The term <term>clinical and demographic information</term> includes—</text>
 <clause id="HDDCD4315E29E48F4BD15ADD0757FBCB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>date of diagnosis;</text> </clause><clause id="H2E6B1AF2E6EC40F2B31529D66A4B1715"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>age at diagnosis;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4E8E6B94C09C4EC2A8ACAB0579A1EB2A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>patient’s gender, race, and ethnicity;</text> </clause><clause id="H7DAA4EA22FA14A519247F93264BFEE84"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>extent of disease at enrollment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9616A2A866E64D6C8667FE2AABF04CFE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>site of metastases;</text> </clause><clause id="HEA0AA857F0754E0897E5372F9DAD42DA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>location of primary tumor coded;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7404FC504CDD49F2B3F13AB73BDBEB03"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>histologic diagnosis;</text> </clause><clause id="HD962E19F461C49EEBDC980F7966CA40F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>tumor marker data when available;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4702D7B99899423893BC4A76E44BD738"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>treatment and outcome data;</text> </clause><clause id="H047F422FEBA74999BFDA4383E09804D4"><enum>(x)</enum><text>information related to specimen quality; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE8AA03C89E024C16BA5B7D482AEAF4E9"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>any other information required by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A1D7F63F0F341618B7290BD250B38FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8CB03A2A5B43432DBD6E394C89D5DD7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and section 399E–1</quote> and inserting <quote>and sections 317U, 399E–1, 417H, and 417H–1</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57ABC96D12824CF7BD288B5A01336FC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2009 through 2013</quote> and inserting <quote>2016 through 2020</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49A4E4CD3E5946599EC99BDCB6F150D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such purpose</quote> and inserting <quote>such purposes</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H177BD312BF7F4F46AF9779A6A60C734F"><enum>102.</enum><header>Improving Childhood Cancer Surveillance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 399E–1 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280e-3a">42 U.S.C. 280e–3a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H99DE296800054C9DB6997CCC184DD92D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (d); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDC7125B2B684C04B761354F23D5B906"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40C96CC3F4F44A1F91E85D80508C7A61" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H8EEC163E1CCB4211AD9B470599317070"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall award grants to State cancer registries to enhance and expand infrastructure to track the epidemiology of cancer in children, adolescents, and young adults. Such registries shall be updated to include each occurrence of such cancers within a period of time designated by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H85DC8150658C4E64A2A9D9DE90457DE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The grants described in subsection (a) may be used for—</text> <paragraph id="H0FE5DBC8B16A4A9CA69E19F4F393822B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying, recruiting, and training all potential sources for reporting childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancer cases;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55F932FE0CDB46D7AD4B86563C53F5D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>developing procedures to implement early inclusion of childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancer cases on State cancer registries through the use of electronic reporting;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6210EE3487EB4FE48F95C49DBE95974D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>purchasing infrastructure to support the early inclusion of childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancer cases on such registries;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4138D7FE4A074B4E8A64D4759FB09CB6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submitting deidentified data to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for inclusion in a national database of childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3FD9531BF444FE2A89576C2713EA5B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>tracking the late effects of childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancers.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H065D47E6C86C4E2BA0FE57A21F4AA867"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that information collected through State cancer registries under this section is collected in coordination with clinical and demographic information collected under section 417E(a).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></section></subtitle><subtitle id="H6D4AD4133797475C914DFB185C3BE7D6"><enum>B</enum><header>Pediatric Expertise at NIH</header>
 <section id="H4891A2EEDF924B279841C073CADC2D26"><enum>111.</enum><header>Inclusion of at least one pediatric oncologist on the National Cancer Advisory Board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Clause (iii) of section 406(h)(2)(A) of the Public Health and Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284a">42 U.S.C. 284a(h)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HF20F36C6041F47EEB4E34A76C4D07957" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H36BAC8A111F3451CA24649C9805609B0" indent="up2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>of the members appointed to the Board—</text> <subclause id="H46B7864C15FC4E7E9D30C1A8687DA767"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than 5 members shall be individuals knowledgeable in environmental carcinogenesis (including carcinogenesis involving occupational and dietary factors); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6A6ECA44A0DC4979B17F06FAC87536E9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not less than one member shall be an individual knowledgeable in pediatric oncology;</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="HBD5B52E126ED4A3D8714D79F07186B16"><enum>112.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding pediatric expertise at the National Cancer Institute</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Director of the National Cancer Institute should ensure that all applicable study sections, committees, advisory groups, and panels at the National Cancer Institute include one or more qualified pediatric oncologists, as appropriate.</text>
				</section></subtitle><subtitle id="HCF9435135B384CFF966993368C384B11" style="OLC"><enum>C</enum><header>NIH Report on Childhood Cancer Activities</header>
 <section id="HE8F59259F3BA4C23AC2C7C88DA683B86"><enum>121.</enum><header>Reporting on childhood malignancy projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 409D(c)(3) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284h">42 U.S.C. 284h(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by—</text> <paragraph id="H7A9E329FD19D484C88CEF54B259F6D1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">striking <quote>public on</quote> and inserting “public on—</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8790E896F0F46F394CC433321843BC5" style="OLC">
							<subparagraph id="H413EE0A53AA5489C8277986A5F243106"><enum>(A)</enum></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EF5EB71E35C4302B241C9C6DB9FB311"><enum>(2)</enum><text>striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H435EFBC097F04013B6504473ED9972D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inserting at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC79732A5E62948DDB38C9E4D44725D50" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5FC7B29AE27743F3AC99D6962362AB98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the childhood malignancy projects conducted under section 399N.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section></subtitle></title><title id="H35AC03EBB9A94F35BDB62C0C1C14E625"><enum>II</enum><header>AVAILABILITY OF PROMISING TREATMENTS</header> <section id="H7C4057DABE814C219EA84A4974E9FCBB"><enum>201.</enum><header>Expanded access policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 561 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb">21 U.S.C. 360bbb</external-xref>) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HEFB7FB5863DA4E6CAD14E7A9D506C137" style="OLC">
					<section id="HE68FF39812CA4A62B6BC49891C53F07D"><enum>561A.</enum><header>Expanded access policy required for investigational drugs</header>
 <subsection id="H67CC6C76F75142B4BD4B284ECEDDE4DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The manufacturer or distributor of one or more investigational drugs for the diagnosis, monitoring, or treatment of one or more serious diseases or conditions shall make publicly available the policy of the manufacturer or distributor on evaluating and responding to requests submitted under section 561(b) for provision of such a drug. A manufacturer or distributor may satisfy the requirement of the preceding sentence by posting such policy as generally applicable to all of such manufacturer’s of distributor’s investigational drugs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H03B5A91F8B5F4554B18978F738B45990"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content of policy</header><text>A policy described in subsection (a) shall include making publicly available—</text> <paragraph id="H6BDC00F4E24341D9906954B43F652476"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contact information for the manufacturer or distributor to facilitate communication about requests described in subsection (a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAE5DDE3D36346E49B730F98CB2CB24E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>procedures for making such requests;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5E9640808B74DA9BAF71F9E799635D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the general criteria the manufacturer or distributor will consider or use to approve such requests; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE98596A0FCD5455E81235C8960B026EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the length of time the manufacturer or distributor anticipates will be necessary to acknowledge receipt of such requests.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C0E1E94A4FF46E29180F8C186FC70A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No guarantee of access</header><text>The posting of policies by manufacturers and distributors under subsection (a) shall not serve as a guarantee of access to any specific investigational drug by any individual patient.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD59F1FED77B5401897990D6291753C1F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Revised policy</header><text>A manufacturer or distributor that has made a policy publicly available as required by this section may revise the policy at any time.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA75BFA66999E4A3A877ABFF79A7433EF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This section shall apply to a manufacturer or distributor with respect to an investigational drug beginning on the later of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0DDE49B188CE4C789B8BD192FDC249D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Childhood Cancer Survivorship, Treatment, Access, and Research Act of 2015</short-title>; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDAC8162377B4728A20E09AAAB0673C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the first initiation of a phase 2 or phase 3 study (as such terms are defined in section 312.21(b) and (c) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations)) with respect to such investigational new drug.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="HDA3ABCC8BB4B42F1A54E04973D2FA41A"><enum>202.</enum><header>Finalizing draft guidance on expanded access</header>
 <subsection id="H1A9368D0D4714DBAA163A2EA43B49A15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall finalize the draft guidance entitled <quote>Expanded Access to Investigational Drugs for Treatment Use—Qs &amp; As</quote>, dated May 2013.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8228401F3FEF4673BE9A748D0610CF94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The final guidance referred to in subsection (a) shall clearly define how the Secretary of Health and Human Services interprets and uses adverse drug event data reported by investigators in the case of data reported from use under a request submitted under section 561(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb">21 U.S.C. 360bbb(b)</external-xref>).</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H2AAD9B5AAD62497C86BE9B69BD9FA04F"><enum>III</enum><header>MAXIMIZING DELIVERY: CARE, QUALITY OF LIFE, SURVIVORSHIP, AND CAREGIVER SUPPORT</header>
			<subtitle id="H0BD9D9EDFD684F249607D149EBA73F8E"><enum>A</enum><header>Childhood Cancer Survivors’ Quality of Life Act</header>
				<section id="HEC9DC37DD4B24DE08DFB30D68685F820"><enum>301.</enum><header>Cancer survivorship programs</header>
 <subsection id="HC2DB5A81BA3049439AB5044D9BA27AF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cancer survivorship programs</header><text>Subpart 1 of part C of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285">42 U.S.C. 285 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HC5D56DEAA0CF454B8EFE9EB7E653C4B4" style="OLC">
							<section id="H2310A5BAD8C84FF5BE84F229109D6115"><enum>417H.</enum><header>Pilot programs to explore model systems of care for pediatric cancer survivors</header>
 <subsection id="H0FF460394B4444C89388DDAC1C8DBA02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall make grants to eligible entities to establish pilot programs to develop, study, or evaluate model systems for monitoring and caring for childhood cancer survivors throughout their lifespan, including evaluation of shared care and medical home and clinic based models for transition to adult care.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H94CED9D7C1F54859992A90E6140DEC9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H676007A12B044215BFE740DFC9DC62D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a medical school;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D75168681FA4219906F20FBAEBA471B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a children’s hospital;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H53A29A216ADD419CA4C0CA39D77ACC14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a cancer center;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10E6A846F30C4767BFB6B1B2D9DCB5E9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a community-based medical facility; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBECE7EE0D9F44EFFA3A8D194107C02BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other entity with significant experience and expertise in treating survivors of childhood cancers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30F8A98D9DB649A29A4F43CF3E0A3053"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The Secretary may make a grant under this section to an eligible entity only if the entity agrees—</text> <paragraph id="HC7268CD8E053417DA25AB4786F699FDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to use the grant to establish a pilot program to develop, study, or evaluate one or more model systems for monitoring and caring for cancer survivors; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE87AA152935B4AF6B98C7904F5D220F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in developing, studying, and evaluating such systems, to give special emphasis to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H00635C015E11458ABC9D9133F8332125"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Design of protocols for different models of follow-up care, monitoring, and other survivorship programs (including peer support and mentoring programs).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF9C85B7D51040409622969329BD998F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Development of various models for providing multidisciplinary care.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H653DD27F767E4027BD5F91D2D635B982"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Dissemination of information and the provision of training to health care providers about how to provide linguistically and culturally competent follow-up care and monitoring to cancer survivors and their families.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F06C2D646FD4A10A82B911D01E0DA8B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Development of support programs to improve the quality of life of cancer survivors.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C5B25D24C5B419997A0D7008F770FD5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Design of systems for the effective transfer of treatment information and care summaries from cancer care providers to other health care providers (including risk factors and a plan for recommended follow-up care).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB80FD1BA17B34EC9878A3D8C1F3903EB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Dissemination of the information and programs described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) to other health care providers (including primary care physicians and internists) and to cancer survivors and their families, where appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H996220C3F5774D3CA5CF64F5358A6905"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Development of initiatives that promote the coordination and effective transition of care between cancer care providers, primary care physicians, and mental health professionals.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB92EB8AE69E340D38759F8AD36305335"><enum>417H–1.</enum><header>Workforce development collaborative on medical and psychosocial care for childhood cancer survivors</header>
 <subsection id="HC59B415803D9435BB2521079D56503E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, convene a Workforce Development Collaborative on Medical and Psychosocial Care for Pediatric Cancer Survivors (referred to in this paragraph as the <term>Collaborative</term>). The Collaborative shall be a cross-specialty, multidisciplinary group composed of educators, consumer and family advocates, and providers of psychosocial and biomedical health services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H008EBE2BE75F42D39161B45ADC383ED3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goals and reports</header><text>The Collaborative shall submit to the Secretary a report establishing a plan to meet the following objectives for medical and psychosocial care workforce development:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9140AA5FFBE34C7C82FDCFF45D7F3CDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identifying, refining, and broadly disseminating to health care educators information about workforce competencies, models, and curricula relevant to providing medical and psychosocial services to persons surviving pediatric cancers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76602E12594245EF8A6CA2F623D54035"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Adapting curricula for continuing education of the existing workforce using efficient workplace-based learning approaches.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9EC42E10BC2347119C8F43A02BEB7415"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Developing the skills of faculty and other trainers in teaching psychosocial health care using evidence-based teaching strategies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F61DA42E3A044048BF2A620FA7D18DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Strengthening the emphasis on psychosocial health care in educational accreditation standards and professional licensing and certification exams by recommending revisions to the relevant oversight organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99D15F91F2D54D35831208819D22E9D4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Evaluating the effectiveness of patient navigators in pediatric cancer survivorship care.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DBE2BB0AFB14955BCA810B12A7505F2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Evaluating the effectiveness of peer support programs in the psychosocial care of pediatric cancer patients and survivors.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD6639752EADE420EA809D67D054572FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HE94E257E7B7D4241B94ABE2C1A2E0AA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3 of the Hematological Cancer Research Investment and Education Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/172">Public Law 107–172</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 541) is amended by striking <quote>section 419C</quote> and inserting <quote>section 417C</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9DC5E8A6DE4C49A7BDFEF9FADEED169B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall take effect as if included in section 3 of the Hematological Cancer Research Investment and Education Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/172">Public Law 107–172</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 541).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HBCE374AB51C24953AFFF7C1F1C9D8037"><enum>302.</enum><header>Grants to improve care for pediatric cancer survivors</header>
 <subsection id="HD2374E42B35043F0917FFA14FB8B8490"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 417E of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285a-11">42 U.S.C. 285a–11</external-xref>), as amended by section 101, is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H4E42BE9345B64842B9EEC4F122EF0198"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">research and awareness</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">research, awareness, and survivorship</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5AC4D3EC4826492D9EB6D175C28FC7F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D4835FF8BFE46EC9530B6E4DF7FB469" style="OLC">
								<subsection id="H0932F515886D4DEDAF28F5F255B608B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improving care for pediatric cancer survivors</header>
									<paragraph id="H63CBA52C2FE841D0BC5532E407493833"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Research on causes of health disparities in pediatric cancer survivorship</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3F1FC128957B4F0DA293AE67A2FD7F95"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Director of NIH, with guidance from the Director of the Institute, in coordination with ongoing research activities, shall make grants to entities to conduct research relating to—</text>
 <clause id="H15B434540C2D4BDCB96142C1EFD978D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>needs and outcomes of pediatric cancer survivors within minority or other medically underserved populations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1D42A9FDA7F040BE8115FE79CBA5F726"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>health disparities in pediatric cancer survivorship outcomes within minority or other medically underserved populations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H423E69F9854240028F458022404FD9C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>barriers that pediatric cancer survivors within minority or other medically underserved populations face in receiving follow-up care; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE1FCBDBFAE2748DB9667CFC1BA3EE657"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>familial, socioeconomic, and other environmental factors and the impact of such factors on treatment outcomes and survivorship.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B81697E8A434E47ADA80B5DF5FF902C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Balanced approach</header><text>In making grants for research under subparagraph (A)(i) on pediatric cancer survivors within minority or other medically underserved populations, the Director of NIH shall ensure that such research addresses both the physical and the psychological needs of such survivors.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B66CB542AFE4061831143B48A373BAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Research on late effects and follow-up care for pediatric cancer survivors</header><text>The Director of NIH, in coordination with ongoing research activities, shall conduct or support research on follow-up care for pediatric cancer survivors, with special emphasis given to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6F39D52A583B4E7697D92E26A8465C50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of indicators used for long-term patient tracking and analysis of the late effects of cancer treatment for pediatric cancer survivors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA845AC52907244F2BC9F6057F1DB039C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the identification of risk factors associated with the late effects of cancer treatment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD73EC58360D443DA7FA01898DC95D56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the identification of predictors of neurocognitive and psychosocial outcomes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC97A6FC69374380975777728E21CF6C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the identification of the molecular underpinnings of long-term complications;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6914C77B7C5543699E2655DF63C0E6AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the development of risk prediction models to identify those at highest risk of long-term complications;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90C33FD3114E4A218818E2F7DDB2E272"><enum>(F)</enum><text>initiatives to protect cancer survivors from the late effects of cancer treatment, by developing targeted interventions to reduce the burden of morbidity borne by cancer survivors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC95187E0E3AD48A1B650571BB7E88570"><enum>(G)</enum><text>transitions in care for pediatric cancer survivors;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF03B42D86114FACB68D0745422363B9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>training of professionals to provide linguistically and culturally competent follow-up care to pediatric cancer survivors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FAB0FBD34C744F5B8FC798035EC9FCD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>different models of follow-up care; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01B713DA462D4448A0B0D1A95C6902C6"><enum>(J)</enum><text>examining the cost-effectiveness of the different models of follow-up care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9E2B23D0B34F4843AD540D4187A6569D"><enum>303.</enum><header>Comprehensive long-term follow-up services for pediatric cancer survivors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 317T the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HEB9A102E41BC4549A9F957CAC8BA63DB" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB217B7F8EE9741FAA7894A3265638786"><enum>317U.</enum><header>Standards for comprehensive long-term care for pediatric cancer survivors through the lifespan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a task force to develop and test standards, outcomes, and metrics for high-quality childhood cancer survivorship care in consultation with a full spectrum of representation of experts in late effects of disease and treatment of childhood cancers, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H484FA9DD90EC42F58A815321743A773E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oncologists who treat children and adolescents;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD96F9F58EFCB4DAAAD0073A51F0443D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oncologists who treat adults;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD20715FF5DBF4B3DB3297716D61582EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>primary care providers engaged in survivorship care;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B21E0B441364193989284213E2BFF98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>survivors of childhood cancer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H878BA3DEDE1C499A8E5F5E19A76D701D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">parents of children who have been diagnosed with and treated for cancer and parents of long-term survivors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05F43CAE70CF47D6A42268DF1B7B66E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>professionals who are engaged in the development of clinical practice guidelines;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D39730CCFB04DCB9C06DC397230E5D7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>nurses and social workers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD25C158909FE4A32BFBFBF38D93CEC01"><enum>(8)</enum><text>mental health professionals;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6FFD73AF8584D8CB7260D94C841C92E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>allied health professionals, including physical therapists and occupational therapists;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7919396FB7A5432BA31C42E647CC7269"><enum>(10)</enum><text>experts in health care quality measurement and improvement; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE655F7E5F1A14D3E8A46FEC286550852"><enum>(11)</enum><text>others, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</section><section id="HBFB7A109C4DC40B5B4ADD64A08301911"><enum>304.</enum><header>Survivorship demonstration project</header>
 <subsection id="H450C099E658F4ECF9C809D2380BE87EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall carry out a demonstration project over a 3-year period, designed to improve the quality and efficiency of care provided to childhood cancer survivors throughout their lifespan, through improved care coordination as survivors transitions to adult care.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HD5A76448FE8F4D449374BD8C1DC05376"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of demonstration sites</header>
 <paragraph id="H4633AB7D78684CA0835EBD129D768F74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Maximum number of sites</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the maximum number of sites does not exceed 10.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H393E29034DF6400A89D7968256A6EBA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diversity of sites</header><text>In selecting entities to participate in the demonstration project, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, include in such selection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H20075C6934D64542B10C38B0DA2DD14C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>small-, medium-, and large-sized sites; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA99F8B98541A4A168588FF70EBCCAE1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sites located in different geographic areas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C5B702930A44EB0A23BF4692363F99D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities under demonstration project</header><text>The activities conducted under the demonstration project under subsection (a) may, in addition to any other activity specified by the Secretary, include activities that seek to develop different models of care coordination, including transitions of care, follow-up care, monitoring, and other survivorship related programs that utilize a multidisciplinary, team based approach to care, including any of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="H95E321FD5F574A9FA33C8A9721EC035A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Coordination of care and transitions of care between cancer care providers, primary care physicians, mental health professionals and any other relevant providers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94422AF7B50E47B58577A933FF9930BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Dissemination of information to, and training of, health care providers about linguistically and culturally competent follow-up care specific to cancer survivors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0734581EE4514B78B15AC8D935101B0F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Development of monitoring programs for cancer survivors and their families.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D61D0897D52499CBE2440EEFADD2847"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Incorporation of peer support and mentoring programs to improve the quality of life of cancer survivors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5FC220BC34742C69138D7A268F6182B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Designing systems and models for the effective transfer of treatment information and care summaries from cancer care providers to other health care providers (including risk factors and a care plan).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF525AE891F24591868F59131C613356"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Evaluation of functional status and incorporation of specific functional needs into the care planning process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2327334C37F5457FAC3AF6CF8BE46045"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Dissemination of the information on activities and programs conducted under this section to other health care providers (including primary care physicians) and to cancer survivors and their families, where appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD9433F94D0A4B4A9223F0EE0BAC3870"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Other items determined by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36265A8E973C44C896B29A3D7C0F1237"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Measures</header><text>The Secretary shall use the following measures to assess the performance of each site:</text>
 <paragraph id="H520B752807C34441831DAEF44E7D74CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Patient care and satisfaction measures.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4F80AD4DD6D4D1D97D06DE3DE7A9F59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Resource utilization measures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC2238CB2CB04B6091A46C16EDB72E97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Adult survivorship measures.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71FB42057D1C4ED89CE6759FD2111E53"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO Report</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to Congress evaluating the success of the demonstration project. Such report shall include an assessment of the impact of the project upon the quality and cost-efficiency of services furnished to individuals under this title, including an assessment of the satisfaction of such individuals with respect to such services that were furnished under such project. Such report shall include recommendations regarding the possible expansion of the demonstration project.</text>
					</subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="H164940A8FE1E44DE9FE4D8B063A625DF"><enum>B</enum><header>Coverage and Payment of High Quality Care</header>
				<section id="HBB830FFE3F2D40CBB21C1445F86803E9"><enum>311.</enum><header>Report by the Comptroller General</header>
 <subsection id="H157A32264EC2431FB38E1E4F41E7C8BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review and submit recommendations to Congress on existing barriers to obtaining and paying for adequate medical care for survivors of childhood cancer.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC2B5A5103CE841AB9E78DBFD1B09317B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out the review and formulating recommendations under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAEECC2975ED3467BBE82939EDA0E675B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify existing barriers to the availability of complete and coordinated survivorship care for survivors of childhood cancer and to the availability of expert pediatric palliative care, including consideration of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA0D752CFA0D2452DA8C98A216293F811"><enum>(A)</enum><text>understanding and education among patients, health care providers, regulators, and third-party payors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4A14E4BE34D48BB899AB181A920C5F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adequacy of payment codes to cover necessary survivorship services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70D504346B4843608F527B6005FA026C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>access to necessary medical and other services for such survivors, including the services described in subsection (c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06E1BECF9B8A4065B162AD3F262BE6E9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lack of pediatric palliative care and hospice services for patients approaching the end of life; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3C53E55968A471C9EFFFF7E48BD4BD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make recommendations to provide improved access and payment plans for childhood cancer survivorship programs and palliative care, including psychosocial services and coverage of such services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68835E5F78F94AC8A8C500F1AC94C825"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Services described</header><text>The services described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFC50CB23DF394E1EBC5953A983398E46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Coordinated multidisciplinary long-term follow-up care with access to appropriate pediatric subspecialists and adult subspecialists with specific expertise in survivorship, including subspecialists with expertise in oncology, radiation oncology, surgery, cardiology, psychiatry or psychology, endocrinology, pulmonology, nephrology, dermatology, gynecology, and urology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF63A00432A345CEA4EB0A89292BE2E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Appropriate organ function testing (particularly screening for potential problems at much younger ages than usually indicated in the general population) and treatment, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H68C373302DD64F39905D081F1FFAC9A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>neuropsychological testing and mental health services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3694EB7B850446FBEDADA98C971838F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fertility testing and treatment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A6784DC4C894B71A81C0AA283A19DCC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluation and treatment for endocrine disorders including growth hormone and testosterone replacement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE21F0379D6E346AFB0FBEAF83A16FF75"><enum>(D)</enum><text>diagnostic imaging to screen for late effects of treatment (including second cancers), such as mammograms and magnetic resonance imaging testing to screen for possible breast cancer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF22439148C3B4CFAB3A21A82ACD887A3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>screening for cardiac problems, such as echocardiograms;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82524A67FB0447D58DDF52315ED7384D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>screening for osteoporosis with bone densitometry, including duel x-ray absorptiometry;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0C0541F192340FDA67EBF307560D023"><enum>(G)</enum><text>dental coverage and necessary dental implants;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB96E461EE30446E5AAC40B2707F8B9FC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>hearing aids; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AD883FE4334457497073DC260CF14D4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>screening for lung problems, such as pulmonary function testing.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle></title></legis-body> </bill> 

