<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9DE5220A7B4D43638244AD2A0DC150E4" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1943 IH: Supreme Court Ethics Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1943</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Supreme Court of the United States to promulgate a code of ethics.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H99C5140B0EC14CD5BDF8F0CE9505E55D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCC1C19F0D458429A9B761B4DB5323B9F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supreme Court Ethics Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE8545E92556A43C2BE89646C09CF0335"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection id="HD34CE8F23E054B539F138F88F616A5D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCC5158F9BF9C4538B40A92015A4C2A58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In Caperton v. A.T. Massey Coal Co., 556 U.S. 868 (2009), Justice Kennedy, writing for the Court, stated that <quote>[judicial codes of conduct] serve to maintain the integrity of the judiciary and the rule of law</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1894437CD3EE4AF7B6D0472B60184CC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Code of Conduct for United States Judges (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Code</quote>) applies to all Federal judges except Justices of the Supreme Court. Justices of the Supreme Court are not formally bound by any code of conduct. Chief Justice John Roberts noted in the 2011 Year-End Report on the Federal Judiciary that while the Judicial Conference, which promulgates the Code, does not have authority to bind the Supreme Court, the Code is nonetheless <quote>the starting point and a key source of guidance for the Justices as well as their lower court colleagues</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD304A87C4A3044689147182E51ECB58D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress has the authority to regulate the administration of the Supreme Court of the United States. For example, Congress sets the number of justices who sit on the Supreme Court and how many constitute a quorum, the term of the court, meaning the dates the court will be in session, and the salaries of the Justices. Additionally, the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) requires most high-level Federal officials in all 3 branches, including the President, Vice President, cabinet members, Justices of the Supreme Court, and Members of Congress, to file annual financial disclosure statements.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EC14D2391674935AE207E27250CE9C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to apply a code of ethics to Justices who sit on the Supreme Court of the United States, being mindful of their preeminence in the Federal judiciary.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HFFEDA3D604AB47D4964692C8A381C955" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Supreme Court code of ethics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Supreme Court of the United States shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate a code of ethics for the Justices of the Supreme Court that shall include the 5 canons of the Code of Conduct for United States Judges adopted by the Judicial Conference of the United States, with any amendments or modifications thereto that the Supreme Court determines appropriate.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


