<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F8F151226FD4389919D217265F0303E" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2110 IH: Consumer Review Freedom Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2110</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150429">April 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To prohibit the use of certain clauses in form contracts that restrict the ability of a consumer to communicate regarding the goods or services that were the subject of the contract.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC703EE5C2D7B4FFA84EB3595DDF85C25" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7D23B873477549138AF8F4C1E82373B7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Review Freedom Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H70CBAFA16BDF4E79A2EEC2EB4B10E9FB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protecting consumer speech</header> <subsection id="H239B4A6FF39F4B69883F6F57E8E33112"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A provision of a form contract is void from the inception of such contract if such provision—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9043CA27FA144B6D857103765AAA1CC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibits or restricts the ability of a person who is a party to the form contract to engage in a covered communication;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F23440E13CE4C74BE9F7807AF169D17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>imposes a penalty or fee against a person who is a party to the form contract for engaging in a covered communication; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4DA69243F524A1192566A9E8A21B972"><enum>(3)</enum><text>transfers or requires the individual to transfer to any person or business any intellectual property rights that the individual may have in any otherwise lawful covered communication about the person or the goods or services provided by the person or business;</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE65BAC5F2CA47F39934E033F58B86C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed to affect—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7775F043368B46D9B813B23C06C18806"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any duty of confidentiality imposed by law (including agency guidance); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA7791FC66024A27BD42E9919EA70B7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any civil action for defamation, libel, or slander, or any similar cause of action.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C2AF99AB1BA4966B82286314B5AA7CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to the extent that a provision of a form contract prohibits disclosure of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEC3038185DC4467697EF3F556603AC86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Trade secrets or commercial or financial information obtained from a person and considered privileged or confidential.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05140953A61C4A7FA0C9C0327E5C23CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Personnel and medical files and similar files the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB863AB3C8481430B944F3F9A0A65B7B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Records or information compiled for law enforcement purposes, the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAED804768E5F4D959BD42247D9DAAEB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unlawful conduct</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a business to offer or enter into a form contract containing a provision described as void in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEF330159B375470B88A12BA4D4959192"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>The Attorney General shall bring an action against any business who violates subsection (d) for a civil penalty of not more than $16,000 for each day that the business so requires the use of such a contract by a distinct person. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF4FF17C33694056BA3AB0777108477D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>State enforcement</header><text>The attorney general of a State may file an action to enforce subsection (d) seeking appropriate relief. In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of that State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by the engagement of any person in a practice that violates any regulation of the Commission prescribed under this section, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in a district court of the United States of appropriate jurisdiction to seek appropriate relief.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4083ED90818C4E1FBE3533D2BB651461"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="HF84745CE4DC342C2960F9D081366019F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>person</quote> means a natural person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83AE3AB00088457DB1B93134E77FBF35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>business</quote> means a legal entity organized to accomplish a business purpose, including either for-profit or not-for-profit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA3C965DFF4641AA9DA80CBFA9BDC50B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>form contract</quote> means a standardized contract used by a business and imposed on a party without a meaningful opportunity for said party to negotiate the standardized terms, but does not include a contract establishing an employer-employee or independent contractor relationship.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DDACE2B9ED943C4B5398CB4EC5E0FB2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered communication</quote> means a person’s written, verbal, or pictorial review, performance assessment of, or other similar analysis of, the products, services, or conduct of a business or person which is a party to the form contract.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DBB12918E83440E8158BF45D45523A0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>written</quote> includes words provided by electronic means.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCE16539365A43E8B37791B8BA0EBE77"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <quote>verbal</quote> includes speech provided by electronic means.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51B2D674E23B4EE39877EE7F27036C4E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <quote>pictorial</quote> includes pictures, photographs, and video provided by electronic means.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4E2E660EAC754E0CAEE92B953A2D6EEB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> 
<paragraph id="H45EB589DF2F2450985A8BC22BA238785"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), and (g) shall apply to any contracts in effect on or after date of enactment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64A2C6D7CEB74E55912BB7988B0C2EC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsections (e) and (f) shall apply to any contracts in effect on or after one year after date of enactment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9DD749AE3B5F4CE88D720A45D043D68F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Relation to state causes of action</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect any cause of action brought by a person that exists or may exist under State law.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

