<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD3DF6438D6344B5AB8B8490F7BB390E9" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 4207 IH: Medicare Fair Drug Pricing Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4207</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151209">December 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and
			 Human Services to determine, on behalf of Medicare beneficiaries, covered
			 part D drug prices for certain covered part D drugs, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H66297D253BB74665B07A1C15A76E7ECE" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA2074BF638F34602ABA0AB5E919997C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Fair Drug Pricing Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD167BA75C4AF4886A65468918DDD3E80"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement to determine lower covered part D drug prices for certain covered part D drugs</header> <subsection id="HD0837B96E1F047A495A2DA2A81D34CFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–11(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H07A7693AC3D8497FA50D435DA872399C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(i) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Noninterference.—</header-in-text>In</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFCEA15D5FD345C8B812333F0488BC41" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id45A2BB92A9324E199FB8C83505678A9A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Noninterference</header> <paragraph id="HFF39D8FB37014FDFA48FE2D47F38A12A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H154D63B7C2A940B1A80B7FF2BD9CDD27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>subject to paragraph (2),</quote> after <quote>part,</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9A27CDD86CF43E8A63EF64C75C4EA52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1330895A8DF44FE1AF384F16681098CC" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H27ED9673A16C489383D731B343E15376"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for specified drugs</header>
							<subparagraph id="HD9AA921C1A7C45DF934FE996D340FF52"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header>
 <clause id="H3F2FB45BDA0F4EB6825E4D44603C3201"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the part D price for specified drugs shall be determined in accordance with the process described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H42E0C7D85B7948E790F633CED63E8023"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Specified drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>specified drug</quote> means a covered part D drug—</text> <subclause id="H25DA2027FAFF4803B146C6ECA886CD42"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is—</text>
 <item id="H0C9E344CB5A1468B95B95F261C6F75B7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a single source drug or biological;</text> </item><item id="H54A563F89A7D4482A287364BFB24F6D8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not a biological product licensed pursuant to an application under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act; and</text>
 </item><item id="H923C19FF3A76440CA8378BF7638E58BF"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>not both manufactured by more than two drug manufacturers and manufactured by at least one such manufacturer as a generic drug; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD2D776B988F44DF9A8E1930B9CE1327E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that—</text> <item id="H80AA9A7E1E5244529F0A948ADD73B2DA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is selected by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph; and</text>
 </item><item id="H5D2318E2DA2C41C2B5E593E2942EB6BE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Secretary determines is a covered part D drug with respect to which there is limited ability for PDP sponsors and MA organizations to negotiate manufacturer rebates, such that the Secretary determines that the failure to apply this paragraph will have a significant fiscal impact on the program under this title.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H7EFB083C155340A993E6A6C9F450CF45"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Part D price defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>part D price</quote> means, with respect to a covered part D drug, the price (including discounts, rebates, and other price concessions) that may be charged to PDP sponsors and MA organizations for such drug for part D eligible individuals who are enrolled under a prescription drug plan or under an MA–PD plan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDC51E6D2289E4F9BB79C6C07157BD312"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Regulations for identification of specified drugs</header><text>The Secretary, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, shall promulgate regulations regarding the identification of single source drugs and biologicals as specified drugs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8BAB442F2A41402E8F7303B67D34E9E9"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Process to petition that drug is no longer a specified drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a process under which a manufacturer for a specified drug may petition the Secretary for the rescinding of a previous identification of a drug as a specified drug under clause (ii) based upon the drug involved no longer being a specified drug.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3E3521FDA1C4B9F9A046B8FF4A2A476"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Price determination process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the process described in this subparagraph, with respect to the part D price for a specified drug for a plan year, is the following:</text>
								<clause id="H0CBE9A9FA85D4BABA349FDCE5A1D2C1E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limited period for negotiation for first plan year</header>
 <subclause id="H350FD5C0531C469FBF8D84AFBA0C0FEB"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall negotiate such price with the drug manufacturer involved for a period of not more than 90 days beginning on the date of identification of the drug as a specified drug for such plan year by the Secretary.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDDC2809775144E99B1590061A23EF97C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Successful negotiations</header><text>In the case that such negotiation with respect to such 90-day period results in a price that is agreed to by both the Secretary and manufacturer, such price shall be the maximum part D price for such specified drug through the end of the plan year beginning after such period.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HB3192A2EBB594C7B96D000930B994F9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Secretary sets price for first plan year in case of failure to negotiate price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that negotiations under clause (i), with respect to a specified drug, do not result in a price for such specified drug that is so agreed to by the Secretary and drug manufacturer, the Secretary shall determine a price for such drug based on—</text>
 <subclause id="H9105139F986249C99EB302C84EFEB664"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the information provided to the Secretary by the drug manufacturer during the 90-day period described in clause (i)(I) regarding costs associated with such drug that are applicable with respect to such drug manufacturer;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H039A7051B6C740E3A587088AC355B3EE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case that payment is made for such drug by the Department of Veterans Affairs or under title XIX, the net priced paid for such drug by such Department or under such title, as applicable;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H27132D4C95734D98A8A185AD8CF93192"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring affordability of such drug, and accessibility to such drug, for individuals entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H796121D616D74316A2615BAD9CA9930D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>such other factors as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">The price determined under this clause shall be the maximum part D price for such specified drug through the end of the plan year beginning after such determination of such price.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H8875B240A86C46E8A0412A7DFDC9674B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Price in subsequent plan years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each plan year that is subsequent to the plan year for which a price is determined for a specified drug under clause (i) or (ii) and in which, on the first day of such subsequent plan year, the identification of such drug as a specified drug still applies, the maximum price for such drug shall be the maximum part D price for the previous year determined under clause (i) or (ii), as applicable, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; U.S. city average) for the 12-month period ending with June of the year before such subsequent plan year.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H970C8ACD43EB459CAD6D708BB69B7014"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining a price for a specified drug under clause (ii), the Secretary may consult with the Comptroller General, the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission, the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission, or other outside, independent experts.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BE210A7D18041FAB8C62FFEBB5920F4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No change in rules for formularies</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H124D16D0B3FF448286525F0B3E785425"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) or (B) shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to establish or require a particular formulary.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H785FC765BC90461BA1BAF23414A186EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Clause (i) shall not be construed as affecting the Secretary’s authority to ensure appropriate and adequate access to covered part D drugs under prescription drug plans and under MA–PD plans, including compliance of such plans with formulary requirements under section 1860D–4(b)(3).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0499CB7034F344A2BAC5BEC9D166AEB2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as—</text> <clause id="H611340F43A004899B2F842C5C5AC8EBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>preventing the sponsor of a prescription drug plan, or an organization offering an MA–PD plan, from obtaining a discount or reduction of the price for a covered part D drug described in subparagraph (A) below the price negotiated under such subparagraph or determined under subparagraph (B); or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H6C53AD0A539E45B5BFE6820189D9E002"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>permitting the Secretary to make proprietary data available to the public.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H126F3951DDE84CC0948655CD4069AF03"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text>
 <clause id="HC9B45EBA4367434C9D42640C6297D9E4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Drug manufacturer</header><text>The term <quote>drug manufacturer</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>manufacturer</quote> in section 1860D–14A(g)(5).</text> </clause><clause id="HA8D1346D6D3044858D187098D8DDE128"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Single source drug or biological</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>single source drug or biological</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1847A(c)(6)(D).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C05BE7397C74DE8B8A9013C6AFBA0AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requiring participation in negotiation process as condition of part D drug coverage</header><text>Section 1860D–14A(b) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–114a(b)) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H787C85027D9043B6B2257830E114F027" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H1BC2EF2036C74857B218EC1E5DE8E95A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Participation in negotiation process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agreement under this subsection shall include, with respect to plans years beginning with plan year 2017, an agreement by the manufacturer, with respect to each specified drug of such manufacturer under section 1860d–11(i)(2), to participate in the negotiation process under such section for such drug, including accepting the price resulting from the negotiation (or, in the case that such negotiation does not result in a price for such drug that is agreed to by the Secretary and the manufacturer, the price resulting from the application of subparagraph (B)(ii) of such section) as the maximum price for such drug for the period provided under such section.<inline-comment display="no">1927(a)(1) is the enforcement of 430B of the PHSA. Enforced through part B of Medicare.</inline-comment></text>
					</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H32965A809982482FB359CC7AC7313A72"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study and report</header>
 <subsection id="H3B429BC2499E49B7A377DD2D4B16A4A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a study examining—</text> <paragraph id="H02AD19DA47444059BFD9EDB802022102"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the amendments made by section 2 on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7D1430BA2C974364A685045FFF8AC9D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cost of single source drugs and biologicals (as defined in section 1847A(c)(6)(D) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(6)(D))) for which payment is made under part B of title XVIII of such Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H658A41FA30944F7F9F0B205B4D1890BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the accessibility of such drugs and biologicals for individuals entitled to benefits under part A of such title or enrolled under part B of such title; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2244FE62C145462EA57CF860A621FF82"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">options that would permit or require the Secretary to create and implement, not later than one year after the date of the report described in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF01D8F6F47824CE8BE93044B3744F76B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a method to apply to such single source drugs and biologicals for which the Secretary determines appropriate—</text>
 <clause id="HF68111D266764D5EAA93409620AA4650"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an authority similar to the authority granted to the Secretary under subparagraph (A) of section 1860D–11(i)(2) of such Act (relating to negotiating with drug manufacturers the part D prices for certain specified drugs); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3F97B457E92B4AE3AFB538E0EA4C630F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a negotiation process similar to the process under subparagraph (B) of such section; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H785C89B1B7654EF28878435911B256BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a method, such as a rebate program, to incorporate the rate negotiated for such drugs and biologicals pursuant to the authority described in subparagraph (A) into payments for such drugs and biologicals under part B of such Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C45936D378748B8BE5AC12A95C58D9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit a report to Congress on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a). Such report shall include recommendations regarding the options examined pursuant to paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


