<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAAA30B86B75C4BA48A3A7D37B62945FE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3107 IH: Belarus Democracy and Sanctions Enforcement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3107</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150716">July 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the continuation in effect of sanctions imposed with respect to Belarus, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1B909DDE37EC4816AA4A13D7AFED9D5C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9580043505A34BE19CA750E15FDC7528" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Belarus Democracy and Sanctions Enforcement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8BA3D6477E0C43CEB989743DCE52AC39"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4860DB5F6F154CC1BE6A933466FBA103"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The authoritarian regime of Alexander Lukashenko continues to abuse the human rights and impede the democratic aspirations of the people of Belarus, including by imprisoning leaders, restricting free media, and denying the freedom of assembly.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91DB6034940A4D528D068445025BEBBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On June 16, 2006, the United States Government imposed sanctions with respect to entities in Belarus for the human rights abuses, public corruption, and measures to undermine democratic processes undertaken by President Lukashenko and his associates.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H644F1C0298BA40559DE545A9903D62DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>President Lukashenko was personally named on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF465AC65EE43463DB1371FBB3F63DB43"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On November 13, 2007, pursuant to Executive Order 13405 (71 Fed. Reg. 35485), the Office of Foreign Assets Control added the Belarusian State Concern for Oil and Chemistry (commonly referred to as <quote>Belneftekhim</quote>) to the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC90FFB67EAD248629A06DA0900880087"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On February 2014, the Lukashenko regime spun the Joint Stock Company Belaruskali and its trading arm, the Joint Stock Company Belarusian Potash Company, out from under the Belneftekhim umbrella, with press reports at the time citing officials of the Government of Belarus as affirming that this legal maneuver was intended specifically to evade sanctions imposed by the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0DDE1E2E79A4F6F94A64111505C7509"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Country Reports on Human Rights Practices for 2013 of the Department of State stated that, in Belarus, <quote>[a]uthorities at all levels operated with impunity and failed to take steps to prosecute or punish officials in the government or security forces who committed human rights abuses</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD8FC5587A3D43EA9BF49D41A93525DF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Government of Belarus plans to hold presidential elections in October 2015, which observers fear may not be free and may result in prolonging President Lukashenko’s authoritarian rule.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H387B06A3CB2949ED91CD3EEDC938C37B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text> <paragraph id="HEA79B1C7252F4A728A90B80368A12EEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to maintain all sanctions imposed with respect to Belarus in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act until the authorities of Belarus respect the human rights and democratic aspirations of the people of Belarus; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD25D0D4C92BE4B94B839EB4B18129B38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to crack down on all attempts by Belarusian entities tied to the Government of Belarus to evade sanctions imposed by the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H049873C976384203AD101BC76FC91C73"><enum>4.</enum><header>Continuation in effect of sanctions</header>
 <subsection id="HBD7C0079636A4143BFA0F62FBE1AEE54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All sanctions imposed by the United States with respect to Belarus in effect on the date of enactment of this Act shall remain in effect until the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Government of Belarus has met the conditions described in section 6(b) of the Belarus Democracy Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/347">Public Law 108–347</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/5811">22 U.S.C. 5811</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7EAFDE25C0394C03839E4EF71CE17980"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="HFC7A1263546D434499F6DCA55010FDB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63209FA7FB7343A6A42BB5F25288A490"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6B5215D2863143CE901B814DF73E0957"><enum>5.</enum><header>Inclusion of Joint Stock Company Belaruskali and Joint Stock Company Belarusian Potash Company on
 the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall include the Joint Stock Company Belaruskali and the Joint Stock Company Belarusian Potash Company on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


