<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2A83C58355804FF392CB01C45486A3FE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2756 IH: Patient Freedom Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2756</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150612">June 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reform the provision of health insurance coverage by promoting health savings accounts,
			 State-based alternatives to coverage under the Affordable Care Act, and
			 price transparency, in order to promote a more market-based health care
			 system, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9B6B751FB5D34861AC1292C847798238" style="OLC">
		<section id="HDF13491CED464265ADB1B3969120D9A8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H08C60B631F644F75A4EB00294C8F584A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patient Freedom Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H815E345D7DCB45489741CEF12696AA83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HDF13491CED464265ADB1B3969120D9A8" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5B872ABB75A54DA5AC10CA884607FDFF" level="section">Sec. 2. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB7A6F07B7B934122B6C328F3E871CDE8" level="title">Title I—Health Reform</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4229FF121E6240F480AA295F0ECAAA5D" level="section">Sec. 100. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H255C200526F6492DBD1E3D682E494076" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Insurance Reforms</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H35C16F6D52E44CED9B70174B0583B7B0" level="section">Sec. 101. State options in response to Burwell decision.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDAAC536C37164F12AF23FA01D3E07F86" level="section">Sec. 102. State alternative option.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE7402C9B5578422AA90856866E222A4B" level="section">Sec. 103. Computation of monthly HSA deposit amount for deposit qualifying residents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3730DACEEEC14DC7BC7517F576EBC340" level="section">Sec. 104. State options for improved access to health insurance coverage in each State.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF8708A33230E4467A6260DE6CB07B825" level="section">Sec. 105. Expanded access and patient protections.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H48DCAA81FBF3493FBF94D9EEEF22AB2D" level="section">Sec. 106. Sunsetting certain ACA provisions; continuation of policies of covering adult children
			 and not applying lifetime or annual limits.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE8CFB514AE2A4E8E83729E54B46035F7" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Medicaid</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEBF2432B65BF48C3A2B6F08CA5DEB99B" level="section">Sec. 111. Application of health savings accounts in relation to Medicaid.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA9B9858C17824BE2BED7C7F43B3771DB" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Provider Price Transparency</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5A2F62BD09E4484AB81C959D93FBA83C" level="section">Sec. 121. Ensuring access to emergency services without excessive charges for out-of-network
			 services.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3AC6E88EA8DA472D8C3F9EF562BFAC3C" level="title">Title II—Reform of Tax Provisions Relating to Health Care</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD442AC9B598C49658C269F9E80D388ED" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Promotion of Health Savings Accounts</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5DBA7BA87C714B3EA9271259BAFDD9F2" level="section">Sec. 201. Repeal of high deductible health plan requirement.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6E8B82331031458CA681998C45462EA8" level="section">Sec. 202. Treatment of HSA after death of account beneficiary.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H33543AD3FC66453682DF44BB23212436" level="section">Sec. 203. Purchase of health insurance from HSA account.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE584510E34D140B58594BBD0122A1A40" level="section">Sec. 204. Publishing of cash price for care paid through health savings accounts.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6EEA4CC6128148F198AB76F545630F37" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Health Care Tax credits</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9972D8E148054B57B13E7C2B21414ADF" level="section">Sec. 211. Limited application of PPACA health premium credit.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCCD09FA228B9433EBAF3229C5C73EA14" level="section">Sec. 212. New HSA credit.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H5B872ABB75A54DA5AC10CA884607FDFF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that there is a need for legislation providing temporary transition funding for those who lose health insurance subsidies in the aftermath of a Supreme Court decision in favor of the plaintiffs-appellants in the case of King v. Burwell.</text>
		</section><title id="HB7A6F07B7B934122B6C328F3E871CDE8"><enum>I</enum><header>Health Reform</header>
 <section id="H4229FF121E6240F480AA295F0ECAAA5D"><enum>100.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HD8521DA85223497A88E4D58454E21F21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Patient-grant electing State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>patient-grant electing State</term> means an electing State that specifies under section 102(a)(4)(B) that it will carry out section 102(b) itself (and not to have section 102(b) carried out by means of the credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0B9635A4A5E42AD89FC0573535A55E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>CHIP</header><text>The term <term>CHIP</term> means the children’s health insurance program established under title XXI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9982AE786DBF4D8E8D9C38C1BEBC85DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Creditable coverage</header><text>The term <term>creditable coverage</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2704(c)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-3">42 U.S.C. 300gg–3(c)(1)</external-xref>), as in effect as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26CE5A32676D4A0B813DE59B23F013F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Default health insurance coverage</header><text>The term <term>default health insurance coverage</term> has the meaning given such term in section 104(c)(2).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C66402000F34DE89E1DA2B8EC9BF14E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deposit qualifying resident</header><text>The term <term>deposit qualifying resident</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102(b)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC303456FD3814376969323A120846A62"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Electing state</header><text>The term <term>electing State</term> means a State that elects under section 101(a)(3) the alternative option described in section 102.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5D098CFCD2584B099C7C6B7F8AFBDF45"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Health insurance coverage</header><text>The term <term>health insurance coverage</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2791(b)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB23BE2558C7849FABC7EBFF3E77724F9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Health savings account; HSA</header><text>The terms <term>health savings account</term> and <term>HSA</term> mean a health savings account established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H08AF10FABE204705BC1D4FEC71A0286E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Health savings deposit</header><text>The term <term>health savings deposit</term> means a deposit made into a health savings account pursuant to section 102.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6E0DFB9AE20E44D3B9896F37D6B6E034"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Medicaid</header><text>The term <term>Medicaid</term> means the program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H392D535261BC4B2EAE0249137866BB75"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Medicare</header><text>The term <term>Medicare</term> means the program under part A or B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6963A270596F43D2847589D76A72D28C"><enum>(12)</enum><header>PPACA</header><text>The term <term>PPACA</term> means the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), as in effect before the date of the enactment of this Act, unless otherwise specified.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFC56E9351CEC43BCA277C61F471327FA"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Qualified health plan coverage</header><text>The term <term>qualified health plan coverage</term> means, with respect to residents of a State, health insurance coverage that meets applicable standards under State law, which standards need not be the same as that previously required of qualified health plans under title I of PPACA, and includes a high deductible health plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and includes coverage under a group health plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4AE39E2EFB994331BB6DDFE39B91AE4E"><enum>(14)</enum><header> Qualified resident</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified resident</term> means, with respect to a State for a month, an individual who is a resident of the State as of the first day of the month and is a citizen or national of the United States or otherwise lawfully residing in the State under color of law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF9F77D31C62543F5A2405BA1A62FCA87"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9A0B112345464DB38D0500DE89126543"><enum>(16)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the 50 States and the District of Columbia.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9EF101A6287040628BEADBA652918089"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Uninsured</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>uninsured</term> means, with respect to an individual, that the individual does not have creditable coverage.</text> </paragraph></section><subtitle id="H255C200526F6492DBD1E3D682E494076"><enum>A</enum><header>Insurance Reforms</header> <section id="H35C16F6D52E44CED9B70174B0583B7B0"><enum>101.</enum><header>State options in response to Burwell decision</header> <subsection id="H49FA6E1CD3C14F909B35428BBF394D99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State may elect, through written notice to the Secretary after the date of the enactment of this Act and in accordance with this subtitle, one of the following three options in relation to the implementation of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act after the decision of the Supreme Court in King v. Burwell:</text>
						<paragraph id="HA619006530354F8E95E0BF192DD7C9C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Continuing implementation of PPACA, including Federal subsidies through a State-established
 Exchange</header><text>Under current law, the State establishing a health insurance Exchange under title I of PPACA, which thereby permits the continuation of Federal premium and cost-sharing subsidies for coverage offered through the Exchange as well as continuation of insurance and other requirements under such title.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HBFF3B4DAFA644931A80F53E211EB1872"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rejection of PPACA, including elimination of Federal subsidies now provided through Federally
 established Exchange</header><text>Under current law, the State not establishing such an Exchange, potentially resulting, post-Burwell, in the loss of such Federal premium and cost-sharing subsidies and the continued application of other requirements under such title.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HDD734734A3754740B31AF23BFDB40010"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Establishing new State and market-based alternative, with alternative per capita Federal deposit
 system</header><text>The State implementing the alternative option described in section 102, which includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HE6669760EC494472B390108D5D1CFAA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the waiver of most requirements imposed under such title; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4592EDA4A9BE4645B7BCC674D8343FDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of a new, HSA- and market-based deposit system for individuals who do not otherwise qualify for Federal or State subsidies for health benefits coverage.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">If a State fails to make an election described in this subsection, the State shall be deemed to
			 have made the election described in paragraph (2). A State may, through
			 written notice to the Secretary, change an election previously made under
 this subsection.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H814BD07522824B59A6F0DFB85786C149"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relation to current Medicaid ACA coverage option</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to change the option of a State with respect to the implementation of Medicaid ACA coverage under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395a">42 U.S.C. 1395a(a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII)</external-xref>), except that a State that elects not to provide medical assistance to individuals under such section may make such individuals deposit qualifying residents under this title.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="HDAAC536C37164F12AF23FA01D3E07F86"><enum>102.</enum><header>State alternative option</header>
 <subsection id="H9DEC7EBC51B54C08BE81F440BEB56FFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State that elects under section 101(a)(3) the alternative option under this section, subject to subsection (d) and section 105, the following shall apply:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD945E98E189A45789B4250C92B76085C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No Federal Exchange</header><text>The Federal Government shall not establish or maintain an Exchange in the State under title I of PPACA.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HE22C4901982E45BB9ADF516B03D8EEBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elimination of individual and employer shared responsibility for health care tax requirements for
 residents and employees in State</header><text>The individual and employer health care responsibilities under the amendments made by title I of PPACA (including under sections 5000A and 4980H of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) shall no longer apply pursuant to section 106 with respect to individuals who are residents of such State and with respect to individuals who are employed in such State, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1818151B33394AD8B625E138D428125C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Modification of insurance requirements</header><text>Except as specifically provided in this title, the requirements under title I of PPACA (including amendments made by such title) relating to health insurance coverage offered in the State shall not apply except to the extent specified by the State.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H11272E9ACCF941C8A8D1832B467C89A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>New deposit system through funding HSAs</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE844DB49FA564DF7A0B8801D4C3F2C71"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Deposit qualifying residents (as defined in subsection (b)(2)) who are residing in the State are eligible for a deposit to a health savings account that may be used for premiums and cost-sharing for health insurance coverage in accordance with subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB20F9114066F46A5A20EF538170AB115"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State specification of manner of carrying out HSA deposit system (patient-grant electing state)</header><text>In making the election under this subsection, a State shall specify whether the State will carry out subsection (b) or if such subsection shall be carried out by means of the credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48CB000E46894041B60D8C6A43E3E7EC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional amounts for population health initiatives for State administered HSA deposit system</header><text>A patient-grant electing State (as defined in section 100(1)) is entitled to receive additional funding under subsection (c) for population health initiatives.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC55BE69B0E74D67911223A62661E298"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposit through payment into HSA for deposit qualifying residents</header>
 <paragraph id="H38AF3C39C11B4C3E968287D9C8ECF011"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The subsidies described in subsection (a)(4) for an electing State shall be furnished for each deposit qualifying resident through the deposit of a contribution into an HSA of the individual in the amount determined under section 103.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1227C673A7394132A38B24CACA403286"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposit qualifying resident defined</header><text>In this title, the term <term>deposit qualifying resident</term> means, with respect to a State and a month, an individual—</text> <subparagraph id="HE9EB61182F294728A1C05917A38042F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is a qualified resident (as defined in section 100(14)) of the State as of the first day of the month (or such other day in the month as the Secretary may specify);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29237F903F444B078B63D5041EF1F640"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to whom an HSA has been established, which HSA may have been established by the State in carrying out this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44F3553F792849F1B129C8FE5A79B0FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who is enrolled in qualified health plan coverage (as defined in section 100(13)), which enrollment may have been effected by the State in carrying out this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E26741B5D9446D78C9E2C00568610B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>who is not eligible for coverage under Medicare, is not enrolled for benefits under Medicaid or CHIP, and is not enrolled for benefits under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code (relating to TRICARE), or title 39 of such Code (relating to veterans’ benefits) or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5 of such Code (relating to the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54FE0CB513EC424FA74DE1E9C9F104BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payment administration</header>
 <subparagraph id="H766CF96FA51B4FA4A25E80DCF77ED38C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an electing State that elects to carry out this subsection through the State, the Secretary shall provide for payment to the State in amounts and in a time and manner sufficient to permit the State to make timely monthly contributions to HSAs under this subsection. The Secretary may provide for payment to the State using the payment methodology described in subsection (d) of section 1903 of the Social Security Act for payments under subsection (a) of such section (applied without regard to any State matching requirement) and may condition such payments upon the provision of such information as the Secretary may require to ensure the proper payments under this subsection. As a condition of receiving payment under this section, a State shall submit such information, in such form, and manner, as the Secretary shall specify, including information necessary to make the computations of amounts under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9DA9B84E39A40E2A0ED9D98B386A34D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal</header><text>In the case of a State electing to carry out this subsection other than through the State, subsidies described in subsection (a)(4) shall be provided through a refundable tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H002502EDEFF6433EBF2D3963FD301EBD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed—</text> <subparagraph id="HE53E3DAD2CBE4EDFA10312A1079B5046"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to prevent an individual from affirmatively electing not to have an HSA established on the individual’s behalf and not to be enrolled under health insurance coverage;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE517F4A6D7AB4C738F18BD050F11D114"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (A), to prevent a State from establishing an HSA for each deposit qualifying resident who does not otherwise have an HSA;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEABC6F08AD04C2C9FB8463F0D3BBB21"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (A), to prevent a State from establishing a mechanism whereby individuals who would be deposit qualifying residents but for paragraph (2)(C) are enrolled under health insurance coverage; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E7EB3CE9751441D960919795484C447"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to prevent a State from changing its State Medicaid plan to eliminate coverage under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII)</external-xref>), in order that individuals otherwise covered under such section may qualify for subsidies under this section.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H565833409DA043989CD78141A5A3B7EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Population health initiative funding</header>
 <paragraph id="HADAE7C26C4EF4F55AB9EA44207D78E48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an electing State for a year, the State is entitled to receive payment from the Secretary of Health and Human Services after the end of such year in an amount equal to 2 percent of the actual aggregate amount deposited under subsection (b) into HSAs for residents of the State for the year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H319DF32E5F78491CB1753D64C64C37BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts paid to a State under paragraph (1) may only be used for population health initiatives (as defined by the Secretary).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H248BAE79C0364D6D834349C7C857767D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entitlement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) constitutes budget authority in advance of appropriations Acts and represents the obligation of the Federal Government to provide for the payment to States of amounts provided under such paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29F11CEB62C94900B91A0CCD281F3087"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requiring rules for computing usual, customary, and reasonable (UCR) prices</header><text>As a condition for a State’s election of the alternative option under this section, the State must provide, through its department of insurance or equivalent agency, for establishment of rules to carry out section 1867(j)(1)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act, as added by section 121(a)(2).</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="HE7402C9B5578422AA90856866E222A4B"><enum>103.</enum><header>Computation of monthly HSA deposit amount for deposit qualifying residents</header>
					<subsection id="H88931928162C4F71939319984FA251AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Computation</header>
 <paragraph id="HF86545443335401399DAAFD2C6CA6886"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop a standardized methodology to determine consistent with this section a monthly HSA deposit amount for deposit qualifying residents in each State for months in each year. Subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), such amount shall be equal to <fraction>1/12</fraction> of the average per capita annual amount computed under subsection (b) for the State for the year, as adjusted for the deposit qualifying resident involved—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8A326571A1A54BA2B96228BF300F655E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for age and geographic area under subsection (c); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE28CB317AA94A42B197E4D531A88031"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for income under subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB919A430189E461FB46D2C98C97D5BA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No variation based on how deposit amount distributed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such amount shall be the same for a deposit qualifying individual without regard to whether the contribution to the individual’s HSA is made by a State under this section or by the Federal Government through the operation of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H93CB897E2C77454CB79FDB0F1AAFCEAF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Patient-grant electing State has flexibility to maintain level of benefits for current ACA
 beneficiaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A patient-grant electing State may elect to increase the amount of the deposit for all deposit qualifying individuals under this section to the amounts that the Secretary estimates would have been paid with respect to such individuals under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and section 1402 of PPACA if those sections had remained in effect in the State with respect to such individuals. Such election shall be made for a year and shall continue from year to year until the State elects to terminate such election.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDDCD2CAAB2C476490F95FC307142E3F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rule for partial deposit for low-income individuals with employer-sponsored insurance (ESI)</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who is covered under a group health plan and with respect to such coverage there is a contribution by an employer which is excluded from the individual’s gross income under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, insofar as the individual is a deposit qualifying resident, the amount of the deposit with respect to the individual shall be reduced, in a manner specified by the Secretary in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and taking into account the income of the individual’s household, by an amount that is approximately equivalent to the estimated amount of the reduction in the amount of income tax resulting from such exclusion (and any reduction in taxes imposed by chapter 21 or chapter 2 of such Code by reason of any exclusion of such contributions from wages and self employment income).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3425792409B04FFBA8EC3EFA9B31D395"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Computation of unadjusted per capita</header>
						<paragraph id="HF0B492D1DDE547A8A175D42F7E4C505D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>For States that continue PPACA Medicaid coverage</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA385A80B98994DCF952047E32CDB1D78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State that provides medical assistance under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII)</external-xref>) during a year, subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), the Secretary shall compute an average per capita annual amount for the State for the year equal to—</text>
 <clause id="H6341F5DF946948AA8A1F36E3DF73AA0B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount specified in subparagraph (B), divided by</text> </clause><clause id="H9B26461FBAAA435EB1B8DCD03A7CC4CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average monthly number of deposit qualifying residents of the State in the year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F6B5CEBDA1448049E23571F3B8933B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount based on PPACA projected Federal expenditures</header><text>The amount specified in this subparagraph for a State for a year is 95 percent of the Secretary’s estimate of the total payments that would have been made (assuming the existence of a State established Exchange in the State) under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and under section 1402 of PPACA with respect to all qualified residents in the State in the year (or taxable year ending with such year, if applicable).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0F8D181581D4027AE30EBEB9D8155B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>For States that do not provide PPACA Medicaid coverage</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9D87BAC7584F4C04A0378F75A4857531"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a State not described in paragraph (1) for a year, subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), the Secretary shall compute an average per capita annual amount for the State for the year equal to—</text>
 <clause id="H8CC0732083F24B499F6D30C180ACC0C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount specified in subparagraph (B) for the State and year, divided by</text> </clause><clause id="H4CEA5821069F41018BD4BB0B08D1254E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average monthly number of deposit qualifying residents of the State in the year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48912D45C58B435A845F7E6A148FFC00"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount based on PPACA and Medicaid projected Federal expenditures</header><text>The amount specified in this subparagraph for a State for a year is equal to the sum of—</text> <clause id="H5183CB74AC1246A5A3475408C28FD4F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">95 percent of the Secretary’s estimate of the total payments that would have been made (assuming the existence of a State-established Exchange in the State) under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and under section 1402 of PPACA with respect to all qualified residents in the year (or taxable year ending with such year, if applicable); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H25F626D2E0594026950A2990A4F204E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary’s estimate of the total payments that would have been made to the State under title XIX of the Social Security Act for individuals eligible to be covered under section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i)(VIII) of the Social Security Act assuming the election of a State to provide Medicaid coverage under such section and assuming the applicable Federal medical assistance percentage were 95 percent with respect to such individuals.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C9C81DCB0D4449979B00E31500C59A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Budget neutral adjustment in payments to take into account election of higher deposits to maintain
 ACA subsidy levels</header><text>If a State makes the election described in subsection (a)(3) with respect to providing higher deposit amounts for certain individuals described in such subsection, then the Secretary shall adjust the average per capita annual amount under paragraph (1) or (2), as applicable to the State, by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H92643237E21641DB8BE41AB5CDA3009F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing the amount described in paragraph (1)(B) (or, if applicable, paragraph (2)(B)(i)) by an amount equal to 95 percent of the aggregate increased deposit level attributable to subsection (a)(3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D180CE37F304572BB017CFFC48BA440"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not counting such an individual as a qualifying resident for purposes of paragraph (1)(A)(ii) (or, if applicable, paragraph (2)(A)(ii)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H952D2AE47F2542B79D6ED4B7F6B12306"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adjustment for costs of partial deposits for low-income ESI individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall adjust the average per capita annual amount under paragraph (1) or (2), as applicable to the State, by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1538A583C1134DF2955E1ED54131709D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing the amount described in paragraph (1)(B) (or, if applicable, paragraph (2)(B)(i)) by an amount equal to 95 percent of the amount of payments under this section that are attributable to individuals described in subsection (a)(4); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCB7190506E74818B19288BA16363D84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not counting any individual described in subsection (a)(4) as a qualifying resident for purposes of paragraph (1)(A)(ii) (or, if applicable, paragraph (2)(A)(ii)).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A6DE4539A5B46988922E14D76514B03"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adjustment for age, geographic area, and income distribution within state</header>
 <paragraph id="HF379C5761D794B149316C79F2DADB2C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall apply such adjustments to the per capita amount computed under subsection (b) as is designed to take into account, in a budget neutral manner and based on the costs estimated under paragraph (2), actuarial differences in health care costs attributable to individuals in different age categories and different geographic locations of primary residences in the State and the reductions based on income under subsection (d). No such adjustment shall be made based on sex.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H866D5CD560044DCAA4244CF64B86E728"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data on average costs of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 15 before the beginning of each year, the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall estimate the average cost of health care for such year for individuals under 65 years of age and may estimate how such average varies for different populations of individuals under age 65. The adjustments under paragraph (1) for age categories for a year shall be based on such estimates made. Not later than such date, the Secretary shall prescribe tables for purposes of making adjustments based on age under paragraph (1) based on such determination which shall apply for taxable years beginning in the succeeding calendar year.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15D1BFBCC5684218822676D25294FE35"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Income-Related phase-Out</header>
 <paragraph id="HE6D0A3128F174EA9ACD43E7CA9757251"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The per capita amount as computed under subsection (b) and adjusted and applied to a deposit qualifying individual under subsection (c) shall be multiplied by a phase-out percentage equal to 100 percent reduced by 1 percentage point for each $1,000 (or fraction thereof) by which the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for the taxable year exceeds $90,000 (or, in the case of a joint return, $150,000), multiplied, for a taxable year ending in a year beginning after December 31, 2015, by the cost-of-living adjustment for the year as described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1">section 1(f)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, but substituting <quote>2015</quote> for <quote>1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DAB34DFB067487B806F4B7AF0DF4EBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Zero per capita amount for married filing separately</header><text>The per capita amount under this section shall be zero in the case of a married couple filing separately.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3730DACEEEC14DC7BC7517F576EBC340"><enum>104.</enum><header>State options for improved access to health insurance coverage in each State</header>
					<subsection id="HF683D3E58F3B46AF83E5013F03CC2DAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State options To improve access</header>
 <paragraph id="HDCEC1A2306504B3F9607BFA8A959FC92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State may carry out any of the functions described in succeeding subsections in order to improve the access of residents of the State to health insurance coverage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0FF8DE70BBF425BBEECE459B6565B2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repurposing State Exchanges</header><text>A State may use or adapt an Exchange that the State has established under title I of PPACA to carry out the any of such functions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18540961B83340038DEC6B9495573A43"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Repurposing federal exchange</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government shall make available to States current capabilities of the Federal Exchange, including the Federal Data Services Hub and Agent Broker Portal, to the extent requested by a State for activities related to enrollment of citizens of the State into health insurance coverage.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EDBD23364CD4331B704A24FF6E5F93D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transparency portal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State may establish and operate an open and transparent marketplace mechanism whereby qualified residents of the State can readily compare, through the use of the Internet, the benefits and prices between different health insurance coverage options made available to them.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H397CAA5AFE41457CBAC6A755DF32F7C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enrollment, subject to individual opt-Out</header>
 <paragraph id="HEA610FBD0ABC49E5BF9766256A7381D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a State may provide for the enrollment of qualified residents of the State who are uninsured in default health insurance coverage offered under section 105(c) and establishing an HSA for such residents who do not have an HSA unless the resident has affirmatively elected not to be so enrolled and not to have an HSA, respectively. Any such enrollment under this paragraph shall be coordinated with the annual open enrollment periods provided under section 105(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60FBDC1AC7E1447091394A40F82F5DA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Simple process for individuals to opt-out</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of a State providing for the enrollment function described in paragraph (1), the State must establish an easy-to-use and transparent means by which individuals may elect not to be enrolled in default health insurance coverage or to have an HSA established on the individual’s behalf, or both.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71F9CF780B80423BADE934D9267EA303"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Risk mitigation mechanisms and reinsurance and risk-Corridor programs</header>
 <paragraph id="H6C65F1488F6746AFB6BB286265D8B6D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, a State may establish—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3C62EAD732E84B8CA8863F33A39836D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mechanisms for risk mitigation or risk adjustment in order to limit volatility in the premiums based on health experience to class-average premiums; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9F1AF3FBC6D452FABACBD230E14E9AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a reinsurance and risk-corridor program that involves no Federal funds with respect to coverage both in the individual market and in the small group market.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H602B216E7FAE481F985372BD506AD795"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basis for risk adjustment</header><text>Mechanisms and programs under paragraph (1) may be based on the health status score of each individual enrolled in health insurance coverage in the individual market and not solely based on the aggregate risk of the risk pool with respect to each plan of health insurance coverage.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF8708A33230E4467A6260DE6CB07B825"><enum>105.</enum><header>Expanded access and patient protections</header>
 <subsection id="H2BF948C299D547C694F6E8C533214332"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition for the election of the alternative option under section 102 in a State, the State must meet the requirements of this section.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H08FDB533EF254EF68AB4B323864807A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual and other open enrollment periods</header>
 <paragraph id="HECCE33AF85C84E6B9D13539DBA5A5B3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The State shall require, in connection with the offering of health insurance coverage in the individual market in the State, that there are uniform annual and other open enrollment periods (such as those for changes in life events, changes in State residency, and involuntary changes in eligibility for coverage under a group health plan) in order to permit qualified residents to enroll in qualified health plan coverage in a manner that promotes continuity of coverage. Such periods shall be consistent with the open enrollment periods established under title I of PPACA, as in effect before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DF156EBE19C4A7A8B0494FA13A9E50B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial open enrollment period</header><text>In addition, the State shall establish an initial open enrollment period during which qualified residents may enroll in qualified health plan coverage without the imposition of any underwriting described in subsection (d)(1)(B). Such period shall be a period of not less than 45 days and shall provide for enrollment to become effective on January 1 of the year specified by the State in which such State election first becomes effective.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F6B33D9368140AC95A3F011E107BCFC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Offering of default health insurance coverage</header>
 <paragraph id="H15A96E0C826E45FCAB05757BA0349F19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The State shall provide for the offering, through one or more contracts with one or more health insurance issuers in the State, of default health insurance coverage (as defined in paragraph (2)) to qualified residents of the State who are otherwise uninsured. Such default coverage shall be made available on a continuous basis during a year. Failure of a qualified resident to enroll in such default coverage or other creditable coverage during a year results in adverse consequences described in subsection (d)(1)(B) to the resident.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BFB3D3BC51B4E3E8BF28F2F8C8BEFC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Default health insurance plan defined</header><text>In this title, the term <term>default health insurance plan</term> means, with respect to a State, health insurance coverage that—</text> <subparagraph id="HEDD74156F962470AACF4082575C1FCA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a high deductible health plan (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) with prescription drug coverage limited to generic drugs for a limited number of chronic conditions (commonly referred to as tier I pharmacy benefit);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E21B3505F6A480DA7BFB401C017F17D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets such requirements as may apply to qualify for the payment of plan premiums from a health savings account under section 223 of such Code (such as age-related premiums and limitation on imposition of preexisting condition exclusions);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89D0D92B00CA4209BADE1C8DB3BAEDBE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has a provider network for covered benefits that is adequate (as determined consistent with guidelines issued by the Secretary) to ensure access to health benefits under such plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73231524B9514A619C9649063D9DEE79"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for coverage of childhood immunizations without cost sharing requirements to the extent such immunizations have in effect a recommendation from the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention with respect to the individual involved; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDC92E59C646431EAAC0D414FAEAB413"><enum>(E)</enum><text>meets such other requirements as the State may specify.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F66C318EFE445ABB545A6B05C0C78AB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consequences respecting continuous coverage</header> <paragraph id="H431EF12DFF4C4175BAC121D083252636"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consequences for not maintaining continuous coverage</header> <subparagraph id="H52C81AC287194F4B8FD3CB42949850CF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Avoidance of consequences by maintaining continuous coverage</header><text>All qualified residents of a State are eligible during the initial open enrollment period provided under subsection (b)(2) to enroll in qualified health plan coverage and, thereafter, to maintain continuous coverage in order to avoid the adverse consequences described in the succeeding provisions of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0973BD39215949948A0FA2A9EDBC3AA7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Underwriting permitted</header><text>In the case of a qualified resident of the State who fails to maintain continuous creditable coverage (not including any breaks in coverage of less than 63 days), the State shall—</text>
 <clause id="H120ABF35EF0B4C7B9B759AD52D030FAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit health insurance issuers for the period specified in subparagraph (C) to medically underwrite (through denial of health insurance coverage, application of preexisting condition limitations, differential premiums, or otherwise) the issuance of health insurance coverage, other than with respect to the issuance of default health insurance coverage under subsection (c); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H11E5F4A624554461BEDF5A15376C0333"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require health insurance issuers, during the subsequent 2-year period in the case of issuance of health insurance coverage other than such default health insurance coverage, to impose a monthly late enrollment penalty in the amount specified in subparagraph (D)(i) and to remit the amount of such penalty collected to the Federal Treasury in accordance with subparagraph (D)(ii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB692719BD6704F6CB005B8FBA454B9C9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Period for application of underwriting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (B)(i), the period specified in this subparagraph is, with respect to an uninsured individual as of a date, a period (not to exceed 18 months) equivalent to number of months in the previous 18-month period in which the individual did not have continuous creditable coverage described in subparagraph (B).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5486960DDB264FA7B6D9591EE0893889"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Monthly late enrollment penalty amount</header>
 <clause id="HF1EA54CC203E438FAB2133007DEA987C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The monthly late enrollment penalty amount specified in this clause for a month is equal to the lesser of 10 percent or the product of—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H964E5BEEFD4842EFBD4A78CBD3E0DAA7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>1 percent of the monthly premium amount for default health insurance coverage with respect to the individual and month; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC95115584C20457F8185337EE615C6BF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of months during the 2-year period (preceding the 18-month period described in subparagraph (B)(i)) in which the resident failed to maintain the continuous coverage described in paragraph (1)(D).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3CC0C382F8FC45CEA33C85F628B50727"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Payment of penalty amount to Federal Treasury</header><text>The amount of the monthly late enrollment penalty collected under this subparagraph shall be paid to the Treasury of the United States in a form and manner specified by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD3AEA17C27D4517869F9353B253066B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Changes in enrollment permitted without medical underwriting during annual open enrollment periods
			 for those maintaining continuous coverage</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7853218CFE7845DE861A5587E4335269"><enum>(A)</enum><header>During second open enrollment period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified resident who maintains continuous coverage (not including any breaks in coverage of less than 63 days) during the period after the initial open enrollment period under subsection (b)(2) and through the second annual open enrollment period established by the State consistent with subsection (b)(1), the State shall require health insurance issuers to permit such residents during such second annual open enrollment period to change the qualified health plan coverage in which the individual is enrolled without medical underwriting.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F7E2F5674DF4C38BBD75F131A64D8CA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>During third and subsequent open enrollment periods</header><text>In the case of a qualified resident who maintains continuous coverage for a period of 18 months or longer (not including any breaks in coverage of less than 63 days) as of the initial date of a third or subsequent annual open enrollment period established by the State under subsection (b)(1), the State shall require health insurance issuers to permit such residents during such an open enrollment period to change the qualified health plan coverage in which the individual is enrolled without medical underwriting.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H48DCAA81FBF3493FBF94D9EEEF22AB2D"><enum>106.</enum><header>Sunsetting certain ACA provisions; continuation of policies of covering adult children and not
			 applying lifetime or annual limits</header>
 <subsection id="HB1382ED32A2E4A49872345BBAB05F42A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (including the amendments made by such title) shall not apply (and the provisions of law amended by such title are restored as if such title had not been enacted) in the case of any State that does not have in effect the election described in section 101(a)(1).</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H11E5211D3F1F47D6B6F5477284F7937E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuation of policies for extension of dependent coverage for adult children and prohibition of
 lifetime and annual coverage limits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9DAF17D2C54A4F98B4D4755B2C5CFE05"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 2711 of the Public Health Service Act (relating to no lifetime or annual limits).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99B86E1A53B44AF8AB990CAC9740911B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 2714 of such Act (relating to extension of dependent coverage).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B4D2DFBA34B496085256D4FEC27A67F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continuation of policies for certain States operating Exchanges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to health insurance coverage in a State that has in effect the election described in section 101(a)(1).</text>
					</subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="HE8CFB514AE2A4E8E83729E54B46035F7"><enum>B</enum><header>Medicaid</header>
				<section id="HEBF2432B65BF48C3A2B6F08CA5DEB99B"><enum>111.</enum><header>Application of health savings accounts in relation to Medicaid</header>
 <subsection id="HA1120747E7B44C809A5CCB38742A000C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC33407C6361F431E997240F28D847AE7" style="OLC">
							<section id="H428AB055C31D403AAAB7FE70ACA58F64"><enum>1947.</enum><header>Provisions relating to health savings accounts</header>
								<subsection id="HD9A152065F7E432E8C5E0748CF372951"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disregarding HSA in determining assets and income for Medicaid eligibility determinations other
 than for long-Term care services</header><text>The assets in a health savings account under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and any income from such assets in such account, shall be disregarded for purposes of determining eligibility and amount of medical assistance under this title, other than for purposes of determining eligibility and the amount of medical assistance for long-term care services (described in section 1917(c)(1)(C)(i)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H355A27F17F85451B86F25488B847BA77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notifications of Treasury of Medicaid eligibility</header><text>In order to meet the requirements of this subsection (for purposes of section 1902(a)(78)), a State shall provide such notice to the Secretary of the Treasury, in such form and manner as such Secretary shall specify, as may be necessary to identify individuals who are eligible for, and receiving, medical assistance under this title in a month in order to carry out <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD0564949C72A416BBFB57519CA9409F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of notification requirement through State plan</header><text>Section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (77) the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4B14784FAA94B798BD2413A7F40141C" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3105FDB2B3864571BB33BF3275C3CD4D"><enum>(78)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for notice in accordance with section 1947(b) to the Secretary of the Treasury of the identity of individuals who are determined eligible for (and receiving) medical assistance under this title;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H45558A9CE9D3444C8FC327BED43D1D29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to eligibility determinations with respect to medical assistance for periods beginning on or after January 1, 2016.</text>
					</subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="HA9B9858C17824BE2BED7C7F43B3771DB"><enum>C</enum><header>Provider Price Transparency</header>
				<section id="H5A2F62BD09E4484AB81C959D93FBA83C"><enum>121.</enum><header>Ensuring access to emergency services without excessive charges for out-of-network services</header>
 <subsection id="H448D15C68510432A971D7A72BB69110D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1867 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395dd">42 U.S.C. 1395dd</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H93ECB961378B405AB4E6F45DC73247DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE2AB175F4B1449FA9BACBF86836D8D0" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HA8D5DB74BA5F4F5AA41C0514B281CC0C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Enforcement with respect to excessive charges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital, physician, or other entity that violates the requirements of subsection (j)(1) with respect to the furnishing of items and services is subject to a civil money penalty of not more than $25,000 for each such violation. The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty under this paragraph in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A1DEB4BD35849FE9B4F36B4EFB45092"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8A0664158CA472AB6B43C7A1BD8ADC6" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H5AB234EB7E144DB9AD711A7DD9469A1D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Protections against excessive out-of-Network charges for emergency services</header> <paragraph id="HCBB11F0254A243C1BA9BD45E97E0F804"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If items or services to screen or treat an emergency medical condition are furnished under this section in a participating hospital with respect to an individual and the individual has not, directly or through a health insurance issuer, group health plan, or other third party, negotiated a payment rate for such items and services, subject to paragraph (2), the charges imposed for such items and services may not be in excess of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H68C82AF0874E41DB99C0D68E6CA7E0C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Physicians’ and other professional services</header><text>For physicians’ services or services of a health care provider to which <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(e)(9)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 applies (and including drugs and biologicals furnished in conjunction with and billed as part of such services), the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="HFF8F2C0F37CB45129D64686FF0CA1014"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the cash price for such services posted pursuant to such section; or</text> </clause><clause id="H09C738518F164D3B8B70D38031D4D2B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>85 percent of the usual, customary, and reasonable (UCR) charge for such services, as determined under rules established by the department of insurance for the State in which the services are furnished.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A70D73830E24F3A886B1BB024214165"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hospital services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For inpatient and outpatient hospital services for which payment rates are established under this title (and including drugs and biologicals furnished in conjunction with and billed as part of such services), the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="H5B00BCCCCA9A474099B4911BE60DB56F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cash price for such services posted pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(e)(9)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HED45443EA6054FF58CE86981317AB49C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>110 percent of the payment rate applicable to such services in the case of an individual entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB94F3C34BFAF47CC98A2EB4AD7BF2452"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Drugs and biologicals</header><text>For drugs and other pharmaceuticals furnished to which a previous subparagraph does not apply, the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="H5AA8451B183944B0A39CE6650B598E65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>twice the acquisition cost to the hospital or other provider for the dose involved; or</text> </clause><clause id="H035ADCA37872402E9BD10C000CD6EA10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the acquisition cost to the hospital or other provider plus $250.</text>
											</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The dollar amount in clause (ii) shall be increased from year to year (beginning with the year
			 after
			 the first year in which this subsection applies) by the same percentage as
			 the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban
			 consumers (all items; U.S. city average) for the year involved (as
			 determined by the Secretary). Any such dollar amount as so increased that
			 is not a multiple of $5 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $5
 (or, if a multiple of $2.50, to the next highest multiple of $5).</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE520715E5208469F87F39D4737D990C2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Other items and services</header><text>For any other items or services, the lesser of—</text> <clause id="HF7EDACC89A464FB6AE20E8E046A89076"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cash price for such items and services posted pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(e)(9)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8CC04234863D4E55830C61B61B2D4FDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>110 percent of the payment basis that would be applicable to payment for such items and services under this title in the case of an individual entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6B38EC349AC45849E8C66BE2353D8DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for items and services furnished as a bundle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of items and services for which there is a single price for a group or bundle of such items and services, the maximum charge permitted under paragraph (1) may not exceed the lesser of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6FE5553B82344568995CF1BB6EDD580A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the price charged for such bundled services; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C05C68A5BE549E19A5BB4305D02494F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the aggregate of the maximum charges permitted under paragraph (1) with respect to items and services included in such bundle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9D71A6DD8B940AD97725573794326D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reference to price disclosure provision</header><text>For requirements relating to the posting of health care prices on the Internet, see <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(e)(9)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by section 204(a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H35F8D626FEEF41D08FF23E1E8F40AC00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to charges imposed for items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2016.</text>
					</subsection></section></subtitle></title><title id="H3AC6E88EA8DA472D8C3F9EF562BFAC3C"><enum>II</enum><header>Reform of Tax Provisions Relating to Health Care</header>
			<subtitle id="HD442AC9B598C49658C269F9E80D388ED"><enum>A</enum><header>Promotion of Health Savings Accounts</header>
				<section id="H5DBA7BA87C714B3EA9271259BAFDD9F2"><enum>201.</enum><header>Repeal of high deductible health plan requirement</header>
 <subsection id="H7D1C63BD34FE4DCE9A840CD978B02148"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H1A6DB8CB9BBA4CFBB2DAD90164B81AB1" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HCEDF152F103C435D8A5443E14FB6E45C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deduction allowed</header><text>In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a deduction for a taxable year an amount equal to the aggregate amount paid in cash during such taxable year by or on behalf of such individual to a health savings account of such individual.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subsection><subsection id="H6950CC9278D54F3F85B0BD67541959F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H3F5025E401F04EFEB98F9D4BDDD74ADC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 223(b)(1) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>that the individual is an eligible individual</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A7FD63001AF4B23A6116588F398C690"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 223(b)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>under a high deductible health plan</quote> each place it appears.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0B23A37BECD4B49A27340472B21EA84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 223(b) of such Code is amended by striking paragraph (8).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AF7556CCDB6417DAF90AFD8D83D5FBE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 223 of such Code is amended by striking subsection (c) and redesignating subsections (d) through (h) as subsections (c) through (g), respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CEC187E41194B30B0CE4B11C46E9B6D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 223(c)(1)(A) of such Code, as redesignated by this Act, is amended by striking <quote>subsection (f)(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (e)(5)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7C7AA6CB07644099E20A8E0C568A2A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 223(f)(1) of such Code, as redesignated by this Act, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAF7A2C653C5B4A8482D1C13D200A9B71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsections (b)(2) and (c)(2)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)(2)</quote>,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9897DBD53EC34531AA408CF5C61687E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (B) thereof—</quote> and all that follows through the end of subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>subparagraph (B) thereof <quote>calendar year 1997</quote>.</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H252400D773C74EA2A5D0992D068F7133"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>amounts under subsections (b)(2) and (c)(2)(A)</quote> in the second sentence and inserting <quote>amounts under subsection (b)(2)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF0AF2202A774D2D9F9C4D9EDBDDF199"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Section 26(b)(2)(U) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 223(f)(4)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 223(e)(4)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H885F24678A774F68B08CCF67E12CE3EA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Sections 35(g)(3), 220(f)(5)(A), 848(e)(1)(B)(v), 4973(a)(5), and 6051(a)(12) of such Code are each amended by striking <quote>section 223(d)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>section 223(c)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3041D795B95549C38CC5BA7BAFD4A39C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Section 106(d)(1) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HA76F6E2DE6874576A92AA251B10911BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>who is an eligible individual (as defined in section 223(c)(1))</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8310AEE6FB8C40C1985DC5094F5FF885"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 223(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 223(c)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85A1332B67E84980B7899C89EE587B3F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Section 408(d)(9) of such Code is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7F4E490CF84341ED913D2E3FAF46D1EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) by striking <quote>who is an eligible individual (as defined in section 223(c)) and</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB98A6E061AC5401CA3A8978BAC8651E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) by striking <quote>computed on the basis of the type of coverage under the high deductible health plan covering the individual at the time of the qualified HSA funding distribution</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56A52970A5E747ACA86D26B24FEAA787"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Section 877A(g)(6) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>223(f)(4)</quote> and inserting <quote>223(e)(4)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE9521976CF4141825ABE1D9478CC8C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Section 4973(g) of such Code is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H202B169423B744F5B014CE40927151FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 223(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 223(c)</quote>,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F934E5CBEBF403FAB5725FA69ADAC47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>223(f)(5)</quote> in paragraph (1) and inserting <quote>223(e)(5)</quote>,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0509FFDA0203492594387903E9B1449F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>section 223(f)(2)</quote> in paragraph (2) and inserting <quote>section 223(e)(2)</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB68C302E671C48E4B22455484961A933"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 223(f)(3)</quote> in the second sentence and inserting <quote>section 223(e)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC32CEC7BEE04685B3A6709E6D4B3132"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Section 4975 of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H3CDFCC8FB8634645ACD4A7E6024EED8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(6)—</text>
 <clause id="H820BD8A6A9084047AEF8A2ECFB2BDF13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 223(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 223(c)</quote>, and</text> </clause><clause id="H476312C860354F8DBB0BDD4F21CEDD00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 223(e)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 223(d)(2)</quote>, and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E92496AB98D434C926428EA11B38AE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1)(E), by striking <quote>section 223(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 223(c)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H122542826A7A4A24952502151502346F"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Section 6693(a)(2)(C) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 223(h)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 223(g)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7E0D4F108624F1F891698F7C41ABBF9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H6E8B82331031458CA681998C45462EA8"><enum>202.</enum><header>Treatment of HSA after death of account beneficiary</header> <subsection id="H71EDF5BB0C7840DEAABE769606F11DEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223(e)(8)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as redesignated by section 201(c)(3) of this Act, is amended to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08AF512702C34B9281278656A663C38D" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HAB16ED59A2E149029E9A91988FFC9CE5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Treatment after death of account beneficiary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual acquires an account beneficiary’s interest in a health savings account by reason of the death of the account beneficiary, such health savings account shall be treated as if the individual were the account beneficiary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD742C67C0B0246FAB4A099D1546A05AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to interests acquired after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="H33543AD3FC66453682DF44BB23212436"><enum>203.</enum><header>Purchase of health insurance from HSA account</header>
 <subsection id="HE256932D65CA41368CE0B0D161D9BB2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as redesignated by section 201(c)(3), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H58DB7E4BA77F4468B84B4031D126B765"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEC399C616C564DB28EF9084E59DCF818"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (iii),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FB114E2F8C94013BC6B13080E672C8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of clause (iv) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC20F1FAEC8C49B5B7F78DAF8A41675F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC59F89F0193647D5ABF429F9346B668E" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H9514384E788445A68BB3059488736310"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of health insurance that meets the requirements of subparagraph (D).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6EE894BA63647A980F8871D25CB68D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55B29882F69E4017B18BBBD6C2EA4255" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HA9E1C20EC41D4F2686CB34270847DF58"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of this subparagraph are as follows:</text> <clause id="HEFEF4D710B674BF29CFBD936CC009E18"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Open enrollment without preexisting condition exclusions</header><text>The health insurance coverage or group health plan must permit, during uniform initial and annual open enrollment periods and for special enrollment periods (such as the loss of coverage through the loss of employment) specified in carrying out section 105(b) of the <short-title>Patient Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>, any individual who has period of continuous coverage of not less than 18 months who is otherwise eligible to enroll under such coverage or plan to be so enrolled without the imposition of any preexisting condition exclusion (as defined for purposes of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act).</text>
									</clause><clause id="H193FFA2C86F7457BBD9F5F16A7FDB4A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Class based premiums for basic benefits</header>
 <subclause id="H69DB88FF3DA4472DB96DAB2D77DE3EC9"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The premium for such coverage or plan shall be established based on class-average status and may vary by age and geographic area, but may not vary based upon the health status of the individual, except that in the case of an individual without continuous coverage for a period of 42 months, such premium may be increased above the class-average in the manner and for the time period specified in section 105(d)(1)(A)(ii) of the <short-title>Patient Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H37E269C027E745CD84A73C06368D7E80"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Establishment of actuarial tables</header><text>In carrying out subclause (I), the Secretary shall enter into a contract with a qualified organization, such as the Academy of Actuaries, for the development of actuarial tables to calculate class-average rates based on age and geography.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6867ECDBC09F4FC9883D638700013A22"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Continuous coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, an individual shall be considered to have continuous coverage as of a time if the individual has no continuous period in which the individual is uninsured (as defined in section 100 of the <short-title>Patient Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>) for longer than 63 days beginning after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A04B1D8C13449808A35A294B3E8E79F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HE584510E34D140B58594BBD0122A1A40"><enum>204.</enum><header>Publishing of cash price for care paid through health savings accounts</header> <subsection id="H285F73666E9044D7A25B05ED772953EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as redesignated by section 201(c)(3), is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5973D42C66AC42FCACF03B44B1CF0BD3" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="HF598D7292ECD4E5E80D6324C6068153E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Cash price transparency required for payments to health care providers</header>
 <subparagraph id="H191E097613564E518724C1ACB3A13553"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A payment to a health care provider with respect to the furnishing of health care items and services by such provider shall not be treated as a qualified medical expense unless the health care provider provides for continuing disclosure (such as through posting on a publicly accessible website) of the cash price the health care provider charges for the furnishing of such items and services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FEB811A09DC49A2861E94AD22A9FB90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form of disclosure</header><text>The disclosure of prices under this subsection shall be in a form and manner specified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary, and shall be designed—</text>
 <clause id="H250C924EECA44531865AD236FD5B120F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to establish a single price for related items and services in a manner similar to the manner in which pricing and payment for such items and services is provided under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H607D5557A8C24EA193DA925F6ED39862"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to make it easy for consumers to compare the prices for similar items and services furnished by different providers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBE29558097845418F2CCD919A901E03"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Failure to furnish services or charge in excess of stated price</header><text>A health care provider shall be treated as not meeting the requirement of subparagraph (A), in the case of items and services for which the provider is disclosing a cash price, if the provider—</text>
 <clause id="H4BB5D2F2F94846558CDD1AF4045A77DC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>refuses to furnish such items or services at the price listed, or</text> </clause><clause id="HA42E46D6514748D0963B080A11039D97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>charges more than the price listed for the furnishing of the items and services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCD8354ADCDE24F119CC3142E346971E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>If the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines that a health care provider has not provided for continuing disclosure of the cash price of health care provider charges under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223(e)(9)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the Secretary may instruct the Secretary of the Treasury that payments made to such provider shall be not treated, for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as an amount used for a qualified medical expense for a period of not to exceed 1 year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H14A6D2590AB049909729CFA511105BDD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text> </subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="H6EEA4CC6128148F198AB76F545630F37"><enum>B</enum><header>Health Care Tax credits</header> <section commented="no" id="H9972D8E148054B57B13E7C2B21414ADF"><enum>211.</enum><header>Limited application of PPACA health premium credit</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HEC9BC28D712747A087C001E909FA76DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC17574C2A534BA583EF1B42CEFE6338" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9D16BEEA345848768BE4C7F2A7FDBC64"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Special rule for residents of States continuing PPACA implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section to any individual who is not a qualified resident (as defined in section 100(14) of the <short-title>Patient Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>) of a State that has elected the option under section 101(a)(1) of such Act in relation to the implementation of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0393C967B064983BBEC6C18B34083AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HCCD09FA228B9433EBAF3229C5C73EA14"><enum>212.</enum><header>New HSA credit</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HE9221DE909404BC294C937895B41AA76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4CD0A9AC0E348F5AAE6AC22C4BCD0C8" style="OLC">
							<section commented="no" id="H401003AC495545DEAEB09C181964285E"><enum>36C.</enum><header>HSA credit</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H6232B8E051A24E68AF6009C8E882731F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subtitle for any taxable year, an amount equal to the HSA credit amount of the individual for the taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H72E96EA6BF904938A84EDD0269DD959E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifying individual</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualifying individual</term> means, with respect to any month, any individual who for such month is deposit qualifying resident (as defined in section 102(b)(2) of the <short-title>Patient Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>) of a State described in section 101(a)(3) of such Act that elects to have section 102(b) of such Act carried out by way of the credit determined under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H339FF0BE0C7A48B7BC3C0E794975C2C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>HSA credit amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>HSA credit amount</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, the sum of the HSA deposit amounts determined under section 103 of the <short-title>Patient Freedom Act of 2015</short-title> with respect to the individual for all months ending during the taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4C43B24B20EF4FFAB5082FC73773DD93"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9A3CCA7FC2EB4C03B1AA9C55C8C247E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reconciliation of credit and advance credit</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3653BEBC33EA4009BC765A2BDDA07DAC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Excess advance payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the advance payments to an individual for a taxable year under subsection (e) exceed the credit allowed by this section with respect to such individual for such taxable year, the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year shall be increased by the amount of such excess.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1F25A988094F496AB18DA518D15E32DD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Advance payment shortfall</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the credit allowed by this section (determined without regard to this subparagraph) with respect to an individual for a taxable year exceeds the advance payments to such individual for such taxable year under subsection (e), the Secretary shall, in lieu of a credit allowed against the tax imposed by this subtitle, make a payment on behalf of such individual to such individual’s health savings account in an amount equal to such excess.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H21BE40DC90E44EC9BD65B5CA9226C90E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Married couples must file joint return</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the taxpayer is married (within the meaning of section 7703) at the close of the taxable year, the credit shall be allowed under this section only if the taxpayer and the taxpayer’s spouse file a joint return for the taxable year.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBF162CFAD5C847EE858F0BAE7F0B271A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Advance payment program</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H7ED51712B0F6454D9CEA17B3A79627B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall establish a program—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H480622DBE7344E01A36BC5C9106EB20F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to make advance determinations with respect to the eligibility of individuals for the credit allowed under this section, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H722B25A8936A4705B28AD9AC7C1FC522"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to make advance payments of the credit allowed under this section directly to the health savings account of any such individual so eligible.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBE25CE4391804DB4BFBE188461A7D75D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such program shall be established under rules similar to the rules of section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, except that advance determinations and advance payments shall be made on request of the individual with respect to whom the determination is to be made and taking into account the enrollment process (including any opt-out election under such process) established under section 104(c)(1) of the <short-title>Patient Freedom Act of 2015</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD7FDD736FB7F4141BD2A78A24AEE8A7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such subpart is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53A5AE8F434B4B79A16F14DA6A59A142" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 36C. HSA credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HEDDBA1F382E04E7BB46EBE5CF9E92D31"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text>
					</subsection></section></subtitle></title></legis-body>
</bill>


