<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H31B8C4B6413E42A39213C01395F31DAE" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2044 IH: Freedom from Government Competition Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2044</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000560">Mr. Graves of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require that the Federal Government procure from the private sector the goods and services necessary for the operations and management of certain Government agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7586D5E8F22E409E8A971F91A3BAC97D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0F56F61B81DF42D5A1C9EA706D921A80" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freedom from Government Competition Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD145D0E1890B4E628C4639B30F8C7D67"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
<paragraph id="H911D3F19CD3047F891752ADE03CDF3CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Private sector business concerns, which are free to respond to the private or public demands of the marketplace, constitute the strength of the United States economic system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DF65F6BE85E4DAD8B9A994C4296DF9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Competitive private enterprises are the most productive, efficient, and effective sources of goods and services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCA0AA6C55AE64C58B60DE04A5C35B01F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Unfair Government competition with the private sector of the economy is detrimental to the United States economic system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD980FB7766BE4076882140FFF171C379"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Unfair Government competition with the private sector of the economy is at an unacceptably high level, both in scope and in dollar volume.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H77670774F93D420486B9197C3CB29C4F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Current law and policy have failed to address adequately the problem of unfair Government competition with the private sector of the economy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A72950A5A8244529A8AAFB15AE463C1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>It is in the public interest that the Federal Government establish a consistent policy to rely on the private sector of the economy to provide goods and services necessary for or beneficial to the operation and management of Federal agencies and to avoid unfair Government competition with the private sector of the economy.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HE4F85CD9432E4CDA88AB9ECFD9EC56CE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>agency</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H466F844138FF48FCAE717EF826C3440C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an executive department as defined by section 101 of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBCAD367237514449AEC7ACC77D730A4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a military department as defined by section 102 of such title; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H809171013D04472385464FD47507626E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an independent establishment as defined by section 104(l) of such title.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H27D4E40615D24BB78178BF3CFACB9BF0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Procurement from private sources</header>
<subsection id="H57E363E488DF46DE9F64BB92013E6AB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the process of governing, the Federal Government should not compete with its citizens. The competitive enterprise system, characterized by individual freedom and initiative, is the primary source of national economic strength. In recognition of this principle, it has been and continues to be the general policy of the Federal Government—</text> <paragraph id="H35E2E329BF3848FCBA9C9AFFE4625615"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to rely on commercial sources to supply the products and services the Government needs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDA541DEA61A8409FB5276D46E3BC5572"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to refrain from providing a product or service if the product or service can be procured more economically from a commercial source; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF381E0949EC41E9B5C5BEC86572F00F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to utilize Federal employees to perform inherently governmental functions (as that term is defined in section 5 of the Federal Activities Inventory Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/270">Public Law 105–270</external-xref>; 112 Stat. 2384)).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H97EA4A7A5386436B8EDCB172725DF675"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, each agency shall obtain all goods and services necessary for or beneficial to the accomplishment of its authorized functions by procurement from private sources.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5C4BDCA65F3D4631B916EACDE32C6814"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>Subsection (b) shall not apply to an agency with respect to goods or services if—</text>
<paragraph id="HF4719C76C31440B99877B0066B449E57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the goods or services are required by law to be produced or performed, respectively, by the agency; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFDC6D22155842418D8B8453DFB5BA1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the head of the agency determines and certifies to Congress in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC7F2AEB7CE574F66A9C8254EDCA152AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal Government production, manufacture, or provision of a good or service is necessary for the national defense or homeland security;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3A9A73DF3084C00851159FEDC214D39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a good or service is so inherently governmental in nature that it is in the public interest to require production or performance, respectively, by Government employees; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA26F1047562349EC8EB221AC8B0F5C99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>there is no private source capable of providing the good or service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5235C65BA3B34B79853697A633551018"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Method of procurement</header><text>The provision of goods and services not exempt by subsection (c)(1) or (c)(2) shall be performed by an entity in the private sector through—</text>
<paragraph id="H588B75110B69465AB306DEB66A3C10A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the divestiture of Federal involvement in the provision of a good or service;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB03B14AA064343B78A4FCFC6867B43D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the award of a contract to an entity in the private sector, using competitive procedures, as defined in section 152 of title 41, United States Code, and section 2302 of title 10, United States Code; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC7960E88D76043609684E1B27432A713"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conducting a public-private competitive sourcing analysis in accordance with the procedures established by the Office of Management and Budget and determining that using the assets, facilities, and performance of the private sector is in the best interest of the United States and that production or performance, respectively, by the private sector provides the best value to the taxpayer.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEF3AFB543EA34DC585A906D66B655A7A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contracted activities</header><text>The head of an agency may utilize Federal employees to provide goods or services previously provided by an entity in the private sector upon completion of a public-private competitive sourcing analysis described in subsection (d)(3), and after making a determination that the provision of such goods or services by Federal employees provides the best value to the taxpayer.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA1D79E06D2E54B76B148620A67BAE8AA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall promulgate such regulations as the Director considers necessary to carry out this section. In promulgating such regulations, the Director shall assure that any State or territory, or political subdivision of a State or territory, complies with the policy and implements the requirements of this section when expending Federal funds.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7F7334A3B13D412AB44B3FE04A9C28E9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study and report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in conjunction with the Comptroller General of the United States, shall carry out a study to evaluate the activities carried out in each agency, including those identified as commercial and inherently governmental in nature in the inventory prepared pursuant to the Federal Activities Inventory Reform Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/270">Public Law 105–270</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/501">31 U.S.C. 501</external-xref> note) and shall transmit a report to the Congress prior to June 30 of each year. The report shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="H444E18B380EC4CAAA266C25A536E20D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation of the justification for exempting activities pursuant to section 4(c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5032DA2B71B9421E919FA9A162CCFA4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a schedule for the transfer of commercial activities to the private sector, pursuant to section 4(d), to be completed within 5 years after the date on which such report is transmitted to the Congress.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


