<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE1F8DB5C06064136906B7DF7F50815C9" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1625 IH: Insider Trading Prohibition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1625</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150325">March 25, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to prohibit certain securities trading and related communications by those who possess material, nonpublic information.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HDF0B859141D749EF93FA8B686CD66A32" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE32E1E36FF5943F2AC82A3F4FA0C8758" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Insider Trading Prohibition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7422C5EB65D94F709762CDC2101FB4AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on insider trading</header> <subsection id="HE01258D3520D4977A56F236BBF033C92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding after section 16 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H218EAA6BF7E94D95913CB300CD492974" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H3EF1120408C94C74ACB6627BCE3B97D7"><enum>16A.</enum><header>Prohibition on insider trading</header> 
<subsection id="HAA4CCBB432674DBBA2AADAFA1424C092"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition against trading securities while in possession of material, nonpublic information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person, directly or indirectly, to purchase, sell, or enter into, or cause the purchase or sale of or entry into, any security, security-based swap, or security-based swap agreement, while in possession of material, nonpublic information relating to such security, security-based swap, or security-based swap agreement, or relating to the market for such security, security-based swap, or security-based swap agreement, if such person knows, or recklessly disregards, that such information has been obtained wrongfully, or that such purchase, sale, or entry would constitute a wrongful use of such information.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HAE1F593775BD46EDA3B6690FDDF83B80" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition against the wrongful communication of certain material, nonpublic information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person whose own purchase or sale of a security, security-based swap, or entry into a security-based swap agreement would violate subsection (a) (referred to in this subsection as the ‘communicating person’), wrongfully to communicate material, nonpublic information relating to such security, security-based swap, or security-based swap agreement, or relating to the market for such security, security-based swap, or security-based swap agreement, to any other person if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H46DF128EBEB141E5B23285C09E656092" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the other person—</text> <subparagraph id="HA85DB7BBDA0A4CB8AC49FC420AFA0BD2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchases, sells, or causes the purchase or sale of, any security or security-based swap or enters into or causes the entry into any security-based swap agreement, to which such communication relates; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F9852C27D7D4AF88EC2F01D3EAFB413" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>communicates the information to another person who makes or causes such a purchase, sale, or entry while in possession of such information; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EDCA5288BAE4F90AFE4CFEC19AC0DA2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such a purchase, sale, or entry while in possession of such information is reasonably foreseeable.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE44F5CC687314397A7EE04435A0E4F0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standard and knowledge requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="H8433DD60D19F40E7BA5FD03C2A85D37E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, trading while in possession of material, nonpublic information under subsection (a) or communicating material nonpublic information under subsection (b) is wrongful only if the information has been obtained by, or its communication or use would constitute, directly or indirectly—</text> <subparagraph id="H458BE2AD28304E739088FFC1874F6AFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>theft, bribery, misrepresentation, or espionage (through electronic or other means);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H64D94B96DABA419BAC363B98FEE6D000"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a violation of any Federal law protecting computer data or the intellectual property or privacy of computer users; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08C8B7E39DED42769C93AF9C1A31922D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conversion, misappropriation, or other unauthorized and deceptive taking of such information, or a breach of any fiduciary duty or any other personal or other relationship of trust and confidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF2695211EE44AECB5DE232307EAA0FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Knowledge requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall not be necessary that the person trading while in possession of such information (as proscribed by subsection (a)), or making the communication (as proscribed by subsection (b)), know the specific means by which the information was obtained or communicated, or whether any personal benefit was paid or promised by or to any person in the chain of communication, so long as the person trading while in possession of such information or making the communication, as the case may be, was aware, or recklessly disregarded that such information was wrongfully obtained or communicated.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HF491B045BBDA47269B4882CDE2D2EC7F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Derivative liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 20(a), no person shall be liable under this section solely by reason of the fact that such person controls or employs a person who has violated this section, if such controlling person or employer did not participate in, profit from, or directly or indirectly induce the acts constituting the violation of this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFD5FD582892044FDAB9A9D56EE1364E9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exempted transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may, by rule, exempt any person, security, or transaction, or any class persons securities, or transactions, from any or all of the provisions of this section, upon such terms and conditions as it considers necessary or appropriate, if the Commission determines that such action is not inconsistent with the purposes of this section. The prohibitions of this section shall not apply to any person who acts at the specific direction of, and solely for the account of, a person whose own securities trading, or communications of material, nonpublic information, would be lawful under this section.</text> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H09E4F4ED20C043AF8B4C44D529A89E9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>) is further amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H420E56A5650047C894BEE75C340B2EB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 21(d)(2), by inserting <quote>or section 16A,</quote> after <quote>section 10(b) of this title</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1762EA3E20A4843B8E442AECBFCA42A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 21A—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H83B5FEB8103143F082A1D165DEED141A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(1), by inserting <quote>and section 16A, </quote> after <quote>thereunder,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC82112B665C146118F0A9F413A2ADE1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h)(1), by inserting <quote>and section 16A, </quote> after <quote>thereunder,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50CDB792991A4E51AE0467E678367AEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 21C(f), by inserting <quote>or section 16A,</quote> after <quote>section 10(b)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

