<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H783331B2AE7940B6BF8682FE88359FFF" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2926 IH: Arizona Sonoran Desert Heritage Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2926</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To designate certain public lands in the Sonoran Desert of the State of Arizona as national
			 conservation areas and wilderness areas, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1B8700279D2B4DC5A168D20FDBED63C9" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9DD1FB92C9BC4119BD61FA07445AA55F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; Table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H9408B973079C4B268A86B644CD80EEB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Arizona Sonoran Desert Heritage Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HE9D4727B83A844709BC80580DDF948D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H9DD1FB92C9BC4119BD61FA07445AA55F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; Table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H406074B612494CD9BB300FA3C230B385" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3DACDD30AD3041F2B71A83116C1A7CB2" level="section">Sec. 3. Belmont-Harquahala and Gila Bend National Conservation Areas.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4BBAE10C9605419BA3770BD996FE544C" level="section">Sec. 4. Designation of wilderness areas.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDEACFB4014C14AC2A7A6374DAAD840CF" level="section">Sec. 5. Special management areas.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H185EC54AAF3A401E826D1CE351B4A446" level="section">Sec. 6. Maps and legal descriptions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD9FC45E5A7EB484BABA74B8AE0CAEBDA" level="section">Sec. 7. Management of national conservation areas, wilderness areas, and special management areas.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8A6765E9F8E44F6EA8F266289E4EB7DB" level="section">Sec. 8. Acquisition of land.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H719D9782356D44F6B7453CB8AD4490AF" level="section">Sec. 9. Border security.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H33B089D55E314A9EA215989EFC4FFAE3" level="section">Sec. 10. Water rights.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H406074B612494CD9BB300FA3C230B385"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H2740CF18B36A468CA5776F01E897F656"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community of Indians which is recognized as eligible by the Secretary for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD587A3F5623D4D05828FAD6DB075C627"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <term>management plan</term> means the management plan developed under section 3 for each national conservation area and section 5 for each special management area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFACB0C61D8E74693B9BE96E9265574EA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Sonoran Desert Heritage Act</quote> and dated May 6, 2013.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0A535F884594491A97E49AC83000ECA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National conservation areas</header><text>The term <term>National Conservation Areas</term> means the Belmont-Harquahala National Conservation Area and the Gila Bend National Conservation Area established by section 3.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAFBCCA4936B4610992AA01F8F1AB265"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public land</header><text>The term <term>public land</term> has the meaning given the term <term>public lands</term> in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F2EF43EAE6242A5AA1BCB1A59673C2F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FE3EFD4F3FC414B992381EC9532AF8E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Special management areas</header><text>The term <term>Special Management Areas</term> means the Sentinel Plain Special Management Area and the Rainbow Valley Special Management Area established by section 5.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF16D87CEB69476799EB41136578763B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Arizona.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6D1F79B4900441D868AE0A56E60144D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Wilderness areas</header><text>The term <term>Wilderness Areas</term> means the wilderness areas designated by section 4.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3DACDD30AD3041F2B71A83116C1A7CB2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Belmont-Harquahala and Gila Bend National Conservation Areas</header>
 <subsection id="H5460498657A34153BA9C43816593A05E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There are established in the State:</text> <paragraph id="HC36A41C9AC57457DBAE35BD9437F4D8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Belmont-harquahala national conservation area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Belmont-Harquahala National Conservation Area, consisting of approximately 276,100 acres, as generally depicted on the map.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC4E9F0AAB94F0ABC61E5D1E714B0BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gila bend national conservation area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Gila Bend National Conservation Area, consisting of approximately 406,298 acres, as generally depicted on the map.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1B283030F1E4B62B0EEEF52AC94800F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the National Conservation Areas is to conserve, and thereby to protect, restore, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the unique and important resources and values of the land, including the ecological, geological, cultural, archaeological, paleontological, natural, scientific, recreational, wilderness, wildlife, riparian, historical, educational, and scenic resources of the public land.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD2DDB116C151443C995630D2D931C309"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration of national conservation areas</header>
 <paragraph id="H937F762369B4476B8001EDE03DEA0FBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the National Conservation Areas—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB6B6732F96441C18D7EBB4CF10D27C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as components of the National Landscape Conservation System;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70ED80D873E1429490CB6E1056625E7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, and thereby protects, and enhances the resources and values of the National Conservation Areas described in subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37EF58194CA04E5A87E91D911FA49F46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <clause id="HE516C623D7DE4A73A408D9674877CA56"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H23BBE57D6830420DA78D5C54BEBADABA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>this Act; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5DBC594F68ED44C4BABF9CDC201A6397"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other applicable laws.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD26055D75ABB4FC7ACE3F761E98B48DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management plans</header>
 <subparagraph id="H914F6E2EB96D494D97F28EC25A0C20B6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop a comprehensive management plan for the long-term protection and management of each of the National Conservation Areas.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E51058DFC7F4501BA05B9CBA0F1CBCD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>Each management plan shall—</text> <clause id="H5CCD56C7B91649B89176E7C98B0DDF43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe the appropriate management and uses of the National Conservation Areas consistent with the conservation purpose as specified in subsections (b) and (c);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2B1D9C8D79A146C0BB6B93FB629C9889"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be developed with extensive public input; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6645C92D02A84D29A3E33669F821F48F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>take into consideration any information developed in studies of the land within the National Conservation Areas.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58643E9AD06C404282E1D51D336D0339"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Uses</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE1C08B17B5C1484795DC8CF9A3C2EB8A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall allow only such uses of the National Conservation Areas as the Secretary determines would further the conservation purpose for which the National Conservation Areas are established.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBADCF25110AA46B89C24004FB144A371"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of motorized vehicles</header>
 <clause id="H33F045CEEEC34F21B5236533D1564015"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clauses (ii) and (iii), use of motorized vehicles in the National Conservation Areas shall be allowed only—</text>
 <subclause id="HD2ABE74D61CF492BAE7430F6D66F7EDB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>before the effective date of each management plan prepared pursuant to paragraph (2), on roads and trails designated for use of motorized vehicles in the management plan that applies on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1F7FBEFDC55E44448573BDE99FFCBAD3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after the effective date of each management plan prepared pursuant to paragraph (2), on roads and trails designated for use of motorized vehicles in that management plan.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H5E880D7C161E48EEB928B86903138A03"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Administrative and emergency response use</header><text>Clause (i) shall not limit the use of motor vehicles in the National Conservation Areas for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB03B3ABBC3E04B30A9EC9E738FE74160"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This subparagraph shall not apply to the Wilderness Areas.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01FBE2C4F99A4F3199BE144CF302AC34"><enum>(C)</enum><header>New roads</header><text>No additional road shall be built within the National Conservation Areas after the date of enactment of this Act unless the road is identified in the Management Plans as necessary for public safety or resource protection.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4BBAE10C9605419BA3770BD996FE544C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of wilderness areas</header>
 <subsection id="HD5EF3857A845473CACD3E5D9E295250A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the following areas in the State are designated as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4FCEB44DCFB64BD29CBE285BD3D4104D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hummingbird springs wilderness addition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain public land in Maricopa County, Arizona, consisting of approximately 17,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which is incorporated in, and shall be considered to be a part of, the Hummingbird Springs Wilderness, as designated by section 101(a)(12) of the Arizona Desert Wilderness Act of 1990 (104 Stat. 4469).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95BE30BA44984567898C385852F1E931"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Woolsey peak wilderness addition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain public land in Maricopa County, Arizona, consisting of approximately 33,523 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which is incorporated in, and shall be considered to be a part of, the Woolsey Peak Wilderness, as designated by section 101(a)(15) of the Arizona Desert Wilderness Act of 1990 (104 Stat. 4469).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F833535793F4E44953C2A96CB0976B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Belmont mountains wilderness</header><text>Certain public land in Maricopa County, Arizona, comprising approximately 19,000 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Belmont Mountains Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7636F94A177640898F60B1E3934AC742"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Saddle mountain centennial wilderness</header><text>Certain public land in Maricopa County, Arizona, comprising approximately 24,200 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Saddle Mountain Centennial Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA42694784B8E45D781BD12FA4547EB49"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gila bend wilderness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain public land in Maricopa County, Arizona, comprising approximately 68,800 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Gila Bend Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46D16F0C79394A0EBE6E3F8271D1E778"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sonoran desert national monument wilderness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain public land in Maricopa County, Arizona, within the Sonoran Desert National Monument, comprising approximately 128,300 acres, as generally depicted on the map, which shall be known as the <quote>Sonoran Desert National Monument Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B3EFFF17F1742D8873FD225BB59A828"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Wilderness Areas designated by this Act shall be managed by the Secretary in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) and this Act, except that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7BFE07F77871479B8456689B82585A09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDE5ABF0751642549AEACD7AD3DAC088"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be considered to be a reference to the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDEACFB4014C14AC2A7A6374DAAD840CF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Special management areas</header>
 <subsection id="H03942EC993664977AE1481A99454B4A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There are established in the State:</text> <paragraph id="H8A7C4444CF5C4466B0AC2604C5BDF5B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sentinel plain special management area</header> <subparagraph id="H9E442AC19BCC4C03A9EA47301C994E9E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Boundary</header><text>The Sentinel Plain Special Management Area, consisting of approximately 120,600 acres, as generally depicted on the map.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB1D1279CC1D4D2BB4389F12EF51F42D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Sentinel Plain Special Management Area is to ensure ecological connectivity and movement of wildlife between the Barry M. Goldwater Air Force Range and the Gila Bend National Conservation Area; to secure native habitat for native species; and to provide recreation and development opportunities that are compatible with native species and with Department of Defense activities related to the Barry M. Goldwater Air Force Range.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D3E7F9D61744B5BAAEB802EAA88AF6D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rainbow valley special management area</header>
 <subparagraph id="H23246964DC074A50B091BC9855C39EA5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Boundary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Rainbow Valley Special Management Area, consisting of approximately 23,400 acres, as generally depicted on the map.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H188F26C06CE44510B8D1381F99ABE589"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Rainbow Valley Special Management Area is to ensure ecological connectivity and movement of wildlife between the Sierra Estrella Mountains and the Sonoran Desert National Monument.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE3A9A37C0AB4DB98864BB4D6A514FAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management plans</header>
 <paragraph id="HBF05817C82FC4E85A3CB50C5BB042641"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop for each of the Special Management Areas a comprehensive management plan for the long-term protection and management of that area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE3EA90B00C84A31A1A28C463B1AC48F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>Each management plan shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD36BAC94DC5D414D999BC76D4A78A024"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the appropriate uses and management of each special management area consistent with the conservation purpose as specified in section 5(a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2634FF8AFC14C3D80988F55D7B0C194"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be drafted with consultation from local, regional, and State jurisdictions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A70C150A42545209F7C0A9DA7341C78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be developed with extensive public input;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H522752C49E3940A6AC6CC9A87BB8A328"><enum>(D)</enum><text>take into consideration any information developed in studies and plans for the land within each special management area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H497BDA2015F7490895411BF216282251"><enum>(E)</enum><text>shall consider cooperative management alternatives between the Bureau of Land Management and local, regional, and State jurisdictions that further the purposes outlined in section 5(a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H101044CCAFE54722A838A3CD44BD16CE"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purposes of ensuring ecological connectivity and movement of wildlife through the Rainbow Valley and Sentinel Plain Special Management Areas, the management plans shall—</text>
 <clause id="H05F1D84240E14A569FE83D870BAAEA0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritize landscape permeability, wildlife connectivity and continued movement of wildlife between the Sierra Estrella Mountains and the Sonoran Desert National Monument across Rainbow Valley, and between the Barry M. Goldwater Air Force Range and the Gila Bend National Conservation Area across Sentinel Plain, respectively;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE31F58E1A3EB4CDCA94EC5E4B206360C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify the means to maintain permeability, connectivity and wildlife movement in the area including, but not limited to, wildlife crossing structures and other infrastructure improvements and the criteria to implement such alternatives;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H17533DA8A2E64931A15B921149F876CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>incorporate current scientific knowledge of wildlife movement for a variety of identified focal species; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4DD96C11127B48AB9173925C857CE3CA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>establish a monitoring program to determine the effectiveness of the plan for wildlife connectivity.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H185EC54AAF3A401E826D1CE351B4A446"><enum>6.</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header>
 <subsection id="HC9F9B7CE01854F87B126D3529CBF3F51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file maps and legal descriptions of the National Conservation Areas, the Wilderness Areas, and the Special Management Areas with—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC2D5F8F61375438E8477ADC5757695DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6452508ED8D84B7D9A93CE0BA077729C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H180F4B4CEEC640D7A3A43D962A4A6350"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under subsection (a) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H355E58848EE74AFFBE7713725EECB92D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under subsection (a) shall be available for public inspection in—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9F2CEAB92CBF4B7DBA6D957D16766B37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D79C56C78A0428FA6C41FBD2DEBD10C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the appropriate office of the Bureau of Land Management in the State.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD9FC45E5A7EB484BABA74B8AE0CAEBDA"><enum>7.</enum><header>Management of national conservation areas, wilderness areas, and special management areas</header>
 <subsection id="H574C204964BF4FE3808C701FC3134FFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Military use</header><text>Nothing in this Act restricts or precludes—</text> <paragraph id="H53304F64B35646B093CB6690436C9113"><enum>(1)</enum><text>overflights of military aircraft over the National Conservation Areas, Wilderness Areas, or Special Management Areas designated by this Act including military overflights that can be seen or heard within the areas;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0CD10EE980B4BDC93476CDF154F4020"><enum>(2)</enum><text>flight testing and evaluation; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H15C87CBD6A854FBB936C966CCACACC6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the designation or creation of new units of special use airspace, or the establishment of military flight training routes, over the National Conservation Areas, Wilderness Areas, or Special Management Areas.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43D1DE2674DE40D49C7718C71C28DA1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hunting, fish and wildlife</header>
 <paragraph id="H8830D3CD4B6F487D9232ADEEA973BE8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hunting</header><text>Nothing in this section or the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) shall affect hunting, under applicable State and Federal laws and regulations, within a covered wilderness area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CB6DF0382E0484294B1F1ABD72F377A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>As provided in section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this section or the Wilderness Act shall be construed as affecting the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State of Arizona with respect to fish and wildlife in the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82043FE61F03467093A3026DDBEF5624"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Wildlife management</header><text>Management activities to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and the habitats to support such populations may be carried out within a covered wilderness area, where consistent with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) and other applicable laws.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C8D66CDDC394A8BBE6D24602DD62396"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cooperative agreement</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the State of Arizona for management of fish and wildlife within a covered wilderness area. The cooperative agreement shall specify the terms and conditions under which the State or a designee of the State may use wildlife management activities in a covered wilderness area consistent with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), and other applicable laws.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0187F1B3A0CA46EAB3F5146FF72C9FD4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Livestock grazing</header>
 <paragraph id="H85799BEFB70E4139A487C4913561A436"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grazing in national conservation areas or special management areas</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall issue and administer any grazing leases or permits in the National Conservation Areas or Special Management Areas in accordance with the laws (including regulations) applicable to the issuance and administration of such leases and permits on other land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A562C14EEAE44C4B9B89B003868AF53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grazing in wilderness areas</header><text>The grazing of livestock in a wilderness area designated by this Act, if established as of the date of enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAB0539ACC06B4A238D1327CE0FF960C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to any reasonable regulations, policies, and practices that the Secretary determines to be necessary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31AA3D556D4645EAB779469EA82106CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H0F4D2606A83F4EBE8C60829DCC97F6AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4A0F8DE4B17E4462AB7EFA25CBF46F10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in Appendix A of the report of the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress (H. Rept. 101–405).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3533E372DD1E4E8084CC5D2FE13D1C85"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Access to private lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide any owner of private property—</text> <paragraph id="H357D77E5A38D402B8A31FC9BD2F88BD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within the boundary of a national conservation area or special management area designated by this Act adequate access to the property; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF868B1D4657F4760BDEC40297CAF4814"><enum>(2)</enum><text>within the boundary of a wilderness area designated by this Act adequate access to the property in accordance with section 5(a) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1134">16 U.S.C. 1134(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A4ECA87497346EEB6AD9D9FA5192F1D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Valid existing rights</header><text>The designation of the National Conservation Areas, Wilderness Areas, and Special Management Areas is subject to valid rights in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0E312F621AF648FA8C78944C60435412"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all public land within the National Conservation Areas, Wilderness Areas, and Special Management Areas, and all land and interests in land acquired by the United States within the National Conservation Areas, Wilderness Areas, or Special Management Areas is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFC923AF188D44B9F9F0BD4CC87C64EAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC164A0210EDD426EBCDC54A28C222F29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H754A2337E95A4DEA9BD142D9ECEB6134"><enum>(3)</enum><text>right-of-way, leasing, or disposition under all laws relating to—</text> <subparagraph id="HEB15F641B8594BBE9E833A7BA43D6F8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>minerals; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D1CBEFF1371444E9D44287FC239ADE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>solar, wind, and geothermal energy.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H817AED15BC7249ECB318DA22598FB6FA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No buffer zones</header> <paragraph id="H97ED286962A64F9A955381736E610295"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this subtitle creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the National Conservation Areas, Wilderness Areas, or Special Management Areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B025D9F133F43E59B0E7BCB28F6D9F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities outside national conservation areas, wilderness areas, and special management areas</header><text>The fact that an activity or use on land outside a National Conservation Area, Wilderness Area, or Special Management Area can be seen or heard within the area shall not preclude the activity or use outside the boundary of the areas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF731D01898994400BB0254CBED3B4D21"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Fire, insects, and diseases</header><text>Subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be desirable and appropriate, the Secretary may undertake such measures as are necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFCD14255F8544BABB3426F1ECA108A39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the Wilderness Areas, in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E1ABD7515114F659A7CE0824E95D8D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (1), in the National Conservation Areas and Special Management Areas in accordance with this Act and any other applicable laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3BBB6846A50A4D3DBF18785BC7A52E0E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Invasive species and noxious weeds</header><text>In accordance with any applicable laws and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be desirable and appropriate, the Secretary may prescribe measures to control nonnative invasive plants and noxious weeds within the National Conservation Areas and Special Management Areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6018D600D04345D3A0BA931401306376"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Native American uses and interests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure access to the National Conservation Areas, Wilderness Areas, and Special Management Areas by members of an Indian tribe for traditional cultural purposes, including spiritual or food-gathering activities. In implementing this paragraph, the Secretary, upon the request of an Indian tribe, may temporarily close to the general public use of one or more specific portions of a national conservation area, wilderness area, or special management area in order to protect the privacy of traditional cultural activities in such areas by members of the Indian tribe. Any such closure shall be made to affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum period necessary for such purposes. Such access shall be consistent with the purpose and intent of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>), commonly referred to as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5A753721F6EC4DDB96488C9133FAE96B"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Utility rights-of-Way</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes the Secretary from renewing an existing utility right-of-way through a national conservation area or special management area in a manner that minimizes harm to the purposes of the national conservation area or special management area described in subsection (b) and section 5(a)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2B509EC12920412E86D357E54084319B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="H44E100454D28479D83AC216EEA264432"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5160672A88AC43A2A3E29DF9020E3E49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other applicable law; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AF9C5EA35E248CCA3FCA2BCD8D5F301"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CDC8C9006C748B788A8C1A545988BEA"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Maintenance of existing communications facilities</header><text>The provisions of this Act shall not be construed to prevent—</text> <paragraph id="HA098B42500B74755B2F57D35DCD5077E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the maintenance of communications facilities, in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act and located in a national conservation area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93CCB367A489446DBD2F3A0577187005"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limited motorized access to such facilities when non-motorized access means are not reasonably available or when time is of the essence, subject to such conditions as the Secretary considers to be desirable.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8052EC4A7F5C40FB94939F592E067CFF"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Maintenance of agua caliente road</header><text>In preparing resource management and travel management plans for the Lower Sonoran Field Office, the Secretary shall provide for protection of the existing, low-standard (BLM Maintenance Level 3) Agua Caliente which provides access to the wilderness and high conservation value lands designated by this Act, and shall assure that the wilderness environment and atmosphere enjoyed by users of this road, which Congress finds is well-matched to the rugged and wild character of the wilderness beyond the roadside, is not degraded by incompatible development within the road corridor or by improvement of the road itself other than as he determines necessary for public safety.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8A6765E9F8E44F6EA8F266289E4EB7DB"><enum>8.</enum><header>Acquisition of land</header>
 <subsection id="H0F59A657D5B24334A90EBE2D69B983C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may acquire non-public land within the boundaries of the National Conservation Areas, the Wilderness Areas, or the Special Management Areas established by this Act only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H96843F47D1A147A58E215822737D16F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Land acquired under this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="H731D8A90A7374DE3B28F329449FE48BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">become part of the National Conservation Areas, the Wilderness Areas, or the Special Management Areas involved; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDFBCDE4BB10452E8F208A320462D3F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with this Act and any other applicable laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H719D9782356D44F6B7453CB8AD4490AF"><enum>9.</enum><header>Border security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAA6178CBD77E4FCB9E1FDB90399290B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevents the Secretary of Homeland Security from undertaking law enforcement and border security activities—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD2C47DC76B594AC2916920064D1A811D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the National Conservation Areas and Special Management Areas outside the Wilderness Areas, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF410590BB5784A2C80F3536E22E4917C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with section 4(c) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(c)</external-xref>), within the Wilderness Areas, including the ability to use motorized access within a Wilderness Area while in pursuit of a suspect;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6254C4102FA4126A4AEFEF6EC9950D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects the 2006 Memorandum of Understanding among the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Agriculture regarding cooperative national security and counterterrorism efforts on public land along the borders of the United States; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD5C6FB51FE94E889627932EB9B92612"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prevents the Secretary of Homeland Security from conducting any low-level overflights over the National Conservation Areas and Special Management Areas or the Wilderness Areas that may be necessary for law enforcement and border security purposes.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H33B089D55E314A9EA215989EFC4FFAE3"><enum>10.</enum><header>Water rights</header>
 <subsection id="H464AF4BC5CB94E18A8CBA97179CB6A91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation of rights</header><text>With respect to each wilderness area designated by this Act, Congress hereby reserves a quantity of water sufficient to fulfill the purposes of this Act. The priority date of such reserved rights shall be the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA2542EE077E844C9A403F9E436E9C612"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Protection of rights</header><text>The Secretary and all other officers of the United States shall take steps necessary to protect the rights reserved by subsection (a), including the filing by the Secretary of a claim for the quantification of such rights in any present or future appropriate stream adjudication in the courts of the State in which the United States is or may be joined and which is conducted in accordance with the McCarran Amendment (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/666">43 U.S.C. 666</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFE64BA2D1EC44FF2997BBDFF75086B8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No relinquishment or reduction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as a relinquishment or reduction of any water rights reserved or appropriated by the United States in the State on or before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA57D0B9034464894B58A8A4B25F94190"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reservation for specific wilderness</header><text>The Federal water rights reserved by this section are specific to the wilderness located in the State designated by this Act. Nothing in this section related to reserved Federal water rights shall be construed as establishing a precedent with regard to any future designations, nor shall it constitute an interpretation of any other Act or any designation made pursuant thereto.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


