<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB2B6F25EE27C4453A3CF0CD5D162D674" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1420 IH: National Traumatic Brain Injury Research and Treatment Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1420</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to establish a surveillance system regarding traumatic brain injury, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H1BCB5CA37611436082E4A36572BA2653" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1F1998D7390F4288B918B224B3CFD6F4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Traumatic Brain Injury Research and Treatment Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H74D3FA424C0D4BFEB2918D3E90272014"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <subsection id="H5810D862A639428AA5E97C420AC4582C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress finds as follows:</text>
<paragraph id="H1BE4EE1120434FA2A96AB7309F03CA92"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State data and monitoring systems provide reliable data on injury causes and risk factors, identify trends in the incidence of traumatic brain injury, enable the development of cause-specific prevention strategies focused on populations at greatest risk, and monitor the effectiveness of such strategies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE680679C240749D8940467EDB127E394"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Since 1995, when the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention published Guidelines for Surveillance of Central Nervous System Injury, additional causes of traumatic brain injury have emerged: military-related traumatic brain injuries; sports-related concussions; traffic injuries resulting from texting while driving; and increasing numbers of falls-related traumatic brain injuries among older adults.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H03D09FF72AB9447EBA5CA871A836BE00"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In their 2013 report, Sports-Related Concussions in Youth: Improving the Science, Changing the Culture, the Institute on Medicine and the National Research Council noted that there is currently a lack of data to accurately estimate the incidence of sports-related concussions across a variety of sports and for youth across the pediatric age spectrum. The report recommended that the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention establish and oversee a national surveillance system to accurately determine the incidence of sports-related concussions, including those in youth ages 5 to 21, taking into account Federal efforts to collect information on traumatic brain injury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5C9A30337C241B6B3B0E512AB4341BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Traumatic brain injury is a substantial public health problem among older persons. As the population of older persons continues to grow in the United States, the need to design and implement proven and cost-effective prevention measures that focus on the leading causes of traumatic brain injury becomes more urgent.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H571EC1B2E06E458EB1781E3FD585F14B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to implement this Act, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention needs to collaborate with Federal agencies reporting military-related traumatic brain injuries, school systems reporting traumatic brain injuries, Medicaid and other Federal programs, and State agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC9098F8A9C764B528DA90E088466533D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishing requirements to improve the research and treatment of traumatic brain injury</header> <subsection id="HE76292528637475FACF9D735D2EF4C48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H669E78D4458B47B59019663254A154B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate existing surveillance and data collections systems that track the incidence and circumstances of traumatic brain injury, including concussion;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H133272C801EE48A0AA0C4E329A117A94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of this Act, submit a report to the Congress outlining the findings of the evaluation under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDB4F498C408F43AFA45E2487BB1A3E2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish a statistically sound, scientifically credible, integrated surveillance system regarding traumatic brain injury, to be known as the <quote>National Traumatic Brain Injury Surveillance System</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7FD45264181847D792FAD819E3998B70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the National Traumatic Brain Injury Surveillance System is designed in a manner that facilitates further research on brain injury.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H568686AD98BC41D28E488DFFF3F2C4BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Content</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="H954E27D3ED4B4FD68C9CCF55B87CAB26"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide for the collection and storage of information (excluding personally identifiable information) on the incidence and prevalence of traumatic brain injury, including concussion, in the United States across the lifespan;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDA68940B54454ADF83E65D4D066B9FF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, shall provide for the collection and storage of other available information (excluding personally identifiable information) on traumatic brain injury, such as information concerning demographics and other information associated with the incidence of a traumatic brain injury, such as—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E53B6A8C76C4E9EBFA011676AF19F01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>age;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H23BC36D6E1D94F2A8D3C09A16C0014ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>race and ethnicity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2F0A21FF02F4D0D93E413E73D420174"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sex;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0B5E9BCFD5EC47F7B7C2EBB9923FAA84"><enum>(D)</enum><text>geographic location;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22FA0B492BF745029B6229DF5A4A5773"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">history of head injury (including injury type and the approximate date of injury);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD6FA0768A7DE48EC9290F40B1CE6D582"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pre-existing conditions, such as learning disabilities and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD22E1B5A7D374C76A530311DF4373547"><enum>(G)</enum><text>co-occurring issues, such as substance abuse or post-traumatic stress disorder;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA58D3F8AF77E48F1BFE89BAF71D44AD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, shall provide for the collection and storage of information relevant to analysis on traumatic brain injury, such as information concerning—</text> <subparagraph id="H08ADF637BAAF4592B5D73A33D01E9DF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impact location on the body and nature of the impact;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B3526F006CE4A35856DB67B195FFD52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>qualifications of personnel making the traumatic brain injury diagnosis;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF79A9B607B9B443CBA6EF1EDEB06DD78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assessment tool used to make the diagnosis;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2A9E45BF39BF49C585FA663A6B53B0C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>signs and symptoms consistent with a head injury;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF19BEA112A641B6B8CB5E9EB3FC7F38"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sport or activity and the level of competition (if a sports-related activity);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H51C4E15B23224598840A08812A5B0437"><enum>(F)</enum><text>use of protective equipment and impact monitoring devices; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B25F296F0BA427C8A16B340E9C065E6"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">severity of the traumatic brain injury; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H616AC26DC37C4BB5AF2949185F2035CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>may address issues identified during the consultation process under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF998E4B3CBCA4F0B9B6C3C312016DC2D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with individuals with appropriate expertise, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H9320C581D59C4EA5906628DC515AE0A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>epidemiologists with experience in disease surveillance or registries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H475E8CD2B881419EB1E0E058C94456F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>representatives of national health associations that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H029A889DA0CB42B784C0000E6B40E75B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>focus on brain injury; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5C90BDBBD8441F386940C0C9EC78DE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have demonstrated experience in research, care, or patient services;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB7CEFC6737AF447E80DB8BE372B98159"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State public health agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35B3389EF9474F47B9889CB09D9C5A27"><enum>(4)</enum><text>health information technology experts or other information management specialists;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3F45A23734E4EA2A0DCC6516B6717DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>clinicians with expertise in brain injury;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56E4154D6996485DB37785B1FDB37AF6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>research scientists with experience conducting brain research or utilizing surveillance systems for scientific research purposes;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF235523604E43558085CE7228945FC4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B74A05DB54E4EE78392CB7B47A3BC36"><enum>(8)</enum><text>behavioral health centers.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE810606E772543CE80505FF00953C8E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, public or private nonprofit entities to carry out activities under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0F87A33170744F9D89EEA9B9C8D3F30F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination with other federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (h), the Secretary shall make information and analysis in the National Traumatic Brain Injury Surveillance System available, as appropriate, to Federal departments and agencies, such as the National Institutes of Health, the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Food and Drug Administration, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, the Department of Education, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and the Department of Defense.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8E1878FF78CD430DA3448D7FDB4BB77F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>Subject to subsection (h), the Secretary shall make information and analysis in the National Traumatic Brain Injury Surveillance System available, as appropriate, to the public, including researchers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8CA0CAABCE0D49FF9533389AF2EAD0CF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that privacy and security protections applicable to the National Traumatic Brain Injury Surveillance System are at least as stringent as the privacy and security protections under HIPAA privacy and security law, including nondisclosure of personally identifiable information.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8676383D0DA14BB7A3BBB79B4B97D010"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress concerning the implementation of this section. Such report shall include information on—</text> <paragraph id="HFE66623DE68A459C960EB3341C9E67F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development and maintenance of the National Traumatic Brain Injury Surveillance System;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H19E52887FEE444198488DC25F76A5CF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the type of information collected and stored in the System;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B8EFE9DCBBE4E68AD27F26974F57A8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use and availability of such information, including guidelines for such use; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4C78D7B54B094AD6975C447BD93E2FEF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the use and coordination of databases that collect or maintain information on traumatic brain injury.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD5D719A6340342ADAC4B6D61E0716228"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H3748A3C1F8CA46508DDDAFB70A4B2769"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National health association</header><text>The term <term>national health association</term> means a national nonprofit organization with chapters, other affiliated organizations, or networks in States throughout the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF9CE479CC5F4CA4824548A2555DA019"><enum>(2)</enum><header>HIPAA privacy and security law</header><text>The term <term>HIPAA privacy and security law</term> has the meaning given to that term in section 3009 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300jj-19">42 U.S.C. 300jj–19</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42B3BC1E7C8B4147AB01B285EDCA0C03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personally identifiable information</header><text>The term <term>personally identifiable information</term> means information which can be used to distinguish or trace an individual’s identity (such as their name, social security number, or biometric records) either alone or when combined with other personal or identifying information which is linked or linkable to a specific individual (such as date of birth, place of birth, and mother’s maiden name).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5FD12C46CDDE4BB0924940105E56C9ED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H73701E8E4DF64348907CB3155FB47278"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Surveillance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>surveillance</term> means the ongoing, systematic collection, analysis, interpretation, and dissemination of data (other than personally identifiable information) regarding a health-related event for use in public health action to reduce morbidity and mortality and to improve health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E5DEAEE961441C88D27F74BE75E6B70"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Traumatic brain injury</header><text>The term <term>traumatic brain injury</term> means an injury to the head arising from blunt or penetrating trauma or from acceleration or deceleration forces associated with one or more of the following: decreased level of consciousness, amnesia, objective neurologic or neuropsychological abnormalities, skull fractures, diagnosed intracranial lesions, or head injury listed as a cause of death in the death certificate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H76AFFE76D2574E6383AE5FB3AAE87280"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this Act, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

