<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCB2FD74517CE465AB6F3DD89D44D984D" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3037 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to hospice care under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3037</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150713">July 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to hospice care under the
			 Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HD495B5A47180485CAD002A4F8A0F5558" style="OLC">
 <section id="H684946A6A20D4E1C9FA20AA3419A0CCF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may cited as the <quote>Hospice Care Access Improvement Act of 2015</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6A029492F68C4E929A01C51DA5D67682"><enum>2.</enum><header>Hospice payment reform demonstration program</header> <subsection id="H34DEC324D3554F669D5AD77F005B3653"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct a demonstration program for a 1-year period during fiscal year 2016 to test the proposed hospice payment methodology revisions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB057140C46348818C9628158AC7C070"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proposed Hospice Payment Methodology Revisions defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>proposed hospice payment methodology revisions</quote> means revisions to the methodology for determining hospice payment rates under section 1814(i)(6)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(i)(6)(D)</external-xref>) contained in the Fiscal Year 2016 Hospice Wage Index and Payment Rate Update and Hospice Quality Reporting Requirements as published by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services on May 5, 2015 (80 Fed. Reg. 25831 et seq.).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD479CB2FD5D24A06A4A9AAC4DD3F3FBA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select one Medicare administrative contractor to conduct the demonstration program. Such contractor shall conduct the demonstration program with respect to all hospice programs under that contractor’s jurisdiction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HADD84856EC4B4B018C1EAE2200A0DD6F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of the demonstration program, which shall include an analysis of the impact of the proposed hospice payment methodology revisions—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE63DAE91EA524982A68C800C766A5271"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the quality of patient care and the ability of hospice programs to provide such care; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H596D83681E364FF4AFEB15DB018DCBA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on access to hospice care for beneficiaries.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB89BB92A691474C87BF337C0A3162B9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than March 31, 2017, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the demonstration program. The report shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC8A6CEC2D4CA420FBAACAD48181B5F2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the evaluation under subsection (d); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E96B4CDA7C24D42B888CA0A7AFFC3B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BD11DE550ED4982844D3B4B405846E5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation of hospice payment methodology revisions</header>
 <paragraph id="H1BE169075C9E4639A9F498B13B39C5E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on implementation of revisions for fiscal years 2016 and 2017</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No revisions to the hospice payment methodology shall be made under section 1814(i)(6)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(i)(6)(D)</external-xref>) for fiscal years 2016 and 2017, except for purposes of the demonstration program required to be conducted under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0881A3CEB2A743A5B2335F0E9F52D3A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation of revisions for fiscal year 2018</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After taking into account the results of the evaluation of the demonstration program and after making any necessary revisions, the Secretary shall implement the proposed hospice payment methodology revisions beginning with fiscal year 2018.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6E784D1B02904529B1B865CEBE1C4365"><enum>3.</enum><header>Hospice program integrity</header>
 <subsection id="H3A2D1F55234F47A1A08C7DE18CE23980"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medical review for certain hospice programs</header><text>Section 1814(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H526C82CA7C714A45B3F620F9DADA4A73" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H966C27CC4E1A4D198742CD2FBE34FFAC" indent="down1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Medical review for certain hospice programs</header>
 <subparagraph id="H577A2C8B29754D58B047BA851C7FBB88"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall implement a process for the medical review of hospice care furnished by a hospice program identified under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H832C336A6A4C4A418F8A4400D0D0F7FA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Identification of hospice programs for medical review</header><text>The Secretary shall identify hospice programs the patients of which will be subject to medical review under subparagraph (A). In identifying such programs, the Secretary shall consider multiple factors in comparison with other similarly situated hospice programs, such as—</text>
 <clause id="H094974BCB78245C083F5006830D22665"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the percentage of patients who were discharged after receiving hospice care for a period of 120 to 180 days and who were alive upon such discharge;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC6E49DC7097040168D0B363D955963C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage of patients who are receiving hospice care from the program at the end of life who receive no skilled hospice care visits in the last week of life; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H090F60C7A5924875AE5F01804638AC56"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the level of per-patient expenditures under this title for patients of the hospice program excluding expenditures for hospice care.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE45124D6EB834342B601CBD3059641FA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on liability of beneficiary where medicare claims are disallowed</header><text>The provisions of this title relating to the limitation on liability of a beneficiary where Medicare claims are disallowed shall apply with respect to this paragraph in the same manner as they apply to subsection (a)(7)(E).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB5F88A63066947C385CEA86E0F063F60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Developing interventions To reduce hospital admissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop and publish guidance, where appropriate and in consultation with interested parties, for hospice programs to develop interventions to reduce hospital admissions and visits to hospital emergency departments by patients of such hospice programs.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HAD25E7FE95F34A4BA233282EA5D6049D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expanding who may perform pre-Hospice evaluation and counseling services</header>
 <paragraph id="H904EDC1862F041349E89C4FE3BA0D93C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1812(a)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395d">42 U.S.C. 1395d(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>hospice program</quote> the following: <quote>, or services that are furnished by a registered nurse who is an employee of a hospice program in consultation, if necessary, with other members of the interdisciplinary group described in section 1861(dd)(2)(B),</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H49E43B4442CB41DDB32696D521E19401"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA027B6C1F2A64019BD641633E9F61860"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall evaluate the impact of the amendment made by paragraph (1). Such evaluation shall include an evaluation of the impact of such amendment on hospital admission rates, hospice care utilization, and length of stay in hospice programs for patients receiving services under section 1812(a)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395d">42 U.S.C. 1395d(a)(5)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CA783F566B747E28F08AFF1F24C0ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report to Congress containing the results of the evaluation under subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07072BC338BF461EB8A672B92F793623"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expanding hospice care access for residents using skilled nursing facilities</header>
 <paragraph id="HD6DE6C8A7DDD45229C65B1E7FF8C8975"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medicare and skilled nursing facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1819 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8426E5ACBB8B4B5E8262088A03A02DAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(4), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BA9C1A49A354473A8BA7A2B48738FBE" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HC9F14B76F64B405EA0366B29AB75B668"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Hospice program contracting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a facility that contracts with a hospice program for hospice care for its residents, such facility shall make a good faith effort to enter into a contract with more than one hospice program participating under this title that provides services in the area served by the facility, if more than one hospice program is available to serve such residents.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE02778767414368B46897FCDB5FCF32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(A)(i), by inserting after <quote>well-being,</quote> the following: <quote>to be fully informed, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, of any financial interest, as specified by the Secretary, the skilled nursing facility has in any hospice program to which a resident is referred,</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6F13A1138114FE7AA471221A010B47C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to skilled nursing facilities in operation 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB77684926E4D4500B2776115DD8901B3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Hospital discharge planning provisions relating to hospice care</header>
 <paragraph id="H2A0BE7C400FE4111B0934178F8A60312"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1861(ee)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(ee)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HA28E3B6612E7447C929FCF0D144299B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>and, in the case of individuals likely to need hospice care, the availability of such care through hospice programs that participate in the program under this title and that serve the area in which the patient resides and that request to be listed by the hospital as available.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2054895C5DA548E1B5CA390875D1A47D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H)(i), by inserting <quote>or hospice care</quote> after <quote>home health services</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E98E4391F0C40E48F3C73FE8094C127"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to discharges occurring on or after 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


