<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H54A983F4F4BC4934BC37FC814D5AB4AE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2715 IH: Stop Child Summer Hunger Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2715</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150610">June 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish a permanent, nationwide
			 summer electronic benefits transfer for children program.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H347771D044B246BC9C00CC6D9FC3AE50" style="OLC">
 <section id="H31BA14ABCDCA4F4B8D206EC7CB9376A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Child Summer Hunger Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAEC0DFC9D7D14C16B4DE266DFA540129"><enum>2.</enum><header>Summer electronic benefits transfer for children program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13(a) of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1761">42 U.S.C. 1761(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6753C6ADB51F456591D5583B6BBD05D6" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H4A0D472F628D4183B6B632C14F6CAB08"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Summer electronic benefits transfer for children program</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA788BD6FF5014E53A1A7979CF9688743"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H286B4E15128E434FBC72DA5EAEA84E37"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Eligible household</header><text>The term <term>eligible household</term> means a household that includes 1 or more children who are eligible to receive free or reduced price lunches under this Act or free or reduced price breakfasts under the <act-name parsable-cite="CNA66">Child Nutrition Act of 1966</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1771">42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF520D6E3D8DD4E4189DA68F08B434FFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Summer EBT card</header><text>The term <term>summer EBT card</term> means an electronic benefit transfer card that is issued to an eligible household under this paragraph and limited to food purchases.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05C3F5B4A1CC469F91D78A4AA0734E96"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall provide to eligible households summer EBT cards for the purpose of providing access to food for children during summer months—</text>
 <clause id="H537B6FB10672474599FED17B2D512918"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to reduce or eliminate the food insecurity and hunger of children; and</text> </clause><clause id="H7075304D1095432590C386C42C1F2D94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to improve the nutritional status of children.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8751887D39E14EF28EE0C9E5EAF32BE9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use</header><text>An eligible household may use a summer EBT card only to purchase food from retail food stores that have been approved for participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the <act-name parsable-cite="FSA77">Food and Nutrition Act of 2008</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), in accordance with section 7(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2016">7 U.S.C. 2016(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83FFDD13E9BA4D06AEFF999604F50A22"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>Each summer EBT card issued shall be in an amount of—</text> <clause id="HB245FA7E59A9406AB44D119A2E08953B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for calendar year 2017, $150 in food assistance per child per summer; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H805328F19C9040FFA1C3D9F94A25FE12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each subsequent calendar year, the amount specified in clause (i) as adjusted to reflect changes in reimbursement rates for school meals under this Act between calendar year 2017 and the most recent calendar year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8852F4D45D6546308407A61FD4C87AB0"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Summer EBT cards shall be issued at the end of the regular school year.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D2131B8DB524DD290995FF8379EDE53"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Funding</header> <clause id="H66DAAF65010A4167AEEA5622BA7BD62D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On October 1, 2016, and on each October 1 thereafter, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Secretary such sums as are necessary to carry out this section, to remain available until expended.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H78AA4C6EB7454275982F7CC46F44A78A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Receipt and acceptance</header><text>The Secretary shall be entitled to receive, shall accept, and shall use to carry out this section the funds transferred under clause (i), without further appropriation. <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic"></added-phrase></text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43C1138597754312810A8426E25DD77A"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <clause id="H31A7CB902BA34CCF8ECDF04D7AF1205E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2016, the Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out this paragraph.</text> </clause><clause id="H6FFA6BD4BD3B48EAB2C4A56BB39580B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Regulations issued under this subparagraph shall require that—</text>
 <subclause id="H6E5B440909C144728B76FF11C746B073"><enum>(I)</enum><text>children shall be eligible to participate and shall be enrolled into the program under this paragraph for a summer without further application if the children are enrolled to participate in the free or reduced price lunch program under this Act or the free or reduced price breakfast program under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1771">42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.</external-xref>) during the school year immediately preceding the summer; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H22AE075E2AC04BB6B9A696ECC9AF906D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>local educational agencies shall distribute to the families of all children enrolled in schools participating in programs authorized under this Act and the <act-name parsable-cite="CNA66">Child Nutrition Act of 1966</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1771">42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.</external-xref>) and, to the maximum extent practicable, the families of all children enrolled in schools of the local educational agency information, as provided by the Secretary,—</text>
 <item commented="no" id="H8F83D6B946374EB5AE7BF9916FB01035"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>regarding the program authorized under this paragraph, including eligibility rules and how children in eligible households that are not automatically enrolled under subclause (I) may apply for program benefits; and</text>
 </item><item id="H6ACC43C35F14458A93845CE4CA0AB6F6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to assist households receiving summer EBT cards in making healthy food choices and maximizing resources.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause><clause id="HA94C7F15903D46B1A8713CDB4D74E283"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Alternative timing</header>
 <subclause id="HD96F22C36A314FFAA3393025C52E1760"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In issuing regulations under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall allow alternative plans for the timing of issuance of the summer electronic benefit cards under subparagraph (D) in any part of a State in which the school year does not include a typical summer break, on the condition that the Secretary determines that no alternative plan increases or decreases Federal costs.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3B8EC0A037AD4FD1A7D9D2CD1389C203"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing regulations under subclause (I), the Secretary shall consider the ability of a State effectively to issue benefits under an alternative schedule.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


