<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H33BBC88B347C429CB2F83D16FA026919" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3 EH: Keystone XL Pipeline Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To approve the Keystone XL Pipeline.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HBC30D55B2E0042408C61BD6CDAF9552C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HED0C279B86EA40F6B2FDF7FBF26CFD82" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keystone XL Pipeline Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H1DB4D6F17585490A99B98007C36C0CE8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Keystone XL approval</header> 
<subsection id="HD84A56BE879F4FF0970EBE51F1C51C17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">TransCanada Keystone Pipeline, L.P. may construct, connect, operate, and maintain the pipeline and cross-border facilities described in the application filed on May 4, 2012, by TransCanada Corporation to the Department of State (including any subsequent revision to the pipeline route within the State of Nebraska required or authorized by the State of Nebraska).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEB48A4EC94FF426B83E8D0B97C06192C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Environmental Impact Statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement issued by the Secretary of State in January 2014, regarding the pipeline referred to in subsection (a), and the environmental analysis, consultation, and review described in that document (including appendices) shall be considered to fully satisfy—</text> 
<paragraph id="H57DDC9EE59E64B6F938C2B86B27B46AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CCAD2F715D34820A3DC36F8E23CDFE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other provision of law that requires Federal agency consultation or review (including the consultation or review required under section 7(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(a)</external-xref>)) with respect to the pipeline and facilities referred to in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H65717E615F7C434AB1AF06D63B577A1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Federal permit or authorization issued before the date of enactment of this Act for the pipeline and cross-border facilities referred to in subsection (a) shall remain in effect.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC3DB4E645754791B5C8B457888E0F14"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except for review in the Supreme Court of the United States, the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit shall have original and exclusive jurisdiction over any civil action for the review of an order or action of a Federal agency regarding the pipeline and cross-border facilities described in subsection (a), and the related facilities in the United States, that are approved by this Act (including any order granting a permit or right-of-way, or any other agency action taken to construct or complete the project pursuant to Federal law).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E18A0C0388646C7A0521EDFF5235D55"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Private property savings clause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act alters any Federal, State, or local process or condition in effect on the date of enactment of this Act that is necessary to secure access from an owner of private property to construct the pipeline and cross-border facilities described in subsection (a).</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20150109" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 9, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


