<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6753BC86865849BC8A435753E58E8ADB" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3878 EH: Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3878</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To enhance cybersecurity information sharing and coordination at ports in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0966DCD309DA4D52A514F9A25A18F36F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA7552768AB0A40E28F70EC507C4463A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAC52F2AF824844F1951BDAFD779ED101"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving cybersecurity risk assessments, information sharing, and coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HA22326565A3943019D8087AEE14A0DDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement a maritime cybersecurity risk assessment model within 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, consistent with the National Institute of Standards and Technology Framework for Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity and any update to that document pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/274">Public Law 113–274</external-xref>, to evaluate current and future cybersecurity risks (as that term is defined in the second section 226 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148</external-xref>));</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BF88389F14C4B8EA1D1A5B5CDB2AA82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate, on a periodic basis but not less than once every two years, the effectiveness of the cybersecurity risk assessment model established under paragraph (1);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB84F7E3B8E25450CAF291CA06DA82CF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek to ensure participation of at least one information sharing and analysis organization (as that term is defined in section 212 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/131">6 U.S.C. 131</external-xref>)) representing the maritime community in the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center, pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(B) of the second section 226 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE4DE1D1C95647BBAE8507B63CE75A63"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish guidelines for voluntary reporting of maritime-related cybersecurity risks and incidents (as such terms are defined in the second section 226 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148</external-xref>)) to the Center (as that term is defined subsection (b) of the second section 226 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148</external-xref>)), and other appropriate Federal agencies; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7022B789ED334F64B18A2A798DEE5BDB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>request the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee established under section 70112 of title 46, United States Code, to report and make recommendations to the Secretary on enhancing the sharing of information related to cybersecurity risks and incidents between relevant Federal agencies and State, local, and tribal governments and consistent with the responsibilities of the Center (as that term is defined subsection (b) of the second section 226 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148</external-xref>)); relevant public safety and emergency response agencies; relevant law enforcement and security organizations; maritime industry; port owners and operators; and terminal owners and operators.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC7986A9F767A4A4688D262C0AD86F4FF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cybersecurity enhancements to maritime security activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall direct—</text>
<paragraph id="H0E3CD1A23C064816B55BB6223CD583F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each Area Maritime Security Advisory Committee established under section 70112 of title 46, United States Code, to facilitate the sharing of cybersecurity risks and incidents to address port-specific cybersecurity risks, which may include the establishment of a working group of members of Area Maritime Security Advisory Committees to address port-specific cybersecurity vulnerabilities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCC4BC2C4FF44A4F87F80E39EA65B33A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that any area maritime security plan and facility security plan required under section 70103 of title 46, United States Code approved after the development of the cybersecurity risk assessment model required by paragraph (1) of section 2 include a mitigation plan to prevent, manage, and respond to cybersecurity risks.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HACD1EA182AB144C6B70C9F01E11402B8"><enum>4.</enum><header>vulnerability assessments and security plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE96FC3D03950478896AE2D7E0BA453DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 70102(b)(1)(C), by inserting <quote>cybersecurity,</quote> after <quote>physical security,</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1EE4E15683E8471A89BEA89DC9C06A7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 70103(c)(3)(C), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end of clause (iv), by redesignating clause (v) as clause (vi), and by inserting after clause (iv) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H64F15D5A11E34F1AA9182D6DD6C9264B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HD7DB410BD00C490CBFA6A65DE38C2854" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevention, management, and response to cybersecurity risks; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20151216" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 16, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


