<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEAD5457AB4C0489EA8DA2C81F6AF4E03" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3603 IH: To grant a Federal charter to the National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3603</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150924">September 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To grant a Federal charter to the National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HF64657AF81CA42D09EC5AC943B1E2B25" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB87373C5B63A42AA8E7CD7300CDB9B9B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Recognition as corporation and grant of Federal charter for National American Indian Veterans,
			 Incorporated</header>
 <subsection id="H8357155CA15B4764BF919917A4B05C77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part B of subtitle II of title 36, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 1503 the following new chapter:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H56D742A503464011BA4F9DA96ED6FD95" style="USC">
					<chapter id="HF600A9B67701475CB9803BFCF0C1F5CB"><enum>1504</enum><header>National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated</header>
						<toc container-level="chapter-container" idref="HF600A9B67701475CB9803BFCF0C1F5CB" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="HFD3F0AB627C4479BBC91696CB714D954" level="section"> Sec.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">150401. Organization.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H834392397CB34D0B990ACB05E4A092B5" level="section"> 150402. Purposes.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H5C2B33C9AD0A4B2A88851825E9C83B78" level="section"> 150403. Membership.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H8F3ACF0DC38A4263ACC97DA664571B1C" level="section"> 150404. Board of directors.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HF8C32F1783954A79AD75CD212E328561" level="section"> 150405. Officers.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HBD989DC7A7F441D78C491363062E99F0" level="section"> 150406. Nondiscrimination.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H33C4383E9F964A13BC5FF8BAA161FADF" level="section"> 150407. Powers.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H7ABFB37804F3481EBBC0892ED33126C5" level="section"> 150408. Exclusive right to name, seals, emblems, and badges.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HE8676A1D11204394A51541B185F0D0D4" level="section"> 150409. Restrictions.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HD60B70B000674FE4ACB5D19B9619E36A" level="section"> 150410. Duty to maintain tax-exempt status.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HCFA15C3E65C64FCB80195CFA1AC05849" level="section"> 150411. Records and inspection.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H6A33F1BBF893439294A2873305A54CB7" level="section"> 150412. Service of process.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H78ED99E4A3324BAF8F8991E81A69E03D" level="section"> 150413. Liability for acts of officers and agents.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H0BB907F3EB4F4D84ADC5826EDAF2E115" level="section"> 150414. Failure to comply with requirements.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H23DC6E64B1AF4CC799B48FBC5D258BC7" level="section"> 150415. Annual report.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="HFD3F0AB627C4479BBC91696CB714D954"><enum>150401.</enum><header>Organization</header>
 <subsection id="H34C9919A7DD349009CE9FE06A1114997"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Charter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated, a nonprofit corporation organized in the United States (in this chapter referred to as the <quote>corporation</quote>), is a federally chartered corporation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3AD92F6E9D124331BE0746EE7647DECB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Independent status of corporation</header><text>The corporation is not an agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H834392397CB34D0B990ACB05E4A092B5"><enum>150402.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of the corporation are those stated in its articles of incorporation, constitution, and bylaws, and include a commitment—</text>
 <paragraph id="H40800EFF23C04CDD8F5A13881A4D5E6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to uphold and defend the Constitution of the United States while respecting the sovereignty of the American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian Nations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70BC7CBC3DC04BA6B3EDDF99E004FB69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to unite under one body all American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian veterans who served in the Armed Forces of United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE91294FF2AB4365B18CB3BE9BE5F912"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to be an advocate on behalf of all American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian veterans without regard to whether they served during times of peace, conflict, or war;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65572D8894124D89B26D28338FF05733"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be an advocate for all veterans suffering from service-connected disabilities;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB018BB33512949ED9244A622060242F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to promote social welfare (including educational, economic, social, physical, cultural values, and traditional healing) in the United States by encouraging the growth and development, readjustment, self-respect, self-confidence, contributions, and self-identity of American Indian veterans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59F32C2DFA9747FE850B7BCD940404F2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to serve as an advocate for the needs of American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian veterans, their families, or survivors in their dealings with all Federal and State government agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H946C970500274428B14B3DCBFBB57BA2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to promote, support, and use research, on a nonpartisan basis, pertaining to the relationship between the American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian veterans and American society; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BE08CC68CE44163819F9C3F76EADC91"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance to all regional areas without veterans committees or organizations and programs by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2B6F5B0409A84BE8948EF0218E6EF3C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing outreach service to those tribes in need; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFE850C3AB8F43C6B933E6020B79EED3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training and educating Tribal Veterans Service Officers for those tribes in need.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H5C2B33C9AD0A4B2A88851825E9C83B78"><enum>150403.</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <subsection id="H9EE49DD59D6A4F9FADCB4847D1EC51A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b) and section 150406 of this title, eligibility for membership in the corporation, and the rights and privileges of members, shall be as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H585CB7819D6C4DC7A74AAB0121B462DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Eligibility for membership in the corporation and the rights and privileges of members shall not be determined by the Federal Government.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H8F3ACF0DC38A4263ACC97DA664571B1C"><enum>150404.</enum><header>Board of directors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to section 150406 of this title, the board of directors of the corporation, and the responsibilities of the board, shall be as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation and in conformity with the laws under which the corporation is incorporated.</text>
 </section><section id="HF8C32F1783954A79AD75CD212E328561"><enum>150405.</enum><header>Officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to section 150406 of this title, the officers of the corporation, and the election of such officers, shall be as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation and in conformity with the laws of the jurisdiction under which the corporation is incorporated.</text>
 </section><section id="HBD989DC7A7F441D78C491363062E99F0"><enum>150406.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In establishing the conditions of membership in the corporation, and in determining the requirements for serving on the board of directors or as an officer of the corporation, the corporation may not discriminate on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, national origin, handicap, or age.</text>
 </section><section id="H33C4383E9F964A13BC5FF8BAA161FADF"><enum>150407.</enum><header>Powers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The corporation shall have only those powers granted the corporation through its articles of incorporation and its constitution and bylaws, which shall conform to the laws of the jurisdiction under which the corporation is incorporated.</text>
						</section><section id="H7ABFB37804F3481EBBC0892ED33126C5"><enum>150408.</enum><header>Exclusive right to name, seals, emblems, and badges</header>
 <subsection id="H01D3D247A4A74141B89C5D136570920B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The corporation shall have the sole and exclusive right to use the names <quote>National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated</quote> and <quote>National American Indian Veterans</quote>, and such seals, emblems, and badges as the corporation may lawfully adopt.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC1929E0ABD314C48A7F19794F4B0AF8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to interfere or conflict with established or vested rights.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HE8676A1D11204394A51541B185F0D0D4"><enum>150409.</enum><header>Restrictions</header>
 <subsection id="HB330AE22F571439AA8BC4FE968292EEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Stock and dividends</header><text>The corporation shall have no power to issue any shares of stock nor to declare or pay any dividends.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H5E12791154404B5880155BA9D7106655"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution of income or assets</header>
 <paragraph id="HADCF1DFD8D3D450EBD8DF106CF4A62A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of the income or assets of the corporation shall inure to any person who is a member, officer, or director of the corporation or be distributed to any such person during the life of the charter granted by this chapter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA163EFAC91DF446FBB64ABA6496C5B60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent the payment of reasonable compensation to the officers of the corporation, or reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses, in amounts approved by the board of directors.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF022508F2A44833B6A1B185079D95BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loans</header><text>The corporation shall not make any loan to any officer, director, member, or employee of the corporation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB82EFFB7718845E5A548925E1A40E5ED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No Federal endorsement</header><text>The corporation shall not claim congressional approval or Federal Government authority by virtue of the charter granted by this chapter for any of its activities.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD60B70B000674FE4ACB5D19B9619E36A"><enum>150410.</enum><header>Duty to maintain tax-exempt status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The corporation shall maintain its status as an organization exempt from taxation as provided in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
						</section><section id="HCFA15C3E65C64FCB80195CFA1AC05849"><enum>150411.</enum><header>Records and inspection</header>
 <subsection id="H5C8058FF8AD94FE0A91BA17B2D27034D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Records</header><text>The corporation shall keep—</text> <paragraph id="H8B0C6AC01FD244BD8E6D6661E94EB44A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>correct and complete books and records of accounts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03A2CCCF318D4B5B855AE7D222FCD06D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>minutes of any proceeding of the corporation involving any of its members, the board of directors, or any committee having authority under the board of directors; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E3A52BF11784E7084EEFBCE8BBA46AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of all members having the right to vote.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6327C9C6366843D6A9716266424A1312"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspection</header>
 <paragraph id="H4D6E298648B342DEA09A20C1A07EFFC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All books and records of the corporation may be inspected by any member having the right to vote, or by any agent or attorney of such member, for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27FCCF1BC0AB42D3BBF97F54087C680A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to contravene the laws of the jurisdiction under which the corporation is incorporated or the laws of those jurisdictions within which the corporation carries on its activities in furtherance of its purposes within the United States and its territories.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6A33F1BBF893439294A2873305A54CB7"><enum>150412.</enum><header>Service of process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to service of process, the corporation shall comply with the laws of the jurisdiction under which the corporation is incorporated and those jurisdictions within which the corporation carries on its activities in furtherance of its purposes within the United States and its territories.</text>
 </section><section id="H78ED99E4A3324BAF8F8991E81A69E03D"><enum>150413.</enum><header>Liability for acts of officers and agents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The corporation shall be liable for the acts of the officers and agents of the corporation when such individuals act within the scope of their authority.</text>
 </section><section id="H0BB907F3EB4F4D84ADC5826EDAF2E115"><enum>150414.</enum><header>Failure to comply with requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the corporation fails to comply with any of the restrictions or provisions of this chapter, including the requirement under section 150410 of this title to maintain its status as an organization exempt from taxation, the charter granted by this chapter shall expire.</text>
						</section><section id="H23DC6E64B1AF4CC799B48FBC5D258BC7"><enum>150415.</enum><header>Annual report</header>
 <subsection id="H0646CD6769BA437AA52E415567C278C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The corporation shall report annually to Congress concerning the activities of the corporation during the preceding fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7FD38F85872D4FA9986EFECC18AA9499"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submittal date</header><text>Each annual report under this section shall be submitted at the same time as the report of the audit of the corporation required by section 10101(b) of this title.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H29D7DC29124A42D492881989297ACB84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters at the beginning of subtitle II of title 36, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 1503 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0B660E1303D484CA33BC97DBFE305FC" style="USC">
					<toc><multi-column-toc-entry bold="on" level="chapter"><toc-enum>1504. </toc-enum><level-header level="chapter">National American Indian Veterans, <linebreak></linebreak>Incorporated</level-header><target>150401</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


