<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H392EF99905A14FD5A4B86A4DCDF3ADBD" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1403 IH: Balancing Trade Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1403</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150317">March 17, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To require that, in cases in which the annual trade deficit between the United States and another country is $10,000,000,000 or more for 3 consecutive years, the President take the necessary steps to create a more balanced trading relationship with that country.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H66E3E5075A3D4E909251804CCA0EF17D" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFB35D6AEA5249E193EFB8FB50BA1845" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Balancing Trade Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA7594530AC6D416DA4EE27F724AD0BB8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Action by the President in cases of large consecutive annual trade deficits with other countries</header> <subsection id="H6B57836B97644F708D3714392E7445E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Action by the President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If in 3 consecutive calendar years the United States has a trade deficit with another country of $10,000,000,000 or more, the President shall take the necessary steps to create a trading relationship with the country that would eliminate or substantially reduce that trade deficit, by entering into an agreement with that country or otherwise.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6DEB46C8E7ED4650A7B3C8CD9DD61993"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>trade deficit</term> means, with respect to the United States and another country, that the value of goods and services that are products of that country and are imported into the United States from that country exceeds the value of goods and services that are products of the United States and are exported from the United States to that country.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD64FD964F3C346ACB60821FBAF118602"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H5D2C4625B0404C6EAFCBEC633981C298"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the Congress a report setting forth—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8D122A41BEB3477E9FF1B5CBC282F184"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the likely reasons for the trade deficits with each country to which subsection (a) applies, as of the date of the report; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA6C34E1821D420FB4F3C73ACDC6F90C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the steps the President intends to take under subsection (a) with respect to each such country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C8B7349E844414CBC6F15BEB9C6F026"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>The President shall submit to the Congress, not later than December 31 of each year, a report on actions taken to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

