<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H46E1CADC9D494ADCA6D4ABDF243725AA" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 836 IH: Health Care Safety Net Enhancement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 836</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001055">Mr. Heck of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve access to emergency medical services, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFFDDC4B879604775B2D1D1317EAAD011" style="OLC">
 <section id="H65B17DDBF8BA4F82BFA32A88DE5DD770" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Care Safety Net Enhancement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFEB2DDB41AF145AA95A11C6ACF17FDFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Constitutional authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The constitutional authority upon which this Act rests is the power of the Congress to provide for the general welfare, to regulate commerce, and to make all laws which shall be necessary and proper for carrying into execution Federal powers, as enumerated in section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States.</text>
 </section><section id="H7D9735F599BD45F598D1509652DD4A9B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection for emergency and related services furnished pursuant to EMTALA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 224(g) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/233">42 U.S.C. 233(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD2A74B5229C34D658BA8B9BD341844CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>An entity</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (6), an entity</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7774F25FBA5447CB3753ADE8667D053"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H9B024C9D593B4AF59412A09865E02D25" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H83734C6F9188453EB5F07F621A4D0777"><enum>(6)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H35CBF73F26DD4423800B00DF93681C7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
 <clause id="H521D7A38C4E74A4D8EC39F0E5A264B9E" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an entity described in subparagraph (B) shall be considered to be an entity described in paragraph (4); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7CCC66ACC71D4B2CBBE03E98607C9475" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the provisions of this section shall apply to an entity described in subparagraph (B) in the same manner as such provisions apply to an entity described in paragraph (4), except that—</text>
 <subclause id="H5283569016BA48F9AF835200E77B0675"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notwithstanding paragraph (1)(B), the deeming of any entity described in subparagraph (B), or of an officer, governing board member, employee, contractor, or on-call provider of such an entity, to be an employee of the Public Health Service for purposes of this section shall apply only with respect to items and services that are furnished to an individual pursuant to section 1867 of the Social Security Act and to post stabilization services (as defined in subparagraph (D)) furnished to such an individual;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H925D9DE8F4C14DAC8F6DE601BCAFD267"><enum>(II)</enum><text>nothing in paragraph (1)(D) shall be construed as preventing a physician or physician group described in subparagraph (B)(ii) from making the application referred to in such paragraph or as conditioning the deeming of a physician or physician group that makes such an application upon receipt by the Secretary of an application from the hospital or emergency department that employs or contracts with the physician or group, or enlists the physician or physician group as an on-call provider;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBA85C0D3EF624C1FAD5B863F0E5943C8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>notwithstanding paragraph (3), this paragraph shall apply only with respect to causes of action arising from acts or omissions that occur on or after January 1, 2016;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDED5A78DA4AA47C6A57AB828AC9DDEB8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>paragraph (5) shall not apply to a physician or physician group described in subparagraph (B)(ii);</text> </subclause><subclause id="HAE6CE36BB9734ADE8A9A438F3E97054B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall make separate estimates under subsection (k)(1) with respect to entities described in subparagraph (B) and entities described in paragraph (4) (other than those described in subparagraph (B)), and the Secretary shall establish separate funds under subsection (k)(2) with respect to such groups of entities, and any appropriations under this subsection for entities described in subparagraph (B) shall be separate from the amounts authorized by subsection (k)(2);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5D0C8F8240C2419BAA8A3CC40C542677"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>notwithstanding subsection (k)(2), the amount of the fund established by the Secretary under such subsection with respect to entities described in subparagraph (B) may exceed a total of $10,000,000 for a fiscal year; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3010223F2D0D426E9325E8300A414738"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>subsection (m) shall not apply to entities described in subparagraph (B).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99E4590B7D8D45B99394F0644FBC9C89" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An entity described in this subparagraph is—</text>
 <clause id="H626E6464872C4C53B239AF8092B971A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a hospital or an emergency department to which section 1867 of the Social Security Act applies; and</text> </clause><clause id="H68F15FD6815A41099ECC4FAE563B78F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a physician or physician group that is employed by, is under contract with, or is an on-call provider of such hospital or emergency department, to furnish items and services to individuals under such section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8935C39E8A04CDE9DD33330919A06F0" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>on-call provider</term> means a physician or physician group that—</text> <clause id="HEE59ABB822A9491693F3B8F4DA8EFC6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has full, temporary, or locum tenens staff privileges at a hospital or emergency department to which section 1867 of the Social Security Act applies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0059F3197B8E4FFC8BA5439557A95529"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not employed by or under contract with such hospital or emergency department, but agrees to be ready and available to provide services pursuant to section 1867 of the Social Security Act or post stabilization services to individuals being treated in the hospital or emergency department with or without compensation from the hospital or emergency department.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EDD7910BEEB4EBFB27D32353BDA3F34" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>post stabilization services</term> means, with respect to an individual who has been treated by an entity described in subparagraph (B) for purposes of complying with section 1867 of the Social Security Act, services that are—</text>
 <clause id="H458D80149A3143BD97B8989F600277D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>related to the condition that was so treated; and</text> </clause><clause id="H467FED9457E74B019A207C9A2AAD26DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provided after the individual is stabilized in order to maintain the stabilized condition or to improve or resolve the condition of the individual.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEF3393D8CF04D889FC06A674D1D58A7" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7CDF43A9732846519FD0AE902D93992C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph (or in any other provision of this section as such provision applies to entities described in subparagraph (B) by operation of subparagraph (A)) shall be construed as authorizing or requiring the Secretary to make payments to such entities, the budget authority for which is not provided in advance by appropriation Acts.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H740CFE309A8A4F44B74CEDF8AC4CD6F7" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary shall limit the total amount of payments under this paragraph for a fiscal year to the total amount appropriated in advance by appropriation Acts for such purpose for such fiscal year. If the total amount of payments that would otherwise be made under this paragraph for a fiscal year exceeds such total amount appropriated, the Secretary shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that the total amount of payments under this paragraph for such fiscal year does not exceed such total amount appropriated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


