<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7CE93279FE85412D92680B131647FBAE" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 727 IH: Puerto Rico Statehood Admission Process Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 727</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150204">February 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000596">Mr. Pierluisi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000689">Mr. Mica</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001179">Mr. Schock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000473">Mr. Takai</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To set forth the process for Puerto Rico to be admitted as a State of the Union.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H472E4DDDB5FB4387A8136B613A88162C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H89FD3BEF5EE1440F84F358800BB2B2B6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puerto Rico Statehood Admission Process Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H84DEB0D0F04C495DA795828B86D7A40A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE4FC6BB5171F4787A10404489EC53C66"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1898, Puerto Rico became a United States territory and persons born in Puerto Rico have been granted United States citizenship since 1917, pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/64/368">Public Law 64–368</external-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60F431A00D7444EB9DCF5B4D29DB7AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 1950, Congress enacted <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/81/600">Public Law 81–600</external-xref>, authorizing Puerto Rico to draft a local constitution. In 1951, a constitutional convention was held in Puerto Rico to draft the constitution. On March 3, 1952, Puerto Rico ratified the constitution and submitted it for approval by Congress. On July 3, 1952, Congress enacted <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/82/447">Public Law 82–447</external-xref>, which made changes to the constitution, and approved the constitution subject to Puerto Rico’s acceptance of these changes. The changes were accepted by the delegates to the constitutional convention, and the constitution of Puerto Rico took effect on July 25, 1952. The constitution establishes a republican form of government, is not repugnant to the Constitution of the United States, and is the functional equivalent of a state constitution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H707EE47E316A44EEA44089E4F69ACA35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On November 6, 2012, the Government of Puerto Rico held a two-part plebiscite organized under local law. The first question asked voters if Puerto Rico should continue to be a territory, and 54 percent of voters rejected territory status. The second question asked voters to express their preference among the three possible alternatives to territory status—statehood, independence, and nationhood in free association with the United States—and 61 percent of voters who selected an option chose statehood. The number of votes cast for statehood on the second question exceeded the number of votes cast for continued territory status on the first question.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30B746586B5E453DA7270290281AEED4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On August 1, 2013, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate held a hearing to receive testimony on the 2012 plebiscite. In his opening statement, the Chairman of the Committee said that <quote>there is no disputing that a majority of the voters in Puerto Rico—54 percent—have clearly expressed their opposition to continuing the current territorial status</quote>. The ranking minority member of the Committee agreed, stating that <quote>it is clear to me that the majority of Puerto Ricans do not favor the current territorial status</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H62A379E450D34B2186CD0D8442E48292"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Also at the August 1, 2013 hearing, the Chairman recognized that <quote>for Puerto Rico to meet its economic and social challenges and to achieve its full potential, this debate over status needs to be settled</quote> and that <quote>the current relationship undermines the United States’ moral standing in the world. For a nation founded on the principles of democracy and the consent of the governed, how much longer can America allow a condition to persist in which nearly four million U.S. citizens do not have a vote in the government that makes the national laws which affect their daily lives?</quote> The Chairman acknowledged that, for Puerto Rico to have full self-government, it must become <quote>a sovereign nation or achieve equality among the States of the Union</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A91249621B4FCDA08470B57BFEEAB3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The President’s Fiscal Year 2014 Budget requested $2.5 million for the first Federally sponsored plebiscite in Puerto Rico’s history, to be held on options that would <quote>resolve Puerto Rico’s future political status</quote> and that are found by the Department of Justice not to be <quote>incompatible with the Constitution and laws and policies of the United States</quote>. This proposal was enacted in January 2014 as part of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1317441B4C044B78E74FB3404A276C9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Alaska and Hawaii are the most recent territories to become States of the Union. <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</external-xref> (July 7, 1958), <quote>an act to provide for the admission of the State of Alaska into the Union</quote>, and <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/86/3">Public Law 86–3</external-xref> (March 18, 1959), <quote>an act to provide for the admission of the State of Hawaii into the Union</quote>, were enacted after a majority of voters in each territory expressed a desire for statehood in plebiscites organized under local law. These Acts of Congress provided that admission would occur if a majority of voters affirmed in a Federally sponsored plebiscite that the territory should <quote>be admitted into the Union as a State</quote>. The Federally sponsored plebiscite in the territory of Alaska was held on August 26, 1958, and Alaska was admitted into the Union on January 3, 1959. The Federally sponsored plebiscite in the territory of Hawaii was held on June 27, 1959, and Hawaii was admitted into the Union on August 21, 1959.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC115BFC141EE460884F077EFE022B6EB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Vote on admission</header>
 <subsection id="H8EF6F59D1FD244F7836A6D2D949EF539"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vote</header><text>The State Elections Commission of Puerto Rico is authorized to provide for a vote on the admission of Puerto Rico into the Union as a State within one year of the date of enactment of this Act, in accordance with rules and regulations determined by the Commission, including qualifications for voter eligibility. The ballot shall ask the following question: <quote>Shall Puerto Rico be admitted as a State of the United States? Yes__ No__</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H39267158BF0044109D4DF245C42CD76B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funds for vote</header><text>The funds made available pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref> may be used to conduct the vote.</text> </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA5D405470AD454AA867B2524093CCCB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Certification and transmittal of results</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the certification of the vote by the State Elections Commission of Puerto Rico, the Governor of Puerto Rico shall transmit the certified results to the President of the United States, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate.</text>
 </section><section id="H7DFD5C5777244A7BAF849D21483AD7C6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Transition process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If a majority of the votes cast in the vote conducted pursuant to section 3 are for Puerto Rico’s admission into the Union as a State—</text>
 <subsection id="HBC2933F663D64208BC577E63251B4BA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Proclamation</header><text>Within 30 calendar days of receipt of the certified results transmitted pursuant to section 4, the President shall issue a proclamation to begin the transition process that will culminate in Puerto Rico’s admission into the Union as a State effective January 1, 2021.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H254255A1A052422991E3AADDE64F152B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>Within 90 calendar days of receipt of the certified results transmitted pursuant to section 4, the President shall appoint a Commission on the Equal Application of Federal Law to Puerto Rico.</text>
 <paragraph id="HFF0F04A7B9E440B9964D3090B60D70FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Commission shall survey the laws of the United States and make recommendations to Congress as to how laws that do not apply to the territory or apply differently to the territory than to the several States should be amended or repealed to treat Puerto Rico equally with the several States as of the date of the admission of Puerto Rico into the Union as a State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8810D72510F549D2A0873BE924AAC9B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Commission shall consist of five persons, at least two of whom shall be residents of Puerto Rico.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE270996F15CB40C4AA9DCAF32217AB5D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Commission shall issue a final report to the President of the United States, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate by July 1, 2018.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AD1DEB6AB73409F9A63FC45FB6ACE1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Upon issuing the final report under paragraph (3), the Commission shall terminate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B50E03B3CB4259BB32E9BCC9F64B3B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.), other than section 14, shall apply to the Commission.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF7C5609AEE644168A4C327565896AD92" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rules for elections for Federal offices</header>
 <subsection id="H7C1E4FC46FEA41FFBC7D3AC892320AB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preparation for Elections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2020, Puerto Rico shall carry out such actions as may be necessary to enable Puerto Rico to hold elections for Federal office in November 2020 in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4995E102DFC64F7CADFFB01415764626"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presidential Election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the election for the office of President and Vice President held in November 2020—</text> <paragraph id="HE7E4AA550CB44AB0835B806117AE84C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Puerto Rico shall be considered a State for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of title 3, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2D2CB6C1AF0494398592B41830AFE62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the electors of Puerto Rico shall be considered electors of a State for purposes of such chapter; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9584EED019B24477883DDF5A30768257"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for purposes of section 3 of such title, the number of electors from Puerto Rico shall be equal to the number of Senators and Representatives to which Puerto Rico is entitled during the One Hundred Seventeenth Congress, as determined in accordance with subsections (c) and (d).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H639701B166F74C42B279474927566517"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Election of Senators</header>
 <paragraph id="H136F25EDA42D48729D564B427BE8EA3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Election of 2 Senators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regularly scheduled general elections for Federal office held in Puerto Rico during November 2020 shall include the election of 2 Senators, each of whom shall first take office on the first day of the One Hundred Seventeenth Congress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DC7A53E279A4661BAD26701738E2EB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>In the election of Senators from Puerto Rico pursuant to paragraph (1), the 2 Senate offices shall be separately identified and designated, and no person may be a candidate for both offices. No such identification or designation of either of the offices shall refer to or be taken to refer to the terms of such offices, or in any way impair the privilege of the Senate to determine the class to which each of the Senators elected shall be assigned.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D3964B069F0419E9D9392F9DA8AF4A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Election of Representatives</header>
 <paragraph id="HC248E8FC9F464333B433CD77891E6688"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the first day of the One Hundred Seventeenth Congress, and until the taking effect of the first reapportionment occurring after the regular decennial census conducted for 2020, Puerto Rico shall be entitled to the number of Representatives to which it would have been entitled for the One Hundred Sixteenth Congress if Puerto Rico had been a State during such Congress, as shown in the statement transmitted by the President to Congress under paragraph (2).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBA89893C722F4685846A4258959A4E3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of initial number</header>
 <subparagraph id="H036364AEDF464F46888EEB3AADCA0C19"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 1, 2019, the President shall submit to Congress a statement of the number of Representatives to which Puerto Rico would have been entitled for the One Hundred Sixteenth Congress if Puerto Rico had been a State during such Congress, in the same manner as provided under section 22(a) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the fifteenth and subsequent decennial censuses and to provide for apportionment of Representatives in Congress</quote>, approved June 28, 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H504128898CD14F5B990C7703AD725E97"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission of number by Clerk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 calendar days after receiving the statement of the President under subparagraph (A), the Clerk of the House of Representatives, in accordance with section 22(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a(b)</external-xref>), shall transmit to the Governor of Puerto Rico and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a certificate of the number of Representatives to which Puerto Rico is entitled during the period described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56C467D4BAE14357A96D036E9BABC7A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination of Office of Resident Commissioner</header><text>Effective on the date on which a Representative from Puerto Rico first takes office in accordance with this subsection, the Office of the Resident Commissioner to the United States, as described in section 36 of the Act of March 2, 1917 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/891">48 U.S.C. 891 et seq.</external-xref>), is terminated.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2042ED0F22F3401AAD08683E073B7B76"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration of Primary Elections</header><text>Puerto Rico may hold primary elections for the offices described in this section at such time and in such manner as Puerto Rico may provide, so long as such elections are held in the manner required by the laws applicable to elections for Federal office.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H419FB05A92924C7A9E9A0D1E8F07ADD8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Issuance of Presidential proclamation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Following the transition process set forth in section 5, the President shall issue a proclamation declaring that Puerto Rico is admitted into the Union on an equal footing with the other States, effective January 1, 2021. Upon issuance of the proclamation by the President, Puerto Rico shall be deemed admitted into the Union as a State.</text>
 </section><section id="H2692AD4C860C48469F62371CE35903F0"><enum>8.</enum><header>State of Puerto Rico</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon the admission of Puerto Rico into the Union as a State—</text> <subsection id="HBDC13E7164A345F0A2F6183C20975251"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State constitution</header><text>The Constitution of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall be accepted as the Constitution of the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB51D24204ACB43B685C578654ABA3DF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Territory</header><text>The State shall consist of all of the territory, together with the waters included in the seaward boundary, of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE1D6C34FFDA34ECBB442389CF25763C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continuity of government</header><text>The persons holding legislative, executive, and judicial offices of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall continue to discharge the duties of their respective offices.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB5C8FF2A80394745BA0FFACA127C11E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continuity of laws</header>
 <paragraph id="HF9A475B1363D4E788796A2BF4874F6CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Territory law</header><text>All of the territory laws in force in Puerto Rico shall continue in force and effect in the State, except as modified by this Act, and shall be subject to repeal or amendment by the Legislature and the Governor of Puerto Rico.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E0D7A0B91BA4057B6402926113478A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal law</header><text>All of the laws of the United States shall have the same force and effect as on the date immediately prior to the date of admission of Puerto Rico into the Union as a State, except for any provision of law that treats Puerto Rico and its residents differently than the States of the Union and their residents, which shall be amended as of the date of admission to treat the State of Puerto Rico and its residents equally with the other States of the Union and their residents.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H10F21CEF8A3043959B044776E26E3BC6"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effect on membership of House of Representatives</header>
			<subsection id="HD337EC13595D47E0AE637831A7E255D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary Increase During Initial Period</header>
 <paragraph id="H62CAC71D156F438595A275E0DDE46803"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Temporary increase</header><text>During the period described in paragraph (1) of section 6(d)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9960EBA96594F0D9765A67D02228468"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the membership of the House of Representatives shall be increased by the number of Members to which Puerto Rico is entitled during such period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B2A024CA8E3471ABFDF25229B2F7ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each such Representative shall be in addition to the membership of the House of Representatives as now prescribed by law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA540A8C45B7E480293D2448E6F2A96B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on existing apportionment</header><text>The temporary increase in the membership of the House of Representatives provided under paragraph (1) shall not, during the period described in paragraph (1) of section 6(d)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4719D397EAAE4D2DB4A3DF3C006DA43F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operate to either increase or decrease the permanent membership of the House of Representatives as prescribed in the Act of August 8, 1911 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2">2 U.S.C. 2</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF9EBC5F4B6847FEB7CEDF1A63F7A68A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affect the basis of reapportionment established by the Act of June 28, 1929, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a</external-xref>), for the Eighty Second Congress and each Congress thereafter.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E28B38A79BE4E409A037CE2E2E8778E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permanent Increase Effective With Next Reapportionment</header>
 <paragraph id="H329F23F8BB714144AD4FAA0100599508"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective with respect to the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress and each succeeding Congress, the House of Representatives shall be composed of a number of Members equal to the sum of 435 plus the number by which the membership of the House was increased under subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HE1D9E94ACB2A46E3B6EFD479FE905EEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reapportionment of Members resulting from increase</header>
 <subparagraph id="H53CA3C59180F42F7920FD310EF6E8643"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 22(a) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the fifteenth and subsequent decennial censuses and to provide for apportionment of Representatives in Congress</quote>, approved June 28, 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a(a)</external-xref>), is amended by striking <quote>the then existing number of Representatives</quote> and inserting <quote>the number of Representatives established with respect to the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5831F9C6BF048EDA2897ADC7F3A5B12"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subparagraph (A) shall apply with respect to the regular decennial census conducted for 2020 and each subsequent regular decennial census.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


