<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H51A456B238F345798B7164DBA3C1A1C3" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2088 : United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2088</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20150610">June 10, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the United States Grain Standards Act to improve inspection services performed at export
			 elevators at export port locations, to reauthorize certain authorities of
			 the Secretary of Agriculture under such Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H156834ABF5FD4A68A0AB9A1A2E7762CD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4CC0FE93EF9D441C860F96C6AE69E9E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Grain Standards Act Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA1F00DD635934C609328A64E1FC912A6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of United States Grain Standards Act</header> <subsection id="HFFF94B756218414585C8EDD0B12EE980"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy and purpose of Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2(b) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/74">7 U.S.C. 74(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H236EE7A46FAF46859DEC5C9BFBB759D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>to both domestic and foreign buyers</quote> and inserting <quote>responsive to the purchase specifications of domestic and foreign buyers</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1D529DF110242A8B0D20C58E62BCB20"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD9C5A7EA1C64143B8B084ACA3CCB31A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AD8A3ADF94647A59F5DC0BE28135FED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DF7E9BC479546298A7826C3CE8ACB73" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H5E422FDF1DA54B3DB77082F2CB2B2004"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide an accurate, reliable, consistently available, and cost-effective official grain inspection and weighing system.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01FF3C73DAF048EAA08911E4A48E7E67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <paragraph id="H719D4179D4F3484B8F621B8C3EF1DEA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Major disaster defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/75">7 U.S.C. 75</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H374E9C1825D24ABC873BB3AC73E3BCFB" style="OLC">
 <item id="idDD6BF3F01630476E955C1FA1BDF1307D" indent="up4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>major disaster</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 102(2) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(2)</external-xref>), except that the term includes a severe weather incident causing a region-wide interruption of government services.</text></item><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF15F92B2BFAC4BF58D411170DB93267B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/75">7 U.S.C. 75</external-xref>) is further amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HB5DE601DEA0D45A3960C479E851A9DD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (a), by striking <quote>otherwise–</quote> and inserting <quote>otherwise:</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E9A5BBEC19C4020B74712AC8060E401"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>the term</quote> at the beginning of each paragraph (other than paragraphs (n) and (t)) and inserting <quote>The term</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3159B08D60AF41B48F1DA5041A0201CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (i)—</text>
 <clause id="H2BB8C1D00C6F42F693CA363B0A3BE66D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Act (the term</quote> and inserting <quote>Act. The term</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6C1CFD6E421A4396B2AEDEE9344D20E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>);</quote> and inserting a period;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4437C350374140EA922D635220B700D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraphs (n) and (t), by striking <quote>the terms</quote> and inserting <quote>The terms</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C55580586404385B860903535F5F6DC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (o)—</text>
 <clause id="H0887AFEAF54A4F39B37FF4BB116F8613"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>personnel (the term</quote> and inserting <quote>personnel. The term</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8111A21906E743EDA5A5A76549A29DB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>);</quote> and inserting a period;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0B7D453A5CF48D19852C33590943D85"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in paragraph (s), by striking <quote>the verb</quote> and inserting <quote>The verb</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC20BB02E36DF41EC9281B005CBDBF6DE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in paragraph (x)—</text>
 <clause id="H5EB55AFA2CD54E6BAF0D4DC60071A231"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>conveyance (the terms</quote> and inserting <quote>conveyance. The terms</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6BFB992D5D064216BC6F830378652F3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>accordingly);</quote> and inserting <quote>accordingly.</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68F9BC56E15F4482AD7E7CC150076853"><enum>(H)</enum><text>by striking the semicolon at the end of each paragraph (other than paragraphs (i), (o), (x), and (y)) and inserting a period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72B9F156E03247F1A1668D2E3AB6C17A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (y), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H585E6903FA694B7BA4BCA0A619E262BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Official inspection and weighing requirements</header> <paragraph id="H3A70A061A6A4464F97BC0F17DC6DC40D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Discretionary waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(a)(1) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/77">7 U.S.C. 77(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended in the first proviso by striking <quote>may waive the foregoing requirement in emergency</quote> and inserting <quote>shall promptly waive the foregoing requirement in the event of an emergency, a major disaster,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H600CA7B2AD6A4180B0F048B5B314EC5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Weighing requirements at export elevators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(a)(2) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/77">7 U.S.C. 77(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>intracompany shipments of grain into an export elevator by any mode of transportation, grain transferred into an export elevator by transportation modes other than barge,</quote> and inserting <quote>shipments of grain into an export elevator by any mode of transportation</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F5EEE1D5B834796AE2E2A164F458C89"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Delegation of official inspection authority</header>
 <paragraph id="HF5A4BCBDA6DA4D5080AD165DCE483476"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorized inspection personnel at export elevators at export port locations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 7(e) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(e)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H941E21B09632402B809DDF7398BF4314" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H252935C2800744ED964881DB74357611" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection, the Secretary shall cause official inspection at export elevators at export port locations, for all grain required or authorized to be inspected by this Act, to be performed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0ACDC03C745B4964841E555AD02C9BB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE558F93B830489EBC9F711BE5F666AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by other persons under contract with the Secretary as provided in section 8 of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1EDE3DF03D154F49980853BB36548094"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delegation to state agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(e) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2068938374F480EAE757AFAAF248CA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause id="HC4A8C2E5285A4D459D1C593B20CC4403"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, meets the criteria</quote> and all that follows through <quote>the Secretary may delegate</quote> and inserting <quote>and meets the criteria specified in subsection (f)(1)(A) of this section, the Secretary may delegate</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC36601310CF14BC798EF5FC088A9F90D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>at export port locations within the State, including export port locations</quote> and inserting <quote>at export elevators at export port locations within the State, including at export elevators at export port locations</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC3B7E7B4A0C446E0BF4B770E9DA078B9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the last sentence, by striking <quote>Any such delegation</quote> and inserting <quote>The delegation under this paragraph of authority to conduct official inspection services shall be for a term not to exceed 5 years, and may be renewed thereafter in accordance with this subsection, except that any such delegation</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81F1BE42B9734682A348CD3C646F55AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by transferring paragraph (4) to the end of subsection (f), redesignating such paragraph as paragraph (5), and, in such paragraph, by striking <quote>or subsection (f)</quote> and inserting <quote>or subsection (e)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEB62C3DCD7B444280B3BCBF3D3D5C71"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7D1F19973524458B5F4B584805A8AA7" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H8F9A4E8251954A448004B58058D2524A" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to delegating authority to a State agency for the performance of official inspection services at export elevators at export port locations pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Secretary shall comply with the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H20642F1DF43D403F9A9E8F7CC8AB6498"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of an application from a State agency requesting the delegation of authority to perform official inspection services on behalf of the Secretary, publish notice of the application in the Federal Register and provide a minimum 30-day comment period on the application.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBCD5646D2E444EAB4896BB92E2F23D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evaluate the comments received under subparagraph (A) with respect to an application and conduct an investigation to determine whether the State agency that submitted the application and its personnel are qualified to perform official inspection services on behalf of the Secretary. In conducting the investigation, the Secretary shall consult with, and review the available files of the Department of Justice, the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Agriculture, and the Government Accountability Office.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H127C0C50392E43938CA165D492BEA850"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Make findings based on the results of the investigation and consideration of public comments received.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0EB3C074E024E7DBFF2426587EC8FDA"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Publish a notice in the Federal Register announcing whether the State agency has been delegated the authority to perform official inspection services at export elevators at export port locations on behalf of the Secretary, and the basis upon which the Secretary has made the decision.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39A4230DC60F40AA87B708A0DB8D8747" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H663FD27E31E4485F973DA0A7E673BAD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except in the case of a major disaster, if a State agency that has been delegated the authority to perform official inspection services at export elevators at export port locations on behalf of the Secretary fails to perform such official services, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, within 90 days after the first day on which inspection services were not performed by the delegated State agency, a report containing—</text>
 <clause id="H850DC63020D44CC197612250485C19D4" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the reasons for the State agency’s failure; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6EAE05A470924A52B7E766414CEDC6A6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rationale as to whether or not the Secretary will permit the State agency to retain its delegated authority.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99F0006EABBA4B2DB9410C5F8E4D1ED9" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State agency may request that the delegation of inspection authority to the agency be canceled by providing written notice to the Secretary at least 90 days in advance of the requested cancellation date.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E04DA8B3CAB4280AA9C87FC1E8140D1" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State agency that has been delegated the authority under paragraph (2) of this subsection to perform official inspection services at an export elevator at an export port location on behalf of the Secretary intends to temporarily discontinue such official inspection services or weighing services for any reason, except in the case of a major disaster, the State agency shall notify the Secretary in writing of its intention to do so at least 72 hours in advance of the discontinuation date. The receipt of such prior notice shall be considered by the Secretary as a mitigating factor in determining whether to maintain or revoke the delegation of authority to the State agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H583294397F4847E891B422A0564BB941"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE50743945DC64FDB96F8149C30E4AE35"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(f)(1) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>other than at export port locations</quote> and inserting <quote>(other than at an export elevator at an export port location)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B1F7B14A10A48D99A640EFACFE01C50" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 16(d) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/87e">7 U.S.C. 87e(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>The Office of Investigation of the Department of Agriculture (or such other organization or agency within the Department of Agriculture which may be delegated the authority, in lieu thereof, to conduct investigations on behalf of the Department of Agriculture)</quote> and inserting <quote>The Office of Inspector General of the Department of Agriculture</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H403B84395D4A43049A31E4EF4905A49D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evaluation of current delegations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall complete a review of each State agency that, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, has been delegated inspection authority under section 7(e) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(e)</external-xref>) and determine if the State agency is qualified to continue to perform official inspection services at export elevators at export port locations on behalf of the Secretary under such section, as amended by this subsection. The Secretary shall conduct the review subject to the requirements of section 7(e) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(e)</external-xref>), as amended by this subsection, and a State agency determined to be qualified to continue to perform such official inspection services shall be subject thereafter to such requirements.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB96B28E161DE41DAA7C6825F8B71958D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Continuity of operations</header><text>Section 7(e) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(e)</external-xref>) is further amended by inserting after paragraph (4), as added by subsection (d), the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4F8FDC3B6E94938B50D5FCECA3B06BD" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H889DDB4CE860494C9EADBF82D604AE84" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except in the case of a major disaster, the Secretary shall cause official inspections at an export elevator at an export port location—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCBB24EC6AC634A9CBA04D58E319A650E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be performed without interruption by official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary or by a State agency delegated such authority under paragraph (2) of this subsection; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F67682C29174D4D9DBEC3CDD69CDFA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if interrupted, to be resumed at the export elevator by utilizing official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary or by another delegated State agency as provided under paragraph (2) of this subsection as follows:</text>
 <clause id="HD9D4FF09C700498E8C6D427ED06CC047"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 6 hours after the interruption, if the interruption is caused by a State agency delegated such authority under this subsection and the Secretary received advance notice of the interruption pursuant to paragraph (4)(C) of this subsection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEAB77D9E780046328547E33072F67271"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 12 hours after the interruption, if the State agency failed to provide the required advance notice of the interruption.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FA7924487A942EC82965D5AD7391818" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB13BB4805CC344C5918DE61F6455ABA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary is unable to restore official inspection services within the applicable time period required by paragraph (5)(B) of this subsection, the interested person requesting such services at the export elevator at an export port location shall be authorized to utilize official inspection personnel, as provided under section 8 of the Act, employed by another State agency delegated authority under paragraph (2) of this subsection or designated under subsection (f)(1) of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0F5CB1D826D4B10817AB9B5A27DCF03" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A delegated or designated State agency providing inspection services under subparagraph (A) may, at its discretion, provide such services for a period of up to 90 days from the date on which the services are initiated, after which time the Secretary may restore official inspection services using official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary or a State agency delegated such authority under this subsection, if available. The State agency shall notify the Secretary in writing of its intention to discontinue inspection services under subparagraph (A) at least 72 hours in advance of the discontinuation date.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF8BC86CDABA487F8994A071A3951035" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall make available to the public, including pursuant to a website maintained by the Secretary, a list of all delegated States and all official agencies authorized to perform official inspections on behalf of the Secretary. This list shall include the name, contact information, and category of authority granted. The Secretary shall update the list at least semiannually.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H9A39C6D4896444D88FE4AAB182526747"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Geographic boundaries for official agencies</header>
 <paragraph id="H54958203E19249F5BB1D09904224C404"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Official inspection authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(f)(2) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(f)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Secretary may</quote> and all that follows through the end of the paragraph and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBE84AD158DDD4D37B0F47735DB405BC4" style="OLC"> <text>the Secretary shall allow a designated official agency to cross boundary lines to carry out inspections in another geographic area if—</text><subparagraph id="HC14E9A4661C248C7BBF3071427389DE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current designated official agency for that geographic area is unable to provide inspection services in a timely manner;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H529CF6D152584F46A8A62F97FC0EACE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person requesting inspection services in that geographic area requests a probe inspection on a barge-lot basis; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9957FE202E9D47D99B5D1D366BBBCCB3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current official agency for that geographic area agrees in writing with the adjacent official agency to waive the current geographic area restriction at the request of the applicant for service.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5249D44B89B4DA7B06922B50A701C8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Weighing authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7A(i)(2) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79a">7 U.S.C. 79a(i)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Secretary may</quote> and all that follows through the end of the paragraph and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H360A6C5B40EF4CCDA58A7441E5DB5AA4" style="OLC">
 <text>the Secretary shall allow a designated official agency to cross boundary lines to carry out weighing in another geographic area if—</text><subparagraph id="H1705FD202C82488AAFB1E85EB481166F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current designated official agency for that geographic area is unable to provide weighing services in a timely manner; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF62E5BF256544A2E9836CD8928D0822D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the current official agency for that geographic area agrees in writing with the adjacent official agency to waive the current geographic area restriction at the request of the applicant for service.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H661B00508FD649219677F8EA764E634A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Duration of designations of official agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(g)(1) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>triennially</quote> and inserting <quote>every 5 years</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H4E1CDB73BCA041958BCE6B58520A1721"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Inspection fees</header> <paragraph id="HD3DE8CBA67054849A1683A47BA7F66BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection and amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(j)(1) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(j)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9584CE69D2114128A4FDC244AF7397C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(A)</quote> after <quote>(1)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76E1754E577C461EB20DA749E8A4C9CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7E3C13106684353A9DC2288ED10F486" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H60FD49DD3E8D4DEEB80F0BCD2C351C0F" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For official inspections and weighing at an export elevator at an export port location performed by the Secretary, performed by a State agency delegated the authority to perform official inspection services at the export elevator on behalf of the Secretary, or performed by a State agency utilized as authorized by subsection (e)(6)(A), the portion of the fees based upon export tonnage shall be based upon a rolling 5-year average of export tonnage volumes. In order to maintain an operating reserve of between 3 to 6 months, the Secretary shall adjust such fees at least annually.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8439D66D1ED04E8DA457F43463B1391E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(j)(4) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79">7 U.S.C. 79(j)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2020</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9720EE5105C4B39B648C03842F7AE62"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Official weighing or supervision at locations where official inspection is provided other than by the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7A(c)(2) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79a">7 U.S.C. 79a(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H18002F5D20564C848FE0B555799041A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>with respect to export port locations</quote> and inserting <quote>with respect to an export elevator at an export port location</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE637CDD9B8CA49658382CC890193FB43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the last sentence by striking <quote>subsection (g) of section 7</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (e) and (g) of section 7</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H759E70A440FF4238AD16153109B1FC6D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Collection of fees for weighing services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7A(l)(3) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79a">7 U.S.C. 79a(l)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2020</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFB99F405114C4DC3A02762CA95318B98"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitation and administrative and supervisory costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7D of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/79d">7 U.S.C. 79d</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2015</quote> and inserting <quote>2020</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H627B5EABCE9B4BB6B7E85DF61BEECD1A"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Issuance of authorizations</header> <paragraph id="HF86A6989363D420984CE7C66F30427C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(b) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/84">7 U.S.C. 84(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>triennially</quote> and inserting <quote>every 5 years</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37E8118A0E56447591E24A78CA94DA7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Persons who may be hired as official inspection personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(e) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/84">7 U.S.C. 84(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H4AF638D06D924C518DCFDA4F83FE337B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(on the date of enactment of the United States Grain Standards Act of 1976)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5223145545074A7C8765AD7286B55769"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>the United States Grain Standards Act</quote> and inserting <quote>this Act</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F75FE51CBCA49A4B4A8F5B5B17D59DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, on the date of enactment of the United States Grain Standards Act of 1976, was performing</quote> and inserting <quote>performs</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB05B3653FF048EFB2190A5C7446AC5C"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 19 of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/87h">7 U.S.C. 87h</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2015</quote> and inserting <quote>2020</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H866C42E8009D441FBC3103896140C565"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Expiration of advisory committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 21(e) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/87j">7 U.S.C. 87j(e)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2020</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H201E12DC31E74044AF5DD9E4CBB1F490"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Technical corrections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 17B(b) of the United States Grain Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/87f-2">7 U.S.C. 87f–2(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H51CD988E8A644E768851C4738C06D113"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>notwithstanding the provisions of section 812 of the Agricultural Act of 1970, as added by the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/612c-3">7 U.S.C. 612c–3</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>notwithstanding section 602 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5712">7 U.S.C. 5712</external-xref>)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H125129643F684948A85902E09665FBDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or the Secretary</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20150609">Passed the House of Representatives June 9, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

