<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC1C1A8ECA4214BEC8932F5882C07E6C9" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2602 IH: Prioritizing Online Threat Enforcement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2602</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150602">June 2, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To enhance enforcement of laws related to cybercrimes against persons, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3A8AE8D884CE425AB3CCF19BC48A2027" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE35F870BDF7142E781BF88E87826AB0F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prioritizing Online Threat Enforcement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDA074701EDC741C7821BBD662BA89B89"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improved investigative and forensic resources for enforcement of laws related to cybercrimes against persons</header> <subsection id="HBD4B61FFB21C464EA1279F45C21CFA13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this subsection, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall, with respect to cybercrimes against persons—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDB96CC91A32A4C91915A73E113A8F672"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that there are at least 10 additional operational agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation designated to support the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice in the investigation and coordination of cybercrimes against persons;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90FF09E23268489181C1F8B436FEEB78"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that each office of a United States Attorney designates at least 1 Assistant United States Attorney as responsible for investigating and prosecuting cybercrimes against persons; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H115A7AEB029942CFA58BD55E0FED3C0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure the implementation of a regular and comprehensive training program—</text> <subparagraph id="HDF659C2128C54AF5BD47E05DE86DD81F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purpose of which is to train agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes and the enforcement of laws related to cy­ber­crimes against persons; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EC4E415DDBA4DDFAF0577998F67C41F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that includes relevant forensic training related to investigating and prosecuting cy­ber­crimes against persons.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A2272EBA12D44348C77AC243B5CA602"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional funding for resources</header>
 <paragraph id="H78E2EDC498B945CBBA0394809DB1957F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise authorized for resources to investigate and prosecute criminal activity, there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5593AEDCC2D44A768CA127178F3F19B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7496D8D4CD5E4CA896FF8CF13FC6FD70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of additional funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available under this subsection shall be used by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Attorney General, for the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice, respectively, to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5C295974BC3B4D4B8C384F0551FFC0EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hire and train law enforcement officers to—</text> <clause id="H6EA6249A45294C059D4518570D30B9FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investigate cybercrimes against person; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEA63FE576BD84F8FA4F71D666130F35C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assist in the prosecution of such crimes; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE446B2A52B54BBC81E82850F92A1248"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enable relevant units of the Department of Justice, including units responsible for investigating cybercrimes against persons, to procure advanced tools of forensic science and expert computer forensic assistance, including from non-governmental entities, to investigate, prosecute, and study such crimes.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H39A350AC614E4285843D9806CFDF1E26"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual reports</header>
 <subsection id="HA7AF833F983E429FAF5C8CD6B1AEB748"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report of the attorney general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress on actions taken to carry out this Act. The initial report required under this subsection shall be submitted by May 1, 2016. All subsequent annual reports shall be submitted by May 1st of each fiscal year thereafter. The report required under this subsection may be submitted as part of the annual performance report of the Department of Justice, and shall include, with respect to the authorizations under section 2, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1BFEB3589DB745B890FE3C0970A60D23"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of law enforcement officers hired and trained.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC72866869ED745C4823436C4EB0AC9CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number and type of investigations and prosecutions resulting from law enforcement officers designated to cybercrimes against persons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FE3BFF7DDEA4CA1BB76286D1BBF9804"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The advanced tools of forensic science procured to investigate, prosecute, and study cy­ber­crimes against persons.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HB96D599697E24A9AB9906FDDFFADB797"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definition of cybercrimes against persons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The term <quote>cybercrimes against persons</quote> means cy­ber­stalk­ing, criminal harassment carried out over the Internet, or threats communicated over the Internet, including violations of section 875 or 2261A of title 18, United States Code.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


