<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4EB13D406AC44681BCF39C320EF47AEB" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2292 IH: Preserving Rehabilitation Innovation Centers Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 2292</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150513">May 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000613">Mr. Dold</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to preserve access to rehabilitation innovation centers under the Medicare program.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9605B4FE64F14B21804FDA4E35AEEEE9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6B583382FD06463BB7A476B2760D3728" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving Rehabilitation Innovation Centers Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H580B7D1C4D0D467FA2A9B95CA4DD71E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
<paragraph id="H2692C4D43A66412EAC1D4BD347DDD6E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the United States, there are an estimated 1,181 inpatient rehabilitation facilities. Among these facilities is a small group of inpatient rehabilitation institutions that are contributing to the future of rehabilitation care medicine, as well as to patient recovery, scientific innovation, and quality of life.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39F662A798874B8BA6ECD38E3733D9EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This unique category of inpatient rehabilitation institutions treats the most complex patient conditions, such as traumatic brain injury, stroke, spinal cord injury, childhood disease, burns, and wartime injuries.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H725BC7D914A44D7BB6338D5D1A9D8A7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These leading inpatient rehabilitation institutions are all not-for-profit or Government-owned institutions and serve a high volume of Medicare or Medicaid beneficiaries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H882A066728084C0E823CA5038A3A4EB2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>These leading inpatient rehabilitation institutions have been recognized by the Federal Government for their contributions to cutting-edge research to develop solutions that enhance quality of care, improve patient outcomes, and reduce health care costs.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H69B6AD1E41564518A57935B5A07CC0DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>These leading inpatient rehabilitation institutions help to improve the practice and standard of rehabilitation medicine across the Nation in urban, suburban, and rural communities by training physicians, medical students, and other clinicians, and providing care to patients from all 50 States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4EF575913344C23B89E2FC97682ADE6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>It is vital that these leading inpatient rehabilitation institutions are supported so they can continue to lead the Nation’s efforts to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H400D800ACC094E22866891E9905AF6FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advance integrated, multidisciplinary rehabilitation research;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CA44F1796424D6997DCA674F3C260B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide cutting-edge medical care to the most complex rehabilitation patients;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H71F9330B6BBD43489F9E99759606B727"><enum>(C)</enum><text>serve as education and training facilities for the physicians, nurses, and other health professionals who serve rehabilitation patients;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF26FC7912DDC4BB0AC9A205EFBFE8357"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure Medicare and Medicaid beneficiaries receive state-of-the-art, high-quality rehabilitation care by developing and disseminating best practices and advancing the quality of care utilized by post-acute providers in all 50 States; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H613F38A2D3CF4E3BAA58C835E351E3D9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support other inpatient rehabilitation institutions in rural areas to help ensure access to quality post-acute care for patients living in these communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HF32CCE6E314E4CE4A0FD7FECC2E3B82F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Indirect costs payment for rehabilitation innovation centers</header> <subsection id="HF658EE1256934BAAB1E69054D39E7DAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1886(j) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(j)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HF73AB6A1F02F44B38EA6919DF53AF6B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (8) as paragraph (9); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FF10AA9B01A43458A96851EB8F40A85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (7) the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7201CB001C414286A051EE91CF27F1D6" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H93F4BFFF296D4A1FA0DBBC80A94FA607"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Indirect costs payment for rehabilitation innovation centers</header>
<subparagraph id="HC63BC30CB202418F9B13D10476ECE38D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Study relating to additional payments to rehabilitation innovation centers to account for higher costs; authority to increase payments</header>
<clause id="H139A486451D74B35AE0F3571F8A51838"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2017, the Secretary shall conduct a study to determine whether there should be an increase in the prospective payment rate that would otherwise be made to a rehabilitation innovation center under this subsection for purposes of covering the additional costs that are incurred by such centers in furnishing items and services to individuals under this title, conducting research, and providing medical training, and if the Secretary determines that such an increase is recommended, the amount of such increase that is needed to cover such additional costs.</text></clause> <clause id="H9CCBEE4761D144FDA7398848313E3569"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authority to increase payments</header><text>Insofar as the Secretary determines under clause (i) that there should be an increase in the prospective payment rate to rehabilitation innovation centers, the Secretary may provide on a prospective basis for an appropriate percentage increase in such rate.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2FB3FD1A84644BE2898938A9E92DCE29"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rehabilitation innovation center defined</header>
<clause id="HA99FFEB53B894018B108B37EBD8BE9EA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (iv), in this paragraph, the term <term>rehabilitation innovation center</term> means a rehabilitation facility that, determined as of the date of the enactment of this paragraph, is described in clause (ii) or clause (iii).</text></clause> <clause id="H15F14DFC127F4525880397AAFC53F6BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Not-for-profit</header><text>A rehabilitation facility described in this clause is a facility that—</text>
<subclause id="H77BF12F3234F4188A29915CC8D43C3FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is classified as a not-for-profit entity under the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services 2010 Provider of Services file;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6950D6FA56BA41A796484F0030645ACB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>holds at least one Federal rehabilitation research and training designation for research projects on traumatic brain injury, spinal cord injury, or stroke rehabilitation research from the Rehabilitation Research and Training Centers or the Rehabilitation Engineering Research Center at the National Institute on Disability and Rehabilitation Research at the Department of Education;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HD25A1E4322E34C6E8B556178AE32917A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has a minimum Medicare case mix index of 1.1144 according to the IRF Rate Setting File for the Correction Notice for the Inpatient Rehabilitation Facility Prospective Payment System for Federal Fiscal Year 2012 (78 Fed. Reg. 59256); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8EF9290865154EB2A1741490BA356D1A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>has at least 300 Medicare discharges per year or at least 200 Medicaid discharges per year.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H9EF14BA02CAE4A9797383EEE2DADB804"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Government-owned</header><text>A rehabilitation facility described in this clause is a facility that—</text> <subclause id="HAFB4E51B0D0E4942B9B25E60010EAE8D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is classified as a Government-owned institution under the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services 2010 Provider of Services file;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HDA37D6845BD0404EA8B6629216235923"><enum>(II)</enum><text>holds at least one Federal rehabilitation research and training designation for research projects on traumatic brain injury, spinal cord injury, or stroke rehabilitation research from the Rehabilitation Research and Training Centers, the Rehabilitation Engineering Research Center, or the Model Spinal Cord Injury Systems at the National Institute on Disability and Rehabilitation Research at the Department of Education;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC854918C1EBB4ADF9D13C31522550F24"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has a minimum Medicare case mix index of 1.1144 according to the IRF Rate Setting File for the Correction Notice for the Inpatient Rehabilitation Facility Prospective Payment System for Federal Fiscal Year 2012 (78 Fed. Reg. 59256); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HDDD3117CB91A4ECAB0214FD4135C2718"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>has a disproportionate share hospital (DSH) percentage of at least 0.6300 according to the IRF Rate Setting File for the Correction Notice for the Inpatient Rehabilitation Facility Prospective Payment System for Federal Fiscal Year 2012 (78 Fed. Reg. 59256).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H561E3E8F147549B6A88C81408CD4887D"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary may consider applications from inpatient rehabilitation facilities that are not described in clause (ii) or (iii) as of the date of the enactment of this paragraph but who are subsequently so described.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEC9995ED20924327B6E515DD6C036F51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report to Congress on access to rehabilitation care in rural communities in States that do not have a rehabilitation innovation center</header>
<paragraph id="H9D525EEDE36B477E96E2DA7B4186B476"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a study on access by individuals (including, but not limited to, Medicare beneficiaries) to rehabilitation care in rural communities in States in which there is no rehabilitation innovation center (as defined in section 1886(j)(8)(B) of the Social Security Act, as added by subsection (a)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBF15230CB3E46A285BC1494377A5982"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2017, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


