<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H972A405F8CA44346B27D1C626F81BB5D" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 351 IH: LNG Permitting Certainty and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 351</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150114">January 14, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for expedited approval of exportation of natural gas, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H249E17BEEDFF47F398A74DCC47FDFDD3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H68982FEA510D4F35BD54EA04B60493B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>LNG Permitting Certainty and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC980D65F499F4A32AAB3ED1B6D102104"><enum>2.</enum><header>Action on applications</header> <subsection id="H16E3447D48A84A20BC9B6938BC61BAD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Decision deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For proposals that must also obtain authorization from the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission or the United States Maritime Administration to site, construct, expand, or operate LNG export facilities, the Department of Energy shall issue a final decision on any application for the authorization to export natural gas under section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) not later than 30 days after the later of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEF1BA684414741A1825748E1158A62AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the conclusion of the review to site, construct, expand, or operate the LNG facilities required by the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S. C. 4321 et seq.); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EA9B261AFD54DDB8B356F18F48A99D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8383A56D23FB41C1819AE583091826F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conclusion of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), review required by the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 shall be considered concluded—</text>
 <paragraph id="H019C310A91E84245A4C1FFA319A604AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a project requiring an Environmental Impact Statement, 30 days after publication of a Final Environmental Impact Statement;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1B417EBCA34B3A96545BEA80F862F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a project for which an Environmental Assessment has been prepared, 30 days after publication by the Department of Energy of a Finding of No Significant Impact; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF638ADCD622472FA44006F143DBEED0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon a determination by the lead agency that an application is eligible for a categorical exclusion pursuant National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 implementing regulations.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DD23A149C27423D94470683B196F0FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Judicial action</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HECFF414A0F0E4C20AA528747CF253DED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the export facility will be located pursuant to an application described in subsection (a) shall have original and exclusive jurisdiction over any civil action for the review of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H55F114967AB94FFF9095A2A56E2F6550" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an order issued by the Department of Energy with respect to such application; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE8EEDF9703947B6A4AF2B1C1E2ED9D8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Energy’s failure to issue a final decision on such application.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FADB45A6B2D4651993F16C0F0D428A5" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the Court in a civil action described in paragraph (1) finds that the Department of Energy has failed to issue a final decision on the application as required under subsection (a), the Court shall order the Department of Energy to issue such final decision not later than 30 days after the Court’s order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AF0737071BB419FBE9A2F6F81B710A2" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Court shall set any civil action brought under this subsection for expedited consideration and shall set the matter on the docket as soon as practical after the filing date of the initial pleading.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H311E28B772CE41AAAA22B131FF003921"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public disclosure of export destinations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F6F75D230834E8EB4CDD5B7CCA637B3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H00CDF1E444B54502ADCAD20E7FF9133E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public Disclosure of LNG Export Destinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition for approval of any authorization to export LNG, the Secretary of Energy shall require the applicant to publicly disclose the specific destination or destinations of any such authorized LNG exports.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


