<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2C064A22D3CE4153ABDEB00496C11F99" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1570 IH: Medicaid and CHIP Territory Transparency and Information Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1570</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150324">March 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000596">Mr. Pierluisi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for greater transparency and information with respect to Federal expenditures under the
			 Medicaid and CHIP programs in the territories of the United States, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H36ECFA2B467F45729ACBA5C5555B9691" style="OLC">
 <section id="H26598B5FC7734EC289A0F5D2AC46D8B6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid and CHIP Territory Transparency and Information Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD4F5000652914654915FC2E89E7F2D03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Publication of information on Federal expenditures under Medicaid and CHIP in the territories</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall publish, and periodically update, on the Internet site of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services information on Medicaid and CHIP carried out in the territories of the United States. Such information shall include, with respect to each such territory—</text>
 <paragraph id="H64DB22D36F6646B486B1377664D6CE51"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the income levels established by the territory for purposes of eligibility of an individual to receive medical assistance under Medicaid or child health assistance under CHIP;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F41D8CE088543C68565286923E83913"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of individuals enrolled in Medicaid and CHIP in such territory;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF45776F89FC94A4E9969B0B00A5717DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any State plan amendments in effect to carry out Medicaid or CHIP in such territory;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE97128F581274F3A915AF1E2B77BE5FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any waiver of the requirements of title XIX or title XXI issued by the Secretary to carry out Medicaid or CHIP in the territory, including a waiver under section 1115 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</external-xref>), any application for such a waiver, and any documentation related to such application (including correspondence);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF58B7A23482E4E2C9D6D5FD351D8ED3E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the amount of the Federal and non-Federal share of expenditures under Medicaid and CHIP in such territory;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF203F270B4224DF6A4B96F0E5FD40A50"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the systems in place for the furnishing of health care items and services under Medicaid and CHIP in such territory;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95CC840EB4B64CCFABCC8CC8A3AE601E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the design of CHIP in such territory; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEC890D1CC7C4D95BB3BA506A695A098"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other information regarding the carrying out of Medicaid and CHIP in the territory that is published on such Internet site with respect to carrying out Medicaid and CHIP in each State and the District of Columbia.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HC0D8EEFC92564E80ACDF4A83B5CF4057"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB3F505511AA34FBFBAA5F74771A7901D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CHIP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>CHIP</term> means the State Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of Social Security Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H783A876FBC4A4458BA0B81C1037A3222"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medicaid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Medicaid</term> means the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8487940D40146B28043AE6A5D0F18E8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Territory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>territory of the United States</term> includes Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


