<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCA522C48FE2847FE97174DE02E8B2AE0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1804 IH: Crude-By-Rail Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1804</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150415">April 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To protect the public, communities across America, and the environment by increasing the safety of
			 crude oil transportation by railroad, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H211DEA174ADC400FB991C7892EC23C55" style="OLC">
 <section id="H701A4FB367554BF2A7206545EE93B4F6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Crude-By-Rail Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7736F64EF78F43CBA7F9F9825CFDC2E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H20B7E62046714F208742B18DEA3055AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>High-hazard flammable train</header><text>The term <term>high-hazard flammable train</term> means a single train transporting 20 or more tank cars loaded with a Class 3 flammable liquid (as defined in section 173.120(a) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42E23BAE0FD848A080B51283F59CE5E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Oil</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>oil</term> means oil of any kind or in any form, including crude, petroleum, fuel oil, sludge, oil refuse, oil mixed with wastes other than dredged spoil, any bitumen or bituminous mixture, oil derived from a bitumen or bituminous mixture, any oil derived from kerogen-bearing sources, developing oils, and emerging oils.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7855526002CD4275BFF925D671716C11"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rail carrier</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rail carrier</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>railroad carrier</quote> in section 20102 of title 49, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H479014E7D42E40CF895AD1E95306EE8B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Worst case discharge</header><text>The term <term>worst case discharge</term> has the meaning given such term in section 130.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H62CBF70313EB4FC5ACD5744CF5D81C5F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Certainty on safety regulations</header>
			<subsection id="H3B5F12A51DDB4D5089101DBE207EEB6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interim national standard for maximum volatility</header>
 <paragraph id="HB5E20B9D8C494322826DFB458A1A7903"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, by regulation, shall establish an interim national standard for the maximum volatility of crude oil transported by rail within the United States. Volatility in the interim national standard shall be measured by the vapor pressure of the crude oil.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H514A9A9F76CE4D8BABF394CC7DEED90D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The national standard established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall take effect not later than 90 days after it is issued by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H299A9DC5053845A390EE9463C236B989"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study of crude oil characteristics and associated safety</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, in collaboration with the Secretary of Energy, shall complete a study of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCA9F1AF2B0AD4AB387711CEB79308EFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the best methods for reliably measuring the volatility of crude oil; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC76DBB5D11D4AADB6EBE10310D8349B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the level of volatility that is consistent with the safest practicable shipment of crude oil by rail.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5F8334C78D64D85B05742D3E9E05DB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final national standard for maximum volatility</header>
 <paragraph id="HBEA1ADA48D5F435499A1546159916070"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the completion of the study under subsection (b), the Secretary of Transportation shall issue a final rule that establishes the maximum volatility of crude oil that is transported by rail.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB71B5CE4E60A4D47A39177EF306FDB05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The maximum volatility standard established pursuant to paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D5071F960CE44D2AE073898D897F60B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be consistent with the findings of the study conducted under subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE766E849257D4F21B9AFE70F64E9CC2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall require that the transportation of crude oil by rail be as safe as practicable.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H70A7917A3C64404CBD481C11434BE6AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tank car design</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue a final rule, based on the safety standards contained in the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking issued on August 1, 2014, and entitled <quote>Enhanced Tank Car Standards and Operational Controls for High-Hazard Flammable Trains</quote>, which requires that all new tank cars designed to transport a Class 3 flammable liquid that are constructed after October 1, 2015, meet or exceed the design standards set forth under option 1 of table 2 in such rulemaking.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8534B7D95D7848F9A757BD5488F38D22"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enhanced braking</header><text>Beginning on the date identified in the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (d), all high-hazard flammable trains shall operate with electronically controlled pneumatic brakes.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H60CA3A4C64984982A2B28D114A3C23C7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Ending use of unsafe tank cars</header>
			<subsection id="HBDE63CA6FEE24012998EC2860378EAAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimum safety standard</header>
 <paragraph id="H1D0BA103511F49BCB5A004533A0427C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Oil</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (4), the Secretary of Transportation shall immediately prohibit the shipment of oil in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9705022A33434160AC2764E54BA1E8D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any DOT–111 tank car that does not meet the requirements of Casualty Prevention Circular 1232, issued by the Association of American Railroads on August 31, 2011; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D9122F5C43842DEB560ECC66665B4BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any unjacketed CPC–1232 tank car.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E84682B489408D9235E189618AF6F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ethanol</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (4), beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall prohibit the shipment of ethanol in any tank car described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2963B89CDA48470588D8DD930395799B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional precautionary measures</header><text>Any rail carrier or shipper who offers for transportation, or transports, in a tank car by rail in commerce to, from, or within the United States, a bulk quantity of oil or ethanol shall take additional precautionary measures to enhance the safe shipment of such liquids, including by avoiding the shipment of such liquids in tank cars with unsafe tank car attributes identified by the Secretary of Transportation, to the extent practicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88310EE0EA244B45BCC1C07FD3D9F0C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), tank cars described in subparagraph (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) may continue to transport oil or ethanol if they have been retrofitted to meet or exceed the design standards set forth under Option 3 of table 2 in the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking issued on August 1, 2014, and entitled <quote>Enhanced Tank Car Standards and Operational Controls for High-Hazard Flammable Trains</quote>. All retrofitted tank cars shall be equipped with electronically controlled pneumatic brakes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEFB0BD082C664056AC055DA2AAA98A44"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Jacketed CPC–1232 tank cars</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish, by regulation, a retrofit standard and timeline for jacketed CPC–1232 tank cars that transport oil or ethanol.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E006282B21C42809661CD314B052944"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit the Secretary of Transportation from issuing, by regulation or order, a safety standard for tank cars transporting oil or ethanol that is more stringent than the requirements referred to in section 3(d).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1D9C10E3EBFE45EDB6AB1A7854D08331"><enum>5.</enum><header>Crude-by-rail inspections</header>
 <subsection id="HFB53A575EEAE4D04941D6091E04DF0B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rail inspections for hazardous material routes</header><text>Rail carriers shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA30117183FA54DF6B1929A8BB38FCD52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>perform at least 2 additional internal rail inspections per calendar year than is required under section 213.237(c) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, on routes that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H836976319BEB4867B9228821FB806811"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rail carrier owns or has been assigned maintenance responsibility under section 213.5 of such title; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DB7E3A6179F4352BEEC106D2362FB12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>over which 1 or more high-hazard flammable trains are operated.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92C2A4BAAC2C478AAB8AE18469C43B83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct at least 4 track geometry inspections each calendar year on routes that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HACCD9C77609C4491A1BF894A52683BA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rail carrier owns or has been assigned maintenance responsibility under such section 213.5; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8AE2103943E4715932CA4AAFB5A1ED8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>over which 1 or more high-hazard flammable trains are operated.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61D5D5D4D4D8446FBB48875F7F25DC6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Energy product inspections</header>
 <paragraph id="HEB34986844D64F5EB5E34F8D998DC375"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inspection requirement</header><text>A person that offers oil for transportation shall complete spot inspections on 5 percent of all individual rail cars loaded with crude oil—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB8E6159264A741DFAE9F7C52E660A34D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to test and record the volatility of the crude oil in such cars; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE215F8423AFA4774B403226161B42F4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to ensure that such crude oil meets—</text>
 <clause id="H24FE2C5B2D8545CA84FB718C31DCA925"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the interim national standard for maximum volatility established pursuant to section 3(a); or</text> </clause><clause id="H0AD0A6BC20214E7A84069B560E5DEC38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any subsequently enacted volatility standard that is more restrictive than such standard.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E8C083163C74F66BCF9D2ED26DA86CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Spot inspections and audits</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC5696A0A4BC84DFD999F1FEEFB24B008"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Spot inspections</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall complete spot inspections on crude oil volatility to ensure that the volatility standards referred to in paragraph (1)(B) are being met.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EAA747DF03C41609DC054B0EA9D5D76"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall audit records of the inspections conducted under paragraph (1) to ensure that the volatility of the crude oil does not exceed the volatility standards referred to in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCC252DE47FF14AAD9FE4CD55817C7656"><enum>6.</enum><header>Penalties for noncompliance</header>
 <subsection id="H9E75F18378534158877BB4BC3E0BED22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fines for violating hazardous materials transportation law</header><text>Section 5123(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3DB7FB98D774E32A7772D4485C9D1E3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H52F179507AF74CDDAD9801C7D50E5514"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Penalty</header> <paragraph id="H1CB7E8F622CD4835ACAFE8674B9E0D39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person that knowingly violates this chapter or a regulation, order, special permit, or approval issued under this chapter is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $500,000 for each such violation. A person acts knowingly when—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5CDC9619F3F945E0AABEDA0389A1C9E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person has actual knowledge of the facts giving rise to the violation; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33FBC1DA8FD34D57B601972465145E10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a reasonable person acting in the same circumstances and exercising reasonable care would have such knowledge.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B28AB00AB9643258766374205DAFDFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enhanced penalty</header><text>If the Secretary finds that a violation under paragraph (1) results in death, serious illness, or severe injury to any person, substantial destruction of property, or significant environmental damage, the Secretary may increase the amount of the civil penalty for such violation to not more than $1,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3ACEE6261BC4BFB97E3719764EF4CE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Separate violation</header><text>A separate violation occurs for each day a person continues to knowingly violate this chapter or any regulation, order, special permit, or approval issued under this chapter.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4EDE2F5893B346E0A7B78035062631D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fines for violating energy product inspections</header><text>A person that offers oil for transportation that violates the maximum volatility rule issued pursuant to subsection (a) or (c) of section 3, or the inspection requirement under section 5(b) shall be liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000,000 for each such violation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE4FD81428A574018AAB31C3F9B28A787"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fines for violating rail inspections</header><text>A rail carrier that violates the rail inspections requirement under section 5(a) shall be liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000,000 for each such violation.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE6E2DAB7E4DA4905B2620B1441F87DCF"><enum>7.</enum><header>Safe transportation of energy products</header>
 <subsection id="H393F254314314AB4A710DB7CEB4C7E85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish or expand safety programs relating to the transportation of energy products and other Class 3 flammable liquids by rail, pipeline, highway, and waterway, which shall include initiatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H033A8D3D89E149B8A13F0C839CD67293"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to expedite rulemaking proceedings;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H090CE26C1BCF40809EB4907A2366354D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conduct technical studies of energy products;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3B654179E084DE08C7ACFB6EDAC46AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to increase rail, pipeline, and energy product inspections;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H721CC2B29E4A4778BA1BCCF0EC97193D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide grants to States for additional railroad track and pipeline inspectors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H367E5C488AC04A03A1C52E864C5D8B1E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to improve notification procedures from State Emergency Response Commission contacts to first responders;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCBAFB39533346EAB512E02EA2FFC7FA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to develop and conduct first responder training programs, in collaboration with the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Department of Homeland Security, the Coast Guard, the Environmental Protection Agency, and national first responder organizations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9AAC289E738405EB46088A0E907ED5F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to conduct technical research on infrastructure-related causes of train and pipeline accidents;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H208705E2DF964985893F09C0BB169022"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to identify ways to mitigate the causes and consequences of train accidents;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7AE9CD2A82C4B79AAFDD1516233C24A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to provide grants to communities to update emergency response plans developed by local emergency planning committees; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H871F5A53AE1C4088BF42E5DBAAA360E9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to audit comprehensive oil spill response plans established under section 8(b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FB4BD69508E451FBDD859CDFD89BD32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the safety initiatives described in subsection (a)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H548A3D8F1446476FB654EEDEEB18B785"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$40,000,000 for fiscal year 2016; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE76AADEBF26F4AC587473B8E306411D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$40,000,000 for fiscal year 2017.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H00C475729F0D40938461CDA12340CAF5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Oil spill response plans</header>
 <subsection id="H50364E801B344DF684EAE2917DD2FF3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this section, the term <term>maximum extent practicable</term> has the meaning given such term in section 130.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H2324109577634BE88B578445C32EFDD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comprehensive response plans</header> <paragraph id="H52D8B8D8E9164C70BE7C48F1EC48D328"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall publish a final rule revising the regulations set out in part 130 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to oil spill prevention and response plans)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF5E11E702E454E01A71008953EBC9F17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to modify the 1,000 barrels (42,000 gallons) requirement for a comprehensive written plan in subsection (b) of section 130.31 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to account for worst-case discharges resulting from accidents involving unit trains or blocks of tank cars; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADD5EEE975F645CEBC1CCA9B278B433E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to include additional requirements in each written plan required under such section 130.31 to respond to a discharge of oil that occurs during transportation by a rail carrier that has a reasonable probability of impacting a water body or other area that is subject to the jurisdiction of the Coast Guard or of the Environmental Protection Agency under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) including such a discharge—</text>
 <clause id="HB1745B8BC278450BA6DD0C21CA70401F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>into or on the navigable waters of the United States;</text> </clause><clause id="HFEC1E640392A411DB2DBEAAF601C09DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on the adjoining shorelines to the navigable waters;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEC8B3F60F8094CF0988535C88467E8BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>inland waters; or</text> </clause><clause id="H0FD15D098A354D73B857D86BCE98BEDF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other impacted lands.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D4BF0CDF929441889E12ABB685DBA59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The additional requirements under paragraph (1)(B) shall be promulgated by the Secretary of Transportation in coordination with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB36615CC446242B79D356CFFA4A07A4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, in the case of potential impacts to a water body or other area subject to the jurisdiction of the Coast Guard; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D7D5DD2C6D4EA790E9735B72C95156"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in the case of potential impacts to a water body or other area subject to the jurisdiction of the Environmental Protection Agency under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC32808D1105144819EAE079BD3AF809E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National contingency plan</header><text>To ensure efficient and timely prevention, preparedness, and response by the lead agency and the rail carrier in the event of a discharge of oil, the President shall, for each comprehensive written plan required under section 130.31(b) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or similar successor regulation)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8691E2DA25B643E3A9415CB6FB6274CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include such plan in the National Contingency Plan required under section 311(d) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1321">33 U.S.C. 1321(d)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20985F05C4C74165B7091360E3F938D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrate such plan into the appropriate Regional Response Plan required under section 300.210(b) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or similar successor regulation).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D8E2416FE2D427599C62AF7298ABD9F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Audits required</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE699D5755A744527B0C7377ACD352B79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a program to audit response plans for rail carriers of oil to ensure that adequate provisions are in place—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0D30F710DE4E4F3CBECFE59199EA4787"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to respond to and remove a worst-case discharge to the maximum extent practicable; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B73FA6E08E4470F817308164E269D0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to mitigate or prevent a substantial threat of a worst-case discharge; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A036DE2999049389C3D96106209F4E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>audit rail carriers of oil to ensure that the shippers and rail carriers with respect to transporting oil by railroad—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5905836068974CEF9357D4ABBC124780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are using appropriate hazardous materials shipping classifications;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72C94A15803D4BE2AD743A6AF4232004"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have developed transportation safety and security plans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDC8B2ADAFBA42888D8E39AD1F2C09E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have made adequate provision for safety and security.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90EC851B25D94803BEE31813DB980F6C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit the Secretary of Transportation from issuing, by regulation or order, a requirement for comprehensive response plans for railroads transporting oil or ethanol that is more stringent than the requirements under subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H67BC5E5AA090486A846A435FA421D38F"><enum>9.</enum><header>Disclosure requirement</header>
 <subsection id="HF70C8C25916E4CBBB133AEFAEC0D12E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A rail carrier may not operate any high-hazard flammable train in any State until the rail carrier has provided the Emergency Response Commission for such State and any local emergency planning committee along the route such train will operate with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5FD5D8943F8641449B567B87235CEE81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a reasonable estimate of the number of such trains that are expected to travel, per week, through the State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6CB8C2D065048A39EF2DCF118663C49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the flammable liquid expected to be transported through the State, in accordance with subpart C of part 172 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H084F5A9BE955452B9DDB92EEF588E268"><enum>(3)</enum><text>all applicable emergency response information required under subpart G of such part;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC658FE1D286D48F6A7E212737478BD1D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the identification of the routes over which the oil or ethanol will be transported; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4329C17983C4C9885958601CDFB52EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the contact information for at least 1 point of contact at the rail carrier responsible for serving as the point of contact for the State Emergency Response Commission and relevant emergency responders.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A9FEE61FA554B319BF6E633A438616E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit the Secretary of Transportation from issuing, by regulation or order, a disclosure requirement for high-hazard flammable train movement that is wider than the requirements under subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCC2FF145215740B5903E605F3988A6B9"><enum>10.</enum><header>Emergency response resource inventory</header>
 <subsection id="HFBE543D0C6ED4A5AAE3DDB6838E816AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Rail carriers shall collaborate to develop an inventory of emergency response resources along routes over which 1 or more high-hazard flammable trains operate for responding to worst case discharges resulting from accidents involving unit trains or blocks of tank cars transporting Class 3 flammable liquids in the event of an incident.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H915B28317D9C4CFAA529EDE84B87F9FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The inventory developed pursuant to subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H3A2923D287F3446CA98CACDFC30EE8A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed description of the type and quantity of private emergency response resources;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39DA0D1FDAA842638CC1C4E10AB675D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sufficient equipment to respond to a worst case discharge from accidents involving unit trains or blocks of tank cars;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE6DEE4204744C27A2E990D325D40F28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sufficient equipment to respond to a fire or explosion that could result from a worst case discharge from accidents involving unit trains or blocks of tank cars;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1A9CF118C1B488B8CFA2B0BA28A3927"><enum>(4)</enum><text>locations for the staging of emergency response equipment; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H89FC1565EA2E41AFBD63962467E91EF9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>contacts for the notification of communities, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9F2B79B95154762B7E4BEF698EEFA3E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access</header><text>Rail carriers shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA57C7CB11E28456EBF89D774E8238D3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide the Department of Transportation with access to the inventory developed under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DDED43232204D5A953CA83A77A55734"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make relevant information from the inventory, upon request, available to emergency responders located along identified routes over which 1 or more high-hazard flammable trains operate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA1280236A5644136B4B0F3D8D8A01B2F"><enum>11.</enum><header>Confidential close call reporting systems</header>
 <subsection id="H82A22816C8624959A05365C06EAED1A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEE1E382A5414D3F956C0091B6296B3A" style="USC">
					<section id="H5646617AE68F4CC78D1562751EA35581"><enum>20168.</enum><header>Confidential close call reporting systems</header>
						<subsection id="HCEAA782B21D944BA96A4E1E255998F13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header>
 <paragraph id="H68E7DC81E52E4AA794A4D6EC4029BD94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Crude-By-Rail Safety Act</short-title>, the Secretary of Transportation shall promulgate regulations setting forth the requirements for an applicable railroad carrier to follow in establishing a confidential close call reporting system program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B3B4F3136B34C06BACF6E29938725B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use any information and experience gathered through research and pilot programs on confidential close call reporting systems in developing the regulations, including continuing the use of third parties for the collection of close call reports and distribution of close call data. The Secretary shall ensure that an applicable railroad carrier's employees receive protection under its program from any related Federal Railroad Administration enforcement actions.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D13DF622AAD4A1CB0C7E7F31A61970A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program development and oversight</header>
 <paragraph id="HD182E588E2054A27AA82735661F23D35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the final regulations under subsection (a), an applicable railroad carrier shall develop a proposed program and submit it to the Secretary of Transportation for review and approval.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD22FE559A7B449A288BB15E8693F98A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A railroad carrier shall describe its proposed program’s core principles and values, explain the rights, roles, and responsibilities of program stakeholders, identify concerns and interests, and describe how the program will operate.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HB04278B916C0446AAF76E1EC14DAE99E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review</header>
 <subparagraph id="H508468863D6D42A0B4E151FAD476B758"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall review and approve or disapprove each proposed program within a reasonable amount of time. If a proposed program is not approved, the Secretary shall notify the applicable railroad carrier in writing as to the specific areas in which the proposed program is deficient. The applicable railroad carrier shall correct all deficiencies within a reasonable period of time following receipt of written notice from the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4783BD6D931D45B8945EFC0EBC1F3E1A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An applicable railroad carrier shall update its program as needed and obtain the Secretary’s approval before making any major changes to its program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7803D1227DE5457387B5D207BE95C466"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Annual reviews</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct an annual review to ensure that each applicable railroad carrier is in compliance with its program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19BDF2303CAC4CB4B3DB04459D7006AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Crude-By-Rail Safety Act</short-title>, each applicable railroad carrier shall establish a confidential close call reporting system.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H6EEE1239F1E44EDFBCDA0696463A2023"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each applicable railroad carrier shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB09666A32EC34FC0984AE9FCD798F57B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a safe environment for its employees to report unsafe events and conditions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CD66D8C66314538961CF2F9CB44E2CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for unsafe events and conditions reported within the scope of a confidential close call reporting system, ensure its employees are protected from railroad carrier discipline;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H352420B02D5E463B844BCB269EA896DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use information collected through the confidential close call reporting system to develop and implement targeted corrective actions, as appropriate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H682875AE39144C8881285EC10678B507"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use information collected by the programs to supplement inspection data in identifying safety issues and emerging risks before they develop into accidents.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0425A6EAB85E4766BD32C0F970E786C6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consensus</header>
 <paragraph id="H8FF63AA1184C4F6997215C0B2135819F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each applicable railroad carrier shall consult with, employ good faith with, and use its best efforts to reach agreement with all of its directly affected employees, including any nonprofit employee labor organization representing a class or craft of directly affected employees of the applicable railroad carrier, on the development and implementation of the proposed program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B61E24FE76540AEA045CAFCB1FD1444"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an applicable railroad carrier and its directly affected employees, including any nonprofit employee labor organization representing a class or craft of directly affected employees of the applicable railroad carrier, cannot reach consensus on the development and implementation of the proposed program, then directly affected employees and such organization may file a statement with the Secretary of Transportation explaining their views on the proposed program on which consensus was not reached. The Secretary shall consider such views during review of the proposed program under subsection (b)(3)(A).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60052F81563B4CF79796BB125AFE5EAE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Voluntary program establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any railroad carrier that is not an applicable railroad carrier may voluntarily establish a program under this section. This section, and any regulations promulgated under this section, shall apply to a program that is voluntarily established.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF86F2A12C32B4A29A0CD38BD6D6F86BD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation may use the confidential close call reporting data—</text> <paragraph id="H78A3BAF2330B48099EE3D8451AE9C875"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when implementing or updating the Federal Railroad Administration's National Inspection Plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43209253C16F4E3BBB3B1C8EF9E1BF61"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when performing focused inspections; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H670AEA3BFCDB47F6A3E6AC951793121A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when developing agency rulemakings and guidance, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H644EB85F5DA74F1CBC8BF80046D900E6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definition of applicable railroad carrier</header><text>In this section, the term <term>applicable railroad carrier</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H56AD6C6A01E94F9DAD3D0D47EEC3CA6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a railroad carrier that is a Class I railroad;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1610D32E09F54740A79313C399ED4D06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a railroad carrier that has inadequate safety performance, as determined by the Secretary; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8395E35575D4416A90F963D47B02F3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a railroad carrier that provides intercity rail passenger or commuter rail passenger transportation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54280A44661246918A564AD1784F4ED8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Transportation such sums as may be necessary to implement this section and to support the nationwide implementation, as the Secretary determines appropriate, of confidential close call reporting system programs.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE96EBD9F74914253B099449F469E414F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD87F7319B64E426A896220FEFE680E63" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">20168. Confidential close call reporting systems.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3DDC49AF56EB46C29602E730015E2229"><enum>12.</enum><header>High-hazard flammable train liability study</header>
 <subsection id="HCBDAA0A6C55F499A8EA2374C7B2F7D0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall contract with the Transportation Research Board of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study on high-hazard flammable train liability.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD95B6E01874742D0827D8F8715F43771"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The study conducted under subsection (a) shall evaluate—</text> <paragraph id="HD1091418F42349809DF04AA2E6D567EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the level of insurance, including self insurance, available in the private market against the full liability potential for damages arising from an incident involving a high-hazard flammable train;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1372D76EAF4343F59999D4816D4D36B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ability of the level and availability of insurance referred to in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF4D65ADFD00E48DBB91C7B4BD3508BFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address externalities that exist because of gaps between insurance coverage and liability risk;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H430C51A5C7AF4A91939E2DC8214366BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to equitably allocate risk and financial responsibility for claims;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7430BC421DE45F1AE74A13C458ADFE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to ensure that rail carriers have sufficient financial capacity to pay claims to those affected by high consequence incidents in a timely manner; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H171F1C9DF0D5438284353D5583B31BCB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to ensure that rail carriers and shippers of high-hazard flammable trains can continue to operate despite the risk of catastrophic disaster; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89BA99B9174D45CEBD797A1B2855960B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the potential applicability to high-hazard flammable trains of—</text> <subparagraph id="H9F5EDDA102F6456AB11AD5ED03E728F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a liability regime modeled after section 170 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2210">42 U.S.C. 2210</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FF34398D13C41FB83C9A9959EF2F092"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a liability regime modeled after subtitle 2 of title XXI of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300aa-10">42 U.S.C. 300aa–10 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H324B91582DBE4D0D8573E920A93C078A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Transportation Research Board of the National Academy of Sciences shall submit a report containing the results of the study and recommendations for addressing high hazard flammable train liability issues to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H32482408A5A14527B2E76377228411DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Transportation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E3BF9E90B364ED3A4B7FF41AA656B1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90EF5530BDC041DA84EFC402F8B82580"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H456E051D235E499C94B07A12EA51733D"><enum>13.</enum><header>Review and recommendations</header> <subsection id="H26CE0631E9FD4424A12540583C7BE358"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation, in cooperation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Commanding General of the United States Army Corps of Engineers, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall conduct a comprehensive review of existing regulations for energy products that are transported by all modes of transportation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H732D2D7A7C6A4181AC297489A0F5424F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review elements</header><text>The review under subsection (a) shall assess the effectiveness of existing regulations and industry capability—</text>
 <paragraph id="H78FECA2366914BFFB440C01030916A24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve the safety of energy product transportation through populated or environmentally sensitive areas;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6957B99A91C42A7BEA0E583056A085A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to maximize, to the extent possible, the stability and uniformity of energy products prior to transportation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8B5CE3656FF41EFB356B9A7A971AF58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to eliminate the occurrence of accidents involving transportation of such products, and minimize the severity of such accidents should they occur;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H569C405656694502B13E3F9EE996AE1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to minimize energy product routing through populated or environmentally sensitive areas;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H233B18F352BC4E4DB2CC60059DDE0364"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to reduce the environmental impact of transporting, loading, or unloading energy products;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H570EF16FADD449CFBA1F0BEBD07B798A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to improve the security of energy product transportation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H058F56F61BC942898053B7A361F6A1AC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to prepare for an appropriate emergency response to accidents.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61BF2AE0CA114E26A117BE504F12BF11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission of review and recommendations</header><text>Not later than June 30, 2016, the Secretary of Transportation, in cooperation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Commanding General of the United States Army Corps of Engineers, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall submit the results of the review under subsection (a) to Congress, in conjunction with recommendations for—</text>
 <paragraph id="H96A0679E099A4C1FA2E8409A5884EE84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improving all aspects of energy product transport by all transportation modes;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDACBFA31F07643F59D269B77FDC0C00D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regulatory measures that the Secretary of Transportation is authorized to undertake that would improve the safety and reduce the environmental and community impact of transporting energy products; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE3343837A164AEDBE574C89E8AB714D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>legislative changes that should be made to improve the safety and reduce the environmental and community impact of transporting energy products.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


