<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB2E0DE39AE0246F1A89B0AD24267E3C8" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3687 IH: Cuba Agricultural Exports Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3687</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151006">October 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To modify the prohibition on United States assistance and financing for certain exports to Cuba
			 under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H93FCFA2B9C084F2B9C1DF76144E57AFC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H48D96F0169C44B1380A3DD7071ACDF8B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cuba Agricultural Exports Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0D71712E3E274916A1A3E4C5C46C8B51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6AB13CE370324742991115108297F8CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has a long history of providing safe and reliable exports. Close proximity to Cuba further lends itself to low transportation costs for United States goods exported to Cuba. The United States is geographically poised to be a significant trading partner in agricultural commodities. United States and Cuban borders are less than 100 miles apart, meaning lower shipping costs and shorter transit times compared to our competitors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4CB1A104868453190D1EDEEEE0BC2D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Cuba imports approximately 80 percent of its food, with global agricultural exports to Cuba doubling over the past decade to $1.9 billion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2209C6954084CF085DF6CC1F54A74DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2005, the United States Department of the Treasury published a final rule narrowing the definition of <quote>cash in advance</quote> for trading with Cuba, requiring that cash payments must be made before United States products leave United States ports, rather than the more customary payment upon delivery. United States firms are precluded from offering credit to ALIMPORT, a state-owned and state-controlled entity that makes all decisions regarding United States imports to the Cuban market, resulting in declining United States agricultural exports to Cuba. Notably, rice exports fell from a value of $64 million in 2004 to essentially $0 in 2009 and subsequent years. Recent action by the Administration reverses that change to the definition of cash in advance, but United States agricultural exporters are still not permitted to extend credit to Cuban buyers, a key disadvantage relative to other exporting nations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5C24307ACBB4FF39B8E2987E18E6D3B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Despite these restrictions, the United States has been the largest exporter of agricultural goods to Cuba over the last decade. However, the United States slipped to being the second leading exporter of agricultural goods to Cuba in 2013 and the third leading exporter of agricultural goods to Cuba in 2014.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDED6BA6BADE44BD68289E998DFC366CF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>While trade opportunities exist, Cuba remains an undemocratic autocracy that oppresses its own people and restricts freedom.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DB27C1F43FD4B3D846342AB5D47BFD7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition, there is no opportunity for United States agricultural businesses to trade directly with the Cuban people and there is no Cuban market. At present, there is just one opportunity for United States businesses to trade with Cuba and that is through ALIMPORT, the state-owned and state-controlled entity described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB047DEBEF22F440DAA3ACB8CFC70E970"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With these cautionary factors in mind, it is important to provide United States farmers and ranchers additional opportunities to benefit from trade with Cuba.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H338CAD2DE4FC4F5B81941F00D4E11FE4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modification of prohibition on United States assistance and financing for certain exports to Cuba
			 under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000</header>
 <subsection id="H8C4838F717EC4D64ACFDF6E63E61333B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assistance for exports to Cuba</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 908 of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7207">22 U.S.C. 7207</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBFDCBE780B53439E813A5FCAF089E5AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and financing</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A81C3869654431D93219BF3CEE4BAA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1667171583C4C3AAFDAD2F018CD1D6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H01056D25182D42159F6E7EDA113E2D0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as subsections (b) and (c), respectively, and by moving such subsections, as so redesignated, 2 ems to the left; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E0C22D30B264543BFDF338BBF10CE2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end of subsection (a) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3378E555AF1442D0BF5D459DCB08A2D4" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H9E15C0C429AE4E03BAAE982CF1EBEF3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for certain programs</header> <subparagraph id="H155996BF27184DC38599C3FBE8390B87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to exports to Cuba under section 202 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5622">7 U.S.C. 5622</external-xref>), section 203 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5623">7 U.S.C. 5623</external-xref>), or section 702 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5722">7 U.S.C. 5722</external-xref>), including any obligation or expenditure of funds by Federal commodity promotion programs established in accordance with a commodity promotion law, as defined by section 501(a) of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7401">7 U.S.C. 7401(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8636968D3A445219C390DFC92EDBE68"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction on certain recipients</header><text>The exception under subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the recipient of the United States assistance would be an entity controlled by the Government of Cuba, including the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Cuba, the Ministry of the Interior of Cuba, or any subdivision of either governmental entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H22D3F5AE55144FC69B9EFAEA6D789444"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (b), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD63CBBD0B618494DABDEE7C233E4BE89"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (c), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(1)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5E2BF51A0BE46E797A327B13C1D3980"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Financing of sales of agricultural commodities to Cuba</header>
 <paragraph id="HD7F5A91D5ECA46B9825B1252F5876100"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than section 908 of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7207">22 U.S.C. 7207</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a)), a person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States may provide payment or financing terms for sales of agricultural commodities to Cuba or an individual or entity in Cuba.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H082D9D75BC3F4C9D8748BDA4A0B7374E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H959A96AC18364FF58A8A910004A14E2A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Agricultural commodity</header><text>The term <quote>agricultural commodity</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5602">7 U.S.C. 5602</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACBE58535AE04E058AC0BC32CD51E1DF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Financing</header><text>The term <quote>financing</quote> includes any loan or extension of credit.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A4F8C50BAF440BB9B38A9E62829D16A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply with respect to exports to Cuba on or after such date of enactment.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H354F37A79EAE4CC1895A63C6C46288B6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authority of persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to invest with respect to
			 certain agricultural business in Cuba</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H275D0B2C99C3457C85F5C268DD65B820"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States may make an investment with respect to the development of an agricultural business in Cuba if the Secretary of State and Secretary of Agriculture jointly determine that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC839D1D9FE9D4F1FBAAB9B69D9EE08B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the agricultural business is not controlled by the Government of Cuba, including the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Cuba, the Ministry of the Interior of Cuba, or any subdivision of either governmental entity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7794EA2E7AF8458EB192090BCFB6830A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the agricultural business does not traffic in property of persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States which was confiscated by the Cuban Government on or after January 1, 1959.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41C4C93F12344F4D91BFD8977C7E31F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H11908473CB3E43E4908E20A113EB3C83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agricultural business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agricultural business</term> means any entity involved in the production, manufacture, or distribution of agricultural products (as such term is defined in section 207 of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1626">7 U.S.C. 1626</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE68E5D3BCEF347458ECAFA8E8FD7C7A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confiscated, Cuban Government, property, and traffic</header><text>The terms <term>confiscated</term>, <term>Cuban Government</term>, <term>property</term>, and <term>traffic</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 4 of the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6023">22 U.S.C. 6023</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB32227F4038B446383397242C89D0844"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>investment</term>, with respect to the development of an agricultural business in Cuba, means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H486E377DE2B34780927ACF5A1016928B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entry into a contract involving the purchase of a share of ownership, including an equity interest, in the development of the agricultural business;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3D84AAE2C264427DA395E6DF065ED067"><enum>(B)</enum><text>entry into a contract providing for participation in royalties, earnings, or profits in the development of the agricultural business; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H35A7037A205A43338675CCD61D418B67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>entry into, or performance or financing of, a contract to sell goods, services, or technology relating to the agricultural business.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


