<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H268C2171C5F7417FBD7C57F46D17BFFF" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1877 IH: Mental Health First Aid Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 1877</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend section 520J of the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants for mental health first aid training programs.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE537A49D2A8B490CB33C57A39F31BD71" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDFBC90EE7ABB4128A79008537D757E79" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health First Aid Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H792831A4B98E4098B5C9E3B8B4F2CC78"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mental health first aid training grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 520J of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-41">42 U.S.C. 290bb–41</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CCBB90D910240279182683C74A41CF6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H488CFD60E734436BB70404FACA39642E"><enum>520J.</enum><header>Mental health first aid training grants</header> 
<subsection id="HC6ACAB64C98944D6850B4C3B697CCC19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall award grants to States, political subdivisions of States, Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and nonprofit private entities to initiate and sustain mental health first aid training programs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6C405904186544139505DEA030ECFD4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header> <paragraph id="H49FFA2429B304CF790ED301F3DFAD59D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible for funding under subsection (a), a mental health first aid training program shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDCA048C60EDF4B5B918F27EEE5D87652"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be designed to train individuals in the categories listed in paragraph (2) to accomplish the objectives described in paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01FFEF73DAEE4EB585A544D5A6FDB67F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that training is conducted by trainers that are properly licensed and credentialed by nonprofit entities as designated by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5499DACB6F1E43819C2C270983828263"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include—</text> <clause id="H6BA518E4675B4E849CE02E58F35385A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at a minimum—</text> 
<subclause id="H2558014AD8274737BF2B0B864B29BDCD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a core live training course for individuals in the categories listed in paragraph (2) on the skills, resources, and knowledge to assist individuals in crisis to connect with appropriate local mental health care services;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H787873E7FBDB45BB97FF89C43A5F78E3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>training on mental health resources, including the location of community mental health centers described in section 1913(c), in the State and local community; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5E5F790440BF4C659465696143CA001E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>training on action plans and protocols for referral to such resources; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD9F4EA46C43C41F493472486A4FFD9CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>where feasible, continuing education and updated training for individuals in the categories listed in paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE61AE1ED6500470E80F3CDBDFDA0B63B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Categories of individuals to be trained</header><text>The categories of individuals listed in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H7EF1DF31E71F4E579710EFE3C38BF7C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Emergency services personnel and other first responders.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3427844C01E140CFBC70A65765C7C6FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Police officers and other law enforcement personnel.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4BD75137D04B4A51919613E28786CE2E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Teachers and school administrators.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9F9810C83AC47A3BA7E8D40A1F0D79F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Human resources professionals.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E0261FE64DD457CA5B38CD9F4098489"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Faith community leaders.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96DB07BD9D664AC0B29071B2EBC402B5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Nurses and other primary care personnel.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEEF08B0CE6A84CF09C007C9F9CA5998A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Students enrolled in an elementary school, a secondary school, or an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB285502B0454F2CAF8F93B01CC563F7"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The parents of students described in subparagraph (G).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74A622387A724C5586A3AC490E146040"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE81A47E52AA41428C562B2D1AF49E66"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Other individuals, audiences or training populations as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22A6E968CF5D4B3896D92B119E439FC5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Objectives of training</header><text>To be eligible for funding under subsection (a), a mental health first aid training program shall be designed to train individuals in the categories listed in paragraph (2) to accomplish each of the following objectives (as appropriate for the individuals to be trained, taking into consideration their age):</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6CF0DA35F4754C7ABAA6D4F625146C82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Safe de-escalation of crisis situations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60A563A01E85418BA8D696609C13DB82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recognition of the signs and symptoms of mental illness, including such common psychiatric conditions as schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, major clinical depression, and anxiety disorders.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H675DE6B3BC6F43FA8F6A7231A785513A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Timely referral to mental health services in the early stages of developing mental disorders in order to—</text> <clause id="HD92C04EAA6BC45208A94661E2A48CB2C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>avoid more costly subsequent behavioral health care; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9FE3F44B69FB4F8F9714ED5A9EF38531"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enhance the effectiveness of mental health services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAB126BE649234FC7A63B17351F6F8445"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution of Awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H382A61CC32A34EC29215243334AF9441"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that grants are equitably distributed among the geographical regions of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A5175A81EA74BC6B844201EF7F8D8D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pay particular attention to the mental health training needs of populations and target audiences residing in rural areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE28AC8682524E658B56070298BC2294"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State, political subdivision of a State, Indian tribe, tribal organization, or nonprofit private entity that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan for the rigorous evaluation of activities that are carried out with funds received under such grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF75CFC221A744D68AD914C735C855E74"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>A State, political subdivision of a State, Indian tribe, tribal organization, or nonprofit private entity that receives a grant under this section shall prepare and submit an evaluation to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including an evaluation of activities carried out with funds received under such grant and a process and outcome evaluation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3446B4436AD548C8A94F75CF75D46C6B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2016 and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2017 and 2018.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

