<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H82FE86DA79004052A9F7EBF34FF80A85" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1043 IH: RESPONSE Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1043</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150224">February 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish the Railroad Emergency Services Preparedness, Operational Needs, and Safety Evaluation
			 (RESPONSE) Subcommittee under the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s
			 National Advisory Council to provide recommendations on emergency
			 responder training and resources relating to hazardous materials incidents
			 involving railroads, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H77B7EEF21B434EE983C73560E6CBC45D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC3A85AEC2C874C5A9C7EB5993C09DBD8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>RESPONSE Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9BCA674B1C7247F593948945E957E3C0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Railroad Emergency Services Preparedness, Operational Needs, and Safety Evaluation Subcommittee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 508 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/318">6 U.S.C. 318</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4D3CA5D4F14F4D8CAD52305CC761CEEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H844B3DC6055748A389FC242F8400F46A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E449A3386B141D89390B6BAAD6E9DC5" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HEB72E2F4212E44AC9203CAAEC2359E92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>RESPONSE Subcommittee</header>
 <paragraph id="HC74B33848E5E4E49A45B232DA7554A8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>RESPONSE Act of 2015</short-title>, the Administrator shall establish, as a subcommittee of the National Advisory Council, the Railroad Emergency Services Preparedness, Operational Needs, and Safety Evaluation Subcommittee (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>RESPONSE Subcommittee</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCADE64FA5EBB4076ACA567D8AC583610"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (c), the RESPONSE Subcommittee shall be composed of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFA3ECD4FC7D34DBB8EBC360566ED7BCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Deputy Administrator for Protection and National Preparedness of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, or designee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78BF755312B148E886602D56C6BAA41A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Emergency Communications of the Department of Homeland Security, or designee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79CF4220CEE5405097B12C40B7240381"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Director for the Office of Railroad, Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Investigations of the National Transportation Safety Board, or designee, only in an advisory capacity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F6E1BBF4CBE4691A31ACA2FEDDFA1FA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Associate Administrator for Railroad Safety of the Federal Railroad Administration, or designee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF22A037BFD545DAA6BB5D5067E7DA1B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Assistant Administrator for Security Policy and Industry Engagement of the Transportation Security Administration, or designee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H910BC7AD0BB046859CAA9A1FE3EDBC70"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Assistant Commandant for Response Policy of the Coast Guard, or designee.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H151AEC9BDBBC4CA6AB375C56BF4DF4F4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Assistant Administrator for the Office of Solid Waste and Emergency Response of the Environmental Protection Agency, or designee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EAA9F761D7341B89C39DA2A8E14E19A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Associate Administrator for Hazardous Materials Safety of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, or designee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3FE962F891C476F98E89AE52F1BF8D8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Chief Safety Officer and Assistant Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, or designee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEA3D2F94D284A90959C32D17C415FF8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Such other qualified individuals as the Administrator shall appoint as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>RESPONSE Act of 2015</short-title> from among the following:</text>
 <clause id="H17475018664F4571B2AB31CE8C923330"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Members of the National Advisory Council that have the requisite technical knowledge and expertise to address rail emergency response issues, including members from the following disciplines:</text>
 <subclause id="H26203B3ABF464AA69862458E55F6580D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Emergency management and emergency response providers, including fire service, law enforcement, hazardous materials response, and emergency medical services.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6E1BC6E07B524152990C7454C65949A8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>State, local, and tribal government officials with expertise in preparedness, protection, response, recovery, and mitigation, including Adjutants General.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H733E7921D6FF46B2AEAB7BFB8C7F62B9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Elected State, local, and tribal government executives.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8EC812BE159A416CA7856B96CCB070BA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Such other individuals as the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H890BA105E7F4409CAEAA0DBB840DA415"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Individuals who have the requisite technical knowledge and expertise to serve on the RESPONSE Subcommittee, including representatives of—</text>
 <subclause id="HF321B48F7C064581AA9DFA1E2D7274A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the rail industry;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7047F0FB5B8F4F368AE54E0CC711C1B9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the oil industry;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFAB174B04E6842088D0D2A30AF27F8DD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the communications industry;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H85FDDD4FEE6B428FB651E1A60453068C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>emergency response providers, including individuals nominated by national organizations representing local governments and personnel;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB69955F2F38C4810B1AC3AC8985A2119"><enum>(V)</enum><text>representatives from national Indian organizations;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB6212638CB824218BA9B73F149C7FF0A"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>technical experts; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF5DD58060497426F9393B0077E7B3B5E"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>vendors, developers, and manufacturers of systems, facilities, equipment, and capabilities for emergency responder services.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H12BEB023200C4A1589430CEAD5C3E577"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Representatives of such other stakeholders and interested and affected parties as the Administrator considers appropriate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA2B3A740C794907AC5E1F70607CCA89"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Deputy Administrator for Protection and National Preparedness shall serve as the Chairperson of the RESPONSE Subcommittee, or designee.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HDE7F8574A3B3446EBFCF21659EA4CA60"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8DC176166A6D4843B85867ED51520B2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The initial meeting of the RESPONSE Subcommittee shall take place not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>RESPONSE Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE79D8BB813C64C0CA8EDF1E3321FBA21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other meetings</header><text>After the initial meeting, the RESPONSE Subcommittee shall meet at least twice annually, with at least 1 meeting conducted in person during the first year, at the call of the Chairperson.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0DA7C6F902F4CC08D4A2371A41E358A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consultation with nonmembers</header><text>The RESPONSE Subcommittee and the program offices for emergency responder training and resources shall consult with other relevant agencies and groups, including entities engaged in federally funded research and academic institutions engaged in relevant work and research, which are not represented on the RESPONSE Subcommittee to consider new and developing technologies and methods that may be beneficial to preparedness and response to rail incidents.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H727CC8D9BC4B43A28A0587AFCCC7CA61"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The RESPONSE Subcommittee shall evaluate the following topics and develop recommendations for improving emergency responder training and resource allocation for hazardous materials incidents involving railroads:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H12ED17C3F0A64941AF74ABC708CDC56C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Quality and application of training for local emergency first responders related to rail hazardous materials incidents, with a particular focus on local emergency responders and small communities near railroads, including the following:</text>
 <clause id="H4829DEAF7A1E4028AEF3248500597255"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Ease of access to relevant training for local emergency first responders, including an analysis of—</text> <subclause id="H57549E418D47409CA3B25BE92C8DEB20"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of individuals being trained;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H647C622BD1264A11901D6C34828DA8BE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of individuals who are applying;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5BE6F8BAA6D3426CBEC12966CAE1B0BE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whether current demand is being met;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC0449A00889F4A4EBB445033F522B14B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>current challenges; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4F3A4473B6A54E4BB385874B723AAB74"><enum>(V)</enum><text>projected needs.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF7312C3D74704A3EAB780124B577E8DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Modernization of course content related to rail hazardous materials incidents, with a particular focus on response to the exponential rise in oil shipments by rail.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5875B2F3D66347089D1EB5857FE3B2A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Training content across agencies and the private sector to provide complementary opportunities for rail hazardous materials incidents courses and materials to avoid overlap, including the following:</text>
 <subclause id="H8876E9D29E6C436DBEC810B6C6AC4397"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Overlap of course content among agencies.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H383B4CE097A5468D8A0FAB0E8FD3E657"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Integrated course content through public-private partnerships.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA1854878322E4324B23808400205F4CC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Regular and ongoing evaluation of course opportunities, adaptation to emerging trends, agency and private sector outreach, effectiveness and ease of access for local emergency responders.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE958AABCA5684C28AC2954D5DA969C2D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Online training platforms, train-the-trainer and mobile training options.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A00490D19004B3183C2E1EEA2DCF83C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Effectiveness of funding levels related to training local emergency responders for rail hazardous materials incidents, with a particular focus on local emergency responders and small communities, including the following:</text>
 <clause id="H2C44A726608E4B5BAEBBAD8616CA28B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Minimizing overlap in resource allocation among agencies.</text> </clause><clause id="HB9F1C6E540544ABEB764F188261DAF0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Minimizing overlap in resource allocation among agencies and private sector.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF056A543E6444A5F95D8D12A417B933B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Maximizing public-private partnerships where funding gaps exists for specific training or cost-saving measures can be implemented to increase training opportunities.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0375EEE189554EAAB2CF6DFCF506B515"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Adaptation of priority settings for agency funding allocations in response to emerging trends.</text> </clause><clause id="H88C14E0D4C4541E8A83C283650DB7B43"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Historic levels of funding across agencies and private sector for rail hazardous materials incidents.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5240B8414EE14B17B890CC474A83E663"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Current funding resources across agencies.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DF8895DBEB34B6584A24A5CEB762283"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Strategy for integration of commodity flow studies, mapping, and access platforms for local emergency responders and how to increase the rate of access to the individual responder in existing or emerging communications technology.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H786FE0286E93486ABAFA801407E1828C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The need for emergency response plans for rail, similar to existing law related to maritime and stationary facility emergency response plans for hazardous materials, including the following:</text>
 <clause id="H782047E199544C13B1DE5C7EA42FE896"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The requirements of such emergency plans on each train and the format and availability of such emergency plans to emergency responders in communities through which the materials travel.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEEA2831F10A8475DB30E368ADCD6FB97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>How the industry would implement such plans.</text> </clause><clause id="HB461131BF2FD4B848D37D390D6531E30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The thresholds that require emergency plans for each train related to hazardous materials in its cargo.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A26C60CF7C349C48583F51B5169B97B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Gaps in existing regulations across agencies.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86A0AB9B3A2C4BA6BFA1DCB419924863"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The need for a rail hazardous materials incident database, including the following:</text>
 <clause id="H7E840229020543E1B6F5E33881FEDBDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An assessment of the appropriate entity to host the database.</text> </clause><clause id="H799B502649254105BDE05ED48FB4CB4F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A definition of <quote>rail hazardous materials incident</quote> that would constitute the level of reporting from the industry.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6CA2A4FE42344E2C8BB6D22415093881"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The projected cost of such a database and how that database would be maintained and enforced.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7AA660AB4DA4690ABD8BE4C658DD9C3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Increasing access to relevant, useful, and timely information for the local emergency responder for training purposes and in the event of a rail hazardous materials incident, including the following:</text>
 <clause id="H5DBC52C98CEA4CF488227354042BF62B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Existing information that the emergency responder can access, what the current rate of access and usefulness is for the emergency responder, and what current information should remain and what should be reassessed.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2C2B86BBB6F6497CB65884164EBC3F14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Utilization of existing technology in the hands of the first responder to maximize delivery of useful and timely information for training purposes or in the event of an incident.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B696B72FD0A41B9A57DC4CA63B8153E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Assessment of emerging communications technology that could assist the emergency responder in the event of an incident.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H167CB7EEB07B4D768FEC7B6791B3B317"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Determination of the most appropriate agencies and offices for the implementation of the recommendations, including—</text>
 <clause id="H60BD442979044BEC902B8D0E35226DAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>recommendations that can be implemented without congressional action and appropriate time frames for such actions; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA4173639AA264101AB7605BBB54A0C87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations that would require congressional action.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9973E3F7C1742FD9CE43A76D988C41E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report</header> <subparagraph id="H82BEBBE3E1D248858A50DED7D890A5CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>RESPONSE Act of 2015</short-title>, the RESPONSE Subcommittee shall submit a report containing the recommendations developed under paragraph (6) to the National Advisory Council.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4836DB04A8C4CCEA7BC5324A3D1EDA3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The National Advisory Council shall take up the RESPONSE Subcommittee’s report within 30 days for review and deliberation. The National Advisory Council may ask for additional clarification, changes, or other information from the RESPONSE Subcommittee to assist in the approval of the recommendations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H693BC27DC91B4D1C95FF0231CA558113"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Recommendation</header><text>Once the National Advisory Council approves the recommendations from the RESPONSE Subcommittee, the National Advisory Council shall submit the report to—</text>
 <clause id="HADA36FBB98504796B721200A40A1F99B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Administrator;</text> </clause><clause id="H08F23369804C4CD2A626406E066A910C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the head of each agency represented on the RESPONSE Subcommittee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H154FA22C068B4ABE84706AE3E51974BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </clause><clause id="H0A6CC90096D44EC7AA117019E498710D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4420D8BCFCCA4A0DB180AE2000534B77"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2EFC01CFA4C476BA86444995B350AA6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Interim activity</header> <subparagraph id="H163C3A29646A410A9C2A4C669CE02EE2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Updates and oversight</header><text>After the submission of the report by the National Advisory Council under paragraph (7), the Administrator shall—</text>
 <clause id="HE6D7FD9E1E5F463F812295A0E7A7EC71"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide quarterly updates to the congressional committees referred to in paragraph (7) regarding the status of the implementation of the recommendations developed under paragraph (6); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB0F961C878B5457F90E2FCB22A5FBC29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinate the implementation of the recommendations described in paragraph (6)(G)(i).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1E9070426504652BBE468284370BE4B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional reports</header><text>After submitting the report required under paragraph (7), the RESPONSE Subcommittee shall submit additional reports and recommendations in the same manner and to the same entities identified in paragraph (7) if needed or requested from Congress or from the Administrator.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BC8C890924A43EB82F9C8A57DEBD0BF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Termination</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC96B2318E1E14910A020A1B3F7B77372"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the RESPONSE Subcommittee shall terminate not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>RESPONSE Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32313DD63375416FB7E2B2D3B977362B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Administrator may extend the duration of the RESPONSE Subcommittee, in 1-year increments, if the Administrator determines that additional reports and recommendations are needed from the RESPONSE Subcommittee after the termination date set forth in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


