<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2D5AA9CA5D3F4AEC8E0AC71C6C8136D8" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 2856 IH: Citizen Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 2856</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150623">June 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish certain procedures for conducting in-person or
			 telephonic interactions by Executive branch employees with individuals,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H40F099BD76EB41A583B08654B274D6F0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8CFB59D812274CFE86BF1E84E83176F6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Citizen Empowerment Act</short-title> of 2015</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7935568B7B344661BF7522ECB261B852" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments</header> <subsection id="H87E0EA7603E84FF78B01DB04E98E821E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part III of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 79 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC67B7218FA954302B4FC92DED1BE8344" style="USC">
					<chapter id="H4EC64AAD82884726B06C5E63B0D30C93"><enum>79A</enum><header>Services to Members of the Public</header>
						<toc container-level="chapter-container" idref="H4EC64AAD82884726B06C5E63B0D30C93" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H198BDEAC993A4135B20A7BAB0C363DAB" level="section">Sec.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H198BDEAC993A4135B20A7BAB0C363DAB" level="section">7921. Procedures for in-person and telephonic interactions conducted by executive branch employees.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="H198BDEAC993A4135B20A7BAB0C363DAB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7921.</enum><header>Procedures for in-person and telephonic interactions conducted by executive branch employees</header>
 <subsection id="H8BCFA3D833F4428DBDB71AA1C8A70E91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5BE03B9417BA447AB35F88C82ACE5CAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>telephonic</term> means by telephone or other similar electronic device; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE2E823B1A497488C8E3F5B1456DDE3A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25CB46290FAA4EB7841FFADBA79A94BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recording of enforcement actions</header>
 <paragraph id="HC41AAEA8D3EA494087A8231BE227095C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recording by individuals</header><text>Any employee of an Executive agency who is conducting an in-person or a telephonic interview, audit, investigation, inspection, or other official in-person or telephonic interaction with an individual, relating to a possible or alleged violation of any Federal statute or regulation that could result in the imposition of a fine, forfeiture of property, civil monetary penalty, or criminal penalty against, or the collection of an unpaid tax, fine, or penalty from, such individual or a business owned or operated by such individual, shall allow such individual to make an audio recording of such in-person or telephonic interaction at the individual’s own expense and with the individual’s own equipment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC608DED5BDCA4B5DB657FE5169DECBE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recording by Federal employees</header><text>Any employee of an Executive agency that is conducting an in-person or a telephonic interaction described in paragraph (1) may record that interaction if such employee—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEF54024DA8B24192A8BEE1DC17455D0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>informs the individual of such recording prior to or at the initiation of the in-person or telephonic interaction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64E7614AD93043F1891481525304DFFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon request of the individual, provides the individual with a transcript or copy of such recording, but only if the individual provides reimbursement for the cost of the transcription and reproduction of such transcript or copy.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE917CAD4D981477796C9E014C3155EAC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Explanations of rights</header>
 <paragraph id="HD7625CB4AAD24F1AB1432A7BD34025E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any employee of an Executive agency shall, before or at an initial in-person or telephonic interview, audit, investigation, inspection, or other official in-person or telephonic interaction, described in subsection (b)(1), provide to the individual a verbal or written notice of the individual’s rights under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBE4B60ECB47E4660BFDF9926B60BB263"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Separate notifications for separate violations</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not, for purposes of any interaction described in subsection (b)(1), be considered satisfied based on a notification previously given if that previous notification was given in the case of a possible or alleged violation separate from the possible or alleged violation at hand.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F1320B671664FC5BC6C4E416BB312EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application to official representative or those holding power of attorney</header><text>Any person who is permitted to represent, before an Executive agency described in subsection (b)(1), an individual permitted to make an audio recording under such subsection of an in-person or a telephonic interaction conducted by an employee of that Executive agency—</text>
 <paragraph id="H716CF19FC1D8414B848A81E74643B578"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be permitted—</text> <subparagraph id="H69E907C6A96546CA9380E9223925D322"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to make an audio recording under subsection (b)(1) as if the person were such individual; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8C8C75964E64FE691C6A0A1F776B6DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to receive a transcript or copy of an audio recording under subsection (b)(2) as if the person were such individual;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EF6EEF7F51A460B8CA698D42C83D5FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall receive the same notice as that which is required to be provided to the individual under subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA6673EF423E4EF0BEAB84444E48D777"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to an audio recording (as referred to in paragraph (1)(A)) and a transcript or copy of a recording (as referred to in paragraph (1)(B)), shall have the same rights as described in subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H834D0CCBD6B749759962A63331F23E88"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Property of audio recording</header><text>Any audio recording or transcript of an audio recording made pursuant to subsection (b)(1) or provided to an individual pursuant to subsection (b)(2)(B) shall be the property of such individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE00DD755462846C89E419872F0103607"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No cause of action</header><text>This section does not create any express or implied private right of action.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBC036E03A109436FA53DB04031839BAF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> <paragraph id="HBEF4A439C8CF483EAE957110C1B3970A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Classified information, public safety, criminal investigation</header><text>This section shall not apply to any in-person or telephonic interaction—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9536935CBFE0456CB63C1A517756FC83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is likely to include the discussion of classified material;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H308950A65E5D4766AFE6BF8BE5D6D485"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is likely to include the discussion of information that, if released publicly, would endanger public safety; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF49013DED15C4E8ABF0C485B4FDEA88D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that, if released, would endanger an ongoing criminal investigation if such investigation is being conducted by a Federal law enforcement officer (as defined by section 2 of the Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Act of 2008) who is employed by a Federal law enforcement agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54B6E5F9455841D7B018E481FD33F530"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination by employees</header><text>An employee of an Executive agency who makes a determination that an exception created by paragraph (1) applies to an in-person or a telephonic interaction or to a series of such interactions shall provide written notification of such determination to any person who would otherwise be permitted to make an audio recording of the interaction under subsection (b)(1) or (d).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2AC04D76EE944FFA86061FCE4E3FBF4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prior law</header><text>For the purposes set forth in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b), this section supersedes section 2511(2)(d) of title 18 and any provision of Federal or State law insofar as such section or provision relates to the recording of an in-person or a telephonic interaction described in subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H73ADFEDDE603413C875B4B6FD66FA7FA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Disciplinary action</header><text>An employee who violates this section shall be subject to appropriate disciplinary action in accordance with otherwise applicable provisions of law.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEDF5ED522FD8430788971C15E32E55CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for part III of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 79 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H504039C98BE74C1189BF00529E2CE2E1" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<multi-column-toc-entry level="chapter"><toc-enum>79A.</toc-enum><level-header level="chapter">Services to Members of the Public</level-header><target>7921</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


