<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E656CE095C34888988CCCE39B6D9F67" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 338 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage charitable contributions of real property for conservation purposes by Native Corporations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 338</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage charitable contributions of real property for conservation purposes by Native Corporations.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H67B88B08A6F5462BAE30074152553757" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H57476C8101D5426DA24945412468B0D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Encouragement of contributions of capital gain real property made for conservation purposes by Native Corporations</header> 
<subsection id="H0C50E770CD9940979383C08D06A64E0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">Section 170(b)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D), and by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF758EF0B531B4A2ABBB4183830D741E2" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H2475B4C0A5C245AE9E7134DCDAD260F8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified conservation contributions by certain Native Corporations</header> <clause id="H78BD3B0EDFA74B3C9B0D60D664E151B7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any qualified conservation contribution (as defined in subsection (h)(1)) which—</text> 
<subclause id="H84CCE223B2B84E508F4E8EA6CFCC0E75"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is made by a Native Corporation, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5E5D6D4581624AC0A895CF0E1A60109B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is a contribution of property which was land conveyed under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">shall be allowed to the extent that the aggregate amount of such contributions does not exceed the excess of the taxpayer’s taxable income over the amount of charitable contributions allowable under subparagraph (A).</continuation-text></clause> 
<clause id="H4C2BC68163C943E08F1765BCF9F41136"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Carryover</header><text>If the aggregate amount of contributions described in clause (i) exceeds the limitation of clause (i), such excess shall be treated (in a manner consistent with the rules of subsection (d)(2)) as a charitable contribution to which clause (i) applies in each of the 15 succeeding years in order of time.</text></clause> <clause id="HAD65689A43F8409095D2A7C0F82C3858"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>Native Corporation</term> has the meaning given such term by section 3(m) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H30DC6F2965E74223AECFCBB51C53D024"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Valid existing rights preserved</header><text>Nothing in this provision shall be construed to modify the existing property rights validly conveyed to Native Corporations under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF521675F46964B92A463FE7B3844F1F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 170(b)(2)(A) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>subparagraph (B) applies</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (B) or (C) apply</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF8D1FFA6EE9B4A7E9F3CF6906BB9E10D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to contributions made in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2014.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

