<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H08483A0B3A20417E96B3C7EDD84FDB73" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 1082 IH: Building upon Unique Indian Learning and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1082</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150225">February 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To strengthen Indian education, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H9D26F399FB3C4427ADE8FF9295325273" style="OLC">
 <section id="H28E32E71C9944A26A7C56202B9DAB904" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building upon Unique Indian Learning and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H741558F0B55C453FAA56321E7084E0E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>In-school facility innovation program contest</header> <subsection id="H0E1943D38EB94F31BC0C1920B7172A30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAF43722B0C8F4B308A2EAB4DD76DDCE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an in-school facility innovation program contest in which institutions of higher education, including Tribal Colleges and Universities (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>)), are encouraged to consider solving the problem of how to improve school facilities for tribal schools and schools served by the Bureau of Indian Education for problem-based learning in their coursework and through extracurricular opportunities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BF22E8EFE6B47D382776068BEFADC4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish an advisory group for the contest described in paragraph (1) that shall include students enrolled at a Tribal College or University, a representative from the Bureau of Indian Education, and engineering and fiscal advisors.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0BF45C7CB584D66AFBAF37A1F7B3FC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of finalists to the Indian Affairs Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall submit the finalists to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF01C018E00B1416DB9EE1B02D94F5C83"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Winners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE5148FA2F27C479F98FC8F738CA529CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the winners of the program contest conducted under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB83DA9D8E2224C0FB0BF687ECE61A440"><enum>(2)</enum><text>award the winners appropriate recognition and reward.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF13C25090B894A02A9646292C8DD3684"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of the Interior and Department of Education Joint Oversight Board</header> <subsection id="H2C77C91921EC4581BE30C1CADC5E54BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education and the Secretary of the Interior shall jointly establish a Department of the Interior and Department of Education Joint Oversight Board, that shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H77204CFA58744666BDF6CD7205EFF8C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be co-chaired by both Departments; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4702CFF2D047E49C43A81D022FBB10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate technical assistance, resource distribution, and capacity building between the 2 departments on the education of and for Native American students.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC595822266474CEC838CBE58A50510FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information To be shared</header><text>The Joint Oversight Board shall facilitate the communication, collaboration, and coordination between the 2 departments of education policies, access to and eligibility for Federal resources, and budget and school leadership development, and other issues, as appropriate.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H62BAEE8977C94D8599B662B22F08CB33"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improve support for teachers and administrators of native american students</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 2 of part A of title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7441">20 U.S.C. 7441 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD77ACED057544FFB84171E9BD9E4B406" style="OLC">
				<section id="H8F17277F2652426EB498CFE2305938E8"><enum>7123.</enum><header>Teacher and administrator pipeline for teachers and administrators of native american students</header>
 <subsection id="HD53D1F6583F8413484C3DEE8136952A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to create or expand a teacher or administrator, or both, pipeline for teachers and administrators of Native American students.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5B39840558A44D3F81B4B35327D8EEB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HC2052DB2A38048E585B8F6D9E4EDF98F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local educational agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF72FCA55ECBB431D8CA16F8795110332"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H96B7CF899DBE432980D67750938629AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H47A9B6B749264881B7FF8935E75F3004"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD25833A6132D4A7891B6E1B545516DE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to Tribal Colleges and Universities (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5960B53C0D1D41ADB5677EDC38691B9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall create a program that shall prepare, recruit, and provide continuing education for teachers and administrators of Native American students, in particular for teachers of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H91113519400548519945B0FC84559DC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">science, technology, engineering, and mathematics;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC638DA299E8D4606BAFE4EF661363AA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subjects that lead to health professions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF8C16CB4D99481E80DEF22212D6BAFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">green skills and <quote>middle skills</quote>, including electrical, welding, technology, plumbing, and green jobs.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C91C219DAE64E71AEAE773D1AC8AB6D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Incentives for teachers and administrators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may provide incentives to teachers and principals who make a commitment to serve high-need, high-poverty, tribal schools, including in the form of scholarships, loan forgiveness, incentive pay, or housing allowances.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB47EAAF5C685418094DE87D21EBF2A52"><enum>(f)</enum><header>School and community orientation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall develop an evidence-based, culturally based school and community orientation for new teachers and administrators of Native American students.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HB6B9B0358C374B298833285BD44B8A1A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Native American student support</header>
 <subsection id="H212E47D4D209443B951E2E27AAC7016D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standards-Based assessments</header><text>Section 1111(b)(3) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33E34A2384444102AB49C8E6E017D78A" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H166389DFB2294BBEAAE355A374618425"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Standards-based education assessments</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, a State shall develop standards-based education assessments and classroom lessons to accommodate diverse learning styles, which assessments may be used by the State in place of the general assessments described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFCF55CF2134E45FEBE164C8325C44E80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall expand programs for Native American school children—</text> <paragraph id="HDCEED9C122504F0CAF3759D14CBAC317"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide support for learning in the children's Native language and culture; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDD44E3266454D9A95431E134C57C8A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide English language instruction.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6D1EB3B14E1481283B4C76AE689FF4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct research on culture- and language-based education to identify the factors that improve education and health outcomes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF9A83B912F654EF9BE44B99E9019676E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Native language teaching</header><text>Section 1119 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESEA">Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6319">20 U.S.C. 6319</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC1D5BFE48BC4ED1AE48636DA864AAC7" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H86C611E589404D6A9D9525C78A6DD3D0"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Qualifications for Native language teachers</header> <paragraph id="H5F547AA98D644BA3BAF58746501FA7C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the requirements of subsection (a) for local educational agencies and States with respect to highly qualified teachers, shall not apply to a teacher of a Native language.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDC311DC1BB74F1CA0BB3D0CDBA2066C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative licensure or certification</header><text>Each State educational agency receiving assistance under this part shall develop an alternative licensure or certification for teachers of a Native language.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BB43168243A4D75B9CF59007F18CCDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant program To ensure the survival and continuing vitality of native american languages</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07B7D181CEC646F8A921EAC47DEBD9BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAB7DCB5271C4218ACEE6C4E802FFFFC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans in the Department of Health and Human Services (established under section 803B of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2991b-2">42 U.S.C. 2991b–2</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A69231F2C904BE7B64764015A0C71E3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means any agency or organization that is eligible for financial assistance under section 803(a) of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2991b">42 U.S.C. 2991b(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB06F425F56D64992B025672C51A0152E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header><text>The Commissioner shall establish a program to provide eligible entities with grants for the purpose of assisting Native Americans to ensure the survival and continuing vitality of Native American languages.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4D408D53EAC4941AB3A1B88A0098766"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64631E2F560F4509B8DA38948E2950BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity may use amounts received under this subsection to carry out activities that ensure the survival and continuing vitality of Native American languages, including—</text>
 <clause id="HDF8B915756014145BDE193E9AA08E73F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the establishment and support of community Native American language projects designed to bring older and younger Native Americans together to facilitate and encourage the transfer of Native American language skills from one generation to another;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD7E3FD004DED41CFB08A8ECCE918687E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the establishment of projects that train Native Americans to—</text> <subclause id="H4EF02E1D05B34BED92BD74BF8F1FD437"><enum>(I)</enum><text>teach a Native American language to others; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA14666C288124008BFF2D104044EB131"><enum>(II)</enum><text>serve as interpreters or translators of a Native American language;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H6D492E36710B4366B311FEF27E87F98D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the development, printing, and dissemination of materials to be used for the teaching and enhancement of a Native American language;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H71D3B828516146808A1C2202BC27395F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the establishment or support of a project to train Native Americans to produce or participate in television or radio programs to be broadcast in a Native American language;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0D239D665435441799EF5C2036F074DA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the compilation, transcription, and analysis of oral testimony to record and preserve a Native American language;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H60852E24FADF44898F74651B242BF2EB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the purchase of equipment, including audio and video recording equipment, computers, and software, required to carry out a Native American language project; and</text>
						</clause><clause id="HB75950373387467AA2D1B2B081A661B0"><enum>(vii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0DBC7D56F0204BAAA9BEAE7296953D00"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the establishment of Native American language nests, which are site-based educational programs that—</text>
 <item id="H6BB1CC98FF11495E8F20AFC3ED234728" indent="up1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>provide instruction and child care through the use of a Native American language for at least 10 children under the age of 7 for an average of at least 500 hours per year per student;</text>
 </item><item id="HCBDD84A7F48D418FBDDA4B42B655AFC9" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>provide classes in a Native American language for parents (or legal guardians) of students enrolled in a Native American language nest (including Native American language-speaking parents); and</text>
 </item><item id="H1D4DCD8E644E46EA94220F75AC4A2733" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>ensure that a Native American language is the dominant medium of instruction in the Native American language nest;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H39D9E749D1C5484C98F5E8972192686E" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the establishment of Native American language survival schools, which are site-based educational programs for school-age students that—</text>
 <item id="H4E470DC7F9FC47308732AB0BA5AB199B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>provide an average of at least 500 hours of instruction through the use of 1 or more Native American languages for at least 15 students for whom a Native American language survival school is the principal place of instruction;</text>
 </item><item id="H4D3EF022DFC344A1BC6633124C187FCC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>develop instructional courses and materials for learning Native American languages and for instruction through the use of Native American languages;</text>
 </item><item id="H1115FF42F554411E85C413085F2D924D"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>provide for teacher training;</text> </item><item id="H366B47022ED641209E51631FBDA23FD0"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>work toward a goal of all students achieving—</text>
 <subitem id="HAC00C5DE896547A390A9019C69C9315A"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>fluency in a Native American language; and</text> </subitem><subitem id="HF3DF4B8905FD4FAEB327EA86B4B2BFAF"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>academic proficiency in mathematics, reading (or language arts), and science; and</text>
 </subitem></item><item id="HF4A3F27BC05A43369EC107F698A1042C"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>are located in areas that have high numbers or percentages of Native American students; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HC193BD6C61214919A92EEBD5E75E65CD" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the establishment of Native American language restoration programs, which are educational programs that—</text>
 <item id="HED128BBFB0B340BBA7E8E2573CB8F446"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>operate at least 1 Native American language program for the community that the educational program serves;</text>
 </item><item id="H74BF5501472445D18FC6BBBF76A13C5A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>provide training programs for teachers of Native American languages;</text> </item><item id="H14F3C18872C949E998B7915D7DB9E0CF"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>develop instructional materials for the Native American language restoration programs;</text>
 </item><item id="H7A80FA737C5A4E82AAE4F8941A267A34"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>work toward a goal of increasing proficiency and fluency in at least 1 Native American language; and</text>
 </item><item id="HD79C5452B33F4C58923D9461839DC804"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>provide instruction in at least 1 Native American language.</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H684A04E8F57B4DC2BBF845A95EB5C934"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Native American language restoration programs</header><text>An eligible entity carrying out a program described in subparagraph (A)(vii)(III) may use amounts made available under this section to carry out—</text>
 <clause id="H0943D44823ED4084AB0E73C10C580771"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Native American language programs, including—</text> <subclause id="H7400FF1E529A4EF7896367943ED46C8B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Native American language immersion programs;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5FDDAE2C26AC4E19AC5D486BB6F27EC3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Native American language and culture camps;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD6357D76E92B4010B85279D40414CCE8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Native American language programs provided in coordination and cooperation with educational entities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF23B8D7FEE224278A640317A8FC2485A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Native American language programs provided in coordination and cooperation with institutions of higher education with expertise in the relevant Native language, particularly Tribal Colleges and Universities (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>));</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE57531270E19441895A7016E0AD8BAB4"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Native American language programs that use a master-apprentice model of learning languages; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H22206F1C3AAD4A2F83ABB1C33F8EFB14"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Native American language programs provided through a regional program to better serve geographically dispersed students;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF46968FE6B7041B9B1AD6F31F0DBADE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Native American language teacher training programs, including—</text> <subclause id="H5641E37FAB9D491FAC62A4D49FA12062"><enum>(I)</enum><text>training programs in Native American language translation for fluent speakers;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC3EE3954E96F4B7E89638987F552192B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>training programs for Native American language teachers; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H305E1DAACD664A74B43C604FF1CB57D8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>training programs for teachers in the use of Native American language materials, tools, and interactive media to teach Native American language; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H71B2CFFFE0514731B2B5AC65C35A71A3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the development of Native American language materials, including books, audio and visual tools, and interactive media programs.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5997F7A3B1945D3805FF2424477E9E5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applications</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6AB32A2518743068C2665825389087A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), in awarding a grant under this subsection, the Commissioner shall select applicants from among eligible entities on the basis of applications submitted to the Commissioner at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Commissioner requires.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9136EE8D596040068266AC49F1769C5C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An application under subparagraph (A) shall include, at a minimum—</text> <clause id="H21FB14DA395B45BDA67438019DF24DD5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a detailed description of the current status of the Native American language to be addressed by the project for which a grant is requested, including a description of existing programs and projects, if any, in support of that language;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H36D0F233B4B74FA5B22963FDE9643CCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a detailed description of the project for which the grant is requested;</text> </clause><clause id="HF7C43A26D77046D1AF6420ED7B12980E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a statement that the objectives of the project are in accordance with the purposes of this subsection;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1B316169BE814BD0AF03EF2BAE9BDDC7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a detailed description of the plan of the applicant to evaluate the project;</text> </clause><clause id="HD5EBA0C3578140958FCEC20EE301BBBB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>if appropriate, an identification of opportunities for the replication or modification of the project for use by other Native Americans;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF218E17BD115402D86B21CF436BD66CE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a plan for the preservation of the products of the Native American language project for the benefit of future generations of Native Americans and other interested persons; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9095603ED7CC45539542CF23A5F11F69"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>in the case of an application for a grant to carry out any purpose specified in paragraph (3)(A)(vii)(III), a certification by the applicant that the applicant has not less than 3 years of experience in operating and administering a Native American language survival school, a Native American language nest, or any other educational program in which instruction is conducted in a Native American language.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA11CCF9A1B594A28B315B9627E44FC52"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participating organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an applicant determines that the objectives of a proposed Native American language project would be accomplished more effectively through a partnership with an educational entity, the applicant shall identify the educational entity as a participating organization in the application.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE32D6D2CDD154EC3B9BFF1954C10B1EF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitations on funding</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCBDC24A529B448BEA2FB1BFC0D025C2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the total cost of a program under this subsection shall not exceed 80 percent.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8E7D278D4F64EE9BA83D3C27C7785A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header> <clause id="H01DE470F90784D6897714F7CF8B5B8DE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The non-Federal share of the cost of a program under this subsection may be provided in cash or fairly evaluated in-kind contributions, including facilities, equipment, or services.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD8A07FBADA5048A98A0C8B9C5517EBEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Source of non-Federal share</header><text>The non-Federal share—</text> <subclause id="H1BA0B766C6A14C299C674C4D23865E85"><enum>(I)</enum><text>may be provided from any private or non-Federal source; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF9E79176EA3B4A78AC36A9363CC44223"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may include amounts (including interest) distributed to an Indian tribe—</text> <item id="H340EF48B5A4344CAB77B3FC2313E03F7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by the Federal Government pursuant to the satisfaction of a claim made under Federal law;</text>
 </item><item id="H63021157D4A040B29536CDC16034ADB0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>from amounts collected and administered by the Federal Government on behalf of an Indian tribe or the members of an Indian tribe; or</text>
 </item><item id="HCA3BA7CC05084E49A17113F5D5914F91"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>by the Federal Government for general tribal administration or tribal development under a formula or subject to a tribal budgeting priority system, including—</text>
 <subitem id="H4F09A2D23BC84D99AE9502023AA24877"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>amounts involved in the settlement of land or other judgment claims;</text> </subitem><subitem id="HB20D014D28F241D8BDDCF09638BC9933"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>severance or other royalty payments; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H7AAC6B7EE687475F81C6CE3F6BCF439E"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>payments under the Indian Self-Determination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450f">25 U.S.C. 450f et seq.</external-xref>) or a tribal budget priority system.</text>
									</subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H887E26BADE7745D9BB63DD2A5C112683"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration</header>
 <clause id="H274DA893086A444EB994FDC2B98F806D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the Commissioner may make grants made under this subsection on a 1-year, 2-year, or 3-year basis.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB8B8071530D3497580A58B935B735415"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Native American language restoration program</header><text>The Commissioner shall only make a grant available under paragraph (3)(A)(vii)(III) on a 3-year basis.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9BA7D8799CB43629F66A5126AD9414E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Administration</header>
					<subparagraph id="H6A4BA24E46C34F498CAF2988B0820304"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Expert panel</header>
 <clause id="H765F9A0C602347B09C45569DF3ACEF7C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after date of enactment of this subsection, the Commissioner shall appoint a panel of experts for the purpose of assisting the Commissioner to review—</text>
 <subclause id="H3C01877C62DA4BA4B602A96D3BDDA5AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>applications submitted under paragraph (4);</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5591B0EFE47A4771ABBD5DB826F45CB8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>evaluations carried out to comply with paragraph (4)(B)(iv); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEF333239641F4AEBB20E7A56D1D55101"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the preservation of products required by paragraph (4)(B)(vi).</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H1CD29B99E6ED488ABC4284845357A919"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Composition</header> <subclause id="H3EB059443838451E9F486BDC65FFD2CD"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The panel shall include—</text>
 <item id="H980DAE85AF9E4EEFBFF74448F6F66040"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a designee of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development;</text> </item><item id="H4B8ADE3CB39D41C7968D5367CCCDE307"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>representatives of national, tribal, and regional organizations that focus on Native American language or Native American cultural research, development, or training; and</text>
 </item><item id="H35C41CA9D9164526947B5A0C6DD5AEF4"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>other individuals who are recognized as experts in the area of Native American language.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H6BEBA570C1AD438FB0EEA67467593108"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The Commissioner shall solicit recommendations for appointments to the panel from Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H744A7E50B0D44436879BA95C99680F2D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the panel shall include—</text> <subclause id="H9189F293EB354441A230F220D8EEBAA4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>making recommendations regarding the development and implementation of regulations, policies, procedures, and rules of general applicability with respect to the administration of this subsection;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE7F17228F6C3424E98DCD8F51CCDE5B9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>reviewing applications received under paragraph (4);</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDEA8457255154F9EBB29C061B07AE1A5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>providing to the Commissioner a list of recommendations for the approval of applications in accordance with—</text>
 <item id="H3BD99C2C59F8495A9D0DEB13262BC381"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>regulations issued by the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and</text> </item><item id="HBB0B751BA03F491380DF0DE091E26718"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the relative need for the project; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HB63B9D0C9FE14195AC1E31173EFE61EA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>reviewing evaluations submitted to comply with paragraph (4)(B)(iv).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61637FCB1F8D49AF81102F439A1C9D95"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Products generated by projects</header> <clause id="HCB74BC1D2932456E83E8215A9CC5577D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), for preservation and use in accordance with the responsibilities of the respective organization under Federal law, a copy of any product of a Native American language project for which a grant is made under this subsection—</text>
 <subclause id="HC3A8363AA31E422EBCE33DC45ECE4FB4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be transmitted—</text> <item id="HC3D1D463D4A4454D84255E30D42C8DE5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development; and</text>
 </item><item id="H8A99594D6B154FDC95029BF8EDDBD2D6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to the Tribal Colleges or Universities where the language addressed in the grant program is inherent; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H5F8E1ACFE61C4E218CE44F517DF6AD03"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may be transmitted, at the discretion of the grantee, to national and regional repositories of similar material.</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="HA1780FB98A9F4638AD3158FB6CA73A10"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exemption</header>
 <subclause id="HFB4BEA6C1D464117BF6FDBED73899CFB"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the Federal recognition of the sovereign authority of each Indian tribe over all aspects of the culture and language of that Indian tribe and subject to subclause (II), an Indian tribe may make a determination—</text>
 <item id="HA2093AE288714FA0AECC30E34E649CCC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>not to transmit a copy of a product under clause (i);</text> </item><item id="HB0E940430730456BA2B16E454CD1AD31"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not to permit the redistribution of a copy of a product transmitted under clause (i); or</text>
 </item><item id="H96D776ED4B634F1C94A793C0B8788FB8"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>to restrict in any manner the use or redistribution of a copy of a product transmitted under clause (i).</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H22A32F4FA2AC4E0BA5E6C151E80877E1"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>Subclause (I) does not authorize an Indian tribe—</text> <item id="HCF867860AFA74E12A7E0B44238CCA089"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to limit the access of the Commissioner to a product described in clause (i) for purposes of administering this subsection or evaluating the product; or</text>
 </item><item id="H4A01FCBDF00644A39BEEEA060F50D21A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to sell a product described in clause (i), or a copy of that product, for profit to the entities referred to in clause (i).</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C489C5CA8E54E11BC5F3CA3CF862C34"><enum>(7)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4EFFAC8391D4E8AB488181813CDE16D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H60F243D5272E4A24BAC5A4CE4046B282"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 803C of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2991b-3">42 U.S.C. 2991b–3</external-xref>) is repealed.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5A995D983AA4A9AAB19808BDD5D12F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Section 816 of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2992d">42 U.S.C. 2992d</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H17F92615E97D4F1184C5246C42E909CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>sections 803(d), 803A, 803C, 804, subsection (e) of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 803(d), 803A, and 804, subsection (d)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57704F4EBF734B04AAF87F5D24DD01F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>other than sections 803(d), 803A, 803C, 804, subsection (e) of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 803(d), 803A, and 804, subsection (d)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD18CCD0EAEC41988667A59262E147D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H85A04EA645334B9DA8109501286ECEAD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Increased access to resources for tribal schools, schools served by the Bureau of Indian Education, and Native American students</header> <subsection id="H30D82B6B68814F54A0ED88441DC3BC34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation for Bureau-Funded Schools and Programs and Schools Operated by a Tribe or Tribal Organization</header> <paragraph id="HFF7CD62F62BA4CDF8ECDF159DCA5260C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall ensure that any program administered by the Department of Education that awards grants, contracts, or other assistance to benefit elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) or prekindergarten or early childhood programs, provides a reservation, as described in this subsection, for 1 or more of the following categories of entities, as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Education for each such grant, contract, or assistance program:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H86C1EE9E427048A0AD88CEA273839B3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Bureau-funded schools (as defined in section 1141 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2021">25 U.S.C. 2021</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74DD77A71509436DB8DCA57C3BF2DA51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Prekindergarten programs or early childhood programs or services operated by a tribe or Indian organization (as defined in such section).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CE259E861114E7FAA1A2167A3B1861B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Elementary schools or secondary schools operated by a tribe or Indian organization (as defined in such section).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6E01AFDFF2746C783FF376F443569E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of Reservation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB472F8CA69884E1EAD32C0AA20C693C7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Existing Reservation of Funds</header><text>In the case of a grant, contract, or assistance program provided by the Department of Education to benefit elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) or prekindergarten or early childhood programs for which funds are reserved for entities described in paragraph (1), or for a group that may include such entities—</text>
 <clause id="HE74795D786794FD6A6B2D25E5C161AEC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the existing reservation of funds is for an amount that is less than 0.5 percent, the amount of such reservation shall be increased to 0.5 percent; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H999E8203688941F1A1F8221421883ADA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the existing reservation of funds is for an amount that is equal to or greater than 0.5 percent, the amount of such reservation shall be maintained.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9EB6438440B44868B6CFF711B2BE7A6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No Existing Reservation of Funds</header><text>In the case of a grant, contract, or assistance program provided by the Department of Education to benefit elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) or prekindergarten or early childhood programs for which no funds are reserved for the entities described in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Education shall reserve 0.5 percent of such funds for such entities, as determined by the Secretary of Education in accordance with paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA68EA47543394AFFB8CEAA75861ED061"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of Reserved Funds</header><text>Funds reserved under this section shall be used in accordance with the uses of funds described for each particular grant, contract, or assistance program. In addition to program support, such reserved funds may be used, in an amount determined by the Secretary of Education, for technical assistance or capacity building to ensure that the schools or programs described in paragraph (1) are provided the assistance to compete for such grants, contracts, or other assistance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A3FC026B6ED4BD4A8DD8F9BE0B39564"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect on Other Laws</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall carry out this subsection notwithstanding any other provision of law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5E0C918D6FA44A2B491EC578CF993BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safe and healthy schools for Native American students</header><text>Subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7131">20 U.S.C. 7131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76EF0D8C234F47C1827A59C68A6F9355" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB53F2E52C374432BB7C8942EFD08D0BB"><enum>4131.</enum><header>Safe and healthy schools for Native American students</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">From funds made available to carry out this subpart, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3CE834A0E44F4BD287A54CD313BF55F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a program to improve school environments and student skill development for healthy choices for Native American students, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7E806E18CD1D41319BDE8617C841A7B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevention regarding—</text> <clause id="H137244D796C3492F9C3C73C09C528361"><enum>(i)</enum><text>alcohol and drug misuse;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAB20129BE7C04BFB85254F852FE0691D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>suicide;</text> </clause><clause id="H1CB7BEA3BFF74121AE7CBCE3F59F4B44"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>violence;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD203ED4294054EE7B62E0567C1287D40"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>pregnancy; and</text> </clause><clause id="HC07C81812AC74150B9CF270653C24C9E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>obesity;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H867B0CA922A54AED9F0F17256A8BB5F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nutritious eating programs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5321BBE88474042A789049745DEFDBE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>anger and conflict management programs;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF205FE90CCB14BF488D5BD5205E226AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a program for school dropout prevention for Native American students; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6199208526741B696B4F222F6502185"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collaborate with the Secretary of Agriculture to establish tribal-school specific school gardens and nutrition programs that are within the tribal cultural context.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H1AC438A2C94748138989AA60EAB0FE13"><enum>7.</enum><header>Funds for Impact Aid</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise appropriated to carry out title VIII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7701">20 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.</external-xref>), there are authorized to be appropriated, and there are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to carry out such title VIII the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBAC08532F3F844E3A8DE6549C287FF6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$750,000,000 for fiscal year 2016.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8EDE13887304E9C9B7AF4F9D701740C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$750,000,000 for fiscal year 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94C678A97C9F42B3BBBA308CC9A31965"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$750,000,000 for fiscal year 2018.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H28E875A3B79D4ED48F2152D2A1F3CF00"><enum>8.</enum><header>Forward Funding for Tribal Colleges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For carrying out the following programs, there are authorized to be appropriated $91,087,500 for fiscal year 2016 which shall become available on July 1, 2016, and shall remain available through September 30, 2017:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4A57F7DFDC3C43078EDD7E0AFBEC4402"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Programs under title V of the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1861">25 U.S.C. 1861 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0360D5E91B3A47188C0112181930B58B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development established under the American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian Culture and Art Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/4401">20 U.S.C. 4401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H900B2CECBA5D4F01A901CAFB71BD3BEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Institutional operations grants for the Haskell Indian Nations University and Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute under the authority of the Act of November 2, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/13">25 U.S.C. 13</external-xref>), popularly known as the Snyder Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26E2D548033E4AAE8DF5FE4C1831DB23"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Scholarships and adult education and special higher education scholarships under the authority of the Act of November 2, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/13">25 U.S.C. 13</external-xref>), popularly known as the Snyder Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7DA6127BC66D4B209846433DDB18FE69"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definition of Tribal School</header>
 <subsection id="H14FBF838071D4866A003C76F06C23FFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>ESEA Definition</header><text>Section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H111937FA3C164C47820D1AA8BD44B929" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3A3C4314EE674839B66C0479873ADA7F"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Tribal School</header><text>The term <term>tribal school</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HCD3BA2FB351D46A4B384B08B3F2BCF72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a school that is a Bureau-funded school, as defined in section 1141 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2021">25 U.S.C. 2021</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0848141170F04362B375836B245B7D7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a prekindergarten program, early childhood program or service, or elementary school or secondary school, operated by an Indian tribe or tribal organization (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAB842092ED84C97B2388CCD68D25EEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a school that is located on Indian lands (as defined in section 8013); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9742F3B775547C1B834E4B66DE78B3A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a school in which a predominance of the students who attend the school are Native American or Alaska Native students, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCC71B935F56A4E58B261CED172CAC2BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition for this Act</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>tribal school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>) (as amended by subsection (a)).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


