<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9DE9F59EF557432B9EE5F4D0C846E884" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3211 IH: To provide for the addition of certain real property to the reservation of the Siletz Tribe in the State of Oregon.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3211</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the addition of certain real property to the reservation of the Siletz Tribe in the
			 State of Oregon.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H510E1475465E41B78ADE0D8C89318E7C" style="OLC">
		<section id="H822935EBB7EE4614A4236B9A44C801A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Purpose; clarification</header>
 <subsection id="HAB346074022A4140B2A2A98B29DF30C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to facilitate fee-to-trust applications for the Siletz Tribe within the geographic area specified in the amendment made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D755BF90EF64136BB42E58426F02E81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Except as specifically provided otherwise by this Act or the amendment made by this Act, nothing in this Act or the amendment made by this Act, shall prioritize for any purpose the claims of any federally recognized Indian tribe over the claims of any other federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H346DBE452254444F82DC5DC99F7F6C83" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of certain property of the Siletz tribe of the State of Oregon</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of the Siletz Tribe Indian Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/711e">25 U.S.C. 711e</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1CC241C8A15470FB1B48F7184A8F5AF" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HF6F1BFF2D9204DC7ABA45399A8201EF9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Treatment of certain property</header>
					<paragraph id="HD525485E22854630B928EFFB07F969E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8654B322EF2249A4B100B7378496C852"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Title</header><text>The Secretary may accept title to any additional number of acres of real property located within the boundaries of the original 1855 Siletz Coast Reservation established by Executive order dated November 9, 1855, comprised of land within the political boundaries of Benton, Douglas, Lane, Lincoln, Tillamook, and Yamhill Counties in the State of Oregon, if that real property is conveyed or otherwise transferred to the United States by or on behalf of the tribe.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14920279398343DB8FD867884FA0ACB4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Trust</header><text>Land to which title is accepted by the Secretary under this paragraph shall be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the tribe.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3081B112F98E43AC82FA7CCB9DA0018B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment as part of reservation</header><text>All real property that is taken into trust under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H3B30268C746D413B8474BBCBB5939B77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be considered and evaluated as an on-reservation acquisition under part 151.10 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3E06C92926D4E2591D9B1C9315397C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>become part of the reservation of the tribe.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C0D7FA946404DD191A532C84E28606E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on gaming</header><text>Any real property taken into trust under paragraph (1) shall not be eligible, or used, for any gaming activity carried out under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


