<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H69070323EC4240B58C79BE00926E8E16" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 3326 IH: Defend Trade Secrets Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3326</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001051">Mr. Hanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/90">chapter 90</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, to provide Federal jurisdiction for the theft
			 of trade secrets, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H4E61B33568474A9E9D99E03A96F9D658" style="OLC">
 <section id="H21CB358072254AAA9119E63B84CD0F2F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defend Trade Secrets Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFE977699765743648E6AADB9E6B51C60"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal jurisdiction for theft of trade secrets</header> <subsection id="HABBCB848372444B8BCC95F98D3308B21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1836 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HB9DB7E182F4246399338F2F431B76433" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H3A937B7473F94B21AF69077D3B165585"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private civil actions</header>
 <paragraph id="HC503B0A114F24E9CB599AA8AF44E38C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An owner of a trade secret may bring a civil action under this subsection if the person is aggrieved by a misappropriation of a trade secret that is related to a product or service used in, or intended for use in, interstate or foreign commerce.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA30F2FADF54201B0CBD93C4FF10C6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil seizure</header>
							<subparagraph id="H857931150DE04968A00F13F3C235A32F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <clause id="HF7680004AE3B44FD880580E060736683"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Based on an affidavit or verified complaint satisfying the requirements of this paragraph, the court may, upon ex parte application, issue an order providing for the seizure of property necessary to prevent the propagation or dissemination of the trade secret that is the subject of the action.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC0E440FFF36A480C82DC8DC522D1D4BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements for issuing order</header><text>The court may not grant an application under clause (i) unless the court finds that it clearly appears from specific facts that—</text>
 <subclause id="HF5A0BD070E2646ECAE69F764822AC89C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an order issued pursuant to Rule 65(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure would be inadequate to achieve the purpose of this paragraph because the party to which the order would be issued would evade, avoid, or otherwise not comply with such an order;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4675C2DA67A24B609D6EF5660ED63065"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an immediate and irreparable injury will occur if such seizure is not ordered;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H97E1DD3664C8409392C5DD52B77AA88D"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the harm to the applicant of denying the application outweighs the harm to the legitimate interests of the person against whom seizure would be ordered of granting the application and substantially outweighs the harm to any third parties who may be harmed by such seizure;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1CD89DB2AB984E16A57FCC281B1C93C2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant is likely to succeed in showing that—</text> <item id="H8E512BEB120B4AC79B0F0FD89C5A3931"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information is a trade secret;</text>
 </item><item id="H2AFB6C0AA9CF4855BD072C8F2A365C07"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person against whom seizure would be ordered—</text> <subitem id="HDE511D63CB08463A8BBFB590E4068410"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">misappropriated the trade secret of the applicant by improper means; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HC2D368EB8D114DFA8D4064E911B70776"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conspired to use improper means to misappropriate the trade secret of the applicant; and</text> </subitem></item><item id="H34A7D7B37107431B80167CD6D97E5CA3"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person against whom seizure would be ordered has possession of the trade secret;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H383B029A644149E1B459179ECB4E598B"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application describes with reasonable particularity the matter to be seized and, to the extent reasonable under the circumstances, identifies the location where the matter is to be seized;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H44445C4EB1314A97B599D498B454DAFA"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the person against whom seizure would be ordered, or persons acting in concert with such person, would destroy, move, hide, or otherwise make such matter inaccessible to the court, if the applicant were to proceed on notice to such person; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2C771A16CBF243BD96DA3838E876CD23"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant has not publicized the requested seizure.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCCB603567AC4FA1A430B53EA53EA96E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements of order</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an order is issued under subparagraph (A), it shall—</text>
 <clause id="HAC2B86619A0045B9ABD1BF218AD3CD92"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set forth findings of fact and conclusions of law required for the order;</text> </clause><clause id="H02696E3D12A843D2AFCC6212D7CB5271"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for the narrowest seizure of property necessary to achieve the purpose of this paragraph and direct that the seizure be conducted in a manner that minimizes any interruption of the business operations of third parties and, to the extent possible, does not interrupt the legitimate business operations of the person accused of misappropriating the trade secret that are unrelated to the trade secret that has allegedly been misappropriated;</text>
								</clause><clause id="H99C61F5093A9415DBD05F37B17D8D19D"><enum>(iii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H800604495CD24977B13877780498B9E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be accompanied by an order protecting the seized property from disclosure by restricting the access of the applicant, including during the seizure, and prohibiting any copies, in whole or in part, of the seized property, to prevent undue damage to the party against whom the order has issued or others, until such parties have an opportunity to be heard in court; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H19D76AEC74E149EB81D2876143B37D55" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if access is granted to the applicant, the access shall be consistent with subparagraph (D);</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H381E8524EE5B422BAE28522CCFEE0281"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set a date for a hearing described in subparagraph (F) at the earliest possible time, and not later than 7 days after the order has issued, unless the party against whom the order is directed and others harmed by the order consent to another date for the hearing, except that a party against whom the order has issued or any person harmed by the order may move the court at any time to dissolve or modify the order after giving notice to the applicant who obtained the order; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB7CBD7FDE6C4C2E9CEA4AD239396896"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the person obtaining the order to provide the security determined adequate by the court for the payment of the damages that any person may be entitled to recover as a result of a wrongful or excessive seizure or wrongful or excessive attempted seizure under this paragraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB3CEEDC64AC4C92BC13FE005E2EC9F8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Protection from publicity</header><text>The court shall take appropriate action to protect the person against whom an order under this paragraph is directed from publicity, by or at the behest of the person obtaining the order, about such order and any seizure under such order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D39882DD47A43D388172BDEF8CFDFC4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Materials in custody of court</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any materials seized under this paragraph shall be taken into the custody of the court. The court shall secure the seized material from physical and electronic access during the seizure and while in the custody of the court. If the seized material includes an electronic storage medium, or if the seized material is stored on an electronic storage medium, the court shall prohibit the medium from being connected to an electronic network or the Internet without the consent of both parties, until the hearing required under subparagraph (B)(iv) and described in subparagraph (F).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF369F6FE0F546D89C9829F529C651B9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Service of order</header><text>The court shall order that service of a copy of the order under this paragraph, and the submissions of the applicant to obtain the order, shall be made by a Federal law enforcement officer, or may be made by a State or local law enforcement officer, who, upon making service, shall carry out the seizure under the order.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48057ABDB2E24B699CF79A19962131FB"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Seizure hearing</header>
 <clause id="H2FE0B5210A9A4AB98B9440EC50E9E63B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Date</header><text>A court that issues a seizure order shall hold a hearing on the date set by the court under subparagraph (B)(iv).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA87F216AA1D74023A3B0252344A60BEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>At a hearing held under this subparagraph, the party obtaining the order shall have the burden to prove that the facts supporting the findings of fact and conclusions of law necessary to support the order are still in effect. If the party fails to meet that burden, the seizure order shall be dissolved or modified appropriately.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C0AA2C85E924837B62C876F37316159"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Dissolution or modification of order</header><text>A party against whom the order has been issued or any person harmed by the order may move the court at any time to dissolve or modify the order after giving notice to the party who obtained the order.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6B8F187177C349708AF7937DD0653F6F"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Discovery time limits</header><text>The court may make such orders modifying the time limits for discovery under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure as may be necessary to prevent the frustration of the purposes of a hearing under this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24B3CC87ACBF48809EEDBF83007177D5"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Action for damage caused by wrongful seizure</header><text>A person who suffers damage by reason of a wrongful or excessive seizure under this paragraph has a cause of action against the applicant for the order under which such seizure was made, and shall be entitled to the same relief as is provided under section 34(d)(11) of the Trademark Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1116">15 U.S.C. 1116(d)(11)</external-xref>). The security posted with the court under subparagraph (B)(v) shall not limit the recovery of third parties for damages.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC6AC4B553074C10A6CA55F48FCEC404"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Motion for encryption</header><text>A party may make a motion at any time, which may be heard ex parte, to encrypt any material seized or to be seized under this paragraph that is stored on an electronic storage medium. The motion shall include, when possible, the desired encryption method.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H328DC35D286D4662B3018529F1669976"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text>In a civil action brought under this subsection with respect to the misappropriation of a trade secret, a court may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8BD9C26842884A519BBE23F70C74D4A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>grant an injunction—</text> <clause id="H40AC7AF944C349EDBA1368F3D06A4E79"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to prevent any actual or threatened misappropriation described in paragraph (1) on such terms as the court deems reasonable, provided the order does not prevent a person from accepting an offer of employment under conditions that avoid actual or threatened misappropriation described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H736019670F194186AE6C7778841E7AE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if determined appropriate by the court, requiring affirmative actions to be taken to protect the trade secret; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H92E709A1EFE64AE6801829AA03BB4585"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in exceptional circumstances that render an injunction inequitable, that conditions future use of the trade secret upon payment of a reasonable royalty for no longer than the period of time for which such use could have been prohibited;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0897F9D25E9D4A508E3DDA4A95137AFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>award—</text> <clause id="H45D29CF5C76A47F39F5D2EBEC5A21F4C"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4E091FD17593498F82ED464345A7A8EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>damages for actual loss caused by the misappropriation of the trade secret; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H096F22F28A8E409ABB90615DB3D3D508" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>damages for any unjust enrichment caused by the misappropriation of the trade secret that is not addressed in computing damages for actual loss; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H5553B980AB024A518F761991F9D52475"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in lieu of damages measured by any other methods, the damages caused by the misappropriation measured by imposition of liability for a reasonable royalty for the misappropriator’s unauthorized disclosure or use of the trade secret;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97F484AFA21A45F994EF0EFE8F771BF4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the trade secret is willfully and maliciously misappropriated, award exemplary damages in an amount not more than 3 times the amount of the damages awarded under subparagraph (B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1604534C66054720881D8B7A6D848082"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if a claim of the misappropriation is made in bad faith, a motion to terminate an injunction is made or opposed in bad faith, or the trade secret was willfully and maliciously misappropriated, award reasonable attorney’s fees to the prevailing party.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5D5A378CBCA4ED3AEA322A7E8EED7D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>The district courts of the United States shall have original jurisdiction of civil actions brought under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1BD611823CF245A5B36C493B869326EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of limitations</header><text>A civil action under subsection (b) may not be commenced later than 5 years after the date on which the misappropriation with respect to which the action would relate is discovered or by the exercise of reasonable diligence should have been discovered. For purposes of this subsection, a continuing misappropriation constitutes a single claim of misappropriation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H307165CB56CF464393C453C4329B8A2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 1839 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB029A457076E469E989867FE93F83561"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7525B41F0BE64B7CAA0E762649DBB2A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0307D6ADF31E49DDAFD3246A57CA362C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H5DB3A6DC9AA04A06AB87D70543FA6228" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H36448DF77ADB4777A21F896D4C0E8503"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>misappropriation</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HF907B6F2C1F541F18250B23FE245D993"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acquisition of a trade secret of another by a person who knows or has reason to know that the trade secret was acquired by improper means; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H431E6527F8F04606B5CC21ABDCCB1FA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disclosure or use of a trade secret of another without express or implied consent by a person who—</text> <clause id="HE0D81F00CD4B4DAEBE7598E642698FBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>used improper means to acquire knowledge of the trade secret;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEA1949BB330241D89A95D4DB3E89BC92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at the time of disclosure or use, knew or had reason to know that the knowledge of the trade secret was—</text>
 <subclause id="H12A0AA3840714FC99EC50806B9A2933A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>derived from or through a person who had used improper means to acquire the trade secret;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5D17DAF13CE846039F9FFAC6D3880CD4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>acquired under circumstances giving rise to a duty to maintain the secrecy of the trade secret or limit the use of the trade secret; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1004D23C89994FC2B878288502CE76D1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>derived from or through a person who owed a duty to the person seeking relief to maintain the secrecy of the trade secret or limit the use of the trade secret; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H5A52E3C2A3CE4D03A32AC9C5F8C421D3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>before a material change of the position of the person, knew or had reason to know that—</text> <subclause id="H3645A434D9634377B13E47E01490E302"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the trade secret was a trade secret; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE5DD1EF9A5DA40888A6E22D39829007A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>knowledge of the trade secret had been acquired by accident or mistake;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2B8362DB4AC40F0BBE58305D2DB4F2E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>improper means</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03E9CA27B649407F9C1EC1214F8B34FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes theft, bribery, misrepresentation, breach or inducement of a breach of a duty to maintain secrecy, or espionage through electronic or other means; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B9F5E1E9ABA49619BC7B853DF88C62D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include reverse engineering or independent derivation; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H961A863CD0344313B86DC456D82CA52D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>Trademark Act of 1946</term> means the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes, approved July 5, 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1051">15 U.S.C. 1051 et seq.</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote> or the <quote>Lanham Act</quote>)</quote>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3782D2587EA48F5AC6D43AA6C841455"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions to prohibition</header><text>Section 1833 of title 18, United States Code, is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or create a private right of action for</quote> after <quote>prohibit</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE4F044389DFE44539AC52E06EAB44089"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H644DCEA41B2940D8A273FEB05558CEF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The section heading for section 1836 of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C63C7CE47134B92A6B61533AB3F7F1D" style="USC">
						<section id="H9AF4960601F44C70B060D584476CD478"><enum>1836.</enum><header>Civil proceedings</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AFE767B602B47E0A306C85DFABA45EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/90">chapter 90</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 1836 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H590555D7D1E04CE28406374BB21FF331" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">1836. Civil proceedings.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H060596A236344CD28966E4A9E438A79D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to any misappropriation of a trade secret (as defined in section 1839 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by this section) for which any act occurs on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC44289439F424E1485E31D28B88D0116"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in the amendments made by this section shall be construed to modify the rule of construction under section 1838 of title 18, United States Code, or to preempt any other provision of law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H09CCF78DFA024B7D810C380B2960A8CA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicability to other laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendments made by this section shall not be construed to be a law pertaining to intellectual property for purposes of any other Act of Congress.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2B03E74B85284FA2AF66077B1E39CE7C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on theft of trade secrets occurring abroad</header>
 <subsection id="H0641928155EA4B6BBFD00FC732882992"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB7BAA9DC8D5942719D58F56F41592072"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB70492F1203144D68AD45F3A8D575297"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign instrumentality, etc</header><text>The terms <quote>foreign instrumentality</quote>, <quote>foreign agent</quote>, and <quote>trade secret</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 1839 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAD23F038E27D4BCDA687CA7249FA4439"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> includes the District of Columbia and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48226AAB694C4292B2732A2D5C9B4A59"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States company</quote> means an organization organized under the laws of the United States or a State or political subdivision thereof.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4452B6B9EFBC49CDA0E9AFAD02DB4F5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Intellectual Property Enforcement Coordinator, the Director, and the heads of other appropriate agencies, shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and make publicly available on the Web site of the Department of Justice and disseminate to the public through such other means as the Attorney General may identify, a report on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H24260DEE55BF46DEAD72935C5A1059D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The scope and breadth of the theft of the trade secrets of United States companies occurring outside of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03827C4FA0CD426295C882F86CCB7E59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The extent to which theft of trade secrets occurring outside of the United States is sponsored by foreign governments, foreign instrumentalities, or foreign agents.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H858C6A3680634211BF54A8B9BCC14164"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The threat posed by theft of trade secrets occurring outside of the United States.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A78EDE983854D6386EC7CDB52CF8663"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The ability and limitations of trade secret owners to prevent the misappropriation of trade secrets outside of the United States, to enforce any judgment against foreign entities for theft of trade secrets, and to prevent imports based on theft of trade secrets overseas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C50F40FC2A24437B354F02133B402D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A breakdown of the trade secret protections afforded United States companies by each country that is a trading partner of the United States and enforcement efforts available and undertaken in each such country, including a list identifying specific countries where trade secret theft, laws, or enforcement is a significant problem for United States companies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D03FD7D18DB4F04B0D11F2C316DA21B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Instances of the Federal Government working with foreign countries to investigate, arrest, and prosecute entities and individuals involved in the theft of trade secrets outside of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3116418C4C604745809A235CF38873A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Specific progress made under trade agreements and treaties, including any new remedies enacted by foreign countries, to protect against theft of trade secrets of United States companies outside of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B84B39F00BF46C6A896C5D0BBBEAA7A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Recommendations of legislative and executive branch actions that may be undertaken to—</text> <subparagraph id="H46CA1D4E9E7E40248B5990139AD1D5A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce the threat of and economic impact caused by the theft of the trade secrets of United States companies occurring outside of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H150D22DD488A428B80DDF455FC0745F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educate United States companies regarding the threats to their trade secrets when taken outside of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D42111EF3D34EA78D2E4AB1F1DDBF7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide assistance to United States companies to reduce the risk of loss of their trade secrets when taken outside of the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ED52E3FB57745DDA51B8A192B05EE92"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide a mechanism for United States companies to confidentially or anonymously report the theft of trade secrets occurring outside of the United States.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD41C90099816487EAB4E2AA392FCD36A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H100A76D5E87C4073AFF7AE11CD184DEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>trade secret theft occurs in the United States and around the world;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H008447A17C854654A41DA8605377888C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>trade secret theft, wherever it occurs, harms the companies that own the trade secrets and the employees of the companies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFC5EB5355DB496EBF0F0EF2C4F6CEDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/90">chapter 90</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code (commonly known as the Economic Espionage Act of 1996), applies broadly to protect trade secrets from theft.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


