<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hjres" measure-number="24" measure-id="id114hjres24" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-21" update-date="2015-02-02">
<title>Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relating to the authority of Congress and the States to regulate political campaign contributions and expenditures, including independent expenditures.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hjres24v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-02-02">
<action-date>2015-01-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Constitutional Amendment</b></p> <p>Declares that nothing in the Constitution shall be construed to prohibit Congress or any state from imposing content-neutral limitations on contributions or expenditures used to refer to a federal election candidate, including contributions or expenditures made independently from a candidate or a candidate's campaign during any period Congress or the state may establish which is proximate to the date of the election in which the candidate is running.</p> <p>Declares that nothing contained in this article shall be construed to abridge the freedom of the press.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
