<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hjres" measure-number="93" measure-id="id114hjres93" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-10" update-date="2016-05-16">
<title>Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hjres93v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-16">
<action-date>2016-05-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Constitutional Amendment </b> <br> <br> This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment prohibiting total outlays for a fiscal year from exceeding total receipts or 18.5% of the economic output of the United States for the fiscal year. The prohibition excludes outlays for repayment of debt principal and receipts derived from borrowing. <br><br> The amendment requires a three-fourths roll call vote of each chamber of Congress to increase the public debt limit or revenue. </p> <p>It also requires the President to submit a balanced budget to Congress annually and specifies that the failure to do so will be considered an impeachable offense. <br> <br> Congress may waive these requirements when: (1) a declaration of war is in effect, or (2) the United States is engaged in a military conflict which causes an imminent and serious military threat to national security that has been declared by a joint resolution. Waivers must identify and be limited to the excess that is necessary for a year due to the identified military conflict.</p> <p><br> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
