<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hjres" measure-number="66" measure-id="id114hjres66" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-09" update-date="2015-09-11">
<title>Iran Accountability and Enforcement Resolution</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hjres66v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-11">
<action-date>2015-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iran Accountability and Enforcement Resolution</strong></p> <p>This resolution authorizes the President to use the U.S. Armed Forces against Iran if the President certifies to Congress that Iran is unable to demonstrate that it has not sought, developed, or acquired nuclear weapons in violation of its obligations under the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPA). </p> <p>It is U.S. policy that Iran must comply with its reaffirmation in the JCPA that it will never seek, develop, or acquire a nuclear weapon. </p> <p>Congress declares that this resolution is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution. </p> <p>Nothing in this resolution supersedes any requirement of the War Powers Resolution.</p> <p>The Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action means the agreement signed at Vienna July 14, 2015, by Iran and by China, France, Germany, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom, and the United States, with the High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, and all implementing materials and agreements related to the JCPA.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
