<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1879 IS: Interior Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1879</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve processes in the Department of the Interior, and for other purposes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Interior Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id90fac98c707e45a381507df29e639572"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="id7df7997662b245a7aaa21d4e86d808d4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The first sentence of section 19 of the Act of June 18, 1934 (commonly known as the <quote>Indian Reorganization Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/479">25 U.S.C. 479</external-xref>), is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="id0019b136075f436fbef7f0957ee757ee"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The term</quote> and inserting <quote>Effective beginning on June 18, 1934, the term</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7bce7491b2784bcf92e269fa2cea6996"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>any recognized Indian tribe now under Federal jurisdiction</quote> and inserting <quote>any federally recognized Indian tribe</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="ide5158686b309443d8cac1a35f1bb46ec"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retroactive protection</header><text>To the extent a trust acquisition by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to the Act of June 18, 1934 (commonly known as the <quote>Indian Reorganization Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/461">25 U.S.C. 461 et seq.</external-xref>), is subjected to a challenge based on whether an Indian tribe was federally recognized or under Federal jurisdiction on June 18, 1934, that acquisition is ratified and confirmed.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id2ec6f2282307493a859414c2b6963f92"><enum>3.</enum><header>Land acquisition applications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act of June 18, 1934 (commonly known as the <quote>Indian Reorganization Act</quote>), is amended by inserting after section 5 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/465">25 U.S.C. 465</external-xref>) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1DB3C4D6FCDA405A863801F83900D03A" style="OLC"> <section id="idf3e588c61a904ae19bf16cf3d02db0ff"><enum>5A.</enum><header>Land acquisition applications</header> <subsection id="id5cd722c149144163a81786e4af4f7c3d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="id6cc640a2bc9b4f9eb058aace46e80a6c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <term>applicant</term> means an Indian tribe or individual Indian (as defined in section 4 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)) who submits an application under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD4577525F33346C59ADE161E3557457A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The term <term>application</term> means an application submitted to the Department by an Indian tribe or individual Indian under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbe929350e50b4ff6beaabac50bf84337"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contiguous</header><text>The term <term>contiguous</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="idD3F52097133D411BAA2D97685FCDA50B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means 2 parcels of land having a common boundary, notwithstanding the existence of non-navigable waters or a public road or right-of-way; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id629C953D53B14509918217D64D3C4372"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes parcels that touch at a point.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3562ceff1a54617915d0bdd6318b191"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Contiguous jurisdiction</header><text>The term <term>contiguous jurisdiction</term> means any county, county equivalent, or Indian tribe with authority and control over the land contiguous to the land under consideration in an application.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7e5c5be39fd447d5b81ebc409570c56b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>County and county equivalent</header><text>The terms <term>county</term> and <term>county equivalent</term> mean the largest territorial division for local government within a State with the authority to enter into enforceable cooperative agreements with Indian tribes or individual Indians, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7f37ef4c26ee4533ad6f9f129b415342"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id49DA5C8D8C58471588B0F763DE27254D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Economic impact</header><text>The term <term>economic impact</term> means any anticipated costs associated with the development of or activity on the land under consideration in an application, including associated costs to a contiguous jurisdiction for utilities, public works, public safety, roads, maintenance, and other public service costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9427B9FCA6034A78AE3C5C7A8A336602"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Final decision</header><text>The term <term>final decision</term> means a decision that is final for the Department, as determined or defined by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id25dbdf67167e49b897973e45f6c057e4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id749c1a7437d04167a3c925b996ed0923"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id08B76D5D7D7C4A41A7056F70E84B30E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header> <paragraph id="idB8C4DD15BD9F457C9A4D7A9272328002"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An Indian tribe or individual Indian seeking to have off-reservation fee or restricted land taken into trust for the benefit of that Indian tribe or individual Indian shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as this section and the Secretary require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2FB0913DD03C4F419115E9907386213F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary may approve complete applications described in paragraph (1) on a discretionary basis, subject to the condition that the application includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2AD086C06141466A9A4A5E6A9EA456FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a written request for approval of a trust acquisition by the United States for the benefit of the applicant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCEA3CB7C97D24463860899A12691C294"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the legal name of the applicant, including, in the case of an applicant that is an Indian tribe, the tribal name of the applicant as the name appears in the list of recognized Indian tribes published by the Secretary in the Federal Register pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/479a-1">25 U.S.C. 479a–1</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9A9A7F831CE8495C9372CF3E216390CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a legal description of the land to be acquired;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE0E968FB443C4E23A8AA5A4FFE7EB3E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the need for the proposed acquisition of the property;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEC024B014DA7412F83A235B84A8B2D38"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the purpose for which the property is to be used;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5B58DB42234845E89E3C53BA020415BA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a legal instrument to verify current ownership, such as a deed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3E2FDFC09C494811AB1E35B37A611642"><enum>(G)</enum><text>statutory authority for the proposed acquisition of the property;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8D2CBDF1F6EE4596BEA6CF84EB1FBF16"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a business plan for management of the land to be acquired, if the application is for business purposes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7EBE1712D5B34F32B2F548C03EB84516"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the location of the land to be acquired relative to State and reservation boundaries; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69C9408E025345D78FC8CDF14B6DEE03"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a copy of any cooperative agreement between the applicant and a contiguous jurisdiction.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6EAB2174A9F94CDCB2AE0A7B5FB47D84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final decision</header><text>After considering an application described in this subsection and in accordance with subsection (c) and any other applicable Federal law or regulation, a final decision to approve or deny the completed application shall be issued.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5de49e0cc9d24aa791470074d8091bf2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Statutory notice and comment requirements</header>
						<paragraph id="id1efcc175fdbc4562a3a3bed409b3e7c6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice and comment requirements for initial applications</header>
							<subparagraph id="id6d56f30d41234135903f87985feed972"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <clause id="id1dcaaa44f984414d8b90f2cfe9ac3c95"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives an initial application, the Secretary shall make that application, whether complete or incomplete, available to the public on the website of the Department, subject to applicable Federal privacy laws.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9a84c5b3bde142f8a442bef9bc5cf5de"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional notice requirement</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives an initial application, the Secretary shall provide by certified mail notice of the application to contiguous jurisdictions.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05ecb26cf6874bb2a5fea46424a1f2ea"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Comment</header><text>Each contiguous jurisdiction notified under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall have not fewer than 30 days, beginning on the date that the contiguous jurisdiction receives the notice, to comment on that initial application.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ac9def87d9943c782d80a8e1c23a797"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice requirement for any application update, modification, or withdrawal</header>
 <subparagraph id="id862ef08257b94265a416048d8a6c7172"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If at any time an application is updated, modified, or withdrawn, not later than 5 days after the date on which the Secretary receives notice of that update, modification, or withdrawal, the Secretary shall make that information available to the public on the website of the Department, subject to any applicable Federal privacy laws.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3dd7addf72124cacbcd4053c6db99566"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>If an application has been updated or modified in any way, the notice described in subparagraph (A) shall include a description of the changes made and the updated or modified application, whether complete or incomplete, available on the website of the Department, subject to any applicable Federal privacy laws.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c109ffd6f85476a8a3a89fc7c52518c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice and comment requirements for completed applications</header>
							<subparagraph id="idfbc034dfb277421eac12d94d4a752392"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <clause id="idddb6291354a94806806d20fd480390c9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a completed application, the Secretary shall make that application available to the public on the website of the Department, subject to any applicable Federal privacy laws.</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide52ab7779bf9467fa42f894439546017"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional notice requirements</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a completed application, the Secretary shall provide by certified mail notice of the application to contiguous jurisdictions.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbfaf45d65b084f34b9e864b74731fe73"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Publication in federal register</header><text>Not later than 5 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a completed application, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the completed application.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18458565067245118cd3ec8a0e59729c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Comment</header><text>Contiguous jurisdictions shall have not fewer than 30 days, beginning on the date on which the contiguous jurisdiction receives notice under subparagraph (A)(ii), to comment on that completed application.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7100ad0432647fd9e4bcd95abbfa9bb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice of decision</header>
 <subparagraph id="id72b655fb43304285a9279b03a7066738"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 days after a final decision to approve or deny an application is issued, the Secretary shall issue a notice of decision and make the notice of decision available to the public on the website of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7d4057a199f4347b134989f0c1c097f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication in federal register</header><text>Not later than 5 days after a final decision to approve or deny an application is issued, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the notice of decision described in subparagraph (A).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc797db94c01a450c81162cb095ccbba3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Encouraging local cooperation</header>
 <paragraph id="ida1739b157ab14a7a9fd311ba6660f601"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage, but may not require, applicants to enter into cooperative agreements with contiguous jurisdictions.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="id09d74c4c49024ceb996438c95cec24a4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header>
 <subparagraph id="id23198EF3522045858F78A965EBD0CF0D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall give weight and preference to an application with a cooperative agreement described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddcaaba8ef518411e84665d9c55445d60"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms of agreement</header><text>A cooperative agreement described in paragraph (1) may include terms relating to mitigation, changes in land use, dispute resolution, fees, and other terms determined by the parties to be appropriate.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDAF8A7ACFDFB456FA273EE26E48015DC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Submission of cooperative agreement</header>
 <clause id="id0CC972E6350B48F8A3EA580D9C331ADE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an applicant submits to the Secretary a cooperative agreement or multiple cooperative agreements executed between the applicant and contiguous jurisdictions, the Secretary shall issue a final decision to approve or deny a complete application not later than—</text>
 <subclause id="id5B3D6A5E69FE42C886C79562E2350435"><enum>(I)</enum><text>60 days after the date of completion of the review process under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) described in clause (ii); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idEF905081323343098038C4821E83670D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if that review process is not applicable, 30 days after the date on which a complete application is received by the Secretary.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="ided918df514414f45bbd2efd68a2e397d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Timeline</header><text>Completion of the review process under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) described in clause (i) may refer to—</text>
 <subclause id="idEEEE5F1324A04D798F0C722C088519B8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the issuance of a categorical exclusion determination in accordance with section 6.204 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id7BF5B5D7984445A0A722CD39719487A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an environmental assessment finding of no significant impact in accordance with section 6.206 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idB422D6EFDD734BDF861DBC3D603A1E1F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the issuance of a record of decision in accordance with section 6.208 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id5fb00c43982742759ce7d038f1dfa33a"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Effect of failure to issue timely final decision</header><text>If the Secretary fails to issue a final decision by the date described in clause (i), the application shall be—</text>
 <subclause id="idBBD99E69A72A42EB8C6D8EC5E838E87E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>deemed approved on an automatic basis; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idD51151A8CAC441BABB92F4735A971F27"><enum>(II)</enum><text>treated as a final decision.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69d071d43320410588102302a25385c1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Cooperative agreement not submitted</header>
 <clause id="idBCC084D3C2164424BA1D8281F39DA33F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an applicant does not submit to the Secretary a cooperative agreement executed between the applicant and contiguous jurisdictions, the Secretary shall issue a written determination of mitigation by the date that is not later than 30 days after a complete application is received by the Secretary, which shall—</text>
 <subclause id="id9407CE6674A044E2BE77A3F491F2C063"><enum>(I)</enum><text>describe whether any economic impacts on contiguous jurisdictions have been mitigated to the extent practicable; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id7F5DE34705CD48FF978C50E325D22502"><enum>(II)</enum><text>explain the basis of that determination.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="idbd7ba39afc434ea39ee00b1bbc7ff72e"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination of mitigation</header><text>The Secretary shall consider a determination of mitigation in making a final decision to approve or deny an application, but that determination shall not halt or unduly delay the regular processing of an application.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb17ba4a2b8924f5da7e2ec3e0996e625"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making a determination of mitigation described in clause (i), the Secretary shall take into consideration—</text>
 <subclause id="id03ac679091894df997de38c109f8ee19"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the anticipated economic impact of approving an application on contiguous jurisdictions; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idc1ca144e793c421d8c76c17a392ff772"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether the absence of a cooperative agreement is attributable to the failure of any contiguous jurisdiction to work in good faith to reach an agreement with the applicant.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="ide1e3a86d020f490ebcce79f36a3b8d45"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary shall provide by certified mail a copy of the determination of mitigation described in clause (i) to the applicant and contiguous jurisdictions not less than 5 days after a determination of mitigation is issued.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id99d2c5124a70473b8f70ff680471d1ad"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Good faith protection</header><text>Failure to submit a cooperative agreement shall not prejudice an application if the Secretary determines that the failure to submit is attributable to the failure of any contiguous jurisdiction to work in good faith to reach an agreement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id42ac7ee1e6f54258b9e21a987a94dadf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reciprocal notice and comment</header><text>The Secretary shall also encourage contiguous jurisdictions to engage in local cooperation through reciprocal notice and comment procedures, particularly with regard to changes in land use.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id46b36c1102834730998c4fb0cf853371"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation</header>
 <paragraph id="idE987B2C06EFD45AB8CDBD9E3724BFB19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall initiate consultation with Indian tribes regarding the implementation of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2A91BC782D07476C95E4E3FF0AFC64CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Summary</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the consultation described in paragraph (1) is initiated, the Secretary shall issue a summary of the consultation and the summary shall be published in the Federal Register.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6EAC1156592841C5813B373894CCDE0E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the summary described in paragraph (2) is published in the Federal Register, the Secretary shall, through a rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, modify existing regulations, guidance, rules, and policy statements, as necessary to carry out this section.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8c2e030b1d3c4017af855c0947877a8e"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Judicial review</header>
 <paragraph id="idbc0685c40b14473f9dc54e29b824c264"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An applicant or contiguous jurisdiction may seek review of a final decision.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id869adb7a1f4a4ef2a346b635602b57dc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative review</header><text>An applicant or contiguous jurisdiction may seek review in a United States district court only after exhausting all available administrative remedies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="idfd90ea70d8094d549a645306517acee2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effect</header>
 <subsection id="idc394d3c8a0ac4936bbc727a1e967ece3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Other land determinations</header><text>Nothing in this Act (or an amendment made by this Act) impacts any other Federal Indian land determination.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ida48be46841864e75898cb7a69b459166"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header>
 <text>Nothing in this Act (or the amendments made by this Act) affects—</text> <paragraph id="id5dff4ba119d74fb785f61d379d710048"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the application or effect of any Federal law other than the Act of June 18, 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/461">25 U.S.C. 461 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2769da91073c456ebf7fdd717e0cd7db"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any limitation on the authority of the Secretary of the Interior under any Federal law or regulation other than the Act of June 18, 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/461">25 U.S.C. 461 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


