<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="private"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1092 IS: For the relief of Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, and Arthur Mkoyan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">VI</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1092</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150427">April 27, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>For the relief of Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, and Arthur Mkoyan.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="ID0A51D7415BF344E38A0EA43A530FDC0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Permanent resident status for
			 Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, and Arthur Mkoyan</header>
			<subsection id="ID4F8E778C5D7E46EE8D0BE859E7B8371E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of section 201 of the <act-name parsable-cite="INA">Immigration and Nationality Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>), Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, and Arthur Mkoyan shall each be eligible for the issuance of an immigrant visa or for adjustment of status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence upon filing an application for issuance of an immigrant visa under section 204 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref>) or for adjustment of status to lawful permanent resident.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ID484036A1856B4B79B08AE0AB662B151D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment of
 status</header><text>If Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, or Arthur Mkoyan enters the United States before the filing deadline specified in subsection (c), Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, or Arthur Mkoyan, as appropriate, shall be considered to have entered and remained lawfully in the United States and shall be eligible for adjustment of status under section 245 of the <act-name parsable-cite="INA">Immigration and Nationality Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>) as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ID600E241F44CB4B12B2C43AF3C7F5E4DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application and
 payment of fees</header><text>Subsections (a) and (b) shall apply only if the application for the issuance of an immigrant visa or the application for adjustment of status is filed with appropriate fees not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ID3AE204551DB2419FBB2F8E316AF5A6F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reduction of
 immigrant visa numbers</header><text>Upon granting an immigrant visa or permanent resident status to Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, and Arthur Mkoyan, the Secretary of State shall instruct the proper officer to reduce by 3, during the current or subsequent fiscal year, the total number of immigrant visas that are made available to natives of the country of birth of Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, and Arthur Mkoyan under section 203(a) of the <act-name parsable-cite="INA">Immigration and Nationality Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>) or, if applicable, the total number of immigrant visas that are made available to natives of the country of birth of Ruben Mkoian, Asmik Karapetian, and Arthur Mkoyan under section 202(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1152">8 U.S.C. 1152(e)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ID9601a209219144eaaad6fea8e72b6f82"><enum>(e)</enum><header>PAYGO</header><text>The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the Senate Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


