<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1454 IS: Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To enhance interstate commerce by creating a National Hiring Standard for Motor Carriers.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0565A04706D54389B98AE34F7461AE1C" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAA4D798289744C91878458E4CC6E10BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id3EBD6354AE524030A22FF2D848980B04" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD2A183463A194BCAA542036C5987E3C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>entity</term> means a person acting as—</text> <subparagraph id="id8159044E43314496B1AB99B6399F3A7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a shipper or a consignee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94C0489B6A62439697850DD0E1D10FF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a broker, a freight forwarder, or a household goods freight forwarder (as such terms are defined in section 13102 of title 49, United States Code);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA3617E97787446A480666352AF1D805C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a non-vessel-operating common carrier, an ocean freight forwarder, or an ocean transportation intermediary (as such terms are defined in section 40102 of title 46, United States Code);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB8E948542322455FA9F091625BEF82C4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an indirect air carrier authorized to operate under a Standard Security Program approved by the Transportation Security Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id457D04AEDACA450FB50AF1250FD1D542"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a customs broker licensed in accordance with section 111.2 of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06311B7206D742B9B161557BBCA36B17"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an interchange motor carrier subject to paragraphs (1)(B) and (2) of section 13902(i); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61AA5CD574994AE7ACC3DC56DD119D0E"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a warehouse (as defined in Article 7–102(13) of the Uniform Commercial Code).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5F909A2CCEC4AA080B1628F6CE9A0AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Motor carrier</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>motor carrier</term> means a motor carrier or a household goods motor carrier (as such terms are defined in section 13102 of title 49, United States Code) that is subject to Federal motor carrier financial responsibility and safety regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03BFE9C1024241B1900EAA3E9DBC322A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, a political subdivision of any such State, any intrastate agency, any other political agency of 2 or more States, the District of Columbia, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idC484481CE6254D96850D20A1D6DCA38D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>National hiring standards for motor carriers</header>
 <subsection id="id8F95B2B95D554BFE9F111A99AF6C2FBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before tendering a shipment, but not more than 35 days before the pickup of a shipment by the hired motor carrier, an entity shall verify that the motor carrier, at the time of such verification—</text>
 <paragraph id="id75A59CB5687B4F52A4F2528B7AA693C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is registered with and authorized by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration to operate as a motor carrier or household goods motor carrier, if applicable;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id609DB0AB855442278F82A624BFF46D9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the minimum insurance coverage required by Federal law; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9401128ECBFF4ADEAFB8AB0FA72135AC"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idE534476106724EB5BC6005866EB84A04"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before the safety fitness regulations are issued pursuant to subsection (c), does not have an unsatisfactory safety fitness rating issued by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration in force at the time of such verification; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBB316A07459D4FE689AD44B9ABA9F4D6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after the safety fitness regulations are issued pursuant to subsection (c), does not have a safety fitness rating issued by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration under such regulations that is the equivalent of the unsatisfactory fitness rating referred to in subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1926f99df97b4ed28e4f054a72bf2c90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Intended use of data</header>
 <paragraph id="id41B63AB9E133499390A1A95208AC143E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Only evidence of an entity’s compliance with subsection (a) may be admitted as evidence or otherwise used in a civil action for damages resulting from a claim of negligent selection or retention of such motor carrier against the entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE0102ACC43364A21AA22072BF4E1D655"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excluded evidence</header><text>All other motor carrier data created or maintained by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration including safety measurement system data or analysis of such data, may not be admitted into evidence in a case or proceeding in which it is asserted or alleged that an entity’s selection or retention of a motor carrier was negligent.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1e8588f9f02b49ff98186729860d8bab"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header>
 <paragraph id="idA4F54B47E8A4473681BCA1340035F3A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall promulgate safety fitness determination regulations that update and revise the standards for establishing an unsatisfactory safety rating for motor carriers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2E2A563176B04174945C0CE6B98A79C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors for an unsatisfactory rating</header><text>In the regulations promulgated pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall determine if a motor carrier is not fit to operate a commercial motor vehicle in or affecting interstate commerce in accordance with section 31144 of title 49, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id28FF07546E7541BC90CACEE02932F60B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance with all safety laws</header><text>All commercial carriers shall comply with all applicable Federal laws pertaining to safety.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H1D6029A55C0A41F29C6D9AAC7F65E8F8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Applicability and effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, this Act shall apply with respect to any action commenced on or after the date of the enactment of this Act without regard to whether the harm that is the subject of the action, or the conduct that caused the harm, occurred before such date of enactment.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


