<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S377 IS: Medicare Ambulance Access, Fraud Prevention, and Reform Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 377</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150204">February 4, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to increase access to ambulance services under the
			 Medicare program and to reform payments for such services under such
 program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H88762CFBE98F47AFB3917FC6299C8746" style="OLC"><section id="H0726362C47CC496F8732A952D93BA5E8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><subsection id="H4420C51C92614AA590D85FECDA03DA40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Ambulance Access, Fraud Prevention, and Reform Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9FEB2F44837D462FA519E98FE0B01D52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="H0726362C47CC496F8732A952D93BA5E8" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD8AE881A541C4BFABF9D6DBFFD81E979" level="section">Sec. 2. Reform to the Medicare ambulance fee schedule.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF16C5994D9CA4CEE8814AF5B8E54626D" level="section">Sec. 3. Prior authorization for ambulance transports of ESRD beneficiaries.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9C805C039E8F4E6485C404BBE3425706" level="section">Sec. 4. Requiring ambulance providers to submit cost and other information.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HD8AE881A541C4BFABF9D6DBFFD81E979"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reform to the Medicare ambulance fee schedule</header><subsection commented="no" id="H39278A3D1E724758AD3F11B4779232AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)</external-xref>) is amended by adding the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0F2A233C66146989DDEF7E513FB6BBC" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="H592280A122884C6BBFCAEFCC910375A1"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Increase in conversion factor for ground ambulance services</header><text>In the case of ground ambulance services furnished on or after April 1, 2015, for purposes of determining the fee schedule amount for such services under this subsection, the conversion factor otherwise applicable to such services shall be increased by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBD077927E76A476C88C78B40D6212B42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to ground ambulance services for which the transportation originates in a qualified rural area, as identified using the methodology described in paragraph (12)(B)(iii), 25.6 percent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7A18971A964A49A88914F7C41882863E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to ground ambulance services not described in subparagraph (A) and for which the transportation originates in a rural area described under paragraph (9) or in a rural census tract described in such paragraph, 3 percent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H00BD625AEE534380A17327DC10C8051E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to ground ambulance services not described in subparagraph (A) or (B), 2 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFE91F25EE36C4FCF8C5B956AE6090A8D"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Increase in mileage rate for ground ambulance services</header><text>In the case of ground ambulance services furnished on or after April 1, 2015, for purposes of determining the fee schedule amount for such services under this subsection, the payment rate for mileage otherwise applicable to such services shall be increased by—</text><subparagraph id="H6CE97A1F51D247DCAEAA3CD41661CE5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to ground ambulance services for which the transportation originates in a qualified rural area, as identified using the methodology described in paragraph (12)(B)(iii), 3 percent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H612B593FA220488AB1E65986E08DBA7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to ground ambulance services not described in subparagraph (A) and for which the transportation originates in a rural area described under paragraph (9) or in a rural census tract described in such paragraph, 3 percent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80C9B001D2F84346A2334B8BCFDEE8AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to ground ambulance services not described in subparagraph (A) or (B), 2 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4DEA454A345B4F53BC6E8B2B54DC6AA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H65DA97AC8F014E2FB600C3316715BDE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a study on how the conversion factor applicable to ground ambulance services under the ambulance fee schedule under section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)</external-xref>), as adjusted under paragraph (16) of such section (as added by subsection (a)), should be modified, if at all, to take into account the cost of providing services in urban, rural, and super-rural areas. In determining such costs, the Secretary shall use the data collected through the data collection system under paragraph (18) of such section, as added by section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3967AFB8EF3E4788ACC9D8AE01DD3B62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2020, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF16C5994D9CA4CEE8814AF5B8E54626D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prior authorization for ambulance transports of ESRD beneficiaries</header><subsection id="HD5A0085F954848B88D408574FB5FC3EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D14AA3C80074FF3B3AE939458FD9F2C" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HA7071B3A8D8C43D88067A6376ACD31F0"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Prior authorization of coverage for ambulance transports of ESRD beneficiaries</header><subparagraph id="H4DCC776A62404BE3893EF7ED3005328D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Process</header><clause id="HB9B19452FACF4E2FB2F5C9691B4E118C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For applicable ESRD ambulance services furnished on or after January 1, 2017, by an applicable ambulance provider, the Secretary shall establish and implement a process under which the Secretary shall determine, in advance of furnishing such a service to an individual, whether payment for such service may not be made because such service is not covered or because of the application of section 1862(a)(1).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED917340D3C54BA8B23F9C0172CDD61E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Denial of payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B)(ii)(II), no payment shall be made under this part for the service unless the Secretary determines pursuant to such process that the service meets the applicable requirements for coverage.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6F0E87B0B57407CAE0CD9409D0DCC14"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements of process</header><text>The process described in subparagraph (A) shall include the following elements:</text><clause id="H112FB7149A2148B5B2BE87588BBF205D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In order to obtain a prior authorization, the applicable ambulance provider shall submit—</text><subclause id="HAE2164795F2442959EBD36681C82D460"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a valid physician certification statement (PCS) for non-emergency ambulance transport; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H69897CC81D914E6E87AE6E9DB4C3ED12"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other documentation determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF834C199289B49B9B51D16A09D1FE4B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD9DD9A0CD4984EAE88730070CE38C0A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Secretary shall respond to a prior authorization request within 7 business days of receiving the request.</text></subclause><subclause id="H7464E813698444249E78F84FF3E1757A" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>If the Secretary does not make a prior authorization determination within 7 business days of the date of the Secretary's receipt of medical documentation needed to make such determination, subparagraph (A)(ii) shall not apply.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7FB352448CCB44D9A39E18CAE2806697"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In making the determination under subparagraph (A) with respect to a service and individual, the Secretary shall evaluate the medical necessity of the service by determining—</text><subclause id="HE19288BA18B640578ACF69A4F6DAAEEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the individual is unable to get up from bed without assistance, unable to ambulate, and unable to sit in a chair or wheelchair;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFA4784CC357B4FCF8172312E04236A1C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether the individual has a medical condition that, regardless of bed confinement, is such that transport by ambulance is medically necessary; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H7D4068BC07AF48719C4CC50F9268129A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whether the individual meets other criteria as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5DB00C3D6E314E4FA168CD93E6C68D21"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>If the prior authorization request is approved, such request shall be retroactive to the date on which such request was received.</text></clause><clause id="H412ADEDBAAD145FDB307C6DA528FE282"><enum>(v)</enum><text>An approved prior authorization shall be valid for a 60-day period. The Secretary may provide for an extension of such period if the Secretary determines such an extension is appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="H8380DC05690F45DE8FFE1FBE7C0954B0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>An approved prior authorization shall be deemed to constitute medical necessity but shall not eliminate the documentation requirements necessary to support a claim for the transport.</text></clause><clause id="HCB45215BEC144107BC587620AF8EC769"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Other elements determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC660FABF0B1641FD87A0CC796AE1A89F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reliance upon contractors</header><text>The Secretary may rely upon contractors to implement the requirements of this paragraph. The contractor’s compensation shall be limited to a demonstration that it has reduced the number of non-emergency basic life support services involving individuals with end-stage renal disease for renal dialysis services (as described in section 1881(b)(14)(B)) furnished other than on an emergency basis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A8A9931AFE34C12AFD995062EB3EBB6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Applicable ESRD ambulance services</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>applicable ESRD ambulance services</term> means ambulance services consisting of non-emergency basic life support services involving transport of an individual with end-stage renal disease for renal dialysis services (as described in section 1881(b)(14)(B)) furnished other than on an emergency basis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B2750503C104495B65DD7545381AC81"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Ambulance provider; applicable ambulance provider defined</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="HCA4C2AA4BC86410EBD2923740A8343EF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Ambulance provider</header><text>The term <term>ambulance provider</term> means a provider of services (as defined in section 1861(u)) or other entity that furnishes ambulance services under this title.</text></clause><clause id="HEC2BCC23B38448D48DD5AEA662F916C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicable ambulance provider</header><text>The term <term>applicable ambulance provider</term> means an ambulance provider (other than an ambulance provider who is a provider of services (as defined in such section)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5FA730006A24DF490C7867EA958A58F"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Implementation</header><clause id="HDB8AFF8458754F9D9FFFCA9E6A657272"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the Secretary may carry out this paragraph through program instruction or otherwise.</text></clause><clause id="H9E1A13656A7F4B928971D8AB08DAF6CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Sufficient notice to prepare</header><text>Not later than June 30, 2016, the Secretary shall make the aspects of the process under this paragraph available to the public.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5F6BF01BB2D9471EA23699EBBEFC9220"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7F2C80FD735D41A684D8C38941C39AB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a supplier or provider or under arrangement with a provider</quote> and inserting <quote>an ambulance provider (as defined in paragraph (18)(E)(i)) or under arrangement with an ambulance provider</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB752726BEA7C4572A8A8D1A3A89A80B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), in the matter following subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>provider or supplier of ambulance services</quote> and inserting <quote>ambulance provider (as defined in paragraph (18)(E)(i))</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40D324E653614E8A86297B1C4742E019"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">ambulance</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">rural</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF712C6CC4CC4011A4F39CBF0BBD334E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">ambulance</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">rural</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75A00261E304412BA81AB3E25155D895"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in each of subparagraphs (B)(ii) and (D)(ii) of paragraph (14), by striking <quote>entity</quote> and inserting <quote>ambulance provider (as defined in paragraph (18)(E)(i))</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9C805C039E8F4E6485C404BBE3425706"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requiring ambulance providers to submit cost and other information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0ACEEE9A244F491A9938B422DD484C46" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H9458EBD582EB458FB555A372A9E3A26C"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Submission of cost and other information</header><subparagraph id="H3BBDA8D0D7D243DABC4249BB801696A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Development of data collection system</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a data collection system (which may include use of a cost survey and standardized definitions) for ambulance providers to collect cost, revenue, utilization, and other information determined appropriate by the Secretary. Such system shall be designed to submit information—</text><clause id="HE28AEFCD102B41D08F6797F2A9DC3961"><enum>(i)</enum><text>needed to evaluate the appropriateness of payment rates under this subsection;</text></clause><clause id="H88B7EE51438841449808109A2A8D07EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on the utilization of capital equipment and ambulance capacity; and</text></clause><clause id="HBA565BDC763748DA99C37D1B728E6A1F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on different types of ambulance services furnished in different geographic locations, including rural areas and low population density areas described in paragraph (12).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB6783C782334620AF5692518BB3E075"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specification of data collection system</header><clause id="HB41065755CB54D14BBAB1E1758F0E631"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2016, the Secretary shall—</text><subclause id="H7BC1057F60304B01A3C7EB93C2D145B9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>specify the data collection system under subparagraph (A) and the time period during which such data is required to be submitted; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H94428B91BF914E08A224F283EE28BCD6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identify the ambulance providers who would be required to submit the information under such data collection system.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD5BFA8095D634902A7B2B695DE0EBDFC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Respondents</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (D)(ii), the Secretary shall determine an appropriate sample of ambulance providers to submit information under the data collection system for each period for which reporting of data is required.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H736997416F5445EDBADBB499BD0CB0F9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Penalty for failure to report cost and other information</header><text>Beginning on July 1, 2017, a 5-percent reduction to payments under this part shall be made for a 1-year prospective period specified by the Secretary to an ambulance provider who—</text><clause id="HA285815844704D1DBC7EBEFF2B6FBE43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is identified under subparagraph (B)(i)(II) or (D)(ii) as being required to submit the information under the data collection system; and</text></clause><clause id="HC31FF6D3484A47A19FCF042908CC73D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not submit such information during the period specified under subparagraph (B)(i)(I).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EB73F0AAA104AC4B65C316398B46759"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Ongoing data collection</header><clause id="H3DB4FAC65C0D4A7A873579A5226AE3EE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Revision of data collection system</header><text>The Secretary may, as determined appropriate, periodically revise the data collection system.</text></clause><clause id="H6A11BA06508045A2BDE12F21D9403CAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent data collection</header><subclause id="HBC068F33BDF84332836687E08903B825"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to continue to evaluate the appropriateness of payment rates under this subsection, the Secretary shall, for years after 2017 (but not less often than once every 3 years), require ambulance providers to submit information for a period the Secretary determines appropriate. The penalty described in subparagraph (C) shall apply to such subsequent data collection periods.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HA41CF0FE1EE74EB3A1BD26D13750A23A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Sample</header><text>For each period described in subclause (I), the Secretary shall determine an appropriate sample of ambulance providers to submit information under the data collection system for such period. In determining which ambulance providers would be required to submit information for such period, the Secretary may not require an ambulance provider who has already submitted information for a previous period to submit information for a subsequent period unless all of the ambulance providers who the Secretary determines are the same type as such ambulance provider have either submitted information or been penalized under subparagraph (C) for not doing so.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A16650850584C46826A7F7600A4A806"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with stakeholders in carrying out the development of the system and collection of information under this paragraph, including the activities described in subparagraphs (A) and (D). Such consultation shall include the use of requests for information and other mechanisms determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA3E0B04484345D794B01252F135F9B9"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Definition of ambulance provider</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>ambulance provider</term> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (18)(E)(i).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DD6967A3DCC48ADB730AFA95437A686"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Administration</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to the collection of information required under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEECD5427FEE4432BCA6D9D05D9741FC"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Limitations on review</header><text>There shall be no administrative or judicial review under section 1869, section 1878, or otherwise of the data collection system or identification of respondents under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8F2B32297CB47BD84B9E927C32FABA8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Funding for implementation</header><text>For purposes of carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide for the transfer, from the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund under section 1841, of $1,000,000 to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account for fiscal year 2016. Amounts transferred under this subparagraph shall remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


