<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1378 IS: Bonuses for Cost-Cutters Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1378</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150519">May 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S377">Mr. Gardner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To strengthen employee cost savings suggestions programs within the Federal Government.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bonuses for Cost-Cutters Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id8F974F923FAB40F4B3B922C8F27B10F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cost savings
			 enhancements</header>
			<subsection id="id50C0F58735D742A8ABDD5516814BAC8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 4512 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id72ACF334D86D400CB382B7B39811F1AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE8D680A57F494E5B9F3738C3297ADDF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or identification of surplus funds or unnecessary budget authority</quote> after <quote>mismanagement</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1781FB03F8CD4465A0C07A0B3BA397DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or identification</quote> after <quote>disclosure</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4E61E687649C4083B1F69682F1A0D323"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or identification</quote> after <quote>disclosure</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB457583AACFA41299159549CC8A53F55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE215EA97DA1E427294E3D409EAFD029D" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id2BBBDA0A494F4D22B81596790CEA9A33"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The Inspector General of an agency or other agency employee designated under subsection (b) shall refer to the Chief Financial Officer of the agency any potential surplus funds or unnecessary budget authority identified by an employee, along with any recommendations of the Inspector General or other agency employee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1B6902B24C9049F0A9429FF8402A52FA"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id54634B5D955B4EB397822D43262BF987"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the Chief Financial Officer of an agency determines that rescission of potential surplus funds or unnecessary budget authority identified by an employee would not hinder the effectiveness of the agency, except as provided in subsection (e), the head of the agency shall transfer the amount of the surplus funds or unnecessary budget authority from the applicable appropriations account to the general fund of the Treasury.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id88E28802B4434DA187E8CCA3531DA9EB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Title X of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/681">2 U.S.C. 681 et seq.</external-xref>) shall not apply to transfers under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDac25f7df0c814ec1a243c85ac87351b0" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any amounts transferred under paragraph (1) shall be deposited in the Treasury and used for deficit reduction, except that in the case of a fiscal year for which there is no Federal budget deficit, such amounts shall be used to reduce the Federal debt (in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury considers appropriate).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id425273D7D0FF41118FAF73DB30F93AB3"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id52BB38A51256419A9BD9BED2C2437617"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The head of an agency may retain not more than 10 percent of amounts to be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury under subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDF493C8252C64046A2093C86BBFFFC93" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Amounts retained by the head of an agency under paragraph (1) may be—</text> <subparagraph id="id21D4A08D0C55497A897A074FB0277736"><enum>(A)</enum><text>used for the purpose of paying a cash award under subsection (a) to 1 or more employees who identified the surplus funds or unnecessary budget authority; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0EE767618CE04FFCB952B038B14AB6F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent amounts remain after paying cash awards under subsection (a), transferred or reprogrammed for use by the agency, in accordance with any limitation on such a transfer or reprogramming under any other provision of law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID32179da5647f45ed84127c39a6a26cb5"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id61910360C88B45BBB9640D70AFDCD603"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The head of each agency shall submit to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management an annual report regarding—</text>
 <subparagraph id="IDe653f36a6c5047dba21ec97b86a79eae" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each disclosure of possible fraud, waste, or mismanagement or identification of potentially surplus funds or unnecessary budget authority by an employee of the agency determined by the agency to have merit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDa5815e09dae94e7eb7321ebe143531f4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total savings achieved through disclosures and identifications described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDc2cfd08fcc044a4ebb968b9e4d63befc" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number and amount of cash awards by the agency under subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDb03ee892caaa4de7a276e8b74492a7af" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4DA0D68F3A7949C0BCC873B1402ECDCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The head of each agency shall include the information described in paragraph (1) in each budget request of the agency submitted to the Office of Management and Budget as part of the preparation of the budget of the President submitted to Congress under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDadbdb4df30a74598b2e57b8a7c9b3b3e" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Government Accountability Office an annual report on Federal cost saving and awards based on the reports submitted under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID4177e92bad5f4f1499a642ce80e2643b"><enum>(g)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB686D699EC0545FEB5A4795B3EB36CB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that the cash award program of each agency complies with this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1314E3D990234F27B7545E972E901A0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress an annual certification indicating whether the cash award program of each agency complies with this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id01341A8788784ABF8CDB83D2D34F67F4"><enum>(h)</enum><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bonuses for Cost-Cutters Act of 2015</short-title>, and every 3 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the operation of the cost savings and awards program under this section, including any recommendations for legislative changes.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id35712F61A3874C27A62CDB2ECAFFCEE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Officers
			 eligible for cash awards</header>
				<paragraph id="id4682BD9C637547F4AC61180B0CA4C4E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 4509 of title 5, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB20151C0DD124A7BA6550FA240CB8033" style="USC">
						<section id="id421E829B284D40EB9DF8B09E56F31168"><enum>4509.</enum><header>Prohibition
				of cash award to certain officers</header>
 <subsection id="id78F47A7D540F49EFB7EA8BA92353B58A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the term <term>agency</term>—</text>
 <paragraph id="idCA35AE91BA254749B8FEACC04FA3611E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has the meaning given that term under section 551(1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id49A0A5C3C40643BC9D62AE6616989087"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes an entity described in section 4501(1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDF5068381DC046D18191A77A22C11578"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An officer may not receive a cash award under this subchapter if the officer—</text>
 <paragraph id="idE6369B448D2942B4BC63ED0E63143E04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serves in a position at level I of the Executive Schedule;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE6FFEAF2AEA145AEBBC3F5BFA80C78BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is the head of an agency; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idADEE4CAD16E549A1A83ECD0693C9D9A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is a commissioner, board member, or other voting member of an independent establishment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id49D2B73A14F7492DBF1CAD931B82596C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and
 conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/45">chapter 45</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 4509 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="id8a955292-e21d-44f7-8f96-e146fe06aa4a" style="USC"><toc><toc-entry idref="id421E829B284D40EB9DF8B09E56F31168" level="section">4509. Prohibition of cash award to certain
				officers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


