<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1485 IS: Water Efficiency Innovation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1485</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150602">June 2, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the advancement of energy-water efficiency research, development, and deployment
			 activities.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Efficiency Innovation Act of 2015</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="id822EA5146D164A99B242DF3EE08F94AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id4EF3E0ABAD1F4EBE86F469F4E70D2D5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Energy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC08FC0C2A3F34D61960D8B2D5F8FCC57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Industrial Assessment Center</header><text>The term <term>Industrial Assessment Center</term> means a center located at an institution of higher education that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id06f9cde416ad4af99cd04588109b838d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receives funding from the Department;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideed94b324edc45fdb24be807cf8cfbb2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides an in-depth assessment of small- and medium-sized manufacturer plant sites to evaluate the facilities, services, and manufacturing operations of the plant sites; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27808a306da94593a961fd21f87147e3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifies opportunities for potential savings for small- and medium-sized manufacturer plant sites from energy efficiency improvements, waste minimization, pollution prevention, and productivity improvement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA5B9D116435448838F6947AFF838501A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idf48b6996213041e495acfcd82039c779"><enum>3.</enum><header>Leveraging existing agency programs to advance energy-water efficiency</header> <subsection id="id8d8772e324874ae0ade618664740d159"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="idc7d2654c62fd42dd88db389103e72596"><enum>(1)</enum><text>through the Industrial Assessment Centers of the Department, the Department provides technical assistance to facilitate efficiency improvements at small- and medium-sized manufacturers while training engineering students for energy careers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6b723b24f13f43029419d3940e981ed7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the efficiency improvements described in paragraph (1) reduce energy demand, help manufacturers operate more competitively, and catalyze the use of new technologies and best practices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcc71ef79738346d385e0d7d19f1c772a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>water and wastewater treatment are energy-intensive processes, and opportunities for efficiency upgrades can be limited by technical expertise, particularly at small utilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5042d2b5ddcc42a0bea7e9a7cd8a22d8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>through the Industrial Assessment Centers of the Department, the Department has recently engaged with the Environmental Protection Agency in a pilot effort to target energy efficiency in water and wastewater treatment facilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7e88c58c25e84c329ae11601196d602a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall expand the Industrial Assessment Centers of the Department, working across Federal agencies as necessary—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3652546ae25f4707b40163622d34c7b0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide comparable assessment services to water and wastewater treatment facilities, including systems that treat municipal, industrial, and agricultural waste; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id088199f93982437babb41d8b6ff96bd0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to equip the Directors of the Industrial Assessment Centers with the training and tools necessary to provide technical assistance on energy savings to those facilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6AE886C64E5C422EAFB12EC3D799FA30"><enum>4.</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out this Act using unobligated funds of the Department.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

