<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1628 IS: To preserve the current amount of basic allowance for housing for certain married members of the uniformed services.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1628</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150618">June 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To preserve the current amount of basic allowance for housing for certain married members of the
			 uniformed services.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id6FCF64107B25412797497CBFBBC16035" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Preservation of current basic allowance for housing for certain married members of the uniformed
 services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, the amount of basic allowance for housing payable under section 403 of title 37, United States Code, as of September 30, 2015, to a member of the uniformed services who is married to another member of the uniformed services shall not be reduced unless—</text>
 <paragraph id="id20F71B2129DF4AD3805812533158F604"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the member and the member's spouse undergo a permanent change of station requiring a change of residence; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id90BAE7DD96EB4494A7A54247E859A739"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the member and the member's spouse move into or commence living in on-base housing.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

