<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1891 IS: Coal Royalty Fairness Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1891</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to improve coal royalties, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id8D56609708BB40FAA8292ACADE2C6B43" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coal Royalty Fairness Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id30F829E67E66495AA1B6E5E3D7B30DD4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Valuation of coal royalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/207">30 U.S.C. 207</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id65697AA5B08B42208D8D3B7DE8FDEA37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking the fourth sentence; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id137B2A9080FE44DA8EEFAC87FF1073C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45F2878E019A41AABCF5A137257220FE" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="id1E10C4CB085448B99B9E145ACDFC6457"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Royalties</header>
 <paragraph id="id05E820894D4C4AD7BC75DBBC2A7DB3BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="id6800dc60bd404a259668e110eb3bee07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assessment value</header> <clause id="idE582F089C048458087AA8520E99013F4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>assessment value</term>, with respect to Federal coal, means—</text>
 <subclause id="idF8BFFAE5EC8D46F5BD6DDD41914B98E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the price of Federal coal paid by the purchaser at final sale; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id76F4CB5B58B143DDA31C9B1B1E3DAD2C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a price imputed by the Secretary based on the coal price index.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id4BDE980F57564FB9B5FEC521B212DC13"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>assessment value</term> does not include, as determined and to the extent determined to be appropriate by the Secretary—</text>
 <subclause id="idA5428268C3AB44538B54BF857E9D167E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transportation costs, as determined in accordance with the transportation cost index; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id9E898144DCDE4602B6215D49F970BEC4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the cost of coal washing.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF92F23481CA54F9CAD816516C1592DDB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Broker</header><text>The term <term>broker</term> means a person that resells Federal coal.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34C0804B1CB94EECAE122F69A19DBB0A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Coal price index</header><text>The term <term>coal price index</term> means the schedule of average market prices of Federal coal (in United States dollars) paid by the purchaser at final sale, based on the quality and type of the Federal coal, as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87BEE4DC64F247049E20C8BA03750C26"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Purchaser</header>
 <clause id="id13AA518E345049889B47593666B33BF7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>purchaser</term> means a person that—</text> <subclause id="idBBC7A386B53D41E38C6DF2EA433E6220"><enum>(I)</enum><text>purchases or contracts to purchase Federal coal—</text>
 <item id="id674D67907A964D64980A33EDC31321CA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>directly from a coal mine operator; or</text> </item><item id="id0984A22BAF7F42829028BE30CE2726C5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>indirectly from a broker; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id78FA72DFE5574D03894AB336FCE8B5BD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>uses that Federal coal in any industrial or energy conversion process.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="idF5506A69AB534B24B5059453B684CAD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>purchaser</term> does not include—</text>
 <subclause id="id6FC6A3908DFB4AB2A10FF6AB76E1E117"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a coal broker; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id140130F3B9F04A4697AF93378C8A6C6B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other third-party intermediary.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE96303A21BCA4F069CF8F2CB0F5454B1"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Quality</header><text>The term <term>quality</term>, with respect to Federal coal, means the quality of Federal coal measured in British thermal units, sulfur, moisture, and other criteria determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5BE3AB6A2EF44521A74C72423BDFEB54"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF8840DA2EAD649BA9585855B6E765CEA"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Transportation cost index</header><text>The term <term>transportation cost index</term> means the transportation cost index established under paragraph (7).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0B64716AD1484F058C8689DCE43FC2BE"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Type</header><text>The term <term>type</term>, with respect to Federal coal, means a general category of coal, such as metallurgical coal or steam coal, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8809E0E054D6491B8DFA9C7822F656FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment rate</header>
 <subparagraph id="id415FA34FFCC64E269236B1A6BC47284F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a lease shall require payment of a royalty in such amount as the Secretary shall determine of not less than 12.5 percent of the assessment value of Federal coal, as determined under paragraph (3).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3BFDD3BE06B84435A089970A86F82C04"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In lieu of the royalty payment rate described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary may establish such lower royalty payment rate as the Secretary determines to be appropriate in the case of Federal coal recovered by an underground mining operation.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7BD1457E9D224961BD2F0761B06E0DE4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Valuation for royalties</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish, as the valuation for Federal coal royalties, the assessment value of Federal coal.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="idC9D66FC75F6C4BB4ABA0451E63B497A3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <subparagraph id="idCBA6F4EF9B614320ADCAACA7A7696C27"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The purchaser of Federal coal shall annually submit to the Secretary a report containing such information as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA0783A1B5254FFA83853BC9F63165CF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>To carry out this subsection, the Secretary may examine the records of any person engaged in the purchase, sale, transportation, or marketing of Federal coal.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0cb1999e1554c5a89ccb4cd99b3104d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coal price index</header>
 <subparagraph id="idb0fe09e4b92149ca84dd4a144016f4fd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall compile the assessment values of coal by type and quality of coal in a coal price index.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45a0743f13e0439ba69e4cbe692bc900"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not less frequently than quarterly, the Secretary shall publish the coal price index, along with a methodological description, including—</text>
 <clause id="idbb7f582d24be4803b327d9144d7deeee"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the method of calculation;</text> </clause><clause id="id4d9f1d3f513348908da8fb8e331fafd1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the data used to calculate the coal price index in an aggregate manner that does not reveal proprietary information; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id08a212417120450d931fb451adbf9a85"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary considers appropriate to ensure transparency.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id591b24cb82c54e4d9856ed2d4f18a026"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other information</header><text>If a person believes that the coal price index significantly deviates from the assessment value of the coal produced by the person, the person may petition the Secretary to use information supplied by the person in lieu of the coal price index, including all information the Secretary requires to accurately determine the assessment value and audit the records of the person.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38B412D98D9D45159CB66577F83B309C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exports</header>
 <subparagraph id="id8DC29B86ABC7458386F3D8CAE5D9170D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In assessing royalties for the export of Federal coal under this subsection, the Secretary may obtain from the exporter of the Federal coal such information as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id277570C54B294795B158C96C8DAB7F80"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment value of exported coal</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), in determining the assessment value of Federal coal that is exported, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="id3A1739B2DF8D4249AE06E8482B2CF0F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use the price of coal free on board the marine vessel used to transport the coal overseas at the port of origin; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idEA171B9315DB46948C89BF1CC7EC84D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>limit any deductions that apply to the assessment value of the Federal coal to costs incurred prior to being free onboard the vessel.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9CE03A0D3C6B4B6DA36400EE4CC8D88E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Uncertain export price</header><text>If the Secretary cannot determine the value of exported coal in accordance with subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="id4F7616BDF66347D9A941A422F0763436"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assess royalties under this subsection based on the coal price index for coal of a similar quantity and type; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6D4B534FA7FE41CFA2D71DF9139A6EDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>limit any deductions that apply to the assessment value of the Federal coal to costs incurred within the contiguous United States.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1898a8d87e7441b48b1895748a448988"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Transportation cost index</header>
 <subparagraph id="id8DE9AF7C65114FEEA7DCBF4857F30819"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the other provisions of this paragraph, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Transportation (in consultation with the Surface Transportation Board and others), shall—</text>
 <clause id="id417a25e77e8e46739f27c2991444c36a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>compile in a transportation cost index the average costs of transporting coal; and</text> </clause><clause id="id386BF2021A1D4D14885263D6F49E89D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determine the amount of any transportation cost deduction under this subsection, on the basis of the transportation cost index.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68dd6d13aa0d46b4a52c8881dfaf1f59"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unit of measurement</header><text>The transportation cost index shall be based on the average transportation costs per ton of coal or another unit of measurement determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b98b43e468642af818a5fb2ad5d4095"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Differences in transportation costs</header><text>The transportation cost index shall take into consideration differences in the costs of transportation, as determined by the Secretary, based on—</text>
 <clause id="ida2f06bc42ff24af2ae7e057703f1328d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the mode of transportation;</text> </clause><clause id="iddb512def89dc4a38b4b22f4a3f592924"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the geographic region, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2440411083874889bbcf32a71d424b85"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other characteristics of the transportation industry that the Secretary considers to be necessary to calculate a fair, transparent, and accurate transportation cost index.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22d29bfae0e94faa98a56089a0b19b5b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The transportation cost index shall not include costs associated with, as determined by the Secretary—</text>
 <clause id="idfb1bf06fc6964094937a5bc204dad7c8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take-or-pay contract penalties;</text> </clause><clause id="id9595b877d86d4fcf91574011181bd113"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>liquidated damages;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id119f8cf01d004c91bf06f2acadbb6607"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the speculative aspects of transportation transactions; or</text> </clause><clause id="idfb33af9eae80473885bd61f45a98772c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other costs that are not directly associated with moving Federal coal from 1 location to another location.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95a490c8209f401b8d828c5204f3a520"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not less than twice annually, the Secretary shall publish the transportation cost index, along with a methodological description, including—</text>
 <clause id="id866feb3ff7cd4f43b439640fae33cb53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the method of calculation;</text> </clause><clause id="id18e1feacaf9d4c73bbf9ed7d05308941"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the data used to calculate the transportation cost index, in an aggregate manner that does not reveal proprietary information; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida895ac1ad3354c02aec211a743571cb0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary considers to be appropriate to ensure transparency.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3dff8eae88884cdda041eb9c7bcfd185"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Other information</header><text>If a person believes that the transportation cost index significantly deviates from the transportation costs of the person, the person may petition the Secretary to use information supplied by the person (other than costs descried in subparagraph (D)) in lieu of the transportation cost index, including all information the Secretary requires to accurately determine cost and audit the records of the person.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFCF1BEDEA1A54E95B91AC3A34A48C10F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reviews</header>
 <subparagraph id="idD558964AE73C4C5E9E9F6FBF240E0E54"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure a transparent, fair, and efficient administration of the Federal coal program, and to ensure that citizens of the United States receive a fair return on Federal coal, not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this subsection and every 3 years thereafter during the 15-year period beginning on that date of enactment, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that describes a review of the Federal coal program, including the administration of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE2D47D9CC7294C14BB40C7A4978F8CF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting a review under this paragraph, the Comptroller General shall consult with—</text> <clause id="id6ED38720A6B244D4A6611E68A45F2ED7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC76B9264123F4BEB8C466EF97DBB66BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Land Management;</text> </clause><clause id="id8D448B391C314508907D45C324A9A846"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Secretary of Transportation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE7D7981BE3E24F3C8BBE900A877C8834"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf620460f9af146fab789122a406053a7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>A review under this paragraph shall include a review of—</text>
 <clause id="id18354e31c78b47d49e7f55531defa008"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total volume of coal production from Federal land;</text> </clause><clause id="ida146476d3878489eb3244f9c674573f5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total volume of remaining coal reserves on Federal land;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id960b44412f1b4c53921a6ddb55ce0269"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the total revenues generated from the Federal coal program, itemized by type of revenue, including lease bonus payments and royalties;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id087d30e068024ee6972df9ad4d605893"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>market prices for coal;</text> </clause><clause id="id056d50ab64684a8e8fb59905c1d8ec72"><enum>(v)</enum><text>market prices for transportation costs and any other deductible costs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbb70d92076e546cfa011f028080806dd"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the appropriateness of royalty rates.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4560879f8f6042cab8ca528eac657438"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Format</header><text>The Comptroller General shall report information in a review under this paragraph—</text>
 <clause id="id7343B2D9AEDF4EE3B838FDE1122C2FE9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the aggregate for the United States; and</text> </clause><clause id="id4B75BBDF3C934F6B923257DFB2F7DE09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>categorized by State for at least the top 10 Federal coal-producing States, as determined by the Comptroller General.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC15FE9C3DD8C46BE8A87765BC0F347F8"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id7E0D23F96AC043D4BEBD9D94594ACDE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>applies to coal mined from Federal land; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD8BE69590D534714926035323A9B8D97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not apply to coal mined from tribal land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

