<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2137 IS: To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide a period for the relocation of spouses and dependents of certain members of the Armed Forces undergoing a permanent change of station in order to ease and facilitate the relocation of military families.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2137</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151006">October 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide a period for the relocation of spouses and
			 dependents of certain
			 members of the Armed Forces undergoing a permanent
			 change of
			 station in order to ease and facilitate the relocation of military
			 families.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="idF4CD7911F946406AB4E7805414848380" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <term>Military Family Stability Act of 2015</term>.</text> </section><section id="id8A10ACB487A74C508AA59EF8FF4F13D0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Period for relocation of spouses and dependents of certain members of the Armed Forces undergoing a permanent change of station</header> <subsection id="id7504EA51BBE54CB5BDD873458B8AFC1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Period of relocation</header> <paragraph id="idD2A68920526E48168D04E05F645FF75D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/88">chapter 88</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1784a">section 1784a</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB31199BE14E3417D987CDCBE084FA7E2" style="USC">
						<section id="idF7058DF3355449D78004BE6795CA8F9F"><enum>1784b.</enum><header>Relocation of spouses and dependents in connection with the permanent change of station of
			 certain members</header>
							<subsection id="idE5015D6FC91E4679AB63A5C2149DDDCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Election of timing of relocation of spouses in connection with PCS</header>
 <paragraph id="id7D7353AC22E1498290E245ECBB11B761"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a member of the armed forces undergoing a permanent change of station and the member's spouse may jointly elect that the spouse may relocate to the location to which the member will relocate in connection with the permanent change of station at such time during the covered relocation period as the member and spouse jointly select.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id47F5223016464CE4926F707EFB9CB5DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members and spouses eligible to make elections</header><text>A member and spouse may make an election pursuant to paragraph (1) as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="idE63DFB7AD6BA499BA9762EF27E451E3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the spouse either—</text>
 <clause id="idA113243151F4456C806E9C40B716AC61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is gainfully employed at the beginning of the covered relocation period concerned; or</text> </clause><clause id="id5D188330D705416596E56D976E06ADAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is enrolled in a degree, certificate, or license granting program at the beginning of the covered relocation period.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57542BE8CB5545E490A716ABBB3D1E47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the member and spouse have one or more dependents at the beginning of the covered relocation period concerned, either—</text>
 <clause id="idFCEE15985D7648E4938FF8813843A452"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least one dependent is a child in elementary or secondary school at the beginning of the covered relocation period;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF4D51D5426314D56B15F0CF6B32D8F3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the spouse or at least one such dependent are covered by the Exceptional Family Member Program at the beginning of the covered relocation period; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idAB326BF2839E41B0AAA6931CF5CEEF07"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the member and spouse are caring at the beginning of the covered relocation period for an immediate family member with a chronic or long-term illness, as determined pursuant to the regulations applicable to the members' armed force pursuant to subsection (g).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0E78F54712044B00ACB2BDB3656B7B45"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the member is undergoing a permanent change of station as an individual augmentee or other deployment arrangement specified in the regulations applicable to the member's armed force pursuant to subsection (g).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7A8DA8EF711F4E32AD6F40E9CBC2958B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>If the member, spouse, or both, meet such other qualification or qualifications as are specified in the regulations applicable to the member's armed force pursuant to subsection (g).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id834329587A144CC69DED236125340164"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In the case of a member and spouse who do not otherwise meet any qualification in subparagraphs (A) through (D), if the commander of the member at the beginning of the covered relocation period determines that eligibility to make the election is in the interests of the member and spouse for family stability during the covered relocation period and in the interests of the armed force concerned. Any such determination shall be made on a case-by-case basis.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2160D55F162D45B78E40632C873D2A3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Election of timing of relocation of certain dependents of unmarried members in connection with PCS</header>
 <paragraph id="id1BBB76EC5B624566AFA31ACB5596B97B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the armed forces undergoing a permanent change of station who has one or more dependents described in paragraph (2) and is no longer married to the individual who is or was the parent (including parent by adoption) of such dependents at the beginning of the covered period of relocation may elect that such dependents may relocate to the location to which the member will relocate in connection with the permanent change of station at such time during the covered relocation period as elected as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5C39FE95E80648108D615277B32C18FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>By the member alone if such individual is dead or has no custodial rights in such dependents at the beginning of such period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94C0D6E78EE34F6491173B376433F1B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>By the member and such individual jointly in all other circumstances.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFA84E860F30349908701BD0545650CCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dependents</header><text>The dependents described in this paragraph are as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9B9E6A5EBCB14CECAA1C017B07AC1481"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Dependents over the age of 19 years for whom the member has power of attorney regarding residence.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBEAA0EFF00EA42A4BB826384D1DCBEFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Dependents under the age of 20 years who will reside with a caregiver according to the Family Care Plan of the member during the covered period of relocation until relocated pursuant to an election under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9EDCCDC27FBC4A888E97B0A93DFD8341"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Housing</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id206F68CDA4334061842F4423C68BA6FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the spouse of a member relocates before the member in accordance with an election pursuant to subsection (a), the member shall be assigned to quarters or other housing facilities of the United States as a bachelor, if such quarters are available, until the date of the member's permanent change of station.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8906922D39CA4F81A7E0D901D51B9108" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If a spouse and any dependents of a member covered by an election under this section reside in housing of the United States at the beginning of the covered period of relocation, the spouse and dependents may continue to reside in such housing throughout the covered period of relocation, regardless of the date of the member's permanent change of station.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC264FB72A4D04B3187B061834D0FCE3F" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If a spouse and any dependents of a member covered by an election under this section are eligible to reside in housing of the United States following the member's permanent change of station, the spouse and dependents may commence residing in such housing at any time during the covered relocation period, regardless of the date of the member's permanent change of station.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE7C2CCD73C6A4521AE4FC0B385E93E06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Basic allowance for housing; stipend</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id304C8EB8D28B4A8698B3E676B8B8A290"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id8E5987E57EF1485D83B7813A023F3B94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of a member undergoing a permanent change of station who is paid basic allowance for housing at the with dependents’ rate at the beginning of the covered relocation period, the member shall be paid basic allowance for housing at the with dependents’ rate for months beginning during the covered relocation period regardless of the date on which the member's spouse and any dependents relocate pursuant to an election under this section or the assignment of the member to quarters or facilities on a bachelor basis pursuant to subsection (c)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id536B5B9FAB4844C3A0114AFEAC6DF13E" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In determining the portion of basic allowance for housing payable to a member under this paragraph that is payable with respect to the member's dependents, the geographic location of the dependents shall govern rather than the geographic location of the member.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id342D4516D3CE46AD9C9E07A6E39CC40B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If quarters are not available for the assignment of a member as described in subsection (c)(1), the member shall be paid an amount (determined in accordance with the regulations applicable to the member's armed force pursuant to subsection (g)) appropriate to compensate the member for cost of the housing in which the member resides in lieu of such quarters until the date on which the member and the member's spouse reside in the same geographic area after the member's permanent change of station. Any amount payable to a member pursuant to this paragraph is in addition to amounts payable to the member under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9EB74A49715742C0BBB8BBD679206B7A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transportation of personal property</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3160033D3CD64B3B95D2CA61C590F272"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any transportation allowances authorized for the transportation of the personal property of a member and spouse making an election under subsection (a) may be allocated among the personal property of the member and spouse in such manner as the member and spouse shall select.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF30626DED4D54202910D11BF8655F9C5" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>transportation allowances</term> and <term>personal property</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 451(b) of title 37.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE1959030C246427D8DAE0912C7D8EF07"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Approval</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id46B1F5B76B854A5896B8CCEABF9F12D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a single approval process for applications for coverage under this section. The process shall apply uniformly among the armed forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id641265F778354AADAB58A8E156ADB03B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Applications for approval for coverage under this section shall consist of such elements (including documentary evidence) as the Secretary shall prescribe for purposes of the approval process required by this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8BE0780DF10C470AA7EB8B5DA95F7FF5" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The approval process required by this subsection shall ensure that the processing of applications for coverage under this section is completed in a timely manner that permits a spouse and any dependents to relocate whenever during the covered relocation period selected in the election concerned. In meeting that requirement, the approval process shall provide for the processing of applications at the lowest level in the chain of command of members as it appropriate to ensure proper administration of this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBC5CD463F8E64190B9A8B4FD912AE4A1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Each Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section with respect to the armed force or forces under the jurisdiction of such Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1F44F7108E9A425A8BFDBCA9B0A50DDC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Covered relocation period defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered relocation period</term>, in connection with the permanent change of station of a member, means the period that—</text> <paragraph id="idD5676F328729444F845C7FA8D6214BED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>begins 180 days before the date of the permanent change of station; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB3A7608C9BAA4E53ADDC36F58EA1DEEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ends 180 days after the date of the permanent change of station.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB948846749134DF5ADBEF4F2DD994EA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of subchapter I of chapter 88 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1784a the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="id3d40794b-ebcc-4323-991c-0a294b188e3f" style="USC"><toc><toc-entry idref="idF7058DF3355449D78004BE6795CA8F9F" level="section">1784b. Relocation of spouses and dependents in connection with the permanent change of
			 station of certain members.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6381496CB75D4CED90E39B63E653C67C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to permanent changes of station of members of the Armed Forces that occur on or after the date that is 180 days after such effective date.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id39DC18E54DA74C6EAE30C6396185BF78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comptroller General of the United States report</header>
 <paragraph id="idD6E1383C9BCD432DAD3CE7B08DD0BB38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on potential actions of the Department of Defense to enhance the stability of military families undergoing a permanent change of station.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id01FC326330614EF582607DE4E5B62D29"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id77372F7811FE40AAB7EA47CD80BBDAC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A comparison of the current percentage of spouses in military families who work with the percentage of spouses in military families who worked in the recent past, and an assessment of the impact of the change in such percentage on military families.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id992b82aded1841878774fdfce371d162"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the effects of relocation of military families undergoing a permanent change of station on the employment, education, and licensure of spouses of military families.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86b4c65529cd4506a30dff3e648f4298"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the effects of relocation of military families undergoing a permanent change of station on military children, including effect on their mental health.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9E0DA1E8ABDC47659AAA8BB731529EEF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An identification of potential actions of the Department to enhance the stability of military families undergoing a permanent change of station and to generate cost savings in connection with such changes of station.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7964EF933D9D47C4A4588A97ADA85476"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other matters as the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

