<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1448 IS: Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary Designation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1448</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To designate the Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary in the State of Oregon.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary Designation Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idED97E6DDB8FD4B18B9C4059997BEE874"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id0bca081707cd43daa4bd374d2cde8890"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Frank Moore has committed his life to family, friends, his country, and fly fishing;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6042919495cc49b1bf567988412f096e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Frank Moore is a World War II veteran who stormed the beaches of Normandy along with 150,000 troops during the D-Day Allied invasion and was awarded the Chevalier of the French Legion of Honor for his bravery;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf94455e251a24186963ebb92f10c4ec1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Frank Moore returned home after the war, started a family, and pursued his passion of fishing on the winding rivers in Oregon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id59a978905845466e9ef66b684e36db4a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>as the proprietor of the Steamboat Inn along the North Umpqua River in Oregon for nearly 20 years, Frank Moore, along with his wife Jeanne, shared his love of fishing, the flowing river, and the great outdoors, with visitors from all over the United States and the world;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9e335096f0154e94b346db977317c2aa"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Frank Moore has spent most of his life fishing the vast rivers of Oregon, during which time he has contributed significantly to efforts to conserve fish habitats and protect river health, including serving on the State of Oregon Fish and Wildlife Commission;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida1a6e02789a4475ebd4f7d585ea6f184"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Frank Moore has been recognized for his conservation work with the National Wildlife Federation Conservationist of the Year award, the Wild Steelhead Coalition Conservation Award, and his 2010 induction into the Fresh Water Fishing Hall of Fame; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id06aaae27150f4a27938c1c0587161815"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in honor of the many accomplishments of Frank Moore, both on and off the river, approximately 104,000 acres of Forest Service land in Oregon should be designated as the <quote>Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id4f25a9dd30a049efa172524ff7bca896"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idc23f5d0846b0432ebfa86768b755f0af"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>O&amp;C Land Grant Act of 2014: Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary</quote> and dated November 3, 2014.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9C0473D93B4C417AA37A5DA2D3E7A313"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sanctuary</header><text>The term <quote>Sanctuary</quote> means the Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary designated by section 4(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id31d29a629db04a1dbd7eea10b2c3c8f3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id563d4eaf6f8f42c79b80264737195481"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Oregon.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idb67861d8cd1b4cbfab86f6e5c48204c3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary, Oregon</header> <subsection id="id2f05d232496a4a44bf9f699b807e207e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The approximately 104,000 acres of Forest Service land in the State, as generally depicted on the Map, is designated as the <quote>Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id62d3a66a2b044822965b2591ab63b8fd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map; legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="id40e765425f8e4f6a98cf61254362b5e0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare a map and legal description of the Sanctuary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idee31a9a717374986874dab10b33b2f6c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddab2ba57587e4a2990c44ef543da2e55"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc859774fc7ec42a1b14395370dc9210b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Sanctuary shall be administered by the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="idDD7CE2F5B8FC4D468F2053D5085D6881"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with all laws (including regulations) applicable to the National Forest System; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id16EB64405D734D16BD1EF770C9118C63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a manner that—</text> <subparagraph id="idEF220573511047C78AA332AA401CD472"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protects, preserves, and enhances the natural character, scientific use, and the botanical, recreational, ecological, fish and wildlife, scenic, drinking water, and cultural values of the Sanctuary;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e963f711a8549c5892d49e97e5f4b05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protects and seeks to enhance the wild salmonid resources of the Sanctuary;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc94a9367afad4098860ac5aeba32f69e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintains or enhances the watershed as a thermal refuge for wild salmonids; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19E4949D06534C9EB79ABF898BF300FE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>preserves opportunities for primitive recreation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2cb5249990bd425b98b7a7354b48752b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife in the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7c1ac7026ec34efc8587fb7b0bcb8c7a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header><text>Nothing in this section creates any protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Sanctuary.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id5620e2194ef34db2bd94087e05adf766"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Protection of tribal rights</header><text>Nothing in this section diminishes any treaty rights of an Indian tribe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id28d94737691c4edcbb2062517cfb89c8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land within the boundaries of the Sanctuary river segments designated by subsection (a) is withdrawn from all forms of—</text>
 <paragraph id="ida7f8b48d2bcc4b74b7264c1303341c65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f2ca8abe13547eaa55c8c5bde0ddd3f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7e0d4935101f45ea8dc967c082fce0e7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id23eccba76bb845e7a2f2bf7ecd3e724f"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow uses of the Sanctuary that are consistent with the purposes and values for which the Sanctuary is established.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ide84c95d8ff224ef9be6a7323b63c4164"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Use of motorized vehicles</header>
 <paragraph id="idC3A73AE8C1934B2A9252BE444D5335B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the use of motorized vehicles within the Sanctuary shall be limited to roads allowed by the Secretary for the use of motorized vehicles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id158A7817A1304B4385842FDFEA8A940D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Off-road vehicle use</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary may allow off-road vehicle use in designated portions of the Sanctuary if the use is consistent with the purposes and values for which the Sanctuary was designated.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idadff760c0cf64adc8ca856bb894f72bf"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Roads</header>
 <paragraph id="id238f7266193d42efaeb5aa42243e53ab"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall decrease the total mileage of system roads that are operational in the Sanctuary to a quantity less than the quantity of mileage in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1F57AB01A9CD4016875BDE3522ECFC78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall prioritize decreasing the mileage of the road network in the Sanctuary to reduce impacts to water quality from sediment delivered to streams by forest roads.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcff2557742954305a6ced4e3f494200a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Temporary roads</header><text>If the Secretary constructs a temporary road as part of a vegetation management project, the Secretary shall close and decommission the temporary road not later than the earlier of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4016b6fd135a474a97249802276f5c3b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is 2 years after the date on which the activity for which the temporary road was constructed is completed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id230641d058f848f7958121713e4c440e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 1 year after the date on which the vegetation management project is completed.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id425d0eed19554951bd54c3ac91e9e47d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No new roads</header><text>The Secretary shall prohibit—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA935177191084BE5BCE2805ADCBDD52C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any new system or nonsystem road within the Sanctuary and key watersheds under the plan entitled <quote>Northwest Forest Plan 1994 Record of Decision for Amendments to Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management Planning Documents Within the Range of the Northern Spotted Owl</quote> after the date of enactment of this Act, except as the Secretary determines to be necessary, if the Secretary determines that no practicable alternative exists, and subject to the availability of appropriations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB2381B534F4144928ABA5BA522930544"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the construction of any new road in any roadless area in the Sanctuary.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


