<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S873 IS: Jay S. Hammond Wilderness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 873</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To designate the wilderness within the Lake Clark National Park and Preserve in the State of Alaska
			 as the Jay S. Hammond Wilderness Area.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jay S. Hammond Wilderness Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idED5AD4BF9BD549319791D9B5EA5F9EC9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id1027ecc136a14d2bba89a540636bfc66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on July 21, 1922, Jay Sterner Hammond was born in Troy, New York;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE2F62325E49341AC8A7E17E57F062BB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hammond studied petroleum engineering at Penn State University, where he was a member of the Triangle Fraternity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id654CFBCD05A04B7BA68799AC053A3BB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Hammond later served as a Marine Corps fighter pilot, serving—</text> <subparagraph id="id8B1B05BEB33840FCAE35A4DD0E64060D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during World War II with the famous Black Sheep Squadron in the South Pacific; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCF1B4F07DC994A98AAE1A2943BA0018F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in China from 1945–1946;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1146a37c73243d38d215c5d19fb2bda"><enum>(4)</enum><text>after leaving military service, Hammond flew to Alaska, where Hammond worked as a Bush pilot, trapper, guide, and laborer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAE0A424D675B4CA299633624E2E1A46E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a war-related illness caused Hammond to enroll at the University of Alaska, Fairbanks, where Hammond earned his degree in biological sciences in 1949;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCF320E721882467CB8210AA52DC83CB4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>after graduating from the University of Alaska, Fairbanks, Hammond went to work as a biologist, field agent, and hunter for the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF781FF5E30CD407D824AD82AFB1CBA7B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in 1950, Hammond was transferred to Southwest Alaska, where Hammond—</text> <subparagraph id="id72B9B175115A4ECCB75F841C3CEF35FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducted predator and prey studies on the caribou herd of the Alaska Peninsula; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBE6698ED801C4E5FAC99074E7665F5BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducted fisheries enforcement efforts out of Dillingham as a pilot;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id58ED64333C3841C4BA14288568D44264"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Hammond—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id470B187A38CC413D8D5891EEA69607B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was 1 of the first people to count 64 brown bears at McNeil River in Southwest Alaska; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id811513B44C904901AAE0F883173F236E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>once recorded nearly 500,000 Black Brant geese eclipsing the sun at Izembek Bay;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5A0B5B094C284B70B6F1809F1F224540"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Hammond later cruised the entire shoreline of 45-mile-long Lake Clark counting wildlife and finding a future homestead site on the shore of Lake Clark;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id08569060a71d48b3ac727a3c4f015b57"><enum>(10)</enum><text>upon Alaska entering the Union in 1959, Hammond ran and won election to the Alaska State House of Representatives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id49F916548D24487AA8123F182E018358"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Hammond served as an independent in the Alaska State House of Representatives from 1959 to 1965;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB93F8784471F4945851364161AB276FD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>in 1960, Hammond changed his party affiliation to Republican;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id255139CCAEBD48129D5AA655CE9DD6AF"><enum>(13)</enum><text>after 3 terms in the Alaska State House of Representatives, Hammond served as a State senator from 1967 to 1973;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB95E3CD0B5C9452BAF7F865AF80A8407"><enum>(14)</enum><text>from 1972 to 1974, Hammond served as mayor of the Bristol Bay Borough;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4C7626D63785421386D20E17E276A448"><enum>(15)</enum><text>during the 1960s and early 1970s, Hammond served as the manager of Bristol Bay Borough during periods in which the State legislature was not in session;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf198c9fa42864cb5b6765b6f84fc3ea4"><enum>(16)</enum><text>in 1974, Hammond was drafted by friends to run for Governor of Alaska, defeating former Republican Walter J. Hickel in the primary, and defeating the first Governor of the State, Democrat William A. Egan, in the general election;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2D7936895E2640F5A462B461AF2FCB71"><enum>(17)</enum><text>the 1974 campaign for Governor was dominated by—</text> <subparagraph id="idF47AB4CAEBE14084937965738AE6B2D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the opposition of Hammond to oil leasing in Kachemak Bay;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id356C13B1DFD44D8EBC1B906C4E79C1ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>concern about State salmon fisheries and environmental management; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4EA0374C48CE4F5FAD2225015FED3D40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>fear about State overspending after the discovery of oil on the North Slope;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1DAA308B769F4CC284821A31E8FA944D"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Hammond—</text> <subparagraph id="id62C8C94B4D5341F9AA986F02A928C6D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>won the Republican primary for Governor in 1974 by 7,874 votes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4D4CB00B26674B15BA468F22676874DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>won the general election for Governor in 1974 by a mere 221 votes after 2 recounts;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25E1D1FACD364022B15E8317A5A7966D"><enum>(19)</enum><text>in 1978, Hammond again defeated Walter J. Hickel in the Republican primary by 98 votes, the closest margin in a statewide election in the history of Alaska;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3FCD9383726940D49947A20F3239F086"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Hammond defeated Walter J. Hickel, a write-in candidate, and Democrat Chancy Croft in the 1978 General Election by 16,000 votes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6e895dfb9fcc4a1bb969190c12d18eaa"><enum>(21)</enum><text>as Governor, Hammond—</text> <subparagraph id="idC132A9A02C094CF69A77D4454F8C2936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oversaw construction of the Trans-Alaska Pipeline;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35C6C5A68D2C439ABC3488B216C27818"><enum>(B)</enum><text>championed the creation of the Alaska Permanent Fund;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id475E53BF09414D57A9D7B3F604E93BDE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>authored the Alaska Permanent Fund Dividend program, which provides citizens of Alaska a yearly dividend check from interest earnings of the State share of petroleum revenues placed in the Alaska Permanent Fund;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1CB1DD17392147EC9DBA1DE6F6B71F2B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>won approval of a constitutional budget reserve;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75BBE9DBC37A474FBD2D10334576DFF7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>opposed the repeal of the State income tax;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD156AE0CC72C42CE8809F894A8A3B875"><enum>(F)</enum><text>championed agricultural development in Interior Alaska; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD0F0F3F30F1448CDA972941ABA266AED"><enum>(G)</enum><text>oversaw the purchase of the Alaska Railroad by the State;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b6c8eaa05ed450cafbe3b4900be4a43"><enum>(22)</enum><text>with respect to environmental issues, Hammond—</text> <subparagraph id="id16F72CB3B4E44911A59BD16E92A9DD2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>opposed construction of a proposed Ramparts hydroelectric dam on the Yukon River;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB6F4FAF0BCFA4FE18D8344E6B124890F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supported the congressional creation of a 200-mile fisheries zone off the coast of the State, which improved State fishery stocks;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC3E7FAB0A91540AF81CAD86AD49B69CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>oversaw the creation of a limited entry fisheries regime in the State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id268212579F5D4CDBA863A382754D3750"><enum>(D)</enum><text>oversaw the creation of the largest State park in the United States, the Wood Tikchik State Park in Southwest Alaska, which contains 1,600,000 acres of wilderness; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFDC5183E19034EB384681D469E24E406"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in 1980, as Governor, oversaw the enactment of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>), which—</text>
 <clause id="id8A50DC510127431295F9C8439E9D69DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>dissolved the placement of 120,000,000 acres of Alaska into protected status under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3203">chapter 3203</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id394B50924AEE4EA6A8B1FDB47BF048F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designated 104,000,000 acres of land as units of the National Park System, units of the National Wildlife Refuge System, National Monuments, components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0F3AF933F7D548C18876C3C07F55A25D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>added 5,500,000 acres in 14 new units of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</text> </clause><clause id="idFD283221D93F41279D7DBFC0CEA3C26B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>added more than 40,000,000 acres in 10 new units of the National Park System, including the 3,860,000-acre Lake Clark National Park and Preserve, bringing to 54,000,000 acres the total size of National Park System holdings in the State;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id399E95CF068D45D69ECDA6AA7BD8139A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>added a number of new units of the National Wildlife Refuge System in the State, bringing to 19 the number of units of the National Wildlife Refuge System covering 76,800,000 acres in the State;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD9A1268F153643FA9335474EE3616A39"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>created 13 components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System running 3,131 miles; and</text> </clause><clause id="id370F3B34EC0A48A88AEB45844F72BE64"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>resulted in Alaska containing 57,900,000 acres of wilderness;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8d801286ec14f6d9848f6fe4bf72d5d"><enum>(23)</enum><text>a talented and prolific writer and poet, Hammond—</text> <subparagraph id="id7FAB0F6CA68547529B2724A1E942E9B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>presented to the University of Alaska Library Archives an impressive collection of speeches, testimony, notebooks, and papers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3E3C10454D1940F5970FE7CAD8F25DB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>wrote several books on life in Alaska, including his first book entitled <quote>Tales of Alaska’s Bush Rat Governor</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAA57E909D9F3441A88E38FD4984B91FB"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Hammond died on August 2, 2005, at age 83, in his sleep, at his homestead at Port Alsworth, Alaska, after having survived—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idEF1B0250E52041BA9CACE19E3728FB7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>5 plane crashes; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA5492F696270404C9C66DF78E6FDADAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>innumerable close calls with death, including during—</text>
 <clause id="id149D8CAE6A964E4AAF9B59F8FC03DF62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Hammond's first flight to Alaska and numerous subsequent flights during Hammond's 59 years in the State; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCF28112B879D44E3802415851A612594"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a fire at the homestead at Lake Clark;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEF12A0302379480984334C8175C85A0C"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Hammond was survived by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id81CE3CBF6B904AA3B5CC87A8C73BD02E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>his wife, Bella; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61F26129F25146CCB0720223D08249D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>his daughters, Heidi and Dana;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide6544336732b4c3fae0ba7450d096503"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Hammond—</text> <subparagraph id="idF08DD85769DD4B75A1A3A96C5F02FEC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was well-respected for reaching across the aisle to forge bipartisan alliances; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5AF382DCCCE54D4F96A7698C3C692A38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enjoyed many close friendships—</text> <clause id="id513DE701C6A14D6DA8175247D16F4201"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with colleagues in both political parties; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFE5646126A4A4178A12A55D5257BD32B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>members of his staff, who were deeply loyal to Hammond; and</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id41817d10a777444ca07d7e5dad5733cc"><enum>(27)</enum><text>the designation of the 2,600,000 acres of wilderness in Lake Clark National Park and Preserve, in which the homestead of Hammond is located, would—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idCC862D5E6D5341E19E0C6DFE5C3970FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>honor Hammond; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82298E25F40A4FFE9AFCA61EC36E8FE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be a fitting tribute to the honorable life and legacy of Hammond, who was described by the Anchorage Municipal Assembly on August 7, 2005, as <quote>the finest example of a true public servant … there are few men who have influence through their quiet articulation of what is right and fair in the way of Jay Hammond</quote>.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id6633E503785144A89FAC607A08F42C51"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of Jay S. Hammond Wilderness Area</header>
 <subsection id="id2F09044CB9214E5DA9296B7126B395E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The approximately 2,600,000 acres of National Wilderness Preservation System land located within the Lake Clark National Park and Preserve designated by section 201(e)(7)(a) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410hh">16 U.S.C. 410hh(e)(7)(a)</external-xref>) shall be known and designated as the <quote>Jay S. Hammond Wilderness Area</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idddd35f15cce544a6bf3899f3806619a9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the wilderness area referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Jay S. Hammond Wilderness Area</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


