<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1689 IS: To amend title 23, United States Code, to reduce the funding available for a State under the national highway performance program and the surface transportation program if the State issues a license plate that contains an image of a flag of the Confederate States of America, including the Battle Flag of the Confederate States of America.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1689</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 23, United States Code, to reduce the funding available for a State under the
			 national highway performance program and the surface transportation
			 program if the State issues a license plate that contains an image of a
			 flag of the Confederate States of America, including the Battle Flag of
			 the Confederate States of America.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id9B0858065E0B46C6870F7066325CEFDE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Reduction of apportionment for certain Federal-aid highway programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 104 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1D41F44C3AFC4ED19AAAF1DA3C453191" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id1132E3872AD343A292A4A816449BC4A6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reduction of apportionment for certain Federal-Aid highway programs</header><text>The amount apportioned to a State under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) shall be reduced by an amount equal to 5 percent of those funds—</text>
 <paragraph id="id832A6399F6634E2A813C2C9F475C07CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>effective beginning on October 1 of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this subsection, for each fiscal year in which the State issues a license plate that contains an image of a flag of the Confederate States of America, including the Battle Flag of the Confederate States of America; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id12C2666304FC48EFBB67C8F9FDC65F76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>effective beginning on October 1 of the second fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this subsection, for each fiscal year in which the State allows a license plate described in paragraph (1) and issued by the State before the first fiscal year referred to in that paragraph to be displayed on a motor vehicle registered in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


