<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-print="no" public-private="public" stage-count="1" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1603 : Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
		<distribution-code>IC</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">S. 1603</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date>September 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc>Referred to the<committee-name committee-id="HAS00"> Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00"> Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type display="yes">AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To actively recruit members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service to serve
			 as Customs and Border Protection Officers.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H7E5117AD2BD0407199586B0F7C94DF62" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8f7c2b7-7853-4c1d-b047-efb202ad3c3d" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a2cd995-2f55-412f-987f-aaae0845add7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d0fab0f-d799-4334-9da7-d2844acfe6e7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Customs and Border Protection Officers at United States ports of entry carry out critical law enforcement duties associated with screening foreign visitors, returning United States citizens, and imported cargo entering the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc591a973-f631-4169-82f0-2ed783548ad8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is in the national interest for United States ports of entry to be adequately staffed with Customs and Border Protection Officers in a timely fashion, including meeting the congressionally funded staffing target of 23,775 officers for fiscal year 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1b981f9-2df5-4103-b780-67e845a74c5f"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimated 250,000 to 300,000 members of the Armed Forces separate from military service every year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id528ee65e-b382-436a-b040-81b8ad4310da"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recruiting efforts and expedited hiring procedures must be enhanced to ensure that qualified individuals separating from military service are aware of, and partake in, opportunities to fill vacant Customs and Border Protection Officer positions.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id962b5b01-3459-4c4b-a1a5-f71e2bd536c3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expedited hiring of appropriate separating service members</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7f7ee9e-4b0c-441c-afdc-c0ee2d5246b2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of transferable qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in conjunction with the Secretary of Defense, shall identify Military Occupational Specialty Codes and Officer Branches, Air Force Specialty Codes, Naval Enlisted Classifications and Officer Designators, and Coast Guard Competencies that are transferable to the requirements, qualifications, and duties assigned to Customs and Border Protection Officers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30126fb7-e95a-4c1a-946b-1eb011f164c6"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hiring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall consider hiring qualified candidates with the Military Occupational Specialty Codes, Air Force Specialty Codes, Naval Enlisted Classifications and Officer Designators, and Coast Guard Competencies identified as transferable under subsection (a) who are eligible for veterans recruitment appointment authorized under section 4214 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4956bd61-44a6-4a56-9a23-8cacaacfa1a7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhancements to existing programs to recruit service members separating from military service for
			 Customs and Border Protection Officer vacancies</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5008c81e-f644-4fc1-88d9-417702c5f1e3"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in conjunction with the Secretary of Defense, and acting through existing programs, authorities, and agreements, where applicable, shall enhance the efforts of the Department of Homeland Security to recruit members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service to serve as Customs and Border Protection Officers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97760f47-02d5-40e7-bcb7-45a6fe55226a"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enhanced recruiting efforts under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc990f584-3c71-4c1c-9378-bd0feeaabdea"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include Customs and Border Protection Officer opportunities in relevant job assistance efforts under the Transition Assistance Program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ba72cbb-adce-49bb-ac3d-dfb6e277d100"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">place U.S. Customs and Border Protection officials or other relevant Department of Homeland Security officials at recruiting events and jobs fairs involving members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ce2fef3-bf81-4517-bd3d-64e338e36722"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide opportunities for local U.S. Customs and Border Protection field offices to partner with military bases in the region;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb338aeb5-fa79-4eb8-b7ad-45eed4d6eafe"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include outreach efforts to educate members of the Armed Forces with Military Occupational Specialty Codes and Officer Branches, Air Force Specialty Codes, Naval Enlisted Classifications and Officer Designators, and Coast Guard Competencies that are transferable to the requirements, qualifications, and duties assigned to Customs and Border Protection Officers of available hiring opportunities to become Customs and Border Protection Officers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a7bd381-6f88-49f1-b080-0cddd1a181e7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Defense to work cooperatively to identify shared activities and opportunities for reciprocity related to steps in hiring U.S. Customs and Border Patrol officers with the goal of minimizing the time required to hire qualified applicants;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38658933-fc63-4c3d-a9bb-080f744b7f8c"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security to work cooperatively to ensure the streamlined interagency transfer of relevant background investigations and security clearances; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35ddd7cf-e2b4-4f6f-b7f1-a732b958ef9a"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include such other elements as may be necessary to ensure that members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service are aware of opportunities to fill vacant Customs and Border Protection Officer positions.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2a40b4d-cd54-4e84-8183-bec63d65ccf8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report to Congress</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebee7047-5097-48aa-b5e9-edeb38327365"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than December 31 of each of the 3 successive years, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes a description and assessment of the efforts of the Department of Homeland Security to hire separating service members as Customs and Border Protection Officers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaed94585-bd05-4db5-9957-2337b181eee6"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Content</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ac21014-1d39-4e45-8481-f8e6973c86be"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of the proposed efforts under section 4, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec9e3228-0a99-435e-8a50-6309cf9b3c3a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">elements of the enhanced recruiting efforts;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ca492fb-12cb-4d33-b439-72f57c7a45cf"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">goals associated with those elements; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba256072-00f5-4039-a28c-b2b5b4b21aa7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the elements and goals will assist in meeting statutorily mandated staffing levels and agency hiring benchmarks;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8eb82d1-9bc2-4a53-b275-275a6a0dfe88"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of the efforts that have been undertaken under section 4;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66caefdb-d361-49c7-887f-8b36ea2d1577"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of separating service members made aware of Customs and Border Protection Officer vacancies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d1aa208-3ea8-48e6-a587-4a5bece495da"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Military Occupational Specialty Codes and Officer Branches, Air Force Specialty Codes, Naval Enlisted Classifications and Officer Designators, and Coast Guard Competencies identified as transferable under section 3(a) and a rationale for such identifications;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc458553d-fd73-46c9-844d-34024adfb0b5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of Customs and Border Protection Officer vacancies filled with separating service members; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided4e2d6a-cd79-4bd0-b003-a02dd3ce9c83"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of Customs and Border Protection Officer vacancies filled with separating service members under veterans recruitment appointment authorized under section 4214 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id277a2c20-8bbf-40d3-baf6-7357d7b52a6c" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f66c117-01da-4373-8a3a-50444f636b03"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to supersede, alter, or amend existing Federal veterans’ hiring preferences or Federal hiring authorities; or</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id401cfbc0-873f-4668-b0a7-24005565c18d"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to authorize the appropriation of additional amounts to carry out this Act.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="Senate" date="20150909">Passed the Senate September 9, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Julie E. Adams,</attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

