<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S545 IS: Pay Our Coast Guard Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 545</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150224">February 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>Making continuing appropriations for Coast Guard pay in the event the Consolidated and Further
			 Continuing Appropriations Act of 2015 expires and the Department of
			 Homeland Security Appropriations Act of 2015 is not enacted.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pay Our Coast Guard Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idb636f96364ff436a930d747a44b3f8ec"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuing appropriations for members of the Coast Guard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated for fiscal year 2015, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for fiscal year 2015 for the Coast Guard are not in effect—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf875ec7cb52e4d23a995dd071dab49fa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary to provide pay and allowances to members of the Coast Guard (as described in section 1 of title 14, United States Code), including the reserve component thereof, who perform active service or inactive-duty training during such period;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20fbdb3f8b354b229af19755a5b7a6ca"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary to provide pay and allowances to civilian employees of the Coast Guard;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id99f2f1e0de2441dcbec695957fbda5d4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary to provide pay and allowances to contractors of the Coast Guard; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf709773e7676485d9dc3529e4d50d1d8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary for—</text> <subparagraph id="id9B3133AE318542D9B7366ADD5D82C0FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the payment of a death gratuity under sections 1475–1477 and 1489 of title 10, United States Code, with respect to members of the Coast Guard;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74D00946FCDE4224B3EAE64A29ABB254"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the payment or reimbursement of authorized funeral travel and travel related to the dignified transfer of remains and unit memorial services under section 481f of title 37, United States Code, with respect to members of the Coast Guard; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id294B878A30FE49D080DD686367612269"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the temporary continuation of a basic allowance of housing for dependents of members of the Coast Guard dying on active duty, as authorized by section 403(l) of title 37, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="iddc7b2772aeb64d6baecdd8153f8052a3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs:</text>
 <paragraph id="idC9314099BCE74C019C185157B4F9AFDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enactment into law of an appropriation (including a continuing appropriation) for any purpose for which amounts are made available in section 2.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEA09D0E0DC5F4CC1A1F715E1B8BAB6C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enactment into law of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id94C12C65589247D790D1DC69FA93D3B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">January 1, 2016.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

