<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1993 IS: 21st Century Conservation Service Corps Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1993</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish the 21st Century Conservation Service Corps to place youth and veterans in the United
			 States in national service positions to protect, restore, and
			 enhance the great outdoors of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Conservation Service Corps Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="id74F55D3691D54CCF995D882B9C2F4CA8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to engage youth and veterans in the United States in national service positions to protect, restore, and enhance the outdoors of the United States, including to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id59ce5baade514a24ad854c6c29c63d42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>channel widespread interest among youth and veterans in the United States in serving in national service positions to help protect, restore, enhance, and increase public access to and use of national parks, public and tribal land or water, and natural, cultural, and historical resources and treasures for the enjoyment and use of future generations while spurring economic development and outdoor recreation by carrying out high-quality, cost-effective 21CSC projects;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf5697e6bbe804a90832043e4e2585c07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that, in any State, tribal land or water, or territory of the United States, the activities and expertise of 21CSC participants will be accessible to public organizations, nonprofit organizations, and tribal agencies responsible for the stewardship of public land or water, private land or water (with a direct or recognized public benefit and in coordination with the owner of such land or water), or tribal land or water; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3ad0e748df2d45a795fc444f4b804be6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>place youth and veterans in national service positions to protect, restore, and enhance the great outdoors of the United States, through collaborative efforts involving relevant Federal departments and Federal agencies to minimize undue duplication, leverage existing resources, and maximize project completion in a cost-effective manner.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="idC2879D82211B41E6AF3EB0F899BE6180"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id7B0E380656764FE38002DBD0D3C1CBC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>21CSC organization</header><text>The term <term>21CSC organization</term> means an organization that is approved by a participating entity for participation in the 21st Century Conservation Service Corps.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id575BBE80F25349D2A57A5A556D11032B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>21CSC participant</header><text>The term <term>21CSC participant</term> means an individual who is selected by a 21CSC organization to serve on a 21CSC project.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idEDC33F36935540718610E33436C65D99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>21CSC project</header><text>The term <term>21CSC project</term> means a project that is carried out by a 21CSC organization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2CBF7B620AB244099D1F33AB4C084FE2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>), except that such term shall not include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7540B6909C2E4E9B91FACD86674EF412"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution outside the United States, as described in subsection (a)(1)(C) of such section; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id64D21C0503BC484C9F8EACA74B409830"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an institution described in section 101(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC5BD55CA54004FE8B7D1D26BAF54967F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Participating entity</header><text>The term <term>participating entity</term> means a Federal entity headed by an officer described in any of paragraphs (1) through (13) of section 5(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9E521A42277241AF83B535C8F27A0290"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5785C11D01044751AF70E3EF720B209E"><enum>(7)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tribal agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tribal agency</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>Indian tribe</quote> in section 101 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12511">42 U.S.C. 12511</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFA1B93784754432C99577725EF56B3B8"><enum>(8)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tribal land or water</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tribal land or water</term> means any real property or water owned by a tribal agency, any real property or water held in trust by the United States for an Indian (for the purpose of this paragraph, as defined in such section) or tribal agency, and any real property or water held by an Indian or tribal agency that is subject to restrictions on alienation imposed by the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6834C187AFFF476B9F7AA988FFFC54F2"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4A90AC08850347A492C445A800C35BC9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Youth</header><text>The term <term>youth</term> means an individual who is not younger than age 15 and not older than age 28.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="idFD6FB25F371941348AF9816F51CE65D0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishing the 21st Century Conservation Service Corps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established a 21st Century Conservation Service Corps (referred to in this Act as the <quote>21CSC</quote>), consisting of 21CSC organizations and 21CSC participants and in partnership with the participating entities, to carry out the purpose of this Act.</text>
		</section><section id="id65882E6BA4714B57A26B7A41C0961788"><enum>5.</enum><header>Participating entities</header>
 <subsection id="id0954AFB516624D27BC922464ED7DDA53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The 21CSC shall be implemented jointly by the participating entities, which shall have the authority to support the 21CSC by carrying out the activities described in subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5E6D34B5F6DC46DBB4D233AC70A6D8E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of entities</header><text>The participating entities shall be the entities headed by each of the following officers:</text> <paragraph id="idf4e159d412a34523bb355ee1d567e44c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id279db9729b8b4403a35dd50a94b34b9b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idea1b3b622b2a4e4c8e4eb582a73736d2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary of Transportation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id05be00929c374725b720077401bf240b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idb565bb9c7ffe4c958862372ce1945254"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id257a959237ba420ebd84b5ab4771eb31"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idb10e6f24875846f190ae04a1530498ed"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id045ab1c102ab449086fcb151dee5f40b"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idec6ec8b6c9a140e2a5a434bdf2e4ff78"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id34bdad3fc81f48cc8c7bb6f7d30004c3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idac144c20d64647049937e67e704580b2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc1a2edb0f0374301b326796e119c454f"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary of the Army (Civil Works).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id67A71770BC85431FA033189B67C4B387"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The head of any other Federal agency designated by the President as necessary to serve as a participating entity.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB6D3588AC6FA4355820C92169A71402E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supporting the 21CSC</header>
 <paragraph id="id54028885CB104BD380546A9EE9AA9B28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The participating entities may support the 21CSC by—</text> <subparagraph id="id8638f325341d48b3bfa76b5451158d44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing standards for the 21CSC;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd023e8a7a2ad4d5f848ea4cfa2d98989"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing a process for organizations to apply and be approved to become 21CSC organizations;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6da8224684144de59efbd8a878fa96a6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing and supporting the public-private partnerships described in subsection (e)(1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc4965d7fd99e4f198ef3300eadc2b9cd"><enum>(D)</enum><text>using or leveraging existing funding or acquiring funding and other resources under section 7 to support 21CSC projects through the cooperative agreements described in subsection (e);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idefd32a25102d40c48f53e3808bb0c87c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>leveraging existing resources described in section 7(b) to expand the use of the 21CSC to meet the missions of such entities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc46ddb4a4c584fb8a3228eb2ea3f36db"><enum>(F)</enum><text>utilizing technology to support 21CSC projects; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idecd73b03b505407b8e9abb7f90cab508"><enum>(G)</enum><text>collecting performance data on 21CSC projects to prepare the reports required by paragraph (3)(A) and demonstrate the impact of such projects.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC6463DE7ACB142A1937FD54AEF917243"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination to minimize undue duplication and maximize project completion in a cost-effective
			 manner</header>
 <subparagraph id="id7FD9C9EC807D4838BD039470FFF40800"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coordination with Federal departments and agencies</header><text>The participating entities shall coordinate with each other and with Federal departments and Federal agencies, affected by or engaging in activities that are similar to 21CSC projects, to—</text>
 <clause id="id87F0CDC768DA425DA039C1DB2C546665"><enum>(i)</enum><text>minimize to the greatest extent possible any undue duplication with specific project activities performed by the Federal departments and Federal agencies described in this subparagraph; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9135955BF328450A87857D9E8CB56C9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maximize project completion in a cost-effective manner by collaborating to leverage existing resources described in section 7(b).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id617C23DF51C642C1A5BDCE94B5714A2A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination among entities</header><text>Each participating entity shall, when feasible, coordinate activities with other participating entities to approve 21CSC organizations and collect the data required by paragraph 3(A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id90C2BE09EE464663AF30EC18556D0C6D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The participating entities shall, when practicable, seek guidance from—</text> <clause id="id5F3F0CD33ACD4DC2B6C2EAE4E98DEDF4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Corporation for National and Community Service, which has extensive experience in developing and administering national service programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id51873F38D15D4CA2A3FD6BAB827D4341"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Department of Veterans Affairs on ways to increase participation of veterans in 21CSC projects.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEE4BE02B17F644E3A91CE7EA5B98FD3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <subparagraph id="id6D7079268C1845968B1F59BCFF2082BA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>21CSC Reports</header> <clause id="id1F41BFC104D348F0B5B4672FEC0B0A19"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, all participating entities shall submit the required data described in clause (ii) to the Corporation for National and Community Service.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id61291BC06301423F99AD2B4751FE150A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Required data</header><text>The Corporation for National and Community Service, in coordination with the participating entities, shall prepare and submit an annual report to the Comptroller General of the United States that includes required data, for the year covered by the report, consisting of—</text>
 <subclause id="ida422157c6dd84ae1b9baeb3b4d363226"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of 21CSC participants engaging in 21CSC projects and the length of the term of service for each participant;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id97e242f88fb540f5aaaa0eea16f42bbd"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total amount of funding provided by participating entities for such service;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id6dc3efad3f0643609fdb77cc96d86c85"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the type of service performed by 21CSC participants and the impact and accomplishments of such service; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idd3f3a9921cd847b2b5344de2c058e9e5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other similar data determined to be appropriate by the Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Corporation for National and Community Service and the participating entities, including data sufficient to determine the effectiveness of 21CSC organizations in carrying out activities to achieve the purpose of this Act in a manner that is cost-effective and does not unduly duplicate or overlap with other activities or programs carried out by Federal departments and Federal agencies.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idE7A9D55C419046D3A12F622465EB9E2A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The Corporation for National and Community Service may coordinate with 21CSC organizations to collect the required data described in clause (ii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEFD93714EC84439E97089CBF1BED8D6D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Comptroller General reports</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of submission of a report under subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall prepare and submit a report to Congress that, with respect to the year covered by the report submitted under subparagraph (A), includes—</text>
 <clause id="id3C7A68903274451AA29BF100FF4FB636"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the data described in subparagraph (A)(ii);</text> </clause><clause id="id87F36A67DCA14100B5B26E7EA97AB695"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment, based on such data, of the effectiveness of 21CSC organizations in achieving the purpose of this Act in a manner that is cost-effective and does not unduly duplicate or overlap with other activities or programs carried out by Federal departments and Federal agencies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC113BA7C8CD040BEAC786B1319F75239"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>recommendations on how to more effectively manage and carry out 21CSC projects to achieve the purpose of this Act in the manner described in clause (ii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id22c5f68afe0341199cdac57c77232121"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Gifts and donations</header><text>The participating entities may accept, use, and dispose of contributions that are gifts or donations of money, services, or property to support the development, implementation, and expansion of 21CSC projects, in accordance with applicable laws, including regulations.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idc67c6ddeffe1453f89647956b37b1f9a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements with 21CSC organizations</header>
 <paragraph id="id750cf5a6362349b1ac65a041c92b9e95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each participating entity shall have the authority to—</text> <subparagraph id="idCC944B3993BB4391B7295EFC4EDF3C8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop public-private partnerships with 21CSC organizations by entering into cooperative agreements with such organizations to support and carry out 21CSC projects; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE994320B96424632AA731049DF7EDEB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>leverage existing resources described in section 7(b) to support such cooperative agreements.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4056cf7f84ca4fc398a255360db39ab7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Type of cooperative agreement</header><text>A cooperative agreement under this subsection may be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id0282b081b55645baa3f46114a95ac198"><enum>(A)</enum><text>limited to an agreement for a specific 21CSC project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf3c157579f804e888e7eb4c2d63f1d92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a broad agreement covering multiple planned or future 21CSC projects; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6198165bfae495283db0a00d62fea22"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an agreement for a 21CSC project to be part of a broader conservation service corps initiative carried out in partnership with a Federal or State government or a tribal agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id62ba8613727e45269866d738cce9b1e6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Set share</header><text>A cooperative agreement under this subsection shall include provisions specifying the share that the 21CSC organization will provide under section 7(c).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id676ACC47655F47639F4E50A7B1EF819E"><enum>6.</enum><header>21CSC organizations and 21CSC projects</header>
 <subsection id="id3A6C713C21D94AA584F2FB9D1DBD8C1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>21CSC organizations</header><text>To be approved as a 21CSC organization, an organization seeking approval shall, to the maximum extent practicable, demonstrate the capability to meet, and provide an assurance that the organization will meet, each requirement under subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id35C43232DE66480A88F7708338CDF5D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>21CSC projects</header>
				<paragraph id="id9DEF843935364BABA020EE13C56BA4D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>21CSC participants engaged by 21CSC organizations</header>
 <subparagraph id="idD444948AAB8B4E45A8382B9BE0FC002B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out a 21CSC project, to the maximum extent practicable, a 21CSC organization shall select individuals to be 21CSC participants who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subparagraph (B), are—</text>
 <clause id="id685E66A2C24141E68199357D1F1EC764"><enum>(i)</enum><text>youth, notwithstanding the requirements under paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 137(a) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12591">42 U.S.C. 12591(a)</external-xref>) for any 21CSC participant participating in a 21CSC project supported and carried out by the Corporation for National and Community Service; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6563B7E3F604459AAA758F4E94FEFA4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>veterans not older than age 35.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id9A61EA20F5884CE894329E28C0169EAF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Citizenship requirement</header><text>To be selected as a 21CSC participant, an individual shall be—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="idC3B905371B5F4DC6A61CCE64158EE1A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a citizen or national of the United States; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="id3472F0BAD42546EAB56862DD96CCA7DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a lawful permanent resident alien of the United States.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC640225EA3ED4D02BF3180AA84B5162D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Emphasis on diversity and inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting 21CSC participants, the organization shall make deliberate outreach efforts to engage traditionally underserved populations, including veterans and disadvantaged youth (as defined in section 101 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12511">42 U.S.C. 12511</external-xref>)).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA12357AF9F2E4FFC9356BBD19A579A99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation for participants</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The organization shall provide compensation to each 21CSC participant that shall include 1 or more of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4FC674017C2B44FFB10B127862551D21"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A wage.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7207C51AB0B24B20B55A1D2EAFC8E132"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A stipend.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8B3B62B440B34D2399FA6381C03F7E28"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A living allowance.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBDA2BDF76ADB467B8340D365757A22A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An educational credit that may be applied towards a program of postsecondary education at a participating institution of higher education that agrees to award such credit for participation in a 21CSC project.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCFC3DC9FE45C4FD59E19A60F3D38881A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Organization of service for participants</header>
 <subparagraph id="id0668724E49DC4F5BB3A0CEBB145A23F5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the 21CSC project, the organization shall, to the maximum extent practicable, organize 21CSC participants as—</text>
 <clause id="idF2B880A901004C2EA7FCFF6C8CABFDB8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>crew-based participants who—</text> <subclause id="id3ABC68060ED04D2091A95E2B0EF038B6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>serve together with other crew-based participants; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id81BC0EF662004D10BECF8321C78C6D3C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are directly supervised by trained and experienced crew-based leaders or conservation professionals; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id392334DD87A249368E42E1C81BE2C91E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individual or small team-based participants who serve—</text> <subclause id="idA890E80C36F2449288A64AC8561ED035"><enum>(I)</enum><text>individually or in a coordinated small team;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idBBA43DBD06F2477AA3C20FAFA56D244E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>under the direction of conservation professionals; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idC5DB99EEAA2C43B7A8C2D489FBDF0759"><enum>(III)</enum><text>on initiatives that require specific skills and dedicated attention.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id16DE7244461F4979A739DDA25E449921"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Veteran and civilian cooperation</header><text>The organization shall, to the extent practicable, encourage cooperation among veteran and civilian 21CSC participants.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA122261A6E664F7C96397C5A76568117"><enum>(4)</enum><header>21CSC projects</header><text>The organization shall carry out a 21CSC project that includes national service involving—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1E75FC28D5914C9CA00D61876D67060F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protecting, restoring, and enhancing national parks, public and tribal land or water, and natural, cultural, and historical resources and treasures;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA9CD875679234850A22F91AFF57B2D9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting outdoor recreation and urban green spaces;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7B3192B7482247BF8F0342A26D8316C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>restoring and safeguarding the natural resources of the United States, such as through trail maintenance, removal of invasive species, wildfire prevention, historic preservation, and disaster relief; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE5B3C86EE4EF43AF81799521B2DC6940"><enum>(D)</enum><text>service that is primarily indoors, such as service in science, policy, or program internships, with a clear benefit for natural, cultural, or historic resources or treasures.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFCAB6984626F4D62B21363027F220D7B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>21CSC participant outcomes</header><text>In carrying out a 21CSC project, the organization shall provide 21CSC participants with—</text> <subparagraph id="idD7833BB082264471867E52589D4B5D90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>job skill development to prepare such participants for success in the 21st century workforce;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB63E5B3D6DE84F03AD4DAAF23156C343"><enum>(B)</enum><text>community skill development to help such participants acquire an ethic of service to others and become more effective resource and community stewards; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idB43511CB16A943BC9703EF6BBF4DB113"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a greater understanding of the natural, cultural, or historic resources or treasures in the United States.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39A7CE83C8FD44C594BAD8C5E20AD14B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion from prevailing wage, hour, and child labor laws</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31E5AE9BB5DE40FE8E47A3B353B095A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prevailing wage and hours laws</header><text>Any form of compensation, including stipends, provided to 21CSC participants under subsection (b)(2) shall not be subject to the requirements of prevailing wage laws under subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0567AE1C54814B4EB02BC5721F64B603"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonemployee status</header><text>A 21CSC participant shall not be considered—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF7DBBEA11E6A4032854D40540419733E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee of the 21CSC organization that selected such participant to serve on a 21CSC project under this Act, in the same manner as a participant is excluded under section 101(30) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12511">42 U.S.C. 12511(30)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5311D660E59B4853893C9C5D65466CE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Federal employee, and shall not be subject to the provisions of law relating to Federal employment, except that such provisions shall apply to any 21CSC participant to the extent provided for a participant or crew leader under section 199M(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12655n">42 U.S.C. 12655n(b)</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id651D267DDEF0416AB7E5CAEC5E360349"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility for noncompetitive hiring status</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA98079F9F28642458812E6E47639AACE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified individual described in paragraph (2) shall be eligible for appointment in the competitive service in the same manner as Peace Corps volunteers as prescribed in Executive Order 11103 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504</external-xref> note; relating to Providing for the Appointment of Former Peace Corps Volunteers to the Civilian Career Services), as amended by Executive Order 12107 (44 Fed. Reg. 1055; relating to the Civil Service Commission and Labor-Management in the Federal Service).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0D7325FE2FB74978AE6A32DA2786142B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified individual</header><text>A qualified individual described in this subsection is an individual who is certified by the corresponding participating entities as having successfully completed 1 or more terms of service, as determined by an agreement between the 21CSC organization and the 21CSC participant, that, in total, are not less than 640 hours.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDCB1715F9D39464BA00A6D77B928C4DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period</header><text>A qualified individual described in paragraph (2) shall be eligible for an appointment under paragraph (1) during the 2-year period beginning on the date on which such individual completes 1 or more terms of service, as determined under paragraph (2), that, in total, are not less than 640 hours.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idEDC9C6383E974CD1AB80BB4FEA8F40D8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Funding</header>
			<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB9E1FCDD734F476EBC89B7A7D31B1D20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investments</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17DD9443F2E543F5BCE14CF24959D0C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to using funding provided under subsections (b) and (c), to fund 21CSC projects, each 21CSC organization shall leverage the funds provided under such subsections by soliciting in cash or in-kind contributions from public or private sources.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2CE7571BF90947EC85ECDAE41684E632"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methods</header><text>To leverage the funds under paragraph (1), each 21CSC organization may solicit contributions by using innovative strategies, such as crowd-funding.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id072FB0DCE0264A4FB1C5C53E7EE05BC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Existing resources</header><text>In addition to using funding provided under subsections (a) and (c), to fund a 21CSC project, each participating entity shall be limited to using existing resources that have been appropriated or allocated to such participating entity, as of the period of implementation of such 21CSC project, under laws and authorities other than this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62CC3F8499A143A584194E07650CA5E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Set share</header><text>A 21CSC organization conducting a 21CSC project shall provide a share of not less than 10 percent of the total cost of such project. The organization may provide the share in cash or in kind from State, local, or private sources.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75A77499001B40D586A4CB7D8D599A1A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 6(b)(1)(A)(i), the requirements and authorities provided under this Act for 21CSC participants, 21CSC organizations, and participating entities with respect to a 21CSC project shall be in addition to the requirements and authorities provided under other Federal law for such participants, organizations, and entities with respect to that project.</text></section></legis-body>
</bill>


