<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1290 IS: TRICARE Portability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1290</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure the ability of covered beneficiaries under the TRICARE program to access care under a
			 health plan under such program in each TRICARE program region, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="idCF6500BF14584EB1B5F6AC681D483F15" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>TRICARE Portability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id412FAA434A2444E6BD1FCF4F2619746D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Portability of health plans under the TRICARE program</header> <subsection id="id1aeeb40d044c493b93a37a954b11a4c2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Health plan portability</header> <paragraph id="idB90E29B625EE4DFFA86931EE03B8154F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that covered beneficiaries under the TRICARE program who are covered under a health plan under such program are able to seamlessly access health care under such health plan in each TRICARE program region.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id49A3418F88BC4BD7907068D4E12D8594"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52E0F236E17B4258A31C6D8F0504A354"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mechanisms To ensure portability</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall do the following:</text> <paragraph id="id979293354fe44691a5588f74ca0f9ddb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Provide for the automatic electronic transfer of demographic, enrollment, and claims information between the contractors responsible for administering the TRICARE program in each TRICARE region when covered beneficiaries under the TRICARE program relocate between such regions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id69c726e228d145feb6d651d03e3f3d3d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ensure such covered beneficiaries are able to obtain a new primary health care provider within ten days of undergoing such relocation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6b12bec4843740bf9008498e3a7157ab"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Develop a process for such covered beneficiaries to receive urgent care without preauthorization while undergoing such relocation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0fe906fc820743719605ae53dab1ba8f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="idF74BDC98B96E489EAF1AF9C3DBAB938C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish information on any modifications made pursuant to subsection (a) with respect to the ability of covered beneficiaries under the TRICARE program who are covered under a health plan under such program to access health care in each TRICARE region on the primary Internet website of the Department that is available to the public; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6ED84AD2342640E09996F160A8D811A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that such information is made available on the primary Internet website that is available to the public of each current contractor responsible for administering the TRICARE program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6020720EF3BC48A7BECC2ECCF0DD9F11"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>covered beneficiary</term> and <term>TRICARE program</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 1072 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

