<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S249 IS: Operation United Assistance Tax Exclusion Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 249</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide that members of the Armed Forces performing hazardous humanitarian services in
			 West Africa to combat the spread of the 2014 Ebola virus outbreak shall be
			 entitled to tax benefits in the same manner as if such services were
 performed in a combat zone.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idBCEADC78DAFE48EEB99954E19164C9AB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Operation United Assistance Tax Exclusion Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id82D5293F02E04F4E864196CDB5E556F9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of certain hazardous humanitarian service as combat zone service for purposes of the combat zone compensation exclusion</header><subsection id="id65F37C74531B4F0A91AC3306E456CBDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/112">section 112</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, service by a qualified member of the Armed Forces during Operation United Assistance shall be treated as service in a combat zone in the same manner as if the President of the United States had by Executive Order designated the Ebola virus disease outbreak area as an area of combat under section 112(c)(2) of such Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="idF0CABB790914485CB9E17174E3EF3117"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="id7408683778144DE98FFB125B24FBF6BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified member of the Armed Forces</header><text>The term <term>qualified member of the Armed Forces</term> means a member of the Armed Forces serving in Operation United Assistance who is required to undergo a program of not less than 21 days of controlled monitoring in a controlled monitoring area upon the individual's return from the Ebola virus disease outbreak area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCB56533A8E5E421DB351863D0543865B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Operation United Assistance</header><text>The term <term>Operation United Assistance</term> means the mission beginning in September 2014 in the Ebola virus disease outbreak area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idACB5164E58B949E4B352960CD0813244"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ebola virus disease outbreak area</header><text>The term <term>Ebola virus disease outbreak area</term> means Liberia, Sierra Leone, and Guinea, and any other region designated by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention as experiencing a widespread Ebola virus disease outbreak as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id57087FEEFB5A40D1AF6C413689A1EF80"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to compensation received for months before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


