<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S823 IS: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 206 West Commercial Street in East Rochester, New York, as the “Officer Daryl R. Pierson Post Office”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 823</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150319">March 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 206 West Commercial Street
			 in East Rochester, New York, as the <quote>Officer Daryl R. Pierson Post Office</quote>.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Officer Daryl R. Pierson Post Office</header>
 <subsection id="idE30646E5649146C9A9ABC15B273CA873"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 206 West Commercial Street in East Rochester, New York, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Officer Daryl R. Pierson Post Office</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idA410721A7D874B86B903F414C85C5EF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Officer Daryl R. Pierson Post Office</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


