<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Considered-and-Passed-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2425 : Patient Access and Medicare Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2425</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to improve payments for complex
			 rehabilitation technology and certain radiation therapy services, to
			 ensure flexibility in applying the hardship exception for meaningful use
			 for the 2015 EHR reporting period for 2017 payment adjustments, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patient Access and Medicare Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H5E06C265BAF34DB5809F04CCF3591D4A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Non-application of Medicare fee schedule adjustments for wheelchair accessories and seat and back
			 cushions when furnished in connection with complex rehabilitative power
			 wheelchairs</header>
			<subsection id="H9F0FB24396D3421E8CD230F3412E6A0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Non-application</header>
 <paragraph id="HBCD05A29D7B44E49A464633CBEBB9E6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall not, prior to January 1, 2017, use information on the payment determined under the competitive acquisition programs under section 1847 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3</external-xref>)) to adjust the payment amount that would otherwise be recognized under section 1834(a)(1)(B)(ii) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(a)(1)(B)(ii)</external-xref>) for wheelchair accessories (including seating systems) and seat and back cushions when furnished in connection with Group 3 complex rehabilitative power wheelchairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C2AEECDC3D541BE9C049739E383BAB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may implement this subsection by program instruction or otherwise.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F1DE5A687054AF8BC74DA82B8BD9B62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study and report</header>
				<paragraph id="H594445E787A44B5180183F9DF92CDBA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF854968E655246EB8449883F419AA520"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on wheelchair accessories (including seating systems) and seat and back cushions furnished in connection with Group 3 complex rehabilitative power wheelchairs. Such study shall include an analysis of the following with respect to such wheelchair accessories and seat and back cushions in each of the groups described in clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (B):</text>
 <clause id="HF9FA3225727447E7A84064FB034F2C15"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The item descriptions and associated HCPCS codes for such wheelchair accessories and seat and back cushions.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFBD0172E9272470D8D94FA553919C941"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A breakdown of utilization and expenditures for such wheelchair accessories and seat and back cushions under title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF2622CA156A540A1B8EBD33838E79863"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A comparison of the payment amount under the competitive acquisition program under section 1847 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3</external-xref>) with the payment amount that would otherwise be recognized under section 1834 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>), including beneficiary cost sharing, for such wheelchair accessories and seat and back cushions.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9E799350EE234994B14D949CDD615809"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The aggregate distribution of such wheelchair accessories and seat and back cushions furnished under such title XVIII within each of the groups described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDE3B9DCDB11A4D48B2A2E6E151DF81D4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Other areas determined appropriate by the Comptroller General.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8679A37DFEF4BFBA35A54C29003F96B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Groups described</header><text>The following groups are described in this subparagraph:</text>
 <clause id="HE95385592B4541EF8EE0B86779925861"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Wheelchair accessories and seat and back cushions furnished predominantly with Group 3 complex rehabilitative power wheelchairs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9905C6A0C7E740639A370CAAB29D7044"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Wheelchair accessories and seat and back cushions furnished predominantly with power wheelchairs that are not described in clause (i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB3739ADB345F4152BD5E5DF289E4A7B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Other wheelchair accessories and seat and back cushions furnished with either power wheelchairs described in clause (i) or (ii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC419C936AE304B428BEB29A2812B965C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than June 1, 2016, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative as the Comptroller General determines to be appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1F57E102BDFE462E940CA5B6C6F0B5FB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transitional payment rules for certain radiation therapy services under the Medicare physician fee
			 schedule</header>
 <subsection id="H2969A03E00F541EA967CD39F2FF2533F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1848 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H351467A1F62A432C80FB912C44255C82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E617DC0A6CA4B7CB41554AE3860D2F3" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HF8C0560AD1F94DAEBFC8BE632C58759F"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Special rule for certain radiation therapy services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The code definitions, the work relative value units under subsection (c)(2)(C)(i), and the direct inputs for the practice expense relative value units under subsection (c)(2)(C)(ii) for radiation treatment delivery and related imaging services (identified in 2016 by HCPCS G-codes G6001 through G6015) for the fee schedule established under this subsection for services furnished in 2017 and 2018 shall be the same as such definitions, units, and inputs for such services for the fee schedule established for services furnished in 2016.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3E0471D68D14BFB9FA6A07A15A967BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(K), by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F90457AD7CF436BA734047FCA1B2218" style="OLC"> <clause id="HB8BB300AD26B49B48EE7F52BC77D9BFE"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Treatment of certain radiation therapy services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Radiation treatment delivery and related imaging services identified under subsection (b)(11) shall not be considered as potentially misvalued services for purposes of this subparagraph and subparagraph (O) for 2017 and 2018.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4CC00243A4B410DACA8EA53C3765442"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress on alternative payment model</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the development of an episodic alternative payment model for payment under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act for radiation therapy services furnished in nonfacility settings.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idD532E732874A4270A6F6B7CC5FC7E223"><enum>4.</enum><header>Ensuring flexibility in applying hardship exception for meaningful use
			 for 2015 EHR reporting period for 2017 payment
			 adjustments</header>
 <subsection id="idC4EDA46615EE48AFB8422AD721A0E125"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligible professionals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1848(a)(7)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(a)(7)(B)</external-xref>) is amended, in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>(and, with respect to the payment adjustment under subparagraph (A) for 2017, for categories of eligible professionals, as established by the Secretary and posted on the Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services prior to December 15, 2015, an application for which must be submitted to the Secretary by not later than March 15, 2016)</quote> after <quote>case-by-case basis</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40BEFF05E1D84D7F97486E048C4FCB5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible hospitals</header><text>Section 1886(b)(3)(B)(ix) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(b)(3)(B)(ix)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF6E3993023B24D999A8003E2953C6E28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence of subclause (I), by striking <quote>(n)(6)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>(n)(6)</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8643D399FDDB47C8AE276E594BD77F82"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (II), in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>(and, with respect to the application of subclause (I) for fiscal year 2017, for categories of subsection (d) hospitals, as established by the Secretary and posted on the Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services prior to December 15, 2015, an application for which must be submitted to the Secretary by not later than April 1, 2016)</quote> after <quote>case-by-case basis</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE6FE22849CA544E4B0BABFCA0D2653E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall implement the provisions of, and the amendments made by, subsections (a) and (b) by program instruction, such as through information on the Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23DAB2F418B94BB4992BDA4EB76DA1D7"><enum>5.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medicare Improvement Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1898(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395iii">42 U.S.C. 1395iii(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$5,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$0</quote>.</text> </section><section id="idd022cfa9-59c8-41e1-85fa-fedddb121035"><enum>6.</enum><header>Strengthening Medicaid Program integrity through flexibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1936 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-6">42 U.S.C. 1396u–6</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idbc915614-6f6e-422f-904c-cb69be82c2e5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>, or otherwise,</quote> after <quote>entities</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id74a26b39-5554-44ac-9978-f0d936a44b2e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id953c8ef8-2740-4c20-b981-a7cc5559228f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>(including the costs of equipment, salaries and benefits, and travel and training)</quote> after <quote>Program under this section</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0061925-5e68-4592-a2a4-41d1f627e904"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>by 100</quote> and inserting <quote>by 100, or such number as determined necessary by the Secretary to carry out the Program,</quote>.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ide7b74c9d-3931-4425-b9a5-34aba4e91f28"><enum>7.</enum><header>Establishing
			 Medicare administrative contractor error reduction incentives</header>
			<subsection id="idf361d676-743a-4b8b-a866-899dd282e54b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1874A(b)(1)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395kk-1">42 U.S.C. 1395kk–1(b)(1)(D)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id49d82ebf-4d9a-44bf-b0d1-17ee94682e07"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">quality</header-in-text>.—The Secretary</quote> and inserting “<header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">quality</header-in-text>.—</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65fa4cfb-ffc8-4884-8ca3-22921aa3e1f3" style="OLC"> <clause id="ida03496d0-670a-4404-8bd2-c88796e4636d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), the Secretary</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;
				and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4619574e-7bc6-4391-b0f9-8b5f70050f6c"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after clause (i), as added by paragraph (1), the following new clauses:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34f3af39-ea04-4568-bcc0-dabf277dc8c9" style="OLC">
						<clause id="id39f313a0-d19c-4eb8-b4d2-4da8e2409b40"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Improper
 payment rate reduction incentives</header><text>The Secretary shall provide incentives for medicare administrative contractors to reduce the improper payment error rates in their jurisdictions.</text>
 </clause><clause id="iddc7b5d9f-7705-4b20-85f8-b03bc782222a"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Incentives</header><text>The incentives provided for under clause (ii)—</text>
 <subclause id="id033bb3db-c5b5-4132-b52b-f3317bdbb18f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>may include a sliding scale of award fee payments and additional incentives to medicare administrative contractors that either reduce the improper payment rates in their jurisdictions to certain thresholds, as determined by the Secretary, or accomplish tasks, as determined by the Secretary, that further improve payment accuracy; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id324f1afb-3bab-4246-9e68-a46b6001f8e1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may include substantial reductions in award fee payments under cost-plus-award-fee contracts, for medicare administrative contractors that reach an upper end improper payment rate threshold or other threshold as determined by the Secretary, or fail to accomplish tasks, as determined by the Secretary, that further improve payment accuracy.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc286cacc-a41a-4896-97d6-52679dfd05fc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective
			 date</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf45ad23-78d8-456d-908f-cecdb68beb71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to contracts entered into or renewed on or after the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3eaadf03-085f-41f3-9e7c-a72d5d95b138"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to existing contracts</header><text>In the case of contracts in existence on or after the date of the enactment of this Act and that are not subject to the effective date under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, when appropriate and practicable, seek to apply the incentives provided for in the amendments made by subsection (a) through contract modifications.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4df43b97-e470-4357-acf5-e59a275cb933"><enum>8.</enum><header>Strengthening
			 penalties for the illegal distribution of a Medicare, Medicaid, or CHIP
 beneficiary identification or billing privileges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1128B(b) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b(b)) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id968f9e78-78da-4bf9-bdd6-557ead7f4afd" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idd2243dcd-01f7-45fa-908d-753506497a75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whoever without lawful authority knowingly and willfully purchases, sells or distributes, or arranges for the purchase, sale, or distribution of a beneficiary identification number or unique health identifier for a health care provider under title XVIII, title XIX, or title XXI shall be imprisoned for not more than 10 years or fined not more than $500,000 ($1,000,000 in the case of a corporation), or both.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="idcd2b5e4b-1d67-435e-a204-8da26592573e"><enum>9.</enum><header>Improving the
			 sharing of data between the Federal Government and State Medicaid
			 programs</header>
			<subsection id="id88d983ea-626b-4cb2-9f05-f180c3d3af9a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a plan to encourage and facilitate the participation of States in the Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program (commonly referred to as the <quote>Medi-Medi Program</quote>) under section 1893(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ddd">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(g)</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idd8638cd5-2bca-43bb-9af1-4e74f4125d05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program
			 revisions To improve Medi-Medi Data Match Program participation by
 States</header><text>Section 1893(g)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ddd">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(g)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide523c79e-b876-4f6c-9de3-111466c2ecd7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>or otherwise</quote> after <quote>eligible entities</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide9042c33-f3ef-40b9-b8ad-81f2920c6e31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idf1a80355-d659-4816-81d2-4d8ec80fc36d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>to review claims data</quote> after <quote>algorithms</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d35257c-07b6-4a21-8ea8-839a8744537e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>service, time, or patient</quote> and inserting <quote>provider, service, time, or patient</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a7a5700-56dd-4a4a-aa8b-f8203d61a7bf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ided555ccb-908d-46ee-a8df-5daa50fa7ef2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>to investigate and recover amounts with respect to suspect claims</quote> after <quote>appropriate actions</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57a35064-8a47-419e-8d80-b25f2638192d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8ac3c00-c6fd-4fb5-9673-2492ca782810"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period and inserting<quote> ; and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id796cada4-ecb9-41d1-bc19-17e8175afba0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1327bc05-26b4-4fcb-bf53-d4a5657fa396" style="OLC">
 <clause id="id83c837c4-a85e-4e52-a592-a0b6b05dabd4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>furthering the Secretary’s design, development, installation, or enhancement of an automated data system architecture—</text>
 <subclause id="ida326895c-0e92-4644-a088-a904bc1262e1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to collect, integrate, and assess data for purposes of program integrity, program oversight, and administration, including the Medi-Medi Program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9ec53202-025a-4532-a9b3-fa13a4e5a0a7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that improves the coordination of requests for data from States.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7aa97ed5-8e4f-4186-98af-1552d2cc382a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Providing
			 states with data on improper payments made for items or services provided
			 to
			 dual eligible individuals</header>
				<paragraph id="idc2e63baf-f983-4edd-8c87-d6df47701897"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement a plan that allows each State agency responsible for administering a State plan for medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act access to relevant data on improper or fraudulent payments made under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) for health care items or services provided to dual eligible individuals.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id60e8d7ca-357e-4084-9fb0-4daf516ca105"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dual eligible
 individual defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>dual eligible individual</term> means an individual who is entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395c">42 U.S.C. 1395c et seq.</external-xref>), or enrolled for benefits under part B of title XVIII of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395j">42 U.S.C. 1395j et seq.</external-xref>), and is eligible for medical assistance under a State plan under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) or under a waiver of such plan.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


