<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1324 RS: Affordable Reliable Electricity Now Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 283</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1324</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 114–159]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150513">May 13, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S379">Mr. Perdue</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S261">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S136">Mr. Cochran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSEV00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>October 29, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</sponsor>, without amendment</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to fulfill certain requirements
			 before regulating standards of performance for new, modified, and
			 reconstructed fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating units, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8EAEF2C382D74ACABB934AC2000772B4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H105002D1EDE246DCB46075CD307EC4F1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Reliable Electricity Now Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAC2820174E8C4362A70FB2DCF4E67AC3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H65272C02ACC347929D6F88A8A4921E1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6DE2513EA3C54590B7C3F92E3B8C99EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Demonstration project</header><text>The term <term>demonstration project</term> means a project to test or demonstrate the feasibility of a carbon capture and storage technology that has Federal Government funding or financial assistance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H819F0098829F4A268027A10B68CD0C84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Existing source</header><text>The term <term>existing source</term> has the meaning given the term in section 111(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(a)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H58504F9E81CD4C38BEC4B307EA0CEC86"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas</header><text>The term <term>greenhouse gas</term> means any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD8249221DBD24F78A68157BB26EFE44C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Carbon dioxide.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FDF2F917BBB42038A161540834C2B9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Methane.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AAA5BC7AA5F46DFA07A22DD60B390F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nitrous oxide.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE694DB42DE824E3B8DC25E1E186C5937"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Sulfur hexafluoride.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7AB0AB86895479C9120B756ABF9EF18"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Hydrofluorocarbons.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B219A1A697942ACA2CD314B14DDCD6A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Perfluorocarbons.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A442C5390344D0F9AE9F4E8383A132A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Modification</header><text>The term <term>modification</term> has the meaning given the term in section 111(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(a)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2B9A9B981864045AADAE41F1E1A813D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Modified source</header><text>The term <term>modified source</term> means any stationary source, the modification of which is commenced after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65366F2E1CB34B16B6A3BF9682507B65"><enum>(7)</enum><header>New source</header><text>The term <term>new source</term> has the meaning given the term in section 111(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(a)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16F7497747884892BDC409736F496EC5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reconstructed source</header><text>The term <term>reconstructed source</term> means any stationary source, the reconstruction (as defined in section 60.15 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act)) of which is commenced after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HDBB222DA7B07473BA16BD12B4B349C0D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Standards of performance for new, modified, and reconstructed fossil fuel-fired electric utility
			 generating units</header>
 <subsection id="H71A9E4F0C2F242A3B46527FB74FC8354"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Administrator may not issue, implement, or enforce any proposed or final rule, in whole or in part, under section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>) that establishes a standard of performance for emissions of any greenhouse gas from any new source, modified source, or reconstructed source that is a fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating unit, unless that rule meets the requirements of subsections (b) and (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H88DD74E2314A49A7B51C0D6339EF9E1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In issuing any rule pursuant to section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>) establishing standards of performance for emissions of any greenhouse gas from new sources, modified sources, or reconstructed sources that are fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating units, the Administrator, for purposes of establishing those standards—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2A9DD97357CD44B28F6E3D67CA847A15"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall separate sources fueled with coal and natural gas into separate categories; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC465C2FA7E4E4D7387F6D1FF507C5B81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not establish a standard based on the best system of emission reduction for new sources within a fossil-fuel category unless—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEB601629822C4910B182E72C74570A1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the standard has been achieved, on average, for at least 1 continuous 12-month period (excluding planned outages) by each of at least 6 units within that category—</text>
 <clause id="H1165C6DB96474CADBA2DD161004C7C7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each of which is located at a different electric generating station in the United States;</text> </clause><clause id="HEC1FA3FA72034A8FB6F87C542A451F4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, collectively, are representative of the operating characteristics of electric generation at different locations in the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C11F8342115492ABEBE2B0667B2E8B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each of which is operated for the entire 12-month period on a full commercial basis; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC38C8C3BE8294A5FB43AD0E4A458E051"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no results obtained from any demonstration project are used in setting the standard.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3F0B8553A9624C7CA8BE4988D7B5E4AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coal with certain heat content</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC56F285942CA4DFFB2E5B26FE8A431F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Separate subcategory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (b)(1), the Administrator shall establish a separate subcategory for new sources, modified sources, or reconstructed sources that are fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating units using coal with an average heat content of 8,300 or less British Thermal Units per pound.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D41FF1AB4E34C7F91634C917495C286"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (b)(2), in issuing any rule pursuant to section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>) establishing standards of performance for emissions of any greenhouse gas from new, modified, or reconstructed sources in the subcategory referred to in paragraph (1), the Administrator shall not establish a standard based on the best system of emission reduction unless—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCEAA09FC0768476986E016636D813CDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that standard has been achieved, on average, for at least 1 continuous 12-month period (excluding planned outages) by each of at least 3 units within that subcategory—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H70CA5093C2524F21BA0A3E58A30E284F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each of which is located at a different electric generating station in the United States;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD803D7C365674C59A8D9D1D03A35AF1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which, collectively, are representative of the operating characteristics of electric generation at different locations in the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HAA15F5C66E3C4D208ABACFC8B5EA53A6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each of which is operated for the entire 12-month period on a full commercial basis; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4B89FDDED04F4D28944B7446835B33C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no results obtained from any demonstration project are used in establishing that standard.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE7F195F6166A4455A5ADFFE78C8FFA70"><enum>4.</enum><header>Standards of performance for existing fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating units,
			 compliance extension, and ratepayer protection</header>
			<subsection id="id0B463974ECCA4B529C3FE6852F5EA7E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header>
 <paragraph id="idBE25AA1946474E5494665C88106C3EB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may not issue, implement, or enforce any proposed or final rule described in paragraph (2), unless that rule meets the requirements of subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7385A911C14F400F8F065086D36A7179"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Description of rule</header><text>A rule referred to in paragraph (1) is any proposed or final rule to address carbon dioxide emissions from existing sources that are fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating units under section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>), including any final rule that succeeds—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7eab9d0a05074fa48532d38b5c4c9b42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposed rule entitled <quote>Carbon Pollution Emission Guidelines for Existing Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 34830 (June 18, 2014)); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6AE691277964494B92677CCABFD10912"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the supplemental proposed rule entitled <quote>Carbon Pollution Emission Guidelines for Existing Stationary Sources: EGUs in Indian Country and U.S. Territories; Multi-Jurisdictional Partnerships</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 65482 (November 4, 2014)).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFE8141710635454D8EBAD25395A9831B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF388D0C116DA4B91AD9E6C284B45527D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before issuing, implementing, or enforcing any rule described in subsection (a)(2), the Administrator shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd85917041dce441daf4f92bf5097ef19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report describing the quantity of greenhouse gas emissions that the rule is projected to reduce, as compared to overall domestic and global greenhouse gas emissions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40bacc148bad46199aeeeac8e1a596c1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct modeling regarding the means by which the source rule in effect on the date of development of the proposed rule, if applicable, impacts each climate indicator used by the Administrator in developing the proposed rule; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2504102eb762438bba05eac359c00260"><enum>(C)</enum><text>issue State-specific model plans to demonstrate with specificity the areas in, and means by which, each State will be required to reduce the greenhouse gas emissions of the State under the rule.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ided3687381404401e81ae47e20d571c3a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>A court shall not consider paragraph (1) in determining whether the Administrator is authorized to issue any rule described in subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9F29989FA55B41F49DF62E20688A5EE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ratepayer protections</header><text>No State shall be required to adopt or submit a State plan, and no State or entity within a State shall become subject to a Federal plan, pursuant to any final rule described in subsection (a), if the Governor of the State makes a determination, and notifies the Administrator, that implementation of the State or Federal plan would have a negative effect on—</text>
 <paragraph id="idC8F2D9405E8D49F7AC155676798179FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>economic growth, competitiveness, and jobs in the State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idADE436328FB342D38CD4C7B128F985AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reliability of the electricity system of the State; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFBFB04F88FC741259AC4E1523EE9E75B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the electricity ratepayers of the State, including low-income ratepayers, by causing electricity rate increases.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb17de867455e45e09c51bbf622ef80ed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extension of compliance dates</header>
				<paragraph id="id9EA81B247EC44E07984525AA202C08F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of compliance date</header>
 <subparagraph id="idBE38458C8CAC4A638496868D60AF49EE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>compliance date</term> means, with respect to any requirement of a final rule described in subsection (a)(2), the date by which any State, local, or tribal government or other person is first required to comply with the requirement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54AF4D36D29F42698F5F2DB7DF4A5404"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>compliance date</term> includes the date by which State plans are required to be submitted to the Administrator under any final rule described in subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide69c1200bdd74735971de4d17fe2bfd1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>Each compliance date of any final rule described in subsection (a)(2) is deemed to be extended by the time period equal to the time period described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8fa3be3449114352af4d1739a40d0161"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period described</header><text>The time period described in this paragraph is the period of days that—</text> <subparagraph id="id74bfad453b234bc78e4a31ba3581759e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>begins on the date that is 60 days after the day on which notice of promulgation of a final rule described in subsection (a)(2) appears in the Federal Register; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideee515beb00f464d850c081babbd98e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ends on the date on which judgement becomes final, and no longer subject to further appeal or review, in all actions (including any action filed pursuant to section 307 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7607">42 U.S.C. 7607</external-xref>)) that—</text>
 <clause id="idfdf2d2f1f32049269c1f3e0cd0f2d356"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are filed during the 60 days described in paragraph (A); and</text> </clause><clause id="id07e9ca537e1e4ae99f73a1cd321814de"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>seek review of any aspect of the rule.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id76aea3ed83274011b728c6876e3b887d"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on effect of noncompliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, noncompliance by a State with any proposed, modified, or final rule described in section 3 or 4 applicable to any new, modified, reconstructed, or existing source shall not constitute a reason for imposing any highway sanction under section 179(b)(1) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7509">42 U.S.C. 7509(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="HB3958982FBF3486E8F83AEDF36BBBD4B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Repeal of earlier rules and guidelines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following rules shall be of no force or effect, and shall be treated as though the rules had never been issued:</text>
 <paragraph id="H75E66C37CBC3416097B9797E2771393F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The proposed rule—</text> <subparagraph id="H06BD2FA21FA540B0BF103A56052016EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entitled <quote>Standards of Performance for Greenhouse Gas Emissions for New Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> (77 Fed. Reg. 22392 (April 13, 2012)); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09B17479B05F477E876D1F05FEE533B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>withdrawn pursuant to the notice entitled <quote>Withdrawal of Proposed Standards of Performance for Greenhouse Gas Emissions for New Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 1352 (January 8, 2014)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7618AFF18D294F8498964924A2BE435B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The proposed rule entitled <quote>Standards of Performance for Greenhouse Gas Emissions from New Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 1430 (January 8, 2014)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id88775bc6e0894c06bd5de6a488831778"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The proposed rule entitled <quote>Carbon Pollution Standards for Modified and Reconstructed Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 34960 (June 18, 2014)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E3BBEA72B8D44478E6C17805488D516"><enum>(4)</enum><text>With respect to the proposed rules described in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), any successor or substantially similar proposed or final rule that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H15ECD4E113F44A7DB482F1022F1947EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is issued prior to the date of enactment of this Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE81259CCB51C4E308ACC93800B0D062E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is applicable to any new, modified, or reconstructed source that is a fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating unit; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BE5BD5B5DE748D3B48BD8CDF65DB552"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not meet the requirements under subsections (b) and (c) of section 3.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54744F55C1714FA386981949D35703E9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any proposed or final rule or guideline under section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>) that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0AFCE1C061954385B5641645886BAD2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is issued prior to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B36703C9E1A48E4BCEAEE8E18574D52"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishes any standard of performance for emissions of any greenhouse gas from any modified source or reconstructed source that is a fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating unit or apply to the emissions of any greenhouse gas from an existing source that is a fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating unit.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idC449C308D8E34058A9BEFB82EB663B79"><enum>7.</enum><header>Restatement of existing law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 111(d) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id98F600FC2349473BB73350A5ABF36C4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(d)(1) The Administrator</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7FF1E6E23B5C4B93850E5295D5CC0217" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="idDEC4ABFE927B4AA4BA772590FB74EE5D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Standards of performance for existing sources; remaining useful life of source</header>
 <paragraph id="idEB9E2A8E2468453CACD2FA3A05BC9043"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB79207541DE04D1D857885BDAF5A1CC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)(i), by striking <quote>section 108(a) or</quote> and all that follows through <quote>but</quote> and insert <quote>section 108(a) or emitted from a source category that is regulated under section 112, but</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3583C5DA607A481A93D352A7472D05C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(2) The Administrator</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9EEAF24874104CEC8F7A4FA1AD9CDB9B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idB102F946AACA41188DEAD2B46078F5D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority of the Administrator</header><text>The Administrator</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1DE07E0DD3874E5EADCD1D6A222181A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the undesignated matter at the end, by striking <quote>In promulgating a standard</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id363C114C22FA455C875E89A4823F16A0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id7790AB53732C456E9E5579C8648AAAEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In promulgating a standard</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6EE690133BFF4FC3AFCCE93AA71E5766"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB263331D7AA5455290026926F93A3C41" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id890B7D4B2BB447B3B34EC2DCD7CA02EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Administrator shall not regulate as an existing source under this subsection any source category regulated under section 112.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>October 29, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported without amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


