<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2430 IS: Travel Facilitation and Safety Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2430</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To permit the recovery of costs incurred by U.S. Customs and Border Protection for preclearance
			 operations activities, and for
			 other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H53E79652C5784C9C8E8FD821FDD49B81" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF205EF042B84482796D33968FF0ABFFD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Travel Facilitation and Safety Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id68BD1390C4B84B6EA9D7878541FBCC8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recovery of initial preclearance operation costs</header> <subsection id="id4c3e6e33af6c43d392cb3bfd9ae61bdd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cost sharing agreements with relevant airport authorities</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may enter into a cost sharing agreement with airport authorities in foreign countries at which preclearance operations are to be established or maintained if—</text>
 <paragraph id="id410770355eca41fe879e2ec79c63696d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an executive agreement to establish or maintain such preclearance operations pursuant to the authorities under section 629 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1629">19 U.S.C. 1629</external-xref>) and section 103(a)(7) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1103">8 U.S.C. 1103(a)(7)</external-xref>) has been signed, but has not yet entered into force; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf1a988fda67d475aacae2d07c36ed07c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>U.S. Customs and Border Protection has incurred, or expects to incur, initial preclearance operations costs in order to establish or maintain preclearance operations under the agreement described in paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0672e8a8ca6f40e8ba1620f57d4e1a61"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of cost sharing agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="id10cf43b5640746828494b39899e24aaa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 13031(e) of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c(e)</external-xref>) and section 286(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(g)</external-xref>), any cost sharing agreement authorized under subsection (a) may provide for the airport authority’s payment to U.S. Customs and Border Protection of its initial preclearance operations costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2295f7851a534c539b003c4a49446464"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing of payments</header><text>The airport authority’s payment to U.S. Customs and Border Protection for its initial preclearance operations costs may be made in advance of the incurrence of the costs or on a reimbursable basis.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id800ac6f3f4054497815898ec4c18f838"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Account</header>
 <paragraph id="ide478c74296c840bea11fec2dcbb5bcb9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All amounts collected pursuant to any cost sharing agreement authorized under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="id32aa1b460cf444a380e261ce1ed65627"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be credited as offsetting collections to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a6e467bb5bb4ca5a2234d6c68cb973d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall remain available, until expended, for the purposes for which such appropriation, account, or fund is authorized to be used; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0db2e7839b0e4d1cb5bd3bea080a9893"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may be collected and shall be available only to the extent provided in appropriations Acts.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id50f11fd64f9048c6ac9369af16e3aedd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Return of unused funds</header><text>Any advances or reimbursements not used by U.S. Customs and Border Protection may be returned to the relevant airport authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id006692d20d444f2a9142b2213e6697a5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to preclude the use of appropriated funds, from sources other than the payments collected under this Act, to pay initial preclearance operation costs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4fe754fe4e6b464aa435175d1a0bf4ec"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Initial preclearance operations costs defined</header>
 <paragraph id="id31e7bfd4aa0345dc9c50a4691b4a644b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <term>initial preclearance operations costs</term> means the costs incurred, or expected to be incurred, by U.S. Customs and Border Protection to establish or maintain preclearance operations at an airport in a foreign country, including costs relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idcd0790cf9db44c419f5eb08e6f1f03dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hiring, training, and equipping new officers of U.S. Customs and Border Protection who will be stationed at United States domestic ports of entry or other facilities of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to backfill such officers to be stationed at an airport in a foreign country to conduct preclearance operations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72e3d8d061794fc4b7b9afc9f80a2489"><enum>(B)</enum><text>visits to the airport authority conducted by personnel of U.S. Customs and Border Protection necessary to prepare for the establishment or maintenance of preclearance operations at such airport, including the compensation, travel expenses, and allowances payable to such personnel attributable to such visits.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id81c8a9609bd64b31b472bf845c2e3e58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The costs described in paragraph (1)(A) shall not include the salaries and benefits of new officers of U.S. Customs and Border Protection once such officers are permanently stationed at a domestic United States port of entry or other domestic facility of U.S. Customs and Border Protection after being hired, trained, and equipped.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0e8e78d0eaf2403f9845b21f0fda5ca9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Collection and disposition of funds collected for immigration inspection services and preclearance
			 activities</header>
 <subsection id="id8fce5c89fcb44d0983eca97567661c39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Immigration and Nationality Act</header><text>Section 286(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the last sentence and inserting <quote>Reimbursements under this subsection may be collected in advance of the provision of such immigration inspection services. Notwithstanding subsection (h)(1)(B), and only to the extent provided in appropriations Acts, any amounts collected under this subsection shall be credited as offsetting collections to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, remain available until expended, and be available for the purposes for which such appropriation, account, or fund is authorized to be used.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7509707d27ee48ffb8a8c5482cd761df"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002</header><text>Section 10412(b) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8311">7 U.S.C. 8311(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82804442ddf14bcdb48c4d81dff27018" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id6525f82921ed44fcbcc51fbe582cb600"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funds collected for preclearance</header><text>Funds collected for preclearance activities—</text> <paragraph id="id5a12504090404672aec12c3d7dc4f6b1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be collected in advance of the provision of such activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id17bdd40df2064d67a978d9a6d3bbbd29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be credited as offsetting collections to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id71201541bd544ab494ff585fb2190b50"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall remain available until expended;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id44a35227968349bb95462e6424a2c5d5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall be available for the purposes for which such appropriation, account, or fund is authorized to be used; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id248ac0360d5a47ee98c23378d197ada5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>may be collected and shall be available only to the extent provided in appropriations Acts.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section><section id="idc08fa909e72944b29011e60715ef00d2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expansion of preclearance at foreign airports</header> <subsection id="id01ced0790c864d84a5138bdab67a04ba"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="id7a8e919b22f24edbb34077b43b08af0f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Preclearance operations provide the ultimate ability for the United States to address potential threats at the earliest possible moment and prior to departure, through the forward deployment of officers of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to last points of departure in a foreign country.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id718d77d8fdc34cf19ae7b95eee285671"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With inspections and examination operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection located in a foreign country, preclearance provides the capability to interdict, address, and work with host-country law enforcement in furtherance of both aviation security and border security in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f81c07d6c994c4eaa2f62ce66e5d4ad"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Under current preclearance operations, officers of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection collect biometrics in the same way that is currently done upon arrival in the United States, in accordance with current regulation, and as part of the routine entry process from certain aliens who are not citizens of the United States prior to boarding flights destined to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id97f64d04f4f34966bbf43499215b8df1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Preclearance operations provide the best means for existing and future biometric security capabilities beyond the United States. Support for preclearance expansion will greatly increase border and aviation security in the United States and foreign countries.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd1d83eeaa39046be8af117eb87792ec1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that each country designated as a visa waiver program country under section 217 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1187">8 U.S.C. 1187</external-xref>) should seek to participate in the preclearance program with the United States, to jointly address security concerns through additional exchange of information and to improve joint ability to secure the that visa waiver program while maintaining the original intent of the program.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idbf76fbec5f12426e869ba510fe2fab6f"><enum>5.</enum><header>Biometric demonstration programs at preclearance locations</header>
 <subsection id="idcaeb99a44c1e41b09c60951196a9e995"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized to select preclearance locations, including preclearance expansion locations, and enter into an agreement with a foreign government or airport to conduct a collaborative biometric demonstration program at such a location to test emerging biometric technologies. The scope of the demonstration program may encompass travelers other than those utilizing preclearance at such a location, provided that such program includes means for information sharing with U.S. Customs and Border Protection operations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idc943be8d353845b6b84f94242e177dfa"><enum>(b)</enum><header>International cooperation and coordination</header><text>Section 233(a) of the Security and Accountability For Every Port Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/983">6 U.S.C. 983(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="ida4c589fdf467487899860db4669334f5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and to establish and maintain, in partnership with foreign governments, demonstration programs to test emerging biometric technologies at foreign airports at which the Secretary has established preclearance operations.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id01174d4bf44a4200b274f78a84125482"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="id303FB76693874598AB15878F86BDC03E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3D3D2B2A4B524F6BAF8FAEF243ABE690"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon and <quote>and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF974BE85DBE84F6B9AB955FFD71ED4D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a83e586cdfa4cdba355877c1a007615" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id79df7d9dfbb1400da4edbc8b356ae28e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lease, loan, provide, or otherwise assist in the deployment of biometric technologies at foreign airports at which the Secretary has established preclearance operations under such terms and conditions as the Secretary prescribes, including nonreimbursable loans or the transfer of ownership of such technologies, and provide the necessary training and technical assistance related to the biometric demonstration programs referred to in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idEA3568D8D48642D29079EF268B822D64"><enum>6.</enum><header>Visa waiver program requirements</header>
 <subsection id="idA08223E4EDAC4BFAB1DAFF2AAC257C34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Information sharing process</header><text>The Director of National Intelligence shall—</text> <paragraph id="id1EC3F56E071641D48F18D8EE74C9274B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a process to share information derived from the Terrorist Identities Datamart Environment (TIDE) database and the Terrorist Screening Database (TSDB), including biometric and biographic information, with countries participating in the visa waiver program established under section 217(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1187">8 U.S.C. 1187(a)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id43C263FA09674F02A447A92F8AC50CB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, certify to Congress that such process may be utilized by such countries.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24956B8AC48242CEBEA6A2B00C6DDF58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuing qualification and designation
 terminations</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 217 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1187">8 U.S.C. 1187</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4AE26AAE87274D0F8F1C9A7DBD6D0D67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Attorney General,</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id60F14C1F4FCD482185827F9F0CF7C0C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="idC44D0B3D40B043108E25D160B1627C25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(iii)—</text>
 <clause id="HE6A505B157C34753892D6F8D45FC8A78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and the Committee on International Relations</quote> and inserting <quote>, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Homeland Security</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA7E00A905F354A0FA51481CED18F86BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and the Committee on Foreign Relations</quote> and inserting <quote>, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4BEF118F24874464903205345B6E383A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFF92F019E0CC437A9478D4DF0A8FE649" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idC7F80AF4E4C643C5BBC574BDB70B8B0B"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Border security</header><text>The government of the country utilizes the process developed by the Director of National Intelligence under section 6(a) of the <short-title>Travel Facilitation and Safety Act of 2015</short-title> to utilize information derived from the Terrorist Identities Datamart Environment (TIDE) database and the Terrorist Screening Database (TSDB) for border security and immigration purposes, including the screening of aliens seeking asylum or refugee status in that country.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


