<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="private"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S955 IS: For the relief of Vichai Sae Tung (also known as Chai Chaowasaree).</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">VI</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 955</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150415">April 15, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>For the relief of Vichai Sae Tung (also known as Chai Chaowasaree).</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8019DE006FBE4C0091DD9CBEB1942EF4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Permanent
 residence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for purposes of the <act-name parsable-cite="INA">Immigration and Nationality Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>), Vichai Sae Tung (also known as Chai Chaowasaree) shall be held and considered to have been lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence as of the date of the enactment of this Act upon payment of the required visa fees.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID6B1E9F25F7D54493994F00DDF3482FA3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reduction of number of
 available visas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon the granting of permanent residence to Vichai Sae Tung (also known as Chai Chaowasaree), as provided in this Act, the Secretary of State shall instruct the proper officer to reduce by the appropriate number during the current fiscal year the total number of immigrant visas available to natives of the country of the alien’s birth under section 203(a) of the <act-name parsable-cite="INA">Immigration and Nationality Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>).</text></section></legis-body></bill>


