<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S144 IS: Local Leadership in Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 144</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150109">January 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S184">Mr. Shelby</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit the Federal Government from mandating, incentivizing, or making financial support
			 conditioned upon a State, local educational agency, or school's adoption
			 of specific instructional content, academic standards, or curriculum, or
			 on the administration of assessments or tests, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Leadership in Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id8444B68F598145B6A267E031D3AF2BC1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibitions in the Elementary and Secondary Education Act</header><subsection id="idE3E811B476A04AB0B049B3B62D589C5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General Prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9527 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7907">20 U.S.C. 7907</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id4E23F82B339B425A9B0CFBA31B2BE818"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsections (a) and (b) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id370E1C7E2E31425BA56A28CB2FEBF1EA" style="OLC"><subsection id="id8DE35DB2A14047B6A3EAADC8DE1698CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General prohibitions</header><paragraph id="id983BE219BD6B4062AFC4EAF7B72F111C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An officer or employee of the Federal Government shall not directly or indirectly, through grants, contracts, or other cooperative agreements under this Act (including waivers under section 9401)—</text><subparagraph id="id3DC63D9BA7D54A799D6B7BDF1E3F19C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mandate, direct, or control a State, local educational agency, or school's academic standards, curriculum, program of instruction, or allocation of State or local resources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0366B39A30054382B58FBC46B53C2D91"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mandate a State or any subdivision thereof to spend any funds or incur any costs not paid for under this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0E0089A0EC624D6B879F30584B36EECC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incentivize a State, local educational agency, or school to adopt any specific academic standards or a specific curriculum or program of instruction, which shall include providing any priority, preference, or special consideration during an application process based on any specific academic standards, curriculum, or program of instruction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id435B7EF43A264F69814CD4939E06FD6F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>make financial support available in a manner that is conditioned upon a State, local educational agency, or school's adoption of specific instructional content, academic standards, or curriculum, or on the administration of assessments or tests, even if such requirements are specified in this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9136ADFCE7E843FA9B3059402EF2FF0D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>mandate or require States to administer assessments or tests to students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id32D95F6426924B7482DA8EF71B03BBB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize an officer or employee of the Federal Government directly or indirectly, whether through grants, contracts, or other cooperative agreements under this Act (including waivers under section 9401), to do any activity prohibited under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id6B6266003EFD4012B4E976B200C66603"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8EC0A9C4AA794E68A535626509C4469B" style="OLC"><subsection id="id10C361D594EF43DA926EAFC51B001CE1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on assessments in title I</header><text>Part A of title I shall be carried out without regard to any requirement that a State carry out academic assessments or that local educational agencies, elementary schools, and secondary schools make adequate yearly progress.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0FC52EEF749D4BA4ABC213D386EC57C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on waiver conditions, requirements, or preferences</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9401 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7861">20 U.S.C. 7861</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2560177C6629457CA5B74A225029769A" style="OLC"><subsection id="id99603B422E7D4E2D9BB6C15299B51E58"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition on waiver conditions</header><paragraph id="idDF832F77C58E49449344BAB17918C6EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not establish as a condition for granting a waiver under this section—</text><subparagraph id="idD35120670A1345179E2C84DA40F0B567"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the approval of academic standards by the Federal government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBDD1199EBFC743F49E019305D283D308"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the administration of assessments or tests to students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7A394276A09E41778DACBFD5725A4F14"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect on previously issued waivers</header><subparagraph id="id45CA5514BDFD47DAADEA76E7D63D85BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any requirement described in paragraph (1) that was required for a waiver provided to a State, local educational agency, Indian tribe, or school under this section before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Local Leadership in Education Act</short-title> shall be void and have no force of law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16198E078DB04DD0B47783C6826D7CC8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibited actions</header><text>The Secretary shall not—</text><clause id="idA90EFFAD6BEE4D13BD681200DF7B3116"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enforce any requirement that is void pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="id994272E0109444F7A5A0F50FCB748DB8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require the State, local educational agency, Indian tribe, or school to reapply for a waiver, or to agree to any other condition to replace any requirement that is void pursuant to subparagraph (A), until the end of the period of time specified under the waiver.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC8C08711C0F6435BABB58FEBC1E2FE59"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No effect on other provisions</header><text>Any other provisions or requirements of a waiver provided under this section before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Local Leadership in Education Act</short-title> that are not affected by subparagraph (A) shall remain in effect for the period of time specified under the waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id3D6DA9514C434FFE886C2342D737901B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition in the General Education Provisions Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 438 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232a">20 U.S.C. 1232a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id416CE159B85E48089E5FC70BA712FAF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>No provision of any applicable program shall be construed to authorize any department, agency, officer, or employee of the United States to</quote> and inserting <quote>A department, agency, officer, or employee of the United States shall not</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95F1A003377F4ECEB7CE840057AAFEAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(including the development of curriculum)</quote> after <quote>over the curriculum</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0EE2EDCFCC5C4B5B99ADBE9A94CF83F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>to</quote> after <quote>institution or school system, or</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idCBD70830C2364E0680755C7D3B844923"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition in Race to the Top Funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XIV of Division A of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 14007 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9E88B84161284AFEAC010AF3646EB8B0" style="OLC"><section id="idD6874CE4F3534360A83F3FB864A73E7E"><enum>14007A.</enum><header>Prohibition on assessments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds provided under section 14006 of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, 123 Stat. 283) shall be used to develop, pilot test, field test, implement, administer, or distribute any assessment or testing materials.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


