<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1432 IS: Carbon Fiber Recycling Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1432</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Energy to conduct a study on the technology, potential lifecycle energy
			 savings, and economic impact of recycled carbon fiber, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="idAFCB3C9F817C403B83C78EA41B930828" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Carbon Fiber Recycling Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id8CA6A6C1B24A4AE4AC1755AF343815BF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recycled carbon fiber study</header> <subsection id="id32C6CDA539934D6E911F54FEFD411F6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5feab954dfe14fea8d01e1e8c833e80c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>current methods for manufacturing carbon fiber are energy intensive, making carbon fiber costly for use in mass-produced applications;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id79bbd123a84d47f09cf7d218cb9adc78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>it takes approximately one-tenth the energy to produce recycled carbon fiber as it does to produce virgin carbon fiber;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb3a161d7e0804796ab13b4627e4adfca"><enum>(3)</enum><text>using recycled carbon fiber in the manufacturing process could result in as great as 40 percent in cost savings compared to the manufacture of virgin fiber; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id69d231d87ed94b499a79dae16dcdce47"><enum>(4)</enum><text>up to 30 percent of carbon fiber manufactured becomes part of the waste stream.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF3F604541E7544A685DB2727FA2DC610"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary of Energy (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct a study on—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5E2B99A40B0A46D196303F1E36F34C59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the technology of recycled carbon fiber and production waste carbon fiber; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1DC2FA5C95034B89B3C25EA77459B6CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the potential lifecycle energy savings and economic impact of recycled carbon fiber.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id530ba105d76b4b36af02e9a95ddb23e6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Factors for consideration</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (b), the Secretary shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="id513801d0313849a0ad4d8a3aee49d347"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the quantity of recycled carbon fiber or production waste carbon fiber that would make the use of recycled carbon fiber or production waste carbon fiber economically viable;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb7a91fd645a44a4686efb591cc877fe4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any existing or potential barriers to recycling carbon fiber or using recycled carbon fiber;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2704ab956a984f1e9dbc323aa2f5956e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any financial incentives that may be necessary for the development of recycled carbon fiber or production waste carbon fiber;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb34c2e09fc5440909ccc383ddb9fff2f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the potential lifecycle savings in energy from producing recycled carbon fiber, as compared to producing new carbon fiber;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddf37ce5e8ac346a6a924e6e65bc1fb55"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the best and highest use for recycled carbon fiber;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id066fe98da9ee40d5963e37a91e2389a6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the potential reduction in carbon dioxide emissions from producing recycled carbon fiber, as compared to producing new carbon fiber;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4566e9a943e64a1d8e7c2e99f346ea88"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any economic benefits gained from using recycled carbon fiber or production waste carbon fiber;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2a7ec99704694941b0819e06eed851d2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>workforce training and skills needed to address labor demands in the development of recycled carbon fiber or production waste carbon fiber; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb868a0f3032e4a01a55a6c17c7dead16"><enum>(9)</enum><text>how the Department of Energy can leverage existing efforts in the industry on the use of production waste carbon fiber.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8386c5fb117b43e0ad39d5c7c7828fa7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the results of the study conducted under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id4dd249484bd74a4b818d43c0955efba5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recycled carbon fiber demonstration project</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall consult with the aviation and automotive industries and existing programs of the Advanced Manufacturing Office of the Department of Energy to develop a carbon fiber recycling demonstration project.</text>
 </section><section id="id2afe8280062a451fb99a4536c557ed5e"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $10,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


