<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1917 IS: To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to an entity that receives compensation for facilitating the donation of fetal tissue derived from an abortion.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1917</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150803">August 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to an entity that receives compensation for facilitating
			 the donation of fetal tissue derived from an abortion.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Limitation on funding</header>
 <subsection id="idc188ef768f7e4b4b802cfe92709c255d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds shall be made available to any affiliate, subsidiary, successor, or clinic of the Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., if that affiliate, subsidiary, successor, or clinic receives compensation for facilitating the donation of fetal tissue products derived from an abortion.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9cb7435a48ca455083b963c2d512e816"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="id48717234320f4ebdb0588c934036dc3d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affect any limitation contained in an appropriations Act relating to abortion; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida909194980ce4e20be474808996f5e15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce overall Federal funding available in support of women’s health.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDEE6C75509694D839EE9E8BC06454A4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investigation and report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall conduct an investigation, and submit to Congress a report on the findings of such investigation, concerning whether or not the Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., or any of its affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, or clinics has engaged in any illegal activity pertaining to fetal tissue products.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


