<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S355 IS: Teach Safe Relationships Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 355</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150203">February 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To support the provision of safe relationship behavior education and training.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Teach Safe Relationships Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id9D8A8116433443BF9C0AC19CD290DB11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fund for the improvement of education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7241">20 U.S.C. 7241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0F2F86F825E1441E856BD604B0760F46" style="OLC">
				<subpart id="id1741ECF3E09A4169931E04313570B207" style="OLC"><enum>22</enum><header>Providing safe relationship behavior education and training</header>
 <section id="id38BC0EF9C8B84F2C887FD2409FF4F372"><enum>5621.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This subpart may be cited as the <quote>Teach Safe Relationships Act of 2015</quote>.</text> </section><section id="idcb363118c15848788579590ce15b2f56"><enum>5622.</enum><header>Statement of purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this subpart:</text>
 <paragraph id="id322b8b918efb42a6939e8619de2b4a0c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To help ensure that all students receive evidence-informed safe relationship behavior education and training, including education and training regarding the prevention of teen and adolescent dating violence or relationship abuse, domestic abuse, and sexual violence and harassment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcbfda8f91e8b4f1586f7e396d0dfad90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To promote safe and healthy relationships between and among students.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id293dcec06a32494489a4b244f9e80010"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To help students and school faculty and staff to develop healthy and respectful attitudes and insights necessary for students to understand themselves in the context of relationships with others and with society.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6ae753d2905d4a779a7f3689c8389cd7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To provide financial assistance to support local educational agencies in meeting the requirements of title IX of the Educational Amendments of 1972.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id0fa1b5215fdb46998bac5f810768b318"><enum>5623.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="id35b05c721e5440c6bdf8cad9f67b2cde"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Educating students about safe relationship behavior will aid in the prevention of unsafe dating practices, including dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idec22900234314f19a3de5e1e54b3b2c9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The <short-title>Violence Against Women Act of 1994</short-title> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13925">42 U.S.C. 13925 et seq.</external-xref>) included programs to develop and implement prevention and intervention policies in middle and high schools, including appropriate responses to, and identification and referral procedures for, students who are experiencing or perpetrating domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, sexual harassment, stalking, or sex trafficking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1246411f668b4df98afa6eddaa59c6ca"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Schools can play an important role in providing students with a knowledge base that may allow students to make informed decisions and form a healthy lifestyle.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6016a61b65b94ee9a22ad682932347b2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the Department of Justice, there is an average of 293,066 victims (age 12 or older) of rape and sexual assault each year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id96073e79f89b4f57a8d91e2e1782de50"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Young women between the ages of 16 and 24 experience the highest rate of intimate partner violence. According to one national study, 29 percent of the young women surveyed who had ever been in a relationship said they had been pressured to have sex or to engage in sexual activity they did not want.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6b7e61331f29477b9935c5c55eb63318"><enum>(6)</enum><text>From 1997 to 2013, females ages 18 to 24 consistently experienced higher rates of rape and sexual assault than females in other age brackets.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1a4e500baed242d4bf1fd4853ea95482"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Partners of all genders and those in same-sex relationships also experience dating violence. A 2013 survey of grade school students found that 43 percent of lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender youth reported being victims of physical dating violence, compared to 29 percent of heterosexual youth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddcfe0542154d47b68674f802641adc1f"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Experiencing dating violence is associated with an increase in sexual risk-taking behaviors, health risks, and is associated with adolescent and unintended pregnancy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id83d982b3bddd43c28c293442a5a6cc5c"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Teaching and learning practices in the United States frequently do not address safe relationship behavior education and training, for example—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idbe532e145d3b47329750c17cbe97069b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sex education curriculum should address emotional relationship health;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide63471c6ea6b45d2abb9879aca0042df"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sexual harassment undermines the ability of schools to provide safe and equitable learning or workplace environments; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74e242b9f8f64cdbbfe0604b65da51ee"><enum>(C)</enum><text>classroom textbooks and educational materials do not sufficiently reflect the promotion of safe and healthy relationships.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ac5796039814fac8c9a8743996d695b"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Efforts to improve the quality of public education must also include efforts to ensure programs for safe relationship behavior training.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide13d9b4dfecb4b1f9c56abf2cdb82255"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Federal support should address not only research and development of innovative model curricula and teaching and learning strategies to promote healthy behavior, but should also assist schools and local communities with implementing a curriculum that includes sexual assault and teen dating violence.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id265a558a131b44fc83508740ce808a69"><enum>5624.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text> <paragraph id="id65AF1C6BEA9745AEBDB8B8D7E52AAED1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consent</header> <subparagraph id="id245DB606A3A44720B10AF087A3D87C99"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>consent</term> means affirmative, unambiguous, and voluntary agreement to engage in a specific sexual activity during a sexual encounter.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id176F11734AC8490183B365808576C431"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consent cannot be given by an individual who is—</text> <clause id="id0995BF06192F43E691EB841DCE0B57F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">asleep, or mentally or physically incapacitated, either through the effect of drugs or alcohol or for any other reason;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC17B47B92E57469293EF51E1538949B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under duress or experiencing a threat, coercion, or force; or</text> </clause><clause id="id7653E4081A654DBAB4F8FDE3530A6CC0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inferred under circumstances in which consent is not clear, including the absence of language or actions that indicate unwillingness (such as saying <quote>no</quote> or <quote>stop</quote>), or the existence of a prior or current relationship or prior or current sexual activity.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id73e2ae43101c4fec9660cf867e482bad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safe relationship behavior education</header><text>The term <term>safe relationship behavior education</term> means education that—</text> <subparagraph id="id56A14B90B13A4D1AB9ECA9E56FCBB1CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is medically accurate and appropriate for an individual's age, developmental stage, and culture;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4BC95743CE5E4AC78B16F140E9BDC65A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promotes safe relationships and teaches students to recognize and prevent—</text>
 <clause id="id3536D7F799394F05AF05C98306122761"><enum>(i)</enum><text>physical and emotional relationship abuse; and</text> </clause><clause id="id1C1D08B2A0984E5B8327368B2348E785"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coercion, violence, or abuse, including teen and adolescent dating violence, domestic abuse, and sexual violence and harassment;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7E9CB8AAB3EE456F89F07DF8712244D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes education regarding relationship communication skills, emotional health, accountability, and well-being in relationships, and consent; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8C7E18C4BA1D4573A59208A3420F970C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>includes education regarding healthy relationships, including the development of healthy attitudes and insights necessary for understanding relationships between oneself, family, partners, others, and society, including skills on healthy self-esteem, and self-efficacy and stress management.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id64eda6dde51a45f99f8d3c1fa0061c47"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sexual assault</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault</term> means any nonconsensual sexual act proscribed by Federal, State, or tribal law, including when a victim lacks capacity to consent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc837bb3fe84e4bdaa1cbf1dcc66a2fee"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sexual harassment</header><text>The term <term>sexual harassment</term> means unwelcome conduct of a sexual nature, including unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, and other verbal, nonverbal, or physical conduct of a sexual nature.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC673D23D25914830AB9C287465E6A59E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sexual violence</header><text>The term <term>sexual violence</term> means physical sexual acts perpetrated against a person’s will or when or where a person is incapable of giving consent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4a7bd30f715f46389fb437720ab0272a"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Teen and adolescent dating violence</header><text>The term <term>teen and adolescent dating violence</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id6A914A609CB547BCB53775E82620C251"><enum>(A)</enum><text>violence committed by a person who is or has been in a social relationship of a romantic or intimate nature with the victim; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE75882F75D6741E3825E6FB748C1524E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>where the existence of such a relationship shall be determined based on a consideration of factors, including—</text>
 <clause id="id9D1AB2893DEC457FABCD2C5133F47272"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the length of the relationship;</text> </clause><clause id="idE0F7198722C1431792DF34FB93BD6134"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the type of relationship; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCBB7DD5A57D74342AE14E945AD561B49"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the frequency of interaction between the persons involved in the relationship.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id46ae7818a6e74c80a688304b4cdf6079"><enum>5625.</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> <subsection id="idbc1652d3d00d4232877caa8e21644425"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants to local educational agencies in order to enable such agencies—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide63da1322f7a41958ece7a2a0a3a8272"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide professional development to school administrators, teachers, and staff in safe relationship behavior education and teaching and learning practices; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id64855f46618d4ddea31d578cf357ec4e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide educational programming and curricula that is age appropriate and developmentally and culturally appropriate for students regarding safe relationship behavior education and training.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide3073fffbdbf4e6c830a6f6f6a0f8402"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Award basis</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants under this section—</text> <paragraph id="id455a5e2f8dca4591b15eb46168574742"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on a competitive basis; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0f1562b60fcc4df997826cb4691cf0da"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a manner that ensures that such grants are equitably distributed among local educational agencies located in rural, urban, and suburban areas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id068cb669640240fbb2bb4841ee6f33ad"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 4 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id66e137f040eb4635a5a0002f46feed61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Policy dissemination</header><text>The Secretary shall disseminate to local educational agencies any Department policy guidance regarding safe relationship behavior training and the promotion of safe and healthy relationships.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8c2d5a65f9ea429d9418f02dee772f94"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each local educational agency that receives a grant under this subpart shall use grant funds to develop and implement curricula for students that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id47B03DB6A34C41E4B03C1366BDA90BB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate elements of effective and evidence-based or evidence-informed programs that include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idbac58949a98b42b9a87e5397d1956ddf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>safe relationship behavior training, including for the prevention of teen and adolescent dating violence, domestic abuse, and sexual violence and harassment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideffcb4427c7648f38cf78f9d4bb11070"><enum>(B)</enum><text>education about healthy relationships between oneself and family, others, and society; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id115dfa8dafd64ef7ac96437fea6c9adf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are age appropriate, developmentally appropriate, and culturally and linguistically appropriate, reflecting the diverse circumstance and realities of young people.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id25f1de6b708945668c58e5b2d13b4e5f"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, a local educational agency shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Each application shall include a description of the local educational agency's—</text>
 <paragraph id="id00D8930795D54A46B43A9BFF97B01734"><enum>(1)</enum><text>need for funds provided under this subpart;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id51DE4D8538144A908B9E25979AEDFDBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>plan for implementing the activities described under subsection (e); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9b82c787fad946c1bb5162e735b9aac5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>measurable objectives for, and expected results from, the use of funds provided by the grant under this subpart.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfd16376574a9491bb48e7cbcfc90898d"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Selection of grantees</header>
 <paragraph id="ida936cc9ec6f54c87bcda39ac70dd80ad"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall determine, based on the peer review process described in paragraph (3), which local educational agencies shall receive funding under this subpart, and the amount of the grant funding under this subpart that each selected local educational agency will receive.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7527c37d44734eaca9af7ee556c9e77c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text>In determining the amount of each grant awarded under this subpart, the Secretary shall take into account the total amount of funds available for all grants under this subpart and the types of activities proposed to be carried out by each local educational agency, in order to ensure that all grants are of sufficient size, scope, and quality to be effective.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida9d3404565d143d99fd8e5f48ac23da5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Peer review process</header><text>The Secretary shall convene a peer review committee to review applications for grants under this subpart and to make recommendations to the Secretary regarding the selection of grantees.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="idEA31C2895ED647558CF7C073970B4E9F"><enum>3.</enum><header>General prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9526(a)(3) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7906">20 U.S.C. 7906(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding <quote>and safe relationship behavior education (as defined in section 5624)</quote> after <quote>abstinence</quote>.</text></section></legis-body>
</bill>


