<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S261 IS: To designate the United States courthouse located at 200 NW 4th Street in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, as the William J. Holloway, Jr. United States Courthouse.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 261</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To designate the United States courthouse located at 200 NW 4th Street in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma,
 as the William J. Holloway, Jr. United States Courthouse.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA5A43BFA57545E2836C92268C8F06D6" style="OLC"><section id="H3E76C98BE4F646BA86D1E14567C97CF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>William J. Holloway, Jr. United States Courthouse</header><subsection id="id19BB2BD3273D4959BDC239ECFEA1D44A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States courthouse located at 200 NW 4th Street in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, shall be known and designated as the <quote>William J. Holloway, Jr. United States Courthouse</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H042A31AFD464413CA9FA508752E1DFF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the United States courthouse referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>William J. Holloway, Jr. United States Courthouse</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


