<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S438 IS: Irrigation Rehabilitation and Renovation for Indian Tribal Governments and Their Economies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 438</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the repair, replacement, and maintenance of certain Indian irrigation projects.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="id0F59A838190B4ECE8861E936CADCA1BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Irrigation Rehabilitation and Renovation for Indian Tribal Governments and Their Economies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IRRIGATE Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id159A2D5328EE4F3387AEF471600D3DC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id4b97388a-e7d0-49d0-a031-781b7375954b" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id2D8F004EBFB14943B82E3F4A541F7AA7" level="title">TITLE I—Indian Irrigation Fund</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id8f614eef-9289-4892-bd09-6936c37cd750" level="section">Sec. 101. Establishment.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idd02b33a9-dfac-4ef1-8a58-d473232e02c5" level="section">Sec. 102. Deposits to Fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id41c0ff77-e6d0-4e57-8ca2-05e3c40059d5" level="section">Sec. 103. Expenditures from Fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="IDe63cfc1ca3d9455b970ca315168da749" level="section">Sec. 104. Investments of amounts.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="ID0ae18133901641d983f658aa9a183dd5" level="section">Sec. 105. Transfers of amounts.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="ID9e89d8e0238c4ebf8bff24a7bab08291" level="section">Sec. 106. Termination.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idA53C352E5B3F4B7491355F380456AF85" level="title">TITLE II—Repair, replacement, and maintenance of certain Indian irrigation projects</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idF3AD91EC445748E68091C4031D80B4C1" level="section">Sec. 201. Repair, replacement, and maintenance of certain Indian irrigation projects.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id0F502DF2B7B14DC58A4B4043B3295F5C" level="section">Sec. 202. Eligible projects.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idbb608925680448a5a7636023a4ec54b0" level="section">Sec. 203. Requirements and conditions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="ida00340e3afd249f29a876e10be919239" level="section">Sec. 204. Study of Indian irrigation program and project management.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id1421b55599c94be2904dff87a040d0c9" level="section">Sec. 205. Tribal consultation and user input.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="IDeb2b0d74de964d43b9b1328f4444faf9" level="section">Sec. 206. Allocation among projects.</toc-entry></toc> </subsection></section><section id="id4b97388a-e7d0-49d0-a031-781b7375954b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="idd65c619c-a6a3-4a3a-b24b-31535d95eaa2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Indian Irrigation Fund established by section 101.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id4cf9e9a0-4194-4ae3-ba6d-1848771e2f27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian
 tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2635A2F267874263BC50C1DFC4477069"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation.</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="id2D8F004EBFB14943B82E3F4A541F7AA7" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Indian Irrigation Fund</header>
 <section id="id8f614eef-9289-4892-bd09-6936c37cd750"><enum>101.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the <quote>Indian Irrigation Fund</quote>, consisting of—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3af5bf63-1ba6-496b-bb8c-715c6675bb08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such amounts as are deposited in the Fund under section 103; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfc9c0726-6f80-470c-aada-bbb951d0bc07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any interest earned on investment of amounts in the Fund under section 105.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="idd02b33a9-dfac-4ef1-8a58-d473232e02c5"><enum>102.</enum><header>Deposits to
		Fund</header>
				<subsection id="idde94c50c-c257-4c87-a150-b166e9fe0abb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2015 through 2036, the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit in the Fund $35,000,000 of the revenues that would otherwise be deposited for the fiscal year in the reclamation fund established by the first section of the Act of June 17, 1902 (32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093).</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="ide46b49a2-a9cc-4d61-8836-5429aaf453f9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of
 amounts</header><text>Amounts deposited in the Fund under subsection (a) shall be used, subject to appropriation, to carry out this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id41c0ff77-e6d0-4e57-8ca2-05e3c40059d5"><enum>103.</enum><header>Expenditures
		from Fund</header>
				<subsection id="id66fd5785-9a1c-49a5-8415-ad5326419f70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2036, the Secretary may, to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts, expend from the Fund, in accordance with this Act, not more than the sum of—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf5b6e99c-4db7-43be-86c4-4fa647daacf9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$35,000,000; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0720c697-cd7c-452b-8005-6fb2e97dc932"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of interest accrued in the Fund.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idad7a3e88-13db-4bb5-9885-d1b494b42ffb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional
 expenditures</header><text>The Secretary may expend more than $35,000,000 for any fiscal year referred to in subsection (a) if the additional amounts are available in the Fund as a result of a failure of the Secretary to expend all of the amounts available under subsection (a) in 1 or more prior fiscal years.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="IDe63cfc1ca3d9455b970ca315168da749"><enum>104.</enum><header>Investments of amounts</header>
 <subsection id="ID2ee1a2b92e314a289509c3482a457614"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not, in the judgment of the Secretary, required to meet current withdrawals.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ID6360711027b14b05b9d5840160e285d5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credits to Fund</header><text>The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to, and form a part of, the Fund.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="ID0ae18133901641d983f658aa9a183dd5"><enum>105.</enum><header>Transfers of amounts</header>
 <subsection id="ID6ccd52ef39cf48d3a6c7683bf5d1784c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amounts required to be transferred to the Fund under this title shall be transferred at least monthly from the general fund of the Treasury to the Fund on the basis of estimates made by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="IDf7c519467c544165a273d59c450bef8e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>Proper adjustment shall be made in amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates are in excess of or less than the amounts required to be transferred.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="ID9e89d8e0238c4ebf8bff24a7bab08291"><enum>106.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On September 30, 2036—</text> <paragraph id="ID7663ab4b34c34bd4bc7efaa7f0884990"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Fund shall terminate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDf904a45c62194c2685d4eabbb0e5dbe4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the unexpended and unobligated balance of the Fund shall be transferred to the reclamation fund established by the first section of the Act of June 17, 1902 (32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093).</text>
				</paragraph></section></title><title id="idA53C352E5B3F4B7491355F380456AF85" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Repair,
		replacement, and maintenance of certain Indian irrigation projects</header>
			<section id="idF3AD91EC445748E68091C4031D80B4C1"><enum>201.</enum><header>Repair,
		replacement, and maintenance of certain Indian irrigation projects</header>
 <subsection id="id5F65FE7B1FEA4867987A34A91AEB06AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to address the deferred maintenance needs of Indian irrigation projects that—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf55fdd9dc27f43d39387199e6220653c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create risks to public or employee safety or natural or cultural resources; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id463deda4db6b42cfbfc669fe0c796d5a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unduly impede the management and efficiency of the Indian irrigation program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC8BC2174F8F64F9399A3EB0F8C5EE9D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Consistent with section 103, the Secretary shall use or transfer to the Bureau of Indian Affairs not less than $35,000,000 of amounts in the Fund, plus accrued interest, for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2036 to carry out maintenance, repair, and replacement activities for 1 or more of the Indian irrigation projects described in section 202 (including any structures, facilities, equipment, or vehicles used in connection with the operation of those projects).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id0F502DF2B7B14DC58A4B4043B3295F5C"><enum>202.</enum><header>Eligible
 projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The projects eligible for funding under section 201(b) are the Indian irrigation projects in the western United States that, on the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="id986a4c8b33aa49cbb612cb59a645e490"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are owned by the Federal Government, as listed in the Federal inventory required by Executive Order 13327 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/121">40 U.S.C. 121</external-xref> note; relating to Federal real property asset management);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0906faf0a1f244859d61b5258feab9ab"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are managed by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (including projects managed under contracts or compacts pursuant to the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450">25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6c9294528af2402cab4e3b63b95b77e3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have deferred maintenance documented by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idbb608925680448a5a7636023a4ec54b0"><enum>203.</enum><header>Requirements and conditions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act and as a precondition to amounts being expended from the Fund to carry out this title, the Secretary, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs, the Commissioner of Reclamation, and representatives of affected Indian tribes, shall develop and submit to Congress—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6cbdb00cf3b54d328bc86298ec330d2b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>programmatic goals to carry out this title that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id79ced877c0e946e69b20913e8827b94a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>would enable the completion of repairing, replacing, improving, or performing maintenance on projects as expeditiously as possible;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f6d1ea317a24a25b473d40d6b895ac5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate or improve the ability of the Bureau of Indian Affairs to carry out the mission of the Bureau of Indian Affairs in operating a project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID299c4198cc8b4b59a0b0eb4fc155a862"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that the results of government-to-government consultation required under section 205 be addressed; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a2fa7bf20a54411b59c12347ca82252"><enum>(2)</enum><text>funding prioritization criteria to serve as a methodology for distributing funds under this title, that take into account—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida08095b1a417497599c5ebdbcfa014ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which deferred maintenance of qualifying irrigation projects poses a threat to public or employee safety or health;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb64dd2cae86e492fbc51dda1db22b340"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which deferred maintenance poses a threat to natural or cultural resources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id230eb902ba764a1b86ea013d290b6921"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which deferred maintenance poses a threat to the ability of the Bureau of Indian Affairs to carry out the mission of the Bureau of Indian Affairs in operating the project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDea1596b688324dfeb8abd8997c98f488"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which repairing, replacing, improving, or performing maintenance on a facility or structure will—</text>
 <clause id="ID5c2ef6a24d7a4c01852936840553ec19"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve public or employee safety, health, or accessibility;</text> </clause><clause id="ID3a042038eba848778ee4631bf0efae5d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assist in compliance with codes, standards, laws, or other requirements;</text>
 </clause><clause id="IDff0866fc1f09408495aa540394f84d77"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>address unmet needs; and</text> </clause><clause id="IDe33e99d727cc42cd9bf7b242df4cf8ab"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assist in protecting natural or cultural resources;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID0c7524ff2e5247a0b2258161529b2e2a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the methodology of the rehabilitation priority index of the Secretary, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63ba0bbf4b9a4a418aa9d09b9eaef46d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the potential economic benefits of the expenditures on job creation and general economic development in the affected tribal communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe8f5bde33a948909a14799997bbfb5e"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the ability of the qualifying project to address tribal, regional, and watershed level water supply needs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7b36834d0de48418bddfd55d1d19477"><enum>(H)</enum><text>such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to prioritize the use of available funds that are, to the fullest extent practicable, consistent with tribal and user recommendations received pursuant to the consultation and input process under section 205.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ida00340e3afd249f29a876e10be919239"><enum>204.</enum><header>Study of
		Indian irrigation program and project management</header>
 <subsection id="ide224b93efa6f40ca90f63085740855b4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tribal consultation and user input</header><text>Before beginning to conduct the study required under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idd472a4502b1d4d01a89947551c52b4af"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Indian tribes that have jurisdiction over the land on which an irrigation project eligible to receive funding under section 202 is located; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id525fcdc910454468bdb1dbeb3a75e179"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit and consider the input, comments, and recommendations of the landowners served by the irrigation project.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6cfd8e3f04aa414d9cdea0292f7e73eb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs, shall complete a study that evaluates options for improving programmatic and project management and performance of irrigation projects managed and operated in whole or in part by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id853fb51e068e445cbd1aaa1c6a6d9ca5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>On completion of the study under subsection (b), the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs, shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id0673e7487e5b42adbe0c2809d92de051"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the results of the study; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4e647bd9021145308868c92d9ecb95a6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes recommendations for improving programmatic and project management and performance in each qualifying project area and for the program as a whole.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id28b1632c5c4c488da9d50019c5268e9b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Of the amounts authorized to be expended from the Fund, $1,000,000 shall be made available during fiscal year 2015 to carry out this section, to remain available until expended.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id1421b55599c94be2904dff87a040d0c9"><enum>205.</enum><header>Tribal
 consultation and user input</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Before expending funds on an Indian irrigation project pursuant to section 201 and not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id48f215310dee47a393223afc37f5dd1d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Indian tribe that has jurisdiction over the land on which an irrigation project eligible to receive funding under section 202 is located; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida825aa10fd674735ae33d14b1cf50c41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit and consider the input, comments, and recommendations of the landowners served by the irrigation project.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="IDeb2b0d74de964d43b9b1328f4444faf9"><enum>206.</enum><header>Allocation among projects</header>
 <subsection id="id4a36a69bebbe4f8b847cbe0c6eb414ca"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure that, for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2036, each Indian irrigation project eligible for funding under section 202 that has critical maintenance needs receives part of the funding under section 201 to address critical maintenance needs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="IDe323406406af478a9de80186c2b13438"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In allocating amounts under section 201(b), in addition to considering the funding priorities described in section 203, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible Indian irrigation projects serving more than 1 Indian tribe within an Indian reservation and to projects for which funding has not been made available during the 15-year period ending on the day before the date of enactment of this Act under any other Act of Congress that expressly identifies the Indian irrigation project or the Indian reservation of the project to address the deferred maintenance, repair, or replacement needs of the Indian irrigation project.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="idBD8E88A5D5494BA69A1220600DF78D6B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cap on Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="id92E79ECC3AC14526877388A887614096"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), in allocating amounts under section 201(b), the Secretary shall allocate not more than $15,000,000 to any individual Indian irrigation project described in section 202 during any consecutive 3-year period.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9D726F6FD8204FA6BC57CBE36F4070A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding the cap described in paragraph (1), if the full amount under section 201(b) cannot be fully allocated to eligible Indian irrigation projects because the costs of the remaining activities authorized in section 201(b) of an irrigation project would exceed the cap described in paragraph (1), the Secretary may allocate the remaining funds to eligible Indian irrigation projects in accordance with this title.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD475EFA1161E46BCB8F3B7C7A6B7202B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Basis of
 funding</header><text>Any amounts made available under this section shall be nonreimbursable.</text>
				</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5BCB93933DA141A3A587B7E7C8F339C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability
 of ISDEAA</header><text>The Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450">25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.</external-xref>) shall apply to activities carried out under this section.</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


