<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S644 IS: To resolve title issues involving real property and equipment acquired using funds provided under the Alaska Kiln Drying Grant Program.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 644</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150303">March 3, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To resolve title issues involving real property and equipment acquired using funds provided under
			 the Alaska Kiln Drying Grant Program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0F4E65C1B60644E48B3F3BDFD8550EC7" style="OLC">
		<section id="H5CD083C508724824B9D845D773CA9A3F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Resolution of real property and equipment title issues under Alaska kiln drying grant program</header>
 <subsection id="id20C275C2FCBD47FDA02F9D25A4ED47D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of program</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Program</quote> means the Alaska Kiln Drying Grant Program that is described—</text>
 <paragraph id="id40E3BCAFE6FF40EB8C6EC6C7016949BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-small" style="appropriations">State and Private Forestry</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="OLC">Forest Service</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="OLC">Department of Agriculture</header-in-text></quote> in title II of the conference report accompanying H.R. 4578 of the 106th Congress (House Report 106–914); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC93D8AC2E50A4320A316FF527A49C1D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the matter under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-small" style="appropriations">State and Private Forestry</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="OLC">Forest Service</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="OLC">Department of Agriculture</header-in-text></quote> in title II of the conference report accompanying H.R. 2217 of the 107th Congress (House Report 107–234).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19D1AE4B038D40D898D90DDA1B9D3266"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Vesting of title</header><text>Notwithstanding chapter IV of subtitle B of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), title to real property and equipment acquired using funds provided by a grant under the Program shall vest in the grant recipient—</text>
 <paragraph id="id061E2E866325477185203931BAE52C77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with the compensation schedule described in subsection (c)(2); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4DB7812C88DD4A4BAD8B298F4FA8E32F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as provided in subsection (d).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31F96219F11C458CA019613E3943C30C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compensation schedule</header>
 <paragraph id="H9F64A028A76740AFB7FD1CA4C7036540"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Period of application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The compensation requirements of this subsection shall apply to a grant provided under the Program during the 4-year period beginning on the date on which the grant was closed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6B21CC0761F4B9CBEF3C2BB23B0683B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If real property or equipment acquired using funds provided by a grant under the Program is no longer to be used for the purposes for which the grant was made, the grant recipient may sell, or may retain title to, the real property or equipment on payment to the Secretary of Agriculture of compensation as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H68EE33F862594E33A60B81AC0914A27A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the first year of the 4-year period, the grant recipient shall pay an amount equal to 80 percent of the proceeds of the sale, if the real property or equipment is sold, or 80 percent of the market value of the real property or equipment, if title is to be retained by the grant recipient.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FC8341B4A844DC9AAD4254692049953"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the second year of the 4-year period, the grant recipient shall pay an amount equal to 60 percent of the proceeds of the sale, if the real property or equipment is sold, or 60 percent of the market value of the real property or equipment, if title is to be retained by the grant recipient.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EC64AE004374952A57B36B2DA2D27F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the third year of the 4-year period, the grant recipient shall pay an amount equal to 40 percent of the proceeds of the sale, if the real property or equipment is sold, or 40 percent of the market value of the real property or equipment, if title is to be retained by the grant recipient.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49377ECDF68549C3A907AC6EF1942520"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the final year of the 4-year period, the grant recipient shall pay an amount equal to 20 percent of the proceeds of the sale, if the real property or equipment is sold, or 20 percent of the market value of the real property or equipment, if title is to be retained by the grant recipient.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H503B7548B53B43A988C4A1103E479679"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Divestiture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the end of the 4-year period beginning on the date on which a grant provided under the Program was closed, real property or equipment acquired using the grant funds may be retained or disposed of by the grant recipient with no further obligation to the Federal Government.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


