<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1566 IS: Cancer Drug Coverage Parity Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1566</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150611">June 11, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to require group and individual health insurance coverage
			 and group health plans to provide for coverage of oral anticancer drugs on
			 terms no less favorable than the coverage provided for anticancer
			 medications administered by a health care provider.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE7774076CF1D4BC09655CCE16624491D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC482D32799974358A29C4AF76F002BB5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cancer Drug Coverage Parity Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H42156F6041FE4174A42892A2C86A4D2E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Parity in coverage for oral anticancer drugs</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H870FC74CB4D74177A9D5FE61B5A7679A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00EE40D67D494B1FAECDABB32C0C334A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2719A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-19a">42 U.S.C. 300gg–19a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H2DDFB134676744DABF51FD2093F8692D" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HB650E48869754663AEE45DDA76C41581"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Parity in coverage for oral anticancer drugs</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0320EBB5A2D74891A9427E21AFC27FEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), a group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, that provides benefits with respect to anticancer medications administered by a health care provider shall provide for coverage for prescribed, patient-administered anticancer medications that are used to kill, slow, or prevent the growth of cancerous cells and that have been approved by the Food and Drug Administration that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF1ED2F517FF142CB9804A958EA81A56B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no less favorable than the coverage for anticancer medications that are intravenously administered or injected by a health care provider; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D5079E2BD774651997BEB45A0AD44C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not subject to any prior authorization, step therapy, dollar or durational limit, copayment, deductible or coinsurance that does not apply to such provider-administered anticancer medications.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB428B958A5EB4214BB03B2339A1B3BEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall only apply to an anticancer medication that is prescribed based on a finding by the treating physician that the medication—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H36C6DED63B51490598FB30F0043031E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is medically necessary for the purpose of killing, slowing, or preventing the growth of cancerous cells; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H49CB14A2602B4D5E80EC01FA4B8828A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is clinically appropriate in terms of type, frequency, extent site, and duration.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAE16CBAC9AF341C4B6B7503F3DDEADC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restriction on certain changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan or health insurance issuer may not, in order to comply with the requirement of paragraph (1), make changes to benefits or replace existing benefits with new benefits under the plan or health insurance coverage designed to have the effect of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7C89E5DE631E4971931A0C973E9D1826"><enum>(A)</enum><text>imposing an increase in out-of-pocket costs with respect to anticancer medications;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H939BCC53EA8446E7A32C7A8E5192B19B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reclassifying benefits with respect to anticancer medications in a way that would increase such costs; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D5C2E30C4D944298FBC2936A4DDC68F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>applying more restrictive limitations on prescribed orally administered anticancer medications than on intravenously administered or injected anticancer medications.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B0EC39C7A554E14ABD90B55F9BA281B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed—</text> <subparagraph id="HEEC3BFA4A32F45D5B1125C669A643AF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to require the use of orally administered anticancer medications as a replacement for other anticancer medications;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8497865A27A54D15B4EB754FD06501B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to prohibit a group health plan or health insurance issuer from requiring prior authorization or imposing other appropriate utilization controls in approving coverage for any chemotherapy; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6626F5FA6E8F4254B08A1F3AECEB6EF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to supersede a State law that provides greater protections with respect to the coverage with respect to orally administered anticancer medications than is provided under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FD75400C70E4A669A929B25A511F046"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 2724(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-23">42 U.S.C. 300gg–23(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 2704</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 2719A, 2725, and 2726</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AC64BBD5C1F4EDBBE7C9608C5D48EAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarifying amendment regarding application to grandfathered plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1251(a)(4)(A) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18011">42 U.S.C. 18011(a)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A4CDA38C321449C96EEB6D0149CB0E7" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H74FF665E44B34387816E9D94639FFA17"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2719A(e).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HF87E2C00C22D483AA787B308001C5FF7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to group health plans for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2016, and with respect to health insurance coverage offered, sold, issued, renewed, in effect, or operated in the individual or group market on or after such date.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


