<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1178 IS: Defending Rivers from Overreaching Policies Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1178</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S358">Mr. Flake</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit implementation of a proposed rule relating to the definition of the term <quote>waters of the United States</quote> under the Clean Water Act, or any substantially similar rule, until a Supplemental Scientific
			 Review Panel and Ephemeral and Intermittent Streams Advisory Committee
			 produce certain reports, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="idCAB112C56B2640BC94DB73DD2C36245B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defending Rivers from Overreaching Policies Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id754FAA5591CB4CF2B8CD3ED6F65B6DD0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waters of the United States</header> <subsection id="id6A6E9A0D12604CEB80C857E1647BA6C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id07d141073cd042ce8b037e3952ac7b9e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>according to the testimony of Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works Jo-Ellen Darcy at the House of Representatives and Senate Joint Hearing on State and Local Impacts of the Administration’s Proposed Expansion of Waters Regulation on February 4, 2015, that proposed expansion of waters regulation <quote>is based on science including a peer-reviewed report on connectivity and the recommendations of EPA’s Science Advisory Board</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4fdd66cbeb30410ba2cc82781fa6b8af"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the proposed rule entitled <quote>Definition of <quote>Waters of the United States</quote> Under the Clean Water Act</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 22188 (April 21, 2014)), was drafted before the science on which the proposed rule was based had been reviewed by the Scientific Advisory Board of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id35bd963d947c46ee818998b4d14a73cc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the final review and synthesis of the scientific evidence was released in January 2015, 2 months after the close of the public comment period for the proposed rule;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf6c45cd418d74cbb9dc5632716e0c920"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the review and synthesis of the scientific evidence found that <quote>the degree and downstream effects of those connections [between parts of a watershed] vary spatially and temporally</quote> and the <quote>connectivity of streams and wetlands to downstream waters occurs along a continuum</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfb5ee3e87b4f48a78a4c7cde1de783ad"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the authors of the review and synthesis were unable to place the water bodies in the case studies <quote>along a gradient of connectivity</quote> and reported that <quote>the research community has not reached a consensus regarding the best methods or metrics to quantify or predict hydrologic or chemical connectivity</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc57c0468c67c4b7699a48e0b61fcbb78"><enum>(6)</enum><text>without a scientific basis for evaluating the degree of connectivity between a particular stream and a traditionally navigable water, it is premature to use the scientific literature to define which connections are <quote>significant</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id71d878f238224af4bfb88c62e19cb087"><enum>(7)</enum><text>because the analysis of the relevant science was completed after the proposed rule described in paragraph (2) was drafted, and because the scientific review failed to produce a method to assess the location of a particular water body on a <quote>gradient of connectivity</quote>, the resulting proposed rule is not effectively based on science; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2215e3cbc9614c33a09a6993b9428a5a"><enum>(8)</enum><text>because the likely cost of implementation of that proposed rule will be greater than the $162,000,000 to $278,000,000 cited in the testimony of Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency Gina McCarthy at the House of Representatives and Senate joint hearing described in paragraph (1), the proposal will have significant impacts on many sectors of the United States economy.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3B00DF192DF74497A8AAEE9D62D0FB0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id165902EAEADF4CEE9C301C02B3F52A9B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEAA6E14E1421400F847B8A5DC772D2B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Commission established under subsection (d)(1).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id35932518E03C47F7A57FD455F173FE05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Panel</header><text>The term <term>Panel</term> means the Panel established under subsection (c)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id89CC5EFB714C4078978329BA8F254B40"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Proposed rule</header><text>The term <term>proposed rule</term> means the proposed rule entitled <quote>Definition of <quote>Waters of the United States</quote> Under the Clean Water Act</quote> (79 Fed. Reg. 22188 (April 21, 2014)).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9967E72B8F474B938C01712B37C8DDB5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcaf9b57d4fe2427daff7cd7bb6937360"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplemental Scientific Review Panel</header>
 <paragraph id="idAB99A9D9AAAB49929A34E20F1B10E2E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall establish a panel, to be known as the <quote>Supplemental Scientific Review Panel</quote>, to submit to the Secretary and the Administrator recommendations regarding metrics, based on the best available scientific information, to quantify the degree of connectivity between any body of water or wetland and a traditionally navigable water.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id751692EB41C4462E9DF20DAE9BEC7F33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <subparagraph id="id7937F1603CF84FA69B61ADE205D5D62D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Panel shall be composed of 9 members, of whom—</text> <clause id="id85235a963fc34995b0fcdae32cfd0c6d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id08d5d87f43a44e4eb12eddd0ce3c0b2d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate;</text> </clause><clause id="idc066b98398c04cfcb2a59ebf60ec6de9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id39cf9f31d0b548e6803cd7b7147bba21"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives; and</text> </clause><clause id="idac3e28f619274b7cb632a61847266465"><enum>(v)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the President of the National Academy of Engineering.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id282764E48F70456CB45F44302DCD695A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Date of appointments</header><text>The appointment of a member of the Panel shall be made not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id776cac4e14344e4285b090798b799652"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Each member of the Panel shall be appointed from among individuals who possess—</text> <clause id="idf177217048864695a73b5e212fb6ac52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expertise in a field of the biogeosciences, such as hydrology, ecology, or geomorphology;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id933b3788052648c7b9c14409f21c64a1"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4E82683B1278472FA2A3C3DDF689BB50"><enum>(I)</enum><text>academic excellence, as determined in accordance with criteria including peer-reviewed journal publications and invited academic conference presentations; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id8580135D1A2347E294192882F0618329" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>practical expertise demonstrated by a record of employment as a professional with equivalent experience as an academic scientist; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id2f835031e7a0423191a6b47e9ecd203e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>experience regarding collecting and interpreting field measurements of streams and wetlands.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b680bcb97834212b7acf9c5b784faff"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In appointing members of the Panel, each appointing officer referred to in subparagraph (A) shall ensure that the Panel includes balanced representation of research expertise across all Level I ecoregions (as defined in section III of the 1997 publication of the Commission for Environmental Cooperation publication entitled <quote>Ecological Regions of North America Toward a Common Perspective</quote>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1FD429400E548B9AA52C9AA3361E69C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>At the first meeting of the Panel, a majority of the members of the Panel present and voting shall elect the Chairperson of the Panel from among the members of the Panel.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDF9EBBD586A6D43A2814C9D7D8FAF76A8"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy on the Panel—</text>
 <clause id="IDA9631872155B4CE58B499962B1D0217B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Panel; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID22AE9E5E9568490B908023D1C2BCBD2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6ace1e442934ef992e204a6d3fc0a30"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Compensation</header>
 <clause id="id0B132E294DDC4C0F96D9DCE660CEEB2F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Panel—</text> <subclause id="id2ad81dcd57ee4993a621a91ddd3165d1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall not be considered to be a Federal employee for any purpose by reason of service on the Panel; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id64e7c29e453643a08e84c1e61119debe"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall serve without pay.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id8330881272354d5ebfc9ab8bafebda53"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Panel shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Panel.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDED55AC0EF5C749C293B8CB5FAD68FE4C"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Initial
 meeting</header><text>The Panel shall hold the initial meeting of the Panel by not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDD209FD1ED0F9443ABD8B94A9D757B60B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Panel shall meet at the call of a majority of the members of the Panel.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDFA8C485DEF7E44919228ECD7C7403119"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Of the members of the Panel, 5 shall constitute a quorum.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id229eaa77bc1845a9a4dbd2fc11f8c1b1"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Rules of procedure</header><text>The Panel may establish rules for the conduct of business of the Panel, subject to the condition that those rules shall not be inconsistent with this Act or any other applicable law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida71a10f8198c44de8dab0a483871445d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Panel shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id164f3a8da5a44ee5bbfa76b234c65465"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommend metrics, based on the best available scientific information and considering the duration, magnitude, and frequency of flows, to quantify the degree of connectivity between any body of water or wetland and a traditionally navigable water;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88d98be8e1884abdaa16bf84940557bf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure the recommended metrics account for regional variability in all types of waterbodies and across all States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and other territories and possessions of the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5040964ee8a4b78b68bb4748d5b56ff"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the Panel first convenes, submit to the Secretary and Administrator a report describing each recommendation of the Panel to which not fewer than 6 members have agreed.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8ed8bc71fd24e6cb2479f9742ba6739"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative support</header>
 <subparagraph id="ida43ea9f54c984640b2a749867d903df2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall provide to the Panel such staff and administrative services as may be necessary and appropriate for the Panel to perform the duties under paragraph (3).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF0DCF9FD7B96416A8C8FB9DD8FF4E383"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Detail of Federal Government employees</header>
						<clause id="ID6494AD933D7D4EC79DB151E93E4BA5BD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>An employee of the Federal Government may be detailed to the Panel without reimbursement.</text>
						</clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID3A4FD5B4FBB244FAA53CA36D5B4E7F64"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Civil service
 status</header><text>The detail of the employee shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddac1ec681b5149dcbdafddb354473e34"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall provide to the Panel such funds as the Secretary and the Administrator determine to be appropriate from amounts made available to the Secretary and the Administrator in appropriations Acts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbe04097e7fe84d7a927017500c2a31f5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Panel shall terminate on the earlier of—</text> <subparagraph id="idCBDD01A5FAA84B1D8AC49BA4F9BE11AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after the date on which the report is submitted under paragraph (3)(C); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1179D6F02A4B4E429144C3AD2F4F91DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida43b1c5391c04c12ae70d7e6302ad4d7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Applicability of Federal Advisory Committee Act</header> <subparagraph id="id593ebf0ffb044ae7a1516e671f563466"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall apply to the Panel.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8b892975570483e9e4d0bbea9ed6693"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public meetings and release of public versions of reports</header><text>The Panel shall—</text> <clause id="id7eabf67f5d3a4290a8dabd00415245cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>hold public hearings and meetings to the extent appropriate; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc10aa8b81a6240ef87b8dcb023026d68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>release public versions of the report required under paragraph (3)(C).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde6572987a824edd892f646182484492"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public hearings</header><text>Any public hearings of the Panel shall be conducted in a manner consistent with the protection of information provided to or developed for or by the Panel as required by any applicable law, regulation, or Executive order.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7F5C3E740FF74254AEA9052C9648F3C3"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ephemeral and Intermittent Streams Advisory Commission</header>
 <paragraph id="id5B3644A049224E7CBE0C9FFD67D80D96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall establish a commission, to be known as the <quote>Ephemeral and Intermittent Streams Advisory Commission</quote>, to develop criteria to define whether a waterbody or wetland has a significant nexus to a traditional navigable water using the metrics developed by the Panel.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idFA15DE78CF8E49EC912648B447C8E229"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <subparagraph id="id7D1540B5F64B4BA2B6D8BFD1E6A838F0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 15 members, of whom—</text> <clause id="idA16C59C1D24740BDA36BE268A93A0811"><enum>(i)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8134861D036A4DF8BA2B348DE3766664"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate;</text> </clause><clause id="idA99D711481724A7AB8C40292830792FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA16A9D45BCED466E81C2A17BA3D0EEDB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives; and</text> </clause><clause id="id729ACC1C01A943B39240882D9314B285"><enum>(v)</enum><text>7 shall be appointed jointly by the Administrator and the Secretary.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD9BFC89314604ACBBE26F216A4F63A3B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Date of appointments</header><text>The appointment of a member of the Commission shall be made not later than the date that is 45 days after the date on which the report of the Panel is submitted under subsection (c)(3)(C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9C9AE0D62BF245729BA841557BD4201E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall be appointed from among individuals who possess—</text> <clause id="id9d107c42c19b4e919782befb19e7e1b3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>experience regarding the permitting process under the <act-name parsable-cite="FWPCA">Federal Water Pollution Control Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id34a9697480e046b0bc67f56e7321d246"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>experience serving on the Panel; or</text> </clause><clause id="id492117E17FE14E0F8CC7E2316FBC3E16"><enum>(iii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idF20750C6B42E4891B868E4E946050006"><enum>(I)</enum><text>expertise in a field of the biogeosciences, such as hydrology, ecology, or geomorphology; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05B0D2A43CED4243AC5AA0EAB37A1833" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>academic excellence, as determined in accordance with criteria including peer-reviewed journal publications and invited academic conference presentations.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4AED0921305E4931BFB5974F44F96DAA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In appointing members of the Commission, each appointing officer referred to in subparagraph (A) shall ensure that the Commission includes—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1477E44E0B8A4EAD94B200546E9DF657"><enum>(i)</enum><text>balanced representation of research expertise across all Level I ecoregions (as defined in section III of the 1997 publication of the Commission for Environmental Cooperation publication entitled <quote>Ecological Regions of North America Toward a Common Perspective</quote>); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86243B8A678A4497B162FA90C2E2D2B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>equal representation of the following groups:</text> <subclause id="id13dc4aa69e85463f8c5065474a5484ca"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Individuals who represent—</text>
 <item id="iddef5a4f171c54f7cbc83c8984817d161"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the interests of builders and developers;</text> </item><item id="idbe47be548c3b4af485ddb6a6272f3dec"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>agricultural interests;</text>
 </item><item id="idcee3f7f9975a4bd6a211b391e0a4ae54"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>energy and mineral development; or</text> </item><item id="id5e0014a64c02404cab5f69652117beca"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the commercial timber industry.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id8602EF88AE104214B9AA8484441CBAA2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Individuals who represent—</text> <item id="idb4933ef16dbb412d89f9cb1f239332b2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>nationally or regionally recognized environmental organizations;</text>
 </item><item id="id77c61559dfbf4e8eb30580359c124601"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>sport, recreational, and commercial fishing interests;</text> </item><item id="iddbbb4954807048f5847e12a103296dd5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>sportsman's organizations; or</text>
 </item><item id="idb69d12e7c4c248549fc5a1f115016885"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>municipal water supply interests.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="id71DD1E2BD1884D508B85A981B1C016B7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Individuals who—</text>
 <item id="idae382c8ed0164fd4ab6ba3afe9275a74"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>hold a State, county, or local elected office;</text> </item><item id="id05aba7ee83d843e5b2d79917495b27f6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>are employed by a State agency responsible for the management of the environment or natural interests; or</text>
 </item><item id="id715b0d56b67b484f8fac2737af1ce55a"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>represent the affected public at-large.</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69278F1CA8E2461D99D75100265C2E78"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>At the first meeting of the Commission, a majority of the members of the Commission present and voting shall elect the Chairperson of the Commission from among the members of the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEC3646B013FA424BAF23C55EDF78066E"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy on the Commission—</text>
 <clause id="id7D5F70159C1B449A975C4DA0025565B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Commission; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id931F416F25A642F1879572465EAAE778"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8FF5E21932D84E1EA1187241469AD031"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Compensation</header>
 <clause id="id03F4F7F0A1654390AB6C08A62B249F84"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Commission—</text> <subclause id="id76B104F7E3DD4E5B8A2E4E4CC02A96CA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall not be considered to be a Federal employee for any purpose by reason of service on the Commission; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9193A768271A47E2836D48D9464BE197"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall serve without pay.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="idC63DCA947A5C41EF94687B18659D96DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Commission.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF8767308DBF645BD838CA61B55AF9EAC"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Initial
 meeting</header><text>The Commission shall hold the initial meeting of the Commission not earlier than the date on which the report of the Panel is submitted under subsection (c)(3)(C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96FB622DA5BB4479B1CFAAD423AD73EE"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of a majority of the members of the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4BCC90A657C546C3B4888CA520FADBC3"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Of the members of the Commission, 9 shall constitute a quorum.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFE6CE9B4331E4DAF9C2D55B369EB24FF"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Rules of procedure</header><text>The Commission may establish rules for the conduct of business of the Commission, subject to the condition that those rules shall not be inconsistent with this Act or any other applicable law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA02A48E0137C4BAF89BFBAC5AD9F3F73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Commission shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idCE117087B0324F48A311757A63189225"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop criteria to define whether a waterbody or wetland has a significant nexus to traditional navigable water using the metrics developed by the Panel;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3dc82e43e9b14b9a812408f906b6b42f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure those criteria account for regional variability in all types of waterbodies and wetlands and across all States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and other territories and possessions of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfe685892c11244219a5eb1e81598f821"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date on which the Commission holds the initial meeting under paragraph (2)(H), submit to the Secretary and the Administrator a draft report that—</text>
 <clause id="id9886820526304e6ca855b5fecf4aa6e3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describes the criteria developed by the Commission; and</text> </clause><clause id="id070f94079cd54b32b5af36670a157a1f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is subject to a 60-day period for public comment; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c80cf0bd7f24975ae77d5c89dda4c4e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>after addressing the comments received during the 60-day comment period under subparagraph (C)(ii), submit to the Secretary and the Administrator a final report.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89B3C64CDF204D698768B06C306EEABD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative support</header>
 <subparagraph id="idA137DC5C6FB04FCCA5367F6AFB67AB62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall provide to the Commission such staff and administrative services as may be necessary and appropriate for the Commission to perform the duties under paragraph (3).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0E67BC991C2D42D58FAC409901D0C6BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Detail of Federal Government employees</header>
						<clause id="id25D84254BCAA4895A5F787CFD8438A3D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>An employee of the Federal Government may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement.</text>
						</clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB783DB990E734E61BC963EECFFAF86E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Civil service
 status</header><text>The detail of the employee shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7BE0F15464F94B6F9711EC2DB2A7E083"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall provide to the Commission such funds as the Secretary and the Administrator determine to be appropriate from amounts made available to the Secretary and the Administrator in appropriations Acts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7E52271CB130487AADD099C9F8B4F251"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate on the earlier of—</text> <subparagraph id="idB1366A9AAB1E44E4A17AF6BB790AF46A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after the date on which the final report is submitted under paragraph (3)(D); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE5D8D084CF074195BCC2C023E0219F61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2211AD89B333472A9011176C7BFD912C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Applicability of Federal Advisory Committee Act</header> <subparagraph id="id4088C2EF9FFD45EE9CB4941C932A2159"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall apply to the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEED476EAACAA46F5B7CAE9A1F9837F23"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public meetings and release of public versions of reports</header><text>The Commission shall—</text> <clause id="id4C339674536C4B50AF3A376526617D1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>hold public hearings and meetings to the extent appropriate; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id708B95CE9DE04E878F7D1B67C158D7E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>release public versions of the reports required under subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (3).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5C57D78DAA734D718710B8507838E2C9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public hearings</header><text>Any public hearings of the Commission shall be conducted in a manner consistent with the protection of information provided to or developed for or by the Commission as required by any applicable law, regulation, or Executive order.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b546ce3b6f749048b4caeff683d05c8"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Administrator are prohibited from developing, finalizing, adopting, implementing, applying, administering, or enforcing the proposed rule or beginning the drafting of any substantially similar rule until the date on which the Secretary and the Administrator receive a final report from the Commission under subsection (d)(3)(D).</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


