<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1077 IS: Advancing Breakthrough Devices for Patients Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1077</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150423">April 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for expedited development of and priority review for breakthrough devices.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Breakthrough Devices for Patients Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id014D9B1853754C29A635E2CAB04B74F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited development of and priority review for breakthrough devices</header>
 <subsection id="idDBB5C2D7C66241E8ABCDA656A719B6E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/351">21 U.S.C. 351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 515A the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC51D8D4DEEBE43728FBF187D8A9178FC" style="OLC">
					<section id="id6D466A1AB1AE482D836FC2BDBF9B324E"><enum>515B.</enum><header>Expedited development of and priority review for breakthrough devices</header>
 <subsection id="idEBC86DEF34344C4185117608FBE34FEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to provide for more effective treatment or diagnosis of life-threatening or irreversibly debilitating human disease or conditions, the Secretary shall establish a program to expedite the development of and provide for the priority review for devices—</text>
 <paragraph id="id33395ad24f1a4281a2a103d4cac8db18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>representing breakthrough technologies;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd5d20a34257947f29f79422d62ccb20e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for which no approved alternatives exist;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc6427780536e45cea5ecce436e86f757"><enum>(3)</enum><text>offering significant advantages over existing approved or cleared alternatives, including the potential, compared to existing approved alternatives, to reduce or eliminate the need for hospitalization, improve patient quality of life, facilitate patients’ ability to manage their own care (such as through self-directed personal assistance), or establish long-term clinical efficiencies; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide43e26af99024fb0a2561684bb460417"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the availability of which is in the best interest of patients.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0fa0b59515bb49c1b92bc97c45aa34ca"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Request for designation</header><text>A sponsor of a device may request that the Secretary designate the device for expedited development and priority review under this section. Any such request for designation may be made at any time prior to the submission of an application under section 515(c), a petition for classification under section 513(f)(2), or a notification under section 510(k).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="idd1ad0eef1fc948f8bf03201b7bbb2c79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation Process</header>
 <paragraph id="idff630ead369d473398c237fd7882787c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 calendar days after the receipt of a request under subsection (b), the Secretary shall determine whether the device that is the subject of the request meets the criteria described in subsection (a). If the Secretary determines that the device meets the criteria, the Secretary shall designate the device for expedited development and priority review.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6a694ed21459404eb2d432313c70407f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Review of a request under subsection (b) shall be undertaken by a team that is composed of experienced staff and managers of the Food and Drug Administration and is chaired by a senior manager.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8d7ccb9d39334ffc8cf8a5ad7a20ca51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>The Secretary may not withdraw a designation granted under this section on the basis of the criteria under subsection (a) no longer applying because of the subsequent clearance or approval of another device that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id0CC613F3C8E042E7B49BB782B31E8B57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was designated under this section; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1BEF7FB055904CDC879BC169994B7C09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was given priority review under section 515(d)(5), as in effect prior to the date of enactment of the <short-title>Advancing Breakthrough Devices for Patients Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9f3743fe763e42f9a8b7019a1c5bec62"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expedited Development and Priority Review</header>
 <paragraph id="ida52da8330a0d4384b10fcef7da85dd04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions</header><text>For purposes of expediting the development and review of devices designated under subsection (c) the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id65f2ddbaa67d460e946a3437f9db142b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assign a team of staff, including a team leader with appropriate subject matter expertise and experience, for each device for which a request is submitted under subsection (b);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd610f89c49da46c7ba876ba0c15cef24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide for oversight of the team by senior agency personnel to facilitate the efficient development of the device and the efficient review of any submission described in subsection (b) for the device;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id385f14c35f21452c80c06bd14d2c4398"><enum>(C)</enum><text>adopt an efficient process for timely dispute resolution;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68887f4b3c4945439615948980154808"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide for interactive and timely communication with the sponsor of the device during the development program and review process;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f1f866a7e5d429e8fcedf59661b1910"><enum>(E)</enum><text>expedite the Secretary’s review of manufacturing and quality systems compliance, as applicable;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id396970ff21a14d7a81559705f1e70a4a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>disclose to the sponsor not less than 5 business days in advance the topics of any consultation the Secretary intends to undertake with external experts or an advisory committee concerning the sponsor’s device and provide the sponsor the opportunity to recommend such external experts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf11d3f1b09754ab0baafa13f726be0d1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provide for advisory committee input, as the Secretary determines appropriate (including in response to the request of the sponsor) for applications submitted under section 515(c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb98b764d25748218df052a23de01769"><enum>(H)</enum><text>assign staff to be available within a reasonable time to address questions by institutional review committees concerning the conditions and clinical testing requirements applicable to the investigational use of the device pursuant to an exemption under section 520(g).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ddde2dcdc4d4caf804e558ecc6c343c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional actions</header><text>In addition to the actions described in paragraph (1), for purposes of expediting the development and review of devices designated under subsection (c), the Secretary, in collaboration with the device sponsor, may, as appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc7646662d5944669b8b68f64c349c4fe"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate with the sponsor regarding early agreement on a data development plan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idecd067c5734f45759495159a38fceac9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take steps to ensure that the design of clinical trials is as efficient as practicable, when scientifically appropriate, such as through adoption of shorter or smaller clinical trials, application of surrogate endpoints, and the use of adaptive trial designs and Bayesian statistics, to the extent scientifically appropriate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3f92c5a3d1b46e28b821effdaf4976d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitate, when scientifically appropriate, expedited and efficient development and review of the device through utilization of timely post-market data collection with regard to application for approval under section 515(c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide90f1086e18041cd8acff91087d4f886"><enum>(D)</enum><text>agree in writing to clinical protocols that the Secretary will consider binding on the Secretary and the sponsor, subject to—</text>
 <clause id="id24c091db7eaa472db68c9bd339631a0f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>changes to such protocols agreed to in writing by the sponsor and the Secretary; or</text> </clause><clause id="id138a9d09c93e44b79d9cadddabae2810"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a decision, made by the director of the office responsible for reviewing the device submission, that a substantial scientific issue essential to determining the safety or effectiveness of such device exists, provided that such decision is in writing, and is made only after the Secretary provides to the device sponsor or applicant an opportunity for a meeting at which the director and the sponsor or applicant are present and at which the director documents the substantial scientific issue.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idaffb4451acea4ebeb61acb32a00ffe5f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority Review Guidance</header>
 <paragraph id="idb30fe9a9ac7d4889af83389cf5094eb3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Content</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Advancing Breakthrough Devices for Patients Act of 2015</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue guidance on the implementation of this section. Such guidance shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id3efa523b203c4bae85dbf8ab60ac8f17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>set forth the process by which a person may seek a designation under subsection (c);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idafab5bd1a4c34d2d91402900dba587fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide a template for requests under subsection (b);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d2582c3f3634ba2bd83d3c083a1e96b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify the criteria the Secretary will use in evaluating a request for designation under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65d2811ef5554c15a9e18e77c09efbdc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identify the standards the Secretary will use in assigning a team of staff, including team leaders, to review devices designated for expedited development and priority review, including any training required for such personnel to ensure effective and efficient review.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddec0ec2e0a654435a0207beb2262f6af"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text>Prior to finalizing the guidance under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall seek public comment on a proposed guidance.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8288d335a91d4c438d3096fdb3a54667"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Construction</header>
 <paragraph id="idA3D9A122C42546978CD0D31A377EC1D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>This section is intended to encourage the Secretary and provide the Secretary sufficient authorities to apply efficient and flexible approaches to expedite the development of, and prioritize the Food and Drug Administration's review of, devices that represent breakthrough devices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id90d3de9bd637466ca39804852e5db731"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect—</text> <subparagraph id="idF1F85D8F047C4EB3A7B65EF00F289CCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the criteria and standards for evaluating an application pursuant to section 515(c), a report and request for classification under section 513(f)(2), or a report under section 510(k), including the recognition of valid scientific evidence as described in section 513(a)(3)(B) and consideration and application of the least burdensome means of evaluating device effectiveness or demonstrating substantial equivalence between devices with differing technological characteristics, as applicable;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39153B7FFB0046FFB97C1D30AFA48EF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the authority of the Secretary with respect to clinical holds under section 520(g)(8)(A); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20504A8EFE7048B09549EE896DABF5BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the authority of the Secretary to act on an application pursuant to section 515(d) before completion of an establishment inspection, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id63DAEFEE152A43AAB54A16889F62C087"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Documentation and review of significant decisions</header><text>Section 517A(a)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360g-1">21 U.S.C. 360g–1(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>a request for designation under section 515B,</quote> after <quote>application under section 515,</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idF3F349B31B21453C8EA3437AC829441F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of previous program</header>
 <paragraph id="idF0B31785B8F248A79D041243FB5C6AD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 515(d) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360e">21 U.S.C. 360e(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id2A90113ACCC9443282C729FDB39BC1D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97732194A935490B92BF889BED3165A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (5).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id68775DF6A66A4C3BB63C28A83FDDA33B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 737(5) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetics Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379i">21 U.S.C. 379i(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>515(d)(6)</quote> and inserting <quote>515(d)(5)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


