<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2309 IS: U.S. Civil Rights Network Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2309</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151119">November 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 54, United States Code, to establish within the National Park Service the U.S. Civil
			 Rights Network, and for other purposes. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H627ADD82A6B64415B40407B800A27388" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9CD86F78543A464A8723DD105EDF1FAE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S. Civil Rights Network Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9CE69C9F5B814F4082C7B817D387C7B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection id="HBCD03B7161254C1EBD8763B1559ED17D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H02EC92B12937461A8C3DEA817A110194"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the African American civil rights movement includes historic events, court decisions, and legislation, the goals of which were—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8F2A8D94B3414A2BAA4D1AC72576CF84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to end segregation based on race;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5395B71E6384F2F87239EE8841806BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to end discrimination against African Americans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E4922D6D0D245CC964B7F82A3572463"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure that African American citizens could exercise their basic constitutional rights, including the right to vote;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD763017E6CAC4E68946D7B1716DF3F04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the civil rights movement—</text> <subparagraph id="H3B9B2C0B8D574D7FB446DD8CBE1D214D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>helped bridge the divides of race, religion, sectional differences, and nationality;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5547270C61D046A6A5582E3EEA61DC1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>spanned State lines; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ADD86EB4910407D84A18ACFAE4A2396"><enum>(C)</enum><text>joined the ideals of liberty and freedom expressed in the Declaration of Independence, the Constitution, and the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a et seq.</external-xref>) to the extraordinary actions of ordinary men and women working in common purpose for equal rights;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9146CCEC59EE4D46817C1B413C3E49D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Park Service and Organization of American Historians conducted a theme study that identified and interpreted sites related to the Civil Rights movement in accordance with the National Park Service Studies Act of 1999 (as enacted in title III of Appendix C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/113">Public Law 106–113</external-xref>; 113 Stat. 1501A–194);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7651FBCFFB0B4B2BB8E957EF48C0A35F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in conducting the theme study referred to in paragraph (3), the National Park Service and Organization of American Historians found that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2A0E4A3F6EC343D58A16ABF9E5980EA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">although many sites relating to the African American civil rights movement have been identified and recognized in existing National Park System units—</text>
 <clause id="HD091742E61484E12945B0982B30C68B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a number of sites relating to the African American civil rights movement have not been recognized;</text> </clause><clause id="H576AA2B229B94C19BAD81AFD48231956"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">many sites relating to the African American civil rights movement are in imminent danger of being lost or destroyed; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5FC1F257D9B7402D9C7239D8EC242F1F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">many important resource types relating to the African American civil rights movement are not adequately represented and protected;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C906C903CEC434B971A02DBA42D28B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there are many important sites relating to the African American civil rights movement that have high potential for preservation and visitor use in a number of States, the District of Columbia, and territories of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H966400F63B464081BA43A99D511E55AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no single site completely reflects and characterizes the African American civil rights movement, since the story of, and resources associated with, the African American civil rights movement involve networks, regions, and territories of the United States rather than individual sites; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF44C448566FB48A089A749B62836298B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the establishment of a variety of partnerships among the Federal Government, State, and units of local government, and the private sector would be most appropriate for the protection, restoration, and interpretation of the U.S. Civil Rights Network;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85DC22E31E87405CA5E35ABF50ECD740"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Park Service can play a vital role in facilitating the creation and sustained success of the U.S. Civil Rights Network; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD3CD3A1AE0433C92E78079AD27CB0F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the story and significance of the African American civil rights movement can best engage the people of the United States through a national program of the National Park Service that links, in a unified and flexible manner—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE941A94AA6784C97B950A0F1F1DF6FDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">historic buildings, structures, and sites relating to the African American civil rights movement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90A51D641A5F447DADD8B15D01403E2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">geographic areas relating to the African American civil rights movement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D4832329C564D319BF5A26214BB0532"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interpretive centers, museums, and institutions relating to the African American civil rights movement; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9366253E91F341E681211D5AAB8DDF93"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs, activities, community projects, exhibits, and multimedia materials relating to the African American civil rights movement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13A5A63EC3E841E887B7A0B4786258D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="HD06C426FEEF840E1A64C75D2CA639B77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to recognize—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H619D94679EE142EBB3191C4E952805BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the importance of the African American civil rights movement; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CDDB81ADC21423F9725E69A74FAEFEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sacrifices made by the people who fought against discrimination and segregation; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A070C0129C3450CA03744DA1190240B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to authorize the National Park Service to coordinate and facilitate Federal and non-Federal activities to commemorate, honor, and interpret—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDB2CC711A6E8483C8A35C77BBB624EE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the history of the African American civil rights movement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B202AA056A04AB68BB713D48F175D85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the significance of the civil rights movement as a crucial element in the evolution of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000a">42 U.S.C. 2000a et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36E333E6A9004CEC857B8A6A1920F418"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the relevance of the African American civil rights movement in fostering the spirit of social justice and national reconciliation.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9DC6AF2323574A67B7411F2176C11B62"><enum>3.</enum><header>U.S. Civil Rights Network Program</header>
 <subsection id="H5A7BD186C9FC4CD8B4A014DC91D12C83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subdivision 1 of Division B of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 3083 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6815B1AE92F4F319883D7B1DBFB9D33" style="USC">
					<chapter id="HF271DA76D5D54A2BAD53B9142B87E10D" style="OLC"><enum>3084</enum><header>U.S. Civil Rights Network </header>
 <section id="HCB9B58F7FE1C4A2B8CC52991D1AC88C6"><enum>308401.</enum><header>Definition of Network</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter, the term <term>Network</term> means the U.S. Civil Rights Network established under section 308402(a).</text> </section><section id="H83319C62CEF44391B5C6EA2D3170DD75"><enum>308402.</enum><header>U.S. Civil Rights Network</header> <subsection id="H06276F98F7DE4E19B7E37ED37FDDEB1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish, within the Service, a program to be known as the <quote>U.S. Civil Rights Network</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6A273DEFD5904FA19AFC175B15EFD879"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Network, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0802D3AB5EC1476193432A0754C61454"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review studies and reports to complement and not duplicate studies of the historical importance of the African American civil rights movement that may be underway or completed, such as the Civil Rights Framework Study;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FB42F8260544638B3E43AB09D5A9E04"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produce and disseminate appropriate educational materials relating to the African American civil rights movement, such as handbooks, maps, interpretive guides, or electronic information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB21EBEEFEBC841C9ADB85686E6DCE212"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enter into appropriate cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding to provide technical assistance under subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01DED683A4E944CA9F98447145B3A285"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H18B6DB4E97B042228C48548D656A752B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>create and adopt an official, uniform symbol or device for the Network; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CDFD660C409456BBE19E8E46ECC56EB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue regulations for the use of the symbol or device adopted under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B005D382C1A43D39A29AB56A39404EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The Network shall encompass the following elements:</text> <paragraph id="H12A85BDB92DA4F5394C960CAC320F8E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All units and programs of the Service that are determined by the Secretary to relate to the African American civil rights movement during the period from 1939 through 1968.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B3A150FCAD44E9B035B679C99B8085"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Other Federal, State, local, and privately owned properties that—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA724853483F4782A7E173E5A22C61A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relate to the African American civil rights movement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87996451FE0F4BA4B00B99F847030A4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a verifiable connection to the African American civil rights movement; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB3354E8F2E1407AAAE923C17FC57181"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are included in, or determined by the Secretary to be eligible for inclusion in, the National Register of Historic Places.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H498522DD71B94855A8752DC24D778D83"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other governmental and nongovernmental facilities and programs of an educational, research, or interpretive nature that are directly related to the African American civil rights movement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4346530CFB504AC0B8AF357918AB916E"><enum>308403.</enum><header>Cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To achieve the purposes of this chapter and to ensure effective coordination of the Federal and non-Federal elements of the Network described in section 308402(c) with System units and programs of the Service, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding with, and provide technical assistance to the heads of other Federal agencies, States, units of local government, regional governmental bodies, and private entities.</text></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H23114593B9B1413A88E3F408F57C84AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for title 54, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 3083 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C9C78E6A1DF4131BD7D065D162637A2" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">3084. U.S. Civil Rights Network.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


