<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1988 IS: Enhancing Security for Military Personnel Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1988</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To enhance the security of military personnel at United States military installations and operating
			 locations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Security for Military Personnel Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id91343b5e29f94d4295ca1c8cd2c575c9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhancing security of military personnel at United States Department of
			 Defense installations</header>
			<subsection id="id4649d4df6ea44b4dbda4c140884bfb3f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan</header>
 <paragraph id="id508b34e6552246309da95def4a4bb899"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a plan to enhance security of military personnel at Department of Defense installations in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id69d6eb9208b04768a9303ca4797d4116"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, the following elements:</text> <subparagraph id="id7b85b1cd5d0e4ad49099dc6474469b59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A summary of current force protection programs and authorities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4adad8656bab48178c0510f50ee75440"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Criteria for establishing and changing security status of locations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34a2d9f969034046a0490a97d6c70470"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of laws, regulations, and instructions that direct Department of Defense security procedures and guidelines.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd0595913f3d45d4a4e7c51c27a8d8bf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of processes that are authorized to be taken to increase security levels.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4433c8a499854e3aa3eb32bc52448813"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of current rules of engagement for security personnel.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide9ab22e4cc564b74b580f5ac0ee5e35d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A description of training requirements for personnel authorized to carry firearms.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide4dda2f65876463c918d174c4dac4776"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A plan for increasing the number of armed security personnel either permanently or through an auxiliary status.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfbf59d2731b4645bbd03c461f42b892"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A plan for providing the necessary authority for military personnel to carry government firearms both concealed and open carry, to and from duty.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id804357ce08a542ed9f55995d181813c1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A plan for allocating resources for current security posture, and recommended changes to security posture.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48c06c2232de403fb7869c27bbee9b77"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Recommendations on changes needed to be made to current force protection procedures and programs, including legislative and resource changes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf85f4b8b8fbe4a43983e12e8df2bb6b5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with service secretaries, chiefs of staff, and commandant</header><text>In preparing the plan required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall coordinate with the secretaries, chiefs of staff, and commandants of the military services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf64552ab7f184bea99b4c3ddf00d9234"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation with State and local and other entities</header><text>In preparing the plan required under paragraph (1), the Secretary should seek consultation with leaders from State and local governments and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8854F47D9E964200AFEA37F39256CE94"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall, after briefing the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives, implement the recommendations included in the plan submitted under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id35d0cb8084a9403fab41d9afa072ebf5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id9e8c934730b94b8c859fd0f18f16fb1b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department of Defense installations</header><text>The term <term>Department of Defense installations</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7BEF4AEF3BBA4878B4337E6739A2E112"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any facility subject to the custody, jurisdiction, or administration of any Department of Defense component, including leased property; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD13E69BEB92B4CAEB30B883640837440"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes military reservations, installations, bases, posts, camps, stations, arsenals, vessels/ships, and laboratories where a Department of Defense component has operational responsibility for facility security and defense.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id44b16636b905433a9ac3a55ef532955b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States</header><text>The term <term>United States</term> includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


