<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1544 IS: Jurassic Pork Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1544</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150610">June 10, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S358">Mr. Flake</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To rescind unused earmarks provided for the Department of Transportation, and for other purposes. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jurassic Pork Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idaa9605493ff8453c9e24a66502c9ab6d"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unused earmarks</header>
 <subsection id="id29a126aa99f94ef19227ca6d9bee17e8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="idBBE420C0F1A742908FD99A59100C6627"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Executive agency</term> under section 105 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE7447FA74F434C75AA5C094522E9D2C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>earmark</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="ideac5db2c793c4552864aad9f53f84bae"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a congressionally directed spending item, as defined in rule XLIV of the Standing Rules of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0af90702c7e74cc1ace92c0b2bda2b8d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a congressional earmark, as defined in rule XXI of the Rules of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9AD57332063E4F83B030F58F7CCF31E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>unused DOT earmark</term> means an earmark of funds provided for the Department of Transportation as to which more than 90 percent of the dollar amount of the earmark of funds remains available for obligation at the end of the 9th fiscal year following the fiscal year during which the earmark was made available.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4251c336b85c405ab9ec75efabb9d2c3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rescission of unused DOT earmarks</header>
 <paragraph id="id5526F58B402E4D8BB992035992D986E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), effective on October 1 of the 10th fiscal year after funds under an unused DOT earmark are made available, all unobligated amounts made available under the unused DOT earmark are rescinded and shall be transferred to the Highway Trust Fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1551B48B9DFA48B883A59DED2A4EDC4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation may delay the rescission of amounts made available under an unused DOT earmark for 1 year if the Secretary determines that an additional obligation of amounts from the earmark is likely to occur during the 10th fiscal year after funds under the unused DOT earmark are made available.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfdee20e40a154eb7bf9a3987a75c73e3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency-Wide identification and report</header>
 <paragraph id="idd596b1e1bbfe40468942f2add7f16283"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency identification</header><text>Each agency shall identify and submit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget an annual report—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8B1EA523B8C64E799D4FB982DC3BF70E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that identifies each earmark for a project of the agency that is ineligible for funding; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2CECDCB834EF4163AE2F39A44AF80360"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that discusses each project of the agency for which—</text>
 <clause id="idA2517B64080C4628B6D274BC27F28BE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>amounts are made available under an earmark; and</text> </clause><clause id="id7D5B6A48D378422080BED336AA1C5021"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as of the end of a fiscal year, unobligated balances remain available.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f883fa23ecb4bb29448a06562c2127f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to Congress and publically post on the website of the Office of Management and Budget an annual report regarding earmarks (including any earmark that is ineligible for funding) that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2f2b312a317548f8b4637764b9aa27ae"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a listing and accounting for earmarks for which unobligated balances remain available, summarized by agency, which shall include, for each earmark—</text>
 <clause id="idA50BEA42EB69478BA81E387017966BAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of funds made available under the original earmark;</text> </clause><clause id="idE782F6E2AE2C42C6A23793817F4134DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of the unobligated balances that remain available;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id76CC3480852740C9870505F7DB0B8B75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the fiscal year through which the funds are made available, if applicable; and</text> </clause><clause id="id2A64699B8D0F4F8AA5714DFD0873CF0D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recommendations and justifications for whether the earmark should be rescinded or retained in the next fiscal year;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id912098ca258848c1a154d58303747193"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of rescissions resulting from this section and the annual savings resulting from this section for the previous fiscal year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id958f7a3483bb4c78acbe2351865b3608"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a listing and accounting for earmarks provided for the Department of Transportation scheduled to be rescinded under subsection (b) at the end of the fiscal year during which the report is submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


