<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1672 IS: Commercial Driver Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1672</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150624">June 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize States to enter into interstate compacts regarding Class A commercial
			 driver’s licenses.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commercial Driver Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idfd299ba5cd324a03bb2e45fd6c0b9155"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interstate compact test program</header>
 <subsection id="id83E956612DFE418CA20C3540442903B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration shall establish a test program to allow States and the District of Columbia to enter into interstate compacts with contiguous States to standardize the requirements for drivers operating commercial motor vehicles in interstate commerce.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id209F83271B0148F18EB652976B48B90A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mutual recognition of licenses</header><text>A commercial driver’s licenses issued by 1 State participating in an interstate compact under subsection (a) shall be recognized as valid in every State that is participating in such compact.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6137EE20E1D4494F9B74452FF6D2E7C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>In developing an interstate compact under this section, participating States shall provide for minimum licensure standards acceptable for interstate travel under this section, which may include, for drivers under the 21 years of age—</text>
 <paragraph id="idCDD4D6307A2A4532A765C77ED7321DF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>age restrictions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idA2BACE3A5BA340B6B15F0FFCCC4D4A85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>distance from origin (measured in air miles);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5F5F34A2DC4D4C4FB79C05F2706A93CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reporting requirements; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2D4D7790AD4843A18F2122ADEC0E8336"><enum>(4)</enum><text>additional hours of service restrictions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2e2ed2c5cde249c9b4ee71f20c83146a"><enum>3.</enum><header>Approval</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An interstate compact described in section 2 may not go into effect until it has been approved by the governor of each State (or the Mayor of the District of Columbia, if applicable) that is a party to the agreement, after consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration.</text>
 </section><section id="idA71791447CAC4CAD92CF43A6651E680C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit, or otherwise change, the authority to operate in Interstate Commerce for drivers over the age of 21, including by setting the minimum age requirement to receive a Class A commercial driver’s license at 18 years of age.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


