<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1513 IS: Second Chance Reauthorization Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1513</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150604">June 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reauthorize the Second Chance Act of 2007.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Second Chance Reauthorization Act </short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id7f0c89835e8e4769b342194844c5d938"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to existing programs</header>
 <subsection id="id092bf6f3d24648fbbce5e7859405ce46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reauthorization of adult and juvenile offender state and local demonstration projects</header><text>Section 2976 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797w">42 U.S.C. 3797w</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idc5d41405cb0a4273a1c1e20770a5bc94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida80660b7004445ddb4c94052649b29ff" style="OLC"> <subsection id="idac8f7ecc48d445f58561ea04ba6d8a80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><text>The Attorney General shall make grants to States, local governments, territories, or Indian tribes, or any combination thereof (in this section referred to as an <quote>eligible entity</quote>), in partnership with interested persons (including Federal corrections and supervision agencies), service providers, and nonprofit organizations for the purpose of strategic planning and implementation of adult and juvenile offender reentry projects.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb93891d92c37454d93dd2e9d8350d40e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="id290c32a9674d47bca50290977a721413"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>or reentry courts,</quote> after <quote>community,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7448f7381f44cb8a504fbee1daa458e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc77cb727c9aa4fad81ed281ed0e73775"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2db2ffc10a594c0f858fda4111b13eda"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43780b839b794279b0852809a5baa9dc" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idd61c687b799c4f1b9141208ce7e98a02"><enum>(8)</enum><text>promoting employment opportunities consistent with the Transitional Jobs strategy (as defined in section 4 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17502">42 U.S.C. 17502</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8166ac79af004c7bb28f443c9f988d74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsections (d), (e), and (f) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida83a3083fd7e402299df35b5fb95afa7" style="OLC"> <subsection id="idfa2e2b6e89794c00abd793d8a05189c3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Combined grant application; priority consideration</header> <paragraph id="id3b645da308294f07823deb3abfb20b54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall develop a procedure to allow applicants to submit a single application for a planning grant under subsection (e) and an implementation grant under subsection (f).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id706ecfffb40f4e3f935b973a24e553b9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority consideration</header><text>The Attorney General shall give priority consideration to grant applications under subsections (e) and (f) that include a commitment by the applicant to partner with a local evaluator to identify and analyze data that will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ide2c2f2af89df4df89516b5a93f7975b7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enable the grantee to target the intended offender population; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide984c11e4e21463490d2e9e25f95340b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serve as a baseline for purposes of the evaluation.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id000b0f6f98f5446995078d8ef9843f76"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Planning grants</header>
 <paragraph id="id73df5da257bd4b4b94e8aa5fbf589f16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Attorney General may make a grant to an eligible entity of not more than $75,000 to develop a strategic, collaborative plan for an adult or juvenile offender reentry demonstration project as described in subsection (h) that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6f8cc73c79034ad4b16c72f2b5f23e11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a budget and a budget justification;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ebad09cd0d94e11af482f418efe432d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the outcome measures that will be used to measure the effectiveness of the program in promoting public safety and public health;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87958151b4864b7ba81fd4b27b5afc3a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the activities proposed;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb991330612fc494ca4c59b449bcf73bf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a schedule for completion of the activities described in subparagraph (C); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b968cdfc9d94178b557cb000967fb5b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the personnel necessary to complete the activities described in subparagraph (C).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id73785fcd22aa4b7a99d171191ae2a210"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum total grants and geographic diversity</header> <subparagraph id="idbd8d761fae7049ae8184cf06657c7040"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The Attorney General may not make initial planning grants and implementation grants to 1 eligible entity in a total amount that is more than $1,000,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id583b72a0a824401cb672f845f904232e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Geographic diversity</header><text>The Attorney General shall make every effort to ensure equitable geographic distribution of grants under this section and take into consideration the needs of underserved populations, including rural and tribal communities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbaf732b27df940d588656e392b9f59bd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period of grant</header><text>A planning grant made under this subsection shall be for a period of not longer than 1 year, beginning on the first day of the month in which the planning grant is made.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcc779a26037e4c86930012f7d1c57d53"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header>
 <paragraph id="id12280ac4d3f047e693cf820e038d9fde"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring an implementation grant under this subsection shall submit to the Attorney General an application that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3b805fd7d11f466cb48cc9de38b20607"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contains a reentry strategic plan as described in subsection (h), which describes the long-term strategy and incorporates a detailed implementation schedule, including the plans of the applicant to fund the program after Federal funding is discontinued;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id535198c8703e4d10b1ce8ce710b9582b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies the local government role and the role of governmental agencies and nonprofit organizations that will be coordinated by, and that will collaborate on, the offender reentry strategy of the applicant, and certifies the involvement of such agencies and organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida34a60229f6f4a20823ba07ed87ecfaf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>describes the evidence-based methodology and outcome measures that will be used to evaluate the program funded with a grant under this subsection, and specifically explains how such measurements will provide valid measures of the impact of that program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id020c2a82cfa84d56885e0b16e8e257c1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>describes how the project could be broadly replicated if demonstrated to be effective.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida773cfb60ee1407e9e985597665c603f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Attorney General may make a grant to an applicant under this subsection only if the application—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id348261d50af642a08d39ba8ee0cd0d97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflects explicit support of the chief executive officer, or their designee, of the State, unit of local government, territory, or Indian tribe applying for a grant under this subsection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1a8f6d470b344ab196f4561ea7a281a0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides discussion of the role of Federal corrections, State corrections departments, community corrections agencies, juvenile justice systems, and tribal or local jail systems in ensuring successful reentry of offenders into their communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29ae8f788dee4670a78facce936dd7ba"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides evidence of collaboration with State, tribal, and local government agencies overseeing health, housing, child welfare, education, substance abuse, victims services, and employment services, and with local law enforcement agencies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36dfa39496734986a6e3acf51fe0bb2c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides a plan for analysis of the statutory, regulatory, rules-based, and practice-based hurdles to reintegration of offenders into the community;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb67d106d65c44ba69fa17a8ba900a4af"><enum>(E)</enum><text>includes the use of a State, local, territorial, or tribal task force, described in subsection (i), to carry out the activities funded under the grant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0968785aee4473b94c25d07f7770b35"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provides a plan for continued collaboration with a local evaluator as necessary to meeting the requirements under subsection (h); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04e0fc92fef94a648f6cd379e5e30b6f"><enum>(G)</enum><text>demonstrates that the applicant participated in the planning grant process or engaged in comparable planning for the reentry project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6cb8c534420848b480a7bd63bb22d12f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority considerations</header><text>The Attorney General shall give priority to grant applications under this subsection that best—</text> <subparagraph id="id11114dd1fda54aeaa1b6bf1023405a8e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>focus initiative on geographic areas with a disproportionate population of offenders released from prisons, jails, and juvenile facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd0733835f31413aabeaae63ee7bd91f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include—</text> <clause id="id4605c3dc1def4fd6a484bd19e53c8d20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>input from nonprofit organizations, in any case where relevant input is available and appropriate to the grant application;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id03510a5703ae4f879c295934daa69444"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consultation with crime victims and offenders who are released from prisons, jails, and juvenile facilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id681045c70b39449da5eb02077df99f25"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordination with families of offenders;</text> </clause><clause id="id07cd825ec3054cbabe52a10bc2a16276"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>input, where appropriate, from the juvenile justice coordinating council of the region;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcf02b8034ff44df3a29dbd5ea736d6ce"><enum>(v)</enum><text>input, where appropriate, from the reentry coordinating council of the region; or</text> </clause><clause id="id4b2787f513c54d839b90831f853bf90d"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>input, where appropriate, from other interested persons;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0606456ef124e35969381070947dd80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrate effective case assessment and management abilities in order to provide comprehensive and continuous reentry, including—</text>
 <clause id="id1b780d1bff614392bb8d36a1235e7ba1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>planning for prerelease transitional housing and community release that begins upon admission for juveniles and jail inmates, and, as appropriate, for prison inmates, depending on the length of the sentence;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id42a379e103744ddd94c0ccde34654023"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establishing prerelease planning procedures to ensure that the eligibility of an offender for Federal, tribal, or State benefits upon release is established prior to release, subject to any limitations in law, and to ensure that offenders obtain all necessary referrals for reentry services, including assistance identifying and securing suitable housing; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6ddaea6447f547a5bd77c049358301ae"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>delivery of continuous and appropriate mental health services, drug treatment, medical care, job training and placement, educational services, vocational services, and any other service or support needed for reentry;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7733ace6612f4d0b8730b8532b2ce3f3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>review the process by which the applicant adjudicates violations of parole, probation, or supervision following release from prison, jail, or a juvenile facility, taking into account public safety and the use of graduated, community-based sanctions for minor and technical violations of parole, probation, or supervision (specifically those violations that are not otherwise, and independently, a violation of law);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75d14e82a32b4fc0b1ff939463042a83"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide for an independent evaluation of reentry programs that include, to the maximum extent possible, random assignment and controlled studies to determine the effectiveness of such programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c68a5a2e39540629bc65dd696eebb51"><enum>(F)</enum><text>target moderate and high-risk offenders for reentry programs through validated assessment tools; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3122a6b81a1240fcbfecbc9f819db605"><enum>(G)</enum><text>target offenders with histories of homelessness, substance abuse, or mental illness, including a prerelease assessment of the housing status of the offender and behavioral health needs of the offender with clear coordination with mental health, substance abuse, and homelessness services systems to achieve stable and permanent housing outcomes with appropriate support service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id286ff0f479aa40fca005057c4621588d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Period of grant</header><text>A grant made under this subsection shall be effective for a 2-year period—</text> <subparagraph id="ide2240a8504f84533ae0df4501b4be5e4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the date on which the planning grant awarded under subsection (e) concludes; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13a43cba34954f31a1c06d9d2a0822bb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an implementation grant awarded to an eligible entity that did not receive a planning grant, beginning on the date on which the implementation grant is awarded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida59bda4f15ac4849990592fbeabf3e99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h)—</text> <subparagraph id="id1c9b5b17422849b69f03d8b93a658f30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe7c34779d1a451e95b47182d6482aaf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb92bb5be228b4d00b3137ddfde53b013" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id1a4828f9fc9e4ac39a0dccfa146a6313"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition of receiving financial assistance under subsection (f), each application shall develop a comprehensive reentry strategic plan that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd182e9e0d6644dc59eeeb402934f413b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contains a plan to assess inmate reentry needs and measurable annual and 3-year performance outcomes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9db7be90cb314cab9285a0b415c84b9a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uses, to the maximum extent possible, randomly assigned and controlled studies, or rigorous quasi-experimental studies with matched comparison groups, to determine the effectiveness of the program funded with a grant under subsection (f); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1efa28afdf44326a26a24964a068d41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes as a goal of the plan to reduce the rate of recidivism for offenders released from prison, jail or a juvenile facility with funds made available under subsection (f).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c18fb1a810c4d0ea56c1fc4a03a2755"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local evaluator</header><text>A partnership with a local evaluator described in subsection (d)(2) shall require the local evaluator to use the baseline data and target population characteristics developed under a subsection (e) planning grant to derive a target goal for recidivism reduction during the 3-year period beginning on the date of implementation of the program.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd6d1debd5c84941b02535139477a1d2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (i)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="id91ef140ce51041958903c43349ff7c5a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>under this section</quote> and inserting <quote>under subsection (f)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f38c6ec33fe442485ed21e8c5d7ebbd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>subsection (e)(4)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (f)(2)(D)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c6d320a1f304e3f8ffb04fe4f46287f"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (j)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7ea97f5426344b6193de97d89eff4a88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>for an implementation grant under subsection (f)</quote> after <quote>applicant</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f23221c30254559a8de74afb38520ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause id="id26a9c1f2e7b54e8abd041fcd9233891e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by inserting <quote>, where appropriate</quote> after <quote>support</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="id06d6522fb95b457693b17ad74a5a4c81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (F), (G), and (H), and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6506f2da1dbc4c18a77f53e05e611248" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id0acc73d7d7524e7d9fefd028fa951125"><enum>(F)</enum><text>increased number of staff trained to administer reentry services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4f2ea8645b446ecb88930361a0a42bd"><enum>(G)</enum><text>increased proportion of individuals served by the program among those eligible to receive services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f233b9cf20e4be8806d06cfd296fd56"><enum>(H)</enum><text>increased number of individuals receiving risk screening needs assessment, and case planning services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ed17386b78740e6a097de002b47892f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>increased enrollment in, and completion of treatment services, including substance abuse and mental health services among those assessed as needing such services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1470c73c9c554fabaa908fae880e2acf"><enum>(J)</enum><text>increased enrollment in and degrees earned from educational programs, including high school, GED, vocational training, and college education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab35754f089e49ea9c68f24bfb72a290"><enum>(K)</enum><text>increased number of individuals obtaining and retaining employment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a15452664a5411b8fc2dcb6853e5a6e"><enum>(L)</enum><text>increased number of individuals obtaining and maintaining housing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b2de56fb4854c14a85c496f6006bd8b"><enum>(M)</enum><text>increased self-reports of successful community living, including stability of living situation and positive family relationships;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1a1a11681a3341088ca5d0d346d5764d"><enum>(N)</enum><text>reduction in drug and alcohol use; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id195a2f64bb6d43dd96843094e307bfe8"><enum>(O)</enum><text>reduction in recidivism rates for individuals receiving reentry services after release, as compared to either baseline recidivism rates in the jurisdiction of the grantee or recidivism rates of the control or comparison group.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8fc51766cfc42e989a0ce060f097606"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>facilities.</quote> and inserting <quote>facilities, including a cost-benefit analysis to determine the cost effectiveness of the reentry program.</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f02f40d6dd44308a6bd28363acfcd9d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>this section</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (f)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50a2c2bc6dd647e3ab7ce67c5126edcf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>this section</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (f)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1767916135d84c63a8b701516836c316"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (k)(1), by striking <quote>this section</quote> each place the term appears and inserting <quote>subsection (f)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9f64680f26f54546a919800b2e1b4dd6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in subsection (l)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idfe554359a750455ab6840a03f1deb9cc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>beginning on the date on which the most recent implementation grant is made to the grantee under subsection (f)</quote> after <quote>2-year period</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81a1b3fb30fc4d058a219c79d69bdfd0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>over a 2-year period</quote> and inserting <quote>during the 2-year period described in paragraph (2)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id75ebb3ce48a04c228a1f65c9474ea5cd"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subsection (o)(1), by striking <quote>appropriated</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>appropriated $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3e2b0e33d5094cd2ba8352b9231e7dd2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4cbd6dfcbd2443ae9752f191908e49e7" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id883dece22fc44524b93eb16c844abbd0"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>reentry court</term> means a program that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id53b8e017ea91450aac60400acaa6b775"><enum>(1)</enum><text>monitors juvenile and adult eligible offenders reentering the community;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0ae858941aaa4882891d102e70a03430"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides continual judicial supervision;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc393de4cf0284bea8f41ba52d3f8eaee"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides juvenile and adult eligible offenders reentering the community with coordinated and comprehensive reentry services and programs, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id0cb26976fc1c4c9c9cf214def6881c05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>drug and alcohol testing and assessment for treatment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3273ad8590a740d9b6044bb69c0c36a5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessment for substance abuse from a substance abuse professional who is approved by the State or Indian tribe and licensed by the appropriate entity to provide alcohol and drug addiction treatment, as appropriate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf60c2aed29ac42148f9a0f538fa847cf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>substance abuse treatment, including medication assisted treatment, from a provider that is approved by the State or Indian tribe, and licensed, if necessary, to provide medical and other health services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f22318fa9d7493f994d443827ddc21a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>health (including mental health) services and assessment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5dcdc20bae6643169a24a170b7277a2b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>aftercare and case management services that—</text>
 <clause id="idabfbe5dfaee845ed9c64a0047562d749"><enum>(i)</enum><text>facilitate access to clinical care and related health services; and</text> </clause><clause id="id2cdb91e2500542fe8e6d8e6785357008"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinate with such clinical care and related health services; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0b9d06cbfb0a454692bdb9039d3df27a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other services needed for reentry;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfcd274df611444088f92abc2233b7b99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>convenes community impact panels, victim impact panels, or victim impact educational classes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id25a3c6e1f44b402299adb4ca4386f786"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provides and coordinates the delivery of community services to juvenile and adult eligible offenders, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id73fde3cd139c4d0b8e83cdeac6aa311c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>housing assistance;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id074c2f2ce9ba4d7aaa0a94eae2634d42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f1e6af2222d45a8834e38c95dea3ca9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>job training;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c36ae6083a640a99fba046c13a163e5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conflict resolution skills training;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f4e3d80550e44b58cf2e7b010631ee3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>batterer intervention programs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ead1532959e4667930778fc4b266314"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other appropriate social services; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd5b818c962c49d59fcd91048b1f4fef"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establishes and implements graduated sanctions and incentives.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9915b192a9334abd84906bc0cb2a5337"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants for family-Based substance abuse treatment</header><text>Part DD of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797s">42 U.S.C. 3797s et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idfbfe661088da40dca63cd9c391ae1f11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797s">42 U.S.C. 3797s</external-xref>), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>nonprofit organizations,</quote> before <quote>and Indian</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id84c04128f2c846a1921d808652fe129e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2923 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797s-2">42 U.S.C. 3797s–2</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2447952f35dc4dc8995f56b71db94160" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="iddfe1249a73474479b94e431bb384dc8a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority considerations</header><text>The Attorney General shall give priority consideration to grant applications for grants under section 2921 that are submitted by a nonprofit organization that demonstrates a relationship with State and local criminal justice agencies, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3181b6f7865a47668a8cc1b5fda6bacf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>within the judiciary and prosecutorial agencies; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idce3e74fc926d40ee8282613c3b9e7155"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with the local corrections agencies, which shall be documented by a written agreement that details the terms of access to facilities and participants and provides information on the history of the organization of working with correctional populations.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5d93482d59504beb8eaaae3c1eac0868"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking section 2926(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797s-5">42 U.S.C. 3797s–5(a)</external-xref>), and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf55790a70bef46818ec0a8eff83c6bec" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id6e557073bc9b4384ad18fbcefd3ffd0e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbb3ab390750c45e98eb07fa728f19757"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant program To evaluate and improve educational methods at prisons, jails, and juvenile
 facilities</header><text>Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3711">42 U.S.C. 3711 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id4e933899ca9a497487aa6bbc513ae9bb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating part KK (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797ee">42 U.S.C. 3797ee et seq.</external-xref>) as part LL;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id32f071acc85e41139b09ae0c22639afe"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating the second part designated as part JJ, as added by the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/199">Public Law 110–199</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 677), relating to grants to evaluate and improve educational methods, as part KK;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida350787bc3be42e7aca5b17025df7836"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating the second section designated as section 3001 and section 3002 (42 U.S.C. 3797dd and 3797dd–1), as added by the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/199">Public Law 110–199</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 677), relating to grants to evaluate and improve educational methods, as sections 3005 and 3006, respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id162354a8e4224bfe991c327aff5c3e29"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 3005, as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="idad598dea962948f9992972326a35d25e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <clause id="id896401ba898343bab70d14b4bd5c1f8a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="id2cf11554731d45ca84c6661c55566308"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id130fda18fab0435d946b0556fe22a10a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81053d16ddf8477e99fe94af3ea57ad1" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id0e48b25c6fa54936ab17156c5cd7e095"><enum>(4)</enum><text>implement methods to improve academic and vocational education for offenders in prisons, jails, and juvenile facilities consistent with the best practices identified in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d73f55895f0473c90032d309df201fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id54056265d488453983d5b9554e1884b5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b), the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26291e4b0ee744a28f0104391f433ffa" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id65a5eccc40ed4fbeb47f266f6019e7c6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Second Chance Reauthorization Act, the Attorney General shall identify and publish best practices relating to academic and vocational education for offenders in prisons, jails, and juvenile facilities. The best practices shall consider the evaluations performed and recommendations made under grants made under subsection (a) before the date of enactment of the Second Chance Reauthorization Act .</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd58f315255dd43598578c9e4cc3450c7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 3006, as so redesignated, by striking <quote>to carry</quote> and all that follows through <quote>2010</quote> and inserting <quote>for each of fiscal years 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, and 2020 for grants for purposes described in section 3005(a)(4)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida7852cccaabc4e5999f14be745187219"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Careers training demonstration grants</header>
 <paragraph id="id99B0C645C105493CAE72BB4F58CB19FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 115 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17511">42 U.S.C. 17511</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idf087c99ac51b43da83e5061913b7557b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Technology careers</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Careers</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF7D36574D7154399A60761C21F5F0784"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="ida4b58a4aa6bc43cf9d6a17e6db2e1823"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and Indian</quote> and inserting <quote>nonprofit organizations, and Indian</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0715a0613e284455af7892de8e4c60dc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>technology career training to prisoners</quote> and inserting <quote>career training, including subsidized employment, when part of a training program, to prisoners and reentering youth and adults</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6bc98a24fd7047feab0d7d88fa3fafb6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="idd12bece15b384a6b944ab7b3924ca752"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>technology careers training</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2a123680a39d4c69b818dc12ff9539b2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>technology-based</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="ideae681f093f145c8b2b0738db5d82f3c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, as well as upon transition and reentry into the community</quote> after <quote>facility</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide91a72129e2f47e9b6bcba2765007da3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFC09EE1D9E8A440EB630A6C3A2773164"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id862235c83ba64c5d991f31e9b5462544"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id140CE66D2EB543729824C2E84F0D8CA3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id252867b8b15043be96bb52e6539b46af"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority consideration</header><text>Priority consideration shall be given to any application under this section that—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide59a803580364ce39b7239446141c77b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides assessment of local demand for employees in the geographic areas to which offenders are likely to return;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida9308c93dcf34f2db250cf3dc830404c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conducts individualized reentry career planning upon the start of incarceration or post-release employment planning for each offender served under the grant;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbe5e7aacfa4d4f218178cf5f5d781a88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demonstrates connections to employers within the local community; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idf1007cde2eac4472bef6dde827b801a4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>tracks and monitors employment outcomes.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9791D1E605F44C8ABE7DAF63B3A83D33"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e), as redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49C6E03FF9954362AA6E784901869D41" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id27dd3b8711b24abca89ccec9e11de600"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, and 2020.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id08BB91FC3EA44A829F81AC3F9881373C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17501">42 U.S.C. 17501</external-xref> note) is amended by striking the item relating to section 115 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE600972E8C6840588CE989899DFD308A" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 115. Careers training demonstration grants.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc6fe036e8df34621a966e4e9195291a1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Offender reentry substance abuse and criminal justice collaboration program</header><text>Section 201(f)(1) of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17521">42 U.S.C. 17521(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb06e7b2558fc4e0cbe735e9c8b9d3c78" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idcde8c5d863e84c1199446f733521903d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="idff8b971f663c4b7892a7aec30355bd63"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Community-Based mentoring and transitional service grants to nonprofit organizations</header>
 <paragraph id="id2167b40d325043aab37d8b7f51edd7eb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 211 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17531">42 U.S.C. 17531</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id1e9d5838e2a44e94aef1489860c467db"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the header, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">MENTORING GRANTS TO NONPROFIT ORGANIZATIONS</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">COMMUNITY-BASED MENTORING AND TRANSITIONAL SERVICE GRANTS TO NONPROFIT ORGANIZATIONS</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56fd0c3e5b964c0581f7797afdc1073a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>mentoring and other</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6499bcd79ff34a8b98dd8acfb5acacb8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id945fed7f6cfc4cfab9b91394949d9892" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id1ad3ed912bfa45858538f056644c19b4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transitional services to assist in the reintegration of offenders into the community, including—</text> <subparagraph id="ide72ab9fa94394f0c90b0e13768a47af6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educational, literacy, and vocational, services and the Transitional Jobs strategy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c9306a85d0846aea5b397d99ef2b050"><enum>(B)</enum><text>substance abuse treatment and services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idecd1b0a88857417cb570c4a1b7226b9e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinated supervision and comprehensive services for offenders, including housing and mental and physical health care;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id695130e1b0e34f98884133220e012cc5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>family services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id755f02c4a7764aa09e2eeaf73a6d79a1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>validated assessment tools to assess the risk factors of returning inmates; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcef564ea730d49eba3bd24ce33c7962c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>this section</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id41e83f3ffc0d432d96e315d2af24d629"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17501">42 U.S.C. 17501</external-xref> note) is amended by striking the item relating to section 211 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB321B47708F64B5C803D49ABEEA93CDA" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 211. Community-based mentoring and transitional service grants.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id18a481ee3394406abfe997fe64d198df"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <paragraph id="idd7ceaf607d9046dea6706585a30e2310"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17502">42 U.S.C. 17502</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96de73486c704fceb624cf6734f99a7a" style="OLC"> <section id="id5e8c27f2a81542919851a99b2a55364a"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="id30d9c068a78b4dbe9fd2b8f441ffdca9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>exoneree</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="id90279cbdd5a74c45b43419a05d5814f5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been convicted of a Federal, tribal, or State offense that is punishable by a term of imprisonment of more than 1 year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1234819c77a8482081584d659c59d0f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has served a term of imprisonment for not less than 6 months in a Federal, tribal, or State prison or correctional facility as a result of the conviction described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec9e85a8b1724269a28a230567b001a6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has been determined to be factually innocent of the offense described in subparagraph (A);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd98d5413eaf4d29836d4a48232de3bf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3791">42 U.S.C. 3791</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddd8e0a3c0b05409dab067569fe581eae"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>offender</term> includes an exoneree;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idDFB376B20622460B9BF7C029361E43B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>recidivism</term> shall be defined in accordance with the measure selected by the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics under section 231(d)(3)(B); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5f1a509d3d414ed0b5be856b0bb61e42"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>Transitional Jobs strategy</term> means an employment strategy for youth and adults who are chronically unemployed or those that have barriers to employment that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3360e03f5d04445cb69a247ac357f8e0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is conducted by State, tribal, and local governments, State, tribal, and local workforce boards, and nonprofit organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9348ad75d9614c8cbc4e45865401faa5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides time-limited employment using individual placements, team placements, and social enterprise placements, without displacing existing employees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7b647af45c98422f821777b5a66d8088"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pays wages in accordance with applicable law, but in no event less than the higher of the rate specified in section 6(a)(1) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206(a)(1)</external-xref>) or the applicable State or local minimum wage law, which are subsidized, in whole or in part, by public funds;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id088cb3596b7d4a63ae70bf786c84787b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>combines time-limited employment with activities that promote skill development, remove barriers to employment, and lead to unsubsidized employment such as a through orientation and individual assessment, job readiness and life skills training, case management and supportive services, adult education and training, child support-related services, job retention support and incentives, and other similar activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7e7830958b54782a7cb611e72957b81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>places participants into unsubsidized employment; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62d577a5b0944112a2679aa97b6fa642"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provides job retention, re-employment services, and continuing and vocational education to ensure continuing participation in unsubsidized employment and identification of opportunities for advancement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0b66cd01873a46a9a6bf75a597cb2afc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17501">42 U.S.C. 17501</external-xref> note) is amended by striking the item relating to section 4 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id899A01D7590E4BF1BF97A8073535669A" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2739ac0e6ff84fa197728eecd834a48d"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Extension of the length of section 2976 grants</header><text>Section 6(1) of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17504">42 U.S.C. 17504(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or under section 2976 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797w">42 U.S.C. 3797w</external-xref>)</quote> after <quote>and 212</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="iddd30e98d1e64497a90ced71368d8e146"><enum>3.</enum><header>Audit and accountability of grantees</header> <subsection id="idc2881d4ef4304706a1d8a244f3295e94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8fcd987c9b9449c485a258a9d991e5f6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered grant program</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id5210e265636d4cddb4f18ba6487e4b2e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>grants awarded under section 115 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17511">42 U.S.C. 17511</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd10338ce21f441fb343e25845a33862"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grants awarded under section 201 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17521">42 U.S.C. 17521</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfbdd6f66a70f4d2bbc1603b05ea75998"><enum>(C)</enum><text>grants awarded under section 211 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17431">42 U.S.C. 17431</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e6ac4d98db444648373429264856938"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered grantee</term> means a recipient of a grant from a covered grant program; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e74c2acfe274b669422f389faac0d5d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>unresolved audit finding</term> means an audit report finding in a final audit report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice that a covered grantee has used grant funds awarded to that grantee under a covered grant program for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved during the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the final audit report is issued.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2ee8cf9348c9495b92e167e4d906ce45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Audit requirement</header><text>Beginning in fiscal year 2016, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of covered grantees to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of such funds. The Inspector General shall determine the appropriate number of covered grantees to be audited each year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2801c88519c94e419cc35a64cc750132"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mandatory exclusion</header><text>A grantee that is found to have an unresolved audit finding under an audit conducted under subsection (b) may not receive grant funds under a covered grant program in the fiscal year following the fiscal year to which the finding relates.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idd43cb22a1bfa4aaf9e87a551fb568375"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>If a covered grantee is awarded funds under the covered grant program from which it received a grant award during the 2-fiscal year period during which the covered grantee is ineligible for an allocation of grant funds as a result of subsection (b), the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8417a5859159449d8c6510b5f9391fd9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deposit an amount equal to the amount of the grant funds that were improperly awarded to the covered grantee into the General Fund of the Treasury; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idac408db97df34f7798d38f562235b9e1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to recoup the costs of the repayment to the Fund from the covered grantee that was erroneously awarded grant funds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc197ce5617714316b2f12aaec7374e66"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority of grant awards</header><text>The Attorney General, in awarding grants under a covered grant program shall give priority to eligible entities that during the 2-year period preceding the application for a grant have not been found to have an unresolved audit finding.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ida7db9ed5191c4c37b169790cf7fb1256"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="id5a539dc899314c4da02bbab374646c1e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>nonprofit</term>, when used with respect to an organization, means an organization that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2ab0478b2a4748dbbc97013041cee5ef"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A nonprofit organization that holds money in offshore accounts for the purpose of avoiding paying the tax described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/511">section 511(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, shall not be eligible to receive, directly or indirectly, any funds from a covered grant program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddcea5efaaabc4c58b4bc4f4e8847070c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Each nonprofit organization that is a covered grantee shall disclose in its application for such a grant, as a condition of receipt of such a grant, the compensation of its officers, directors, and trustees. Such disclosure shall include a description of the criteria relied upon to determine such compensation.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf955a36d7b3c4816b67aa4328cbfc9c8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Conference expenditures</header>
 <paragraph id="id1a0a31edd453455c925813d0a0b05b04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Justice under this Act, or any amendments made by this Act, may be used by the Attorney General, or by any individual or organization awarded discretionary funds through a cooperative agreement under this Act, or any amendments made by this Act, to host or support any expenditure for conferences that uses more than $20,000 in Department funds, unless the Deputy Attorney General or such Assistant Attorney Generals, Directors, or principal deputies as the Deputy Attorney General may designate, provides prior written authorization that the funds may be expended to host a conference. A conference that uses more than $20,000 in such funds, but less than an average of $500 in such funds for each attendee of the conference, shall not be subject to the limitations of this paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id16e325c2f6914c7c9b95645c6599fd53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Written approval</header><text>Written approval under paragraph (1) shall include a written estimate of all costs associated with the conference, including the cost of all food and beverages, audiovisual equipment, honoraria for speakers, and any entertainment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcc3ecfc4386b4bcaa46bdf486ff2f31a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Deputy Attorney General shall submit an annual report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives on all approved conference expenditures referenced in this paragraph.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id51ae7dc474c840fba44c1073a7c8c2e0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition on lobbying activity</header>
 <paragraph id="id2b503b810cca41c5a9b34ef16b79ae2b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts made available under a covered grant program may not be used by any covered grantee to—</text> <subparagraph id="ide115cf2adb96404e8113b5f476c58a95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lobby any representative of the Department of Justice regarding the award of grant funding; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53362cc4c6964a07a274cdf3d20b2e01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lobby any representative of the Federal Government or a State, local, or tribal government regarding the award of grant funding.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f175b7749ac4a4b99da7d46f9c72a65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that a covered grantee has violated paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc0136b59d5fe4e26a4d064b9bb035025"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require the covered grantee to repay the grant in full; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c58dd27e450454e84badd7b4aef2a09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prohibit the covered grantee from receiving a grant under the covered grant program from which it received a grant award during at least the 5-year period beginning on the date of such violation.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8a3ce1816ae141f6a641681bc0986ca8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal reentry improvements</header>
 <subsection id="id36683a19843f4b35ac801790d05edf2f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Responsible reintegration of offenders</header><text>Section 212 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17532">42 U.S.C. 17532</external-xref>) is repealed.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id82f43f74b9e945bf96f93aa4dd9c05d0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal prisoner reentry initiative</header><text>Section 231 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17541">42 U.S.C. 17541</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id42a4b6febdea49afa3024c589d240b79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> <subparagraph id="id07c9bd2726e74407ba9a64e011ab9085"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Elderly and family reunification for certain nonviolent offenders pilot program</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Program for certain aging offenders</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEC203886C2584D92B4AEA5F7778BCFF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="id6FEF78C5CE48445C90960F9B2D9A5A75"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF585B990696145D78B9BA6ABEF19F362" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id0622EE50A07D44CDAE61E4876FB055C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall conduct a program to place eligible aging offenders from Bureau of Prisons facilities on home detention until the expiration of the prison terms of the offenders.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="idA1481EECBEBD4134B6CAF5B3BFBAFEF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subclause id="idA27C85563C1C487EB90EA22FFA21DB63"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>pilot</quote>;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idAC97624433ED472882804A6A0A66753E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>elderly</quote> and inserting <quote>aging</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id6B15F8647FEC46A8A443586228747509"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, upon written request from either the Bureau of Prisons or an eligible aging offender</quote> after <quote>to home detention</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id339F631413074FD58B2B077820B94112"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <subclause id="idD439C3E675ED44FB81EA2AC9D40650EE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>elderly</quote> and inserting <quote>aging</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5F6CF201504A418D9077095365971AA4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>pilot</quote>;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD48B3154833B4E108C75DB1FF873B781"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>elderly</quote> and inserting <quote>aging</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69B6037AB9694DF0ACC7C21FF6BE1FCE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC7F19844D0B44A0296B4FACED416A6E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19ec24985b164a65966b7e8fdabe239c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), as redesignated—</text> <clause id="idA9B2751B3E1F4215812F8080406B9572"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>elderly</quote> each place the term appears and inserting <quote>aging</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id429D8E2FA4B1488B9E35B6D30147DF50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>Congress</quote> and all that follows through <quote>paragraph (3).</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>Congress annually the number of inmates who applied for consideration under the program; the number of applications approved and the number denied at the facility level and the number of applications approved and the number denied by the Director; for those denied at either point, the statutory basis for the denial; the average length of time to adjudicate an application, from initial filing to final determination; and the cost savings associated with releasing aging inmates to home detention and additional ways to increase savings that could be achieved under the program without endangering public safety.</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8D60075B81204660960F40D2BC6BE841"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), as redesignated—</text> <clause id="id541D50E5085647958C8EAD29FB0B43A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <subclause id="id58d0313b12084e7cb5dc6a99d43d351b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">elderly</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">aging</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id3D5A10837467473FAC0975DDEE086E53"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>elderly</quote> and inserting <quote>aging</quote>;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id2BA9292762704C8686A0310091024CE5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>65 years</quote> and inserting <quote>60 years</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idd37bd786c59749519b46936181f35f81"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text>
 <item id="id0977480D710B44CF84243F9496076755"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>that is not life imprisonment</quote>;</text> </item><item id="idA90AA5FA5B2A4B4986F2B597AE7344F1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the greater of 10 years or 75 percent</quote> and inserting <quote><fraction>2⁄3</fraction></quote>; and</text>
 </item><item id="id0DD1F5450E3F43698B08A0443CE0599C"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or in the case of an offender sentenced to life in prison, the offender has served 30 years</quote> after <quote>was sentenced</quote>;</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="id65F09329B8484A7C9274B4172C5D1F84"><enum>(V)</enum><text>by striking clause (iii);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idF5787420D3C04E8BA2A9AF442479CED4"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (iv) through (vii) as clauses (iii) through (vi), respectively;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id69B6D0633E2048FCBAEF4DC254E38FBF"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>in clause (iii), as redesignated, by inserting <quote>while in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons</quote> after <quote>clause (ii)</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id12F56089BFE54975A3DA814A2FFF09A9"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>in clause (vi), as redesignated, by inserting <quote>, after reviewing the offender's age, health, and behavioral record in custody,</quote> after <quote>Prisons</quote>; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id39BF5CB5BE684F1D9DE8199602604882"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>April 9, 2008</quote> and inserting <quote>November 1, 2014</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF7B0AA9C273F4C0B96B7A4F31A35BBB4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61C4C4B0A1A24DFFBC8096AE99BEDD87" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id686508A48AF84957AF7C5D08973EA51C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Second Chance Reauthorization Act</short-title>, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the state of accessibility for inmates with mobility impairments at facilities operated by the Bureau of Prisons, which shall include a description of efforts being made to address any lack of accessibility identified.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idedd8add06ad34aa9bd3c9293210f68ae"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (h);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc2b731409db743558a33868d4f0e4503"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (i) as subsection (h); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5ef722d78fba4520a3850aac24884723"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>2009 and 2010</quote> and inserting <quote>2016 through 2020</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id53c65df625eb4824aae06d061f9b394b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enhancing reporting requirements pertaining to community corrections</header><text>Section 3624(c) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf739388922c447329866f9c3a321fe84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>, and number of prisoners not being placed in community corrections facilities for each reason set forth</quote> before <quote>, and any other information</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idaa4d1c4e97494899a87052e92372703d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>the Second Chance Act of 2007</quote> and inserting <quote>the <short-title>Second Chance Reauthorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0508f821b10846ffbc4de46320b0028c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of study on effectiveness of depot naltrexone for heroin addiction</header><text>Section 244 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17554">42 U.S.C. 17554</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8b6401de7e3e4ee19444ed3df9069e1b"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for research</header><text>Section 245 of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17555">42 U.S.C. 17555</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id81a198aae6db42539ed4d333367fcaef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>243, and 244</quote> and inserting <quote>and 243</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id733d4f8f11c442509a64072f61d3d6aa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2009 and 2010</quote> and inserting <quote>$5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, and 2020</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id37167e3b3cdc44d695cb52baebc745d2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal prisoner recidivism reduction programming enhancement</header> <paragraph id="ideb61cf7a39b84fcabfcc5bab992f6f79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3621 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id02690fd4f8b1433a97cc0b26173dd73e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id707422ca2e1d493ba28c29601e2c13eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac269dbe635446e1b22901b8e80d6b53" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="id3c134f2a4d9c4d1c91883caaddd66f6f"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Partnerships To expand access to reentry programs proven To reduce recidivism</header>
 <paragraph id="idad72ded026dd4096a974c2a90ad0b8c4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>The term <term>demonstrated to reduce recidivism</term> means that the Director of Bureau of Prisons has determined that appropriate research has been conducted and has validated the effectiveness of the type of program on recidivism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida6f27def431248be99c453c48aac4a4c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility for recidivism reduction partnership</header><text>A faith-based or community-based nonprofit organization that provides mentoring or other programs that have been demonstrated to reduce recidivism is eligible to enter into a recidivism reduction partnership with a prison or community-based facility operated by the Bureau of Prisons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id34cb6431169f4f3f8c3bba451155aa73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recidivism reduction partnerships</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall develop policies to require wardens of prisons and community-based facilities to enter into recidivism reduction partnerships with faith-based and community-based nonprofit organizations that are willing to provide, on a volunteer basis, programs described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f929ec2ea0e46b2a3ba40b79b324149"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall submit to Congress an annual report on the last day of each fiscal year that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3ea3bc543efb4481941e72ba118ee844"><enum>(A)</enum><text>details, for each prison and community-based facility for the fiscal year just ended—</text> <clause id="id24d72cfdba674a3680ca7a0dd0dfb683"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of recidivism reduction partnerships under this section that were in effect;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id088fc8c7ad194748989721d9b58dfbb6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of volunteers that provided recidivism reduction programming; and</text> </clause><clause id="id3e72157630a34e3aa2cc15a4e218558e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of recidivism reduction programming hours provided; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50ec07215af4488d8c97575327b58a48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>explains any disparities between facilities in the numbers reported under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7f4a1f2d3424ddc870456d6cf06b14f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8f314641dda34c02b9ca8f627d627cac"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Repeals</header>
 <paragraph id="id3c02afbd83844ac9b8b76468e0ef7eb6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 2978 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797w-2">42 U.S.C. 3797w–2</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id57714a3e278a4638891abcc0210e6abc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Part CC of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797q">42 U.S.C. 3797q et seq.</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2c376ba0abe5448f9f8eb4369b984ae6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal interagency reentry coordination</header>
 <subsection id="ida3db8224566b4365908222b902d3fe48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reentry coordination</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the heads of such other agencies of the Federal Government as the Attorney General considers appropriate, and in collaboration with interested persons, service providers, nonprofit organizations, and State, tribal, and local governments, shall coordinate on Federal programs, policies, and activities relating to the reentry of individuals returning from incarceration to the community, with an emphasis on evidence-based practices and protection against duplication of services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id587bd95969c34c87ac98ebad0ef064c4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation and coordination with the participating agencies, shall provide a report to Congress summarizing achievements and including recommendations for Congress that would further reduce barriers to successful reentry.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


