<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S143 IS: United States Merchant Marine Academy Improvements Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 143</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150109">January 9, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To allow for improvements to the United States Merchant Marine Academy and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id3E6FD90674C94EC1ACFD02010D0733B7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Merchant Marine Academy Improvements Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idF7EAC36DE1134E33BB9BC02E7832F6F2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Melville Hall of United States Merchant Marine Academy</header><subsection id="id5336E45181C2401E84BB6BC89E0BF3C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gift to the Merchant Marine Academy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Maritime Administrator may accept a gift of money from the Foundation under section 51315 of title 46, United States Code, for the purpose of renovating Melville Hall on the campus of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7CF8DBC2FCD74900B456DE86389FBA4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered gifts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A gift described in this subsection is a gift under subsection (a) that the Maritime Administrator determines exceeds the sum of—</text><paragraph id="id86C349119FEA4FC5BCD42154DA591333"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the minimum amount that is sufficient to ensure the renovation of Melville Hall in accordance with the capital improvement plan of the United States Merchant Marine Academy that was in effect on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0671D63A243A4B7CA5380DBD633F812D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">25 percent of the amount described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD2B62914FF294803A8823870EA744401"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Operation contracts</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), in the case that the Maritime Administrator accepts a gift of money described in subsection (b), the Maritime Administrator may enter into a contract with the Foundation for the operation of Melville Hall to make available facilities for, among other possible uses, official academy functions, third-party catering functions, and industry events and conferences.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2C648ED3C3C347D881AEC7CBE1EA8818"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contract terms</header><text>The contract described in subsection (c) shall be for such period and on such terms as the Maritime Administrator considers appropriate, including a provision, mutually agreeable to the Maritime Administrator and the Foundation, that—</text><paragraph id="id8A1DD40EA8E248FDA829893C30DCE7D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>requires the Foundation—</text><subparagraph id="id64D77C559C7C4F958DEDBBB2D66B9CEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at the expense solely of the Foundation through the term of the contract to maintain Melville Hall in a condition that is as good as or better than the condition Melville Hall was in on the later of—</text><clause id="id170408DB598E456497B5FFB19A024E73"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date that the renovation of Melville Hall was completed; or</text></clause><clause id="id86F38ADF482C49C2A7B8E4314206FFD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date that the Foundation accepted Melville Hall after it was tendered to the Foundation by the Maritime Administrator; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B0EE721A5AA4B21A7513FA7FA1AF3EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to deposit all proceeds from the operation of Melville Hall, after expenses necessary for the operation and maintenance of Melville Hall, into the account of the Regimental Affairs Non-Appropriated Fund Instrumentality or successor entity, to be used solely for the morale and welfare of the cadets of the United States Merchant Marine Academy; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id20D3541F41014D7AAC3975D6F7879A79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibits the use of Melville Hall as lodging or an office by any person for more than 4 days in any calendar year other than—</text><subparagraph id="idB8E1EE21CE094EF181F0D8BC3678C900"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE44A29C075DB4F609DCE7F5169D296FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the administration and operation of Melville Hall.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4990F6F854274AD09A81B1FDE8A7F1B2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id8842FFC1740542D59E1C361F975E681C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contract</header><text>The term <term>contract</term> includes any modification, extension, or renewal of the contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD6725BFFCF8340D78C8BC1691D6A690A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Foundation</term> means the United States Merchant Marine Academy Alumni Association and Foundation, Inc.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF5B8F3AA2B414559BE147167F4BFF655"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed under section 3105 of title 41, United States Code, as requiring the Maritime Administrator to award a contract for the operation of Melville Hall to the Foundation.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


