<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1252 IS: Global Food Security Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1252</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150507">May 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize a comprehensive strategic approach for United States foreign assistance to developing
			 countries to reduce global poverty and hunger, achieve food and nutrition
			 security, promote inclusive, sustainable, agricultural-led economic
			 growth,
			 improve nutritional outcomes, especially for women and children, build
			 resilience among vulnerable populations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Food Security Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="ida3380cf011e547e7b5c47d8bdcd39f28"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="id422fd58f331e44aeb4943d8047bb7b86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (referred to in this section as the <quote>FAO</quote>), 805,000,000 people worldwide suffer from chronic hunger. Hunger and malnutrition rob people of health and productive lives and stunt the mental and physical development of future generations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc26aa09db5734942a32fe12852ec3aec"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the January 2014 <quote>Worldwide Threat Assessment of the US Intelligence Community</quote>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id86E61A997BD2456A80F74341E4F5A569"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <quote>[l]ack of adequate food will be a destabilizing factor in countries important to US national security that do not have the financial or technical abilities to solve their internal food security problems</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE793766C0D5947028B532523B31A42CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>[f]ood and nutrition insecurity in weakly governed countries might also provide opportunities for insurgent groups to capitalize on poor conditions, exploit international food aid, and discredit governments for their inability to address basic needs</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a48e4e9c3a74cc4b2f018f9bbfc4a30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Decades of research have shown that there are multiple underlying causes of food insecurity and poor nutrition, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDC725CC13F57488BA0193122CBC07C3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the lack of availability of, access to, and consumption of nutritious food;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6098DA0FA85F4D5BB21A88C0F8A4C365"><enum>(B)</enum><text>limited investments to improve agricultural productivity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7116D0BD23AF458CB80761033ABE8FC8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>social and gender inequality;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52559B437F074ED48DE4BC342BD13E26"><enum>(D)</enum><text>insufficient value chains and market development for farmers, including small-scale producers, which lead to post-harvest loss; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id122FA6DDB7BC410A905F8B24E5B790E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>weak institutions in government and civil society.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0980fe2de0ff46e79e598d0a7e7cc83e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Agriculture, which comprises large portions of the total labor force in many developing countries, is an essential component of inclusive economic growth. According to the World Bank’s 2008 World Development Report, growth in the agricultural sector has been twice as effective in reducing poverty as growth in other sectors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idad849deea4724350aa6c4885f66bbd97"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Women, who are often heads of households and small farmers, are especially vulnerable to food insecurity. Women frequently face stricter constraints than men in accessing markets and resources. In its 2010–2011 report, the FAO estimated that if women farmers had the same access to inputs as men, they could increase their farm yields by 20 to 30 percent. According to the FAO, this <quote>could raise total agricultural output in developing countries by 2.5–4 percent</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id40f974bd0ae94d1da5191b9d9823150d"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to UNICEF—</text> <subparagraph id="id07B14AE4CE59477BB06D8608676BB8E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>more than 161,000,000 children younger than 5 years of age suffer from chronic malnutrition (also referred to as stunting); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB1602EA28C804AC8A6FD465DBD792036"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 in 3 women in the developing world are anemic, which leads to severe health and developmental consequences.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF92F4DF4CB514F97BA519527A436E5CE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>According to the United Nations World Food Programme, poor nutrition causes 45 percent of deaths in children younger than 5 years of age.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfa7a8e7ce3b7476cb01dd019bebffe46"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Malnutrition can—</text> <subparagraph id="id971B5E146946419C9BF5DB42126FECE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>undermine future earning potential by up to 20 percent; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3A6770BE74354C1E8D1DE9133A18D9CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inhibit economic growth by up to 3 percent of gross domestic product.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBAFB879A3CA9449995610C75CC4F1061"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to The Cost of Hunger in Africa Study by the African Union Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="idF7B660769422434088688DCDE129089F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the economic costs associated with child undernutrition are substantial, ranging from 2 percent to 16 percent of the gross national product in several African nations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51E51F412663418F8ABEFD8E1A4961F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adults who suffer from stunting as children are less productive than nonstunted workers and are less able to contribute to the economy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEE417CA619684B78A72D3B3CDF65675C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>According to Save the Children’s 2013 Food for Thought report, if the current malnutrition rates continue, global output could be reduced by an estimated $125,000,000,000 by 2030, as the young children of today reach working age.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida4621d8d70e64f9eb735316f6504924f"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A comprehensive approach to sustainable food and nutrition security should not only respond to emergency food shortages, but should also address malnutrition, resilience to food and nutrition insecurity, building the capacity of poor, rural populations to improve their agricultural productivity, and incomes, removing institutional impediments to agricultural development, value chain access and efficiency, including processing and storage, enhancing agribusiness development, access to markets and activities that address the specific needs and barriers facing women and small-scale producers, education, and collaborative research.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id64829b3f20cb483aa03622de4941ad75"><enum>(12)</enum><text>An effective, sustainable approach to combating food insecurity requires consultation with, and participation from, multiple stakeholders, including government, the private sector, international organizations, international and local nongovernmental stakeholders, grassroots and civil society organizations, faith-based organizations, and higher education research institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5C175B5C85D840BA91F55D3D3198EC11"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Nongovernmental organizations, faith-based organizations, community-based organizations, private voluntary organizations, academic institutions, and cooperatives can increase the effectiveness of public investments by building local capacity, strengthening food and nutrition security and resilience, and leveraging additional resources.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide466f32faf234f6bab61457f7faba1a8"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The United States has provided consistent global leadership in addressing food security and investing in agricultural development and humanitarian assistance. In 2010, the United States Government launched Feed the Future (referred to in this paragraph as <quote>FTF</quote>), an initiative designed to expand and better coordinate the United States investments in improving global food security. FTF is a whole-of-government approach that works across agricultural value chains and focuses on the dual objectives of improving farmer productivity, income, and livelihoods in developing countries and improving the nutrition of women and children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfdacd04a1d4a4d33ad6801de6e86cee4"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The United States Government spearheaded the creation of the Global Agriculture and Food Security Program (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>GAFSP</quote>), which mobilizes contributions from a wide range of international donors to support the goals of FTF. As of 2014, the GAFSP had received pledges totaling $1,300,000,000 from 10 donors and reached an estimated 12,000,000 direct beneficiaries in 25 countries.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="ide9e55a339b4c41af99bf17f3624c6afe"><enum>3.</enum><header>Policy objectives; sense of Congress</header>
 <subsection id="idFC0685956543451F87B7BC7AD892E74D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is in the national security interest of the United States to promote global food and nutrition security, consistent with national agriculture investment plans, which is reinforced through programs, activities, and initiatives that—</text>
 <paragraph id="idCC2E50E7DB0A46ABBC151C1DD96307F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eradicate hunger and malnutrition, especially for women and children;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id87FE29CCC1CA4E9298E5A7452480A101"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist foreign countries to achieve long-term, sustainable, and inclusive agricultural development by emphasizing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id471524C9F0C74A4FAAAA2A9EDE550F86"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increased productivity, resiliency, local management capacity, income, and growth;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57A0D1784DFF484782A885611BF0F6B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduction in poverty and long-term vulnerability to food and nutrition insecurity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB953952FDAAB4ADE996FBF8F7383B252"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improved skills building and market linkages for producers, especially for women and small-scale producers, who face specific constraints in accessing markets, networks, and resources; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5FA70405EB9B4F468BE8F642D64954F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the effective use of United States taxpayer dollars to further these objectives.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbaf25e23e4974524803642ad2c003764"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the President, or a designee of the President, in providing assistance under this Act, should—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide0f5384185714a2b996f8a7e6dec3933"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate, through a whole-of-government approach, the efforts of relevant Federal departments and agencies to develop and implement the strategy set forth in section 5(a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3BD9656CEA8E48D186C45B308D7BF6DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>utilize, to the maximum extent possible, open and streamlined solicitations, grants, and cooperative agreements to allow for the participation of a wide range of implementing partners; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61babc82ae9d4881ab09c2e5cd373c95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strengthen and expand partnerships between developing country institutions of agricultural sciences with universities in the United States, with a focus on building the agricultural capacities of universities in developing nations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id553c9289a8d74a4d9dba1c929576a2b3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="ida3c3fb88fc66423fa2a7310e3de9b014"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id03b672877aed44f7bae25e5935990be9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde0c19fc648346f0ad19fd94b13991cf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id995C287A6755424CBDA9C5072A7178DA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04f4c63c5a4b4140a4df7afe2d3e0e30"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9BEED105E13C400A86D135FA470B404B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf2b54c63f634ff88c9e22e942eebc79"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id99872f0e62404138b7bcb620324426fd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Feed the future innovation labs</header><text>The term <term>Feed the Future Innovation Labs</term> means research partnerships led by United States universities that advance solutions to reduce global hunger, poverty, and malnutrition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id79CBEDD1A6FC43E1808DB1D0295F16B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Feed the future strategy</header><text>The term <term>Feed the Future Strategy</term> means the strategy developed and implemented pursuant to section 5(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id241a2cca0d5841778c60b7494f4fe1bc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Food and nutrition security</header><text>The term <term>food and nutrition security</term> means access to, and availability, utilization, and stability of, sufficient food to meet caloric and nutritional needs for an active and healthy life.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd8592dc31497463ba7ead8553562688d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Malnutrition</header><text>The term <term>malnutrition</term> means poor nutritional status caused by nutritional deficiency or excess.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idaad15cedc97a446097da1ed8ad6440e1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text>The term <term>resilience</term> means the ability of people, households, communities, countries, and systems to mitigate, adapt to, and recover from shocks and stresses in a manner that reduces chronic vulnerability and facilitates inclusive growth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3961d55e01c34de596104d5389ac905e"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Small-scale producer</header><text>The term <term>small-scale producer</term> means farmers, pastoralists, and fishers that have a low asset base and limited resources, including land, capital, skills and labor, and, in the case of farmers, typically farm on fewer than 5 hectares of land.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbe06c4db39fc4caa82d24aea7d468541"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Stunting</header><text>The term <term>stunting</term> refers to a condition that—</text> <subparagraph id="idDBBDEE1B9E1A4D82B1B410007BE6CBDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is measured by a height-to-age ratio that is more than 2 standard deviations below the median for the population;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09B94F9592964002A2B30FB6BA50CC58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>manifests in children who are younger than 2 years of age;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id052B625957FF41EA9039322C251EF785"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a process that can continue in children after they reach 2 years of age, resulting in an individual being <quote>stunted</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2222041A90AB4B458F6091AB1377F52F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is a sign of chronic malnutrition; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4553E11B63BE4D5581E5F7A520F1EFB5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>can lead to long-term poor health, delayed motor development, impaired cognitive function, and decreased immunity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5178C604A99140C8B70CBF1A6C4B0B7D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Sustainable</header><text>The term <term>sustainable</term> means the ability of a target country, community, implementing partner, or intended beneficiary to maintain the programs authorized and the outcomes achieved pursuant to this Act over time.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id756AEE70F9BB499A9FDAE2375C2E74C6"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Target country</header><text>The term <term>target country</term> means a developing country that is selected to participate in agriculture and nutrition security programs under the Feed the Future Strategy.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="ided4a597e0a34429c81adba11776b24af"><enum>5.</enum><header>Comprehensive food security strategy</header>
			<subsection id="id36dd92d6c7fe46fca9717ea9f9cb17a6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Feed the future strategy</header>
 <paragraph id="id4A55970CEDE046B299ACC60B2B693ED0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, or a designee of the President, shall coordinate the development and implementation of a United States whole-of-government strategy to accomplish the policy objectives set forth in section 3(a), which shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3895211c2cd14c74a66ceb9ad57d258e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support and be aligned with country-owned agriculture, nutrition, and food security policy and investment plans developed with input from relevant governmental and nongovernmental sectors within target countries and regional bodies, including—</text>
 <clause id="id55C11C2085A44F1F8EBA42730E290EA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>representatives of the private sector;</text> </clause><clause id="id12AA25B3927142DABCD27107DE35A1DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>agricultural producers, including women and small-scale producers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF2034AF870544A6A8C2AA91EA04D2B27"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>international and local civil society organizations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id00954E4CE8254EB0AC6DFA20221FFB73"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>faith-based organizations; and</text> </clause><clause id="id0943FCE352CB48C089A4D3B7AF88B109"><enum>(v)</enum><text>research and academic institutions;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idddbe88c7bbe14c87b396ed26a8db0ab9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support inclusive, sustainable agricultural value chain development, with small-scale producers, especially women, gaining greater access to the inputs, skills, networking, resource management capacity, bargaining power, financing, and market linkages needed to sustain their long-term economic prosperity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2505B90D233847CEA14961859C6E7A89"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the improvement of the nutritional status of women and children, especially during the critical 1,000-day window starting at the beginning of a woman’s pregnancy and ending 2 years after her child’s birth, with a focus on reducing child stunting;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28BE0D06829748A5B27B84CF4B1B743F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>urge target countries and communities to respect and promote the land tenure rights of local communities, particularly those of women and small-scale producers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2ebbad3994f49eaa9744af63a93a32c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support the long-term success of programs by building the capacity of local organizations and institutions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e68da4a391f4ac6976c43764f22f954"><enum>(F)</enum><text>integrate resilience and nutrition strategies into food security programs, such that chronically vulnerable populations are better able to build safety nets, secure livelihoods, access markets, manage resources, and access opportunities for longer-term economic growth;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80396167d0a64aa8b5b2ba5b7fa224a0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>develop community and producer resilience to natural disasters, emergencies, and natural occurrences that adversely impact productivity and livelihoods;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8d8a12fd4604ee8866957a0964a7fd9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>harness science, technology, and innovation, including the research conducted at Feed the Future Innovation Labs, or any successor entities, throughout the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6039a2da57f24fce83e0979d37d119a8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>leverage resources and expertise through partnerships with the private sector, farm organizations, cooperatives, civil society, research entities, and academic institutions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b50b53a734244698befa1d3e2c2a64b"><enum>(J)</enum><text>support collaboration between United States universities and public and private institutions in developing countries to promote agricultural development and innovation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd35a4e5cbacc4d4b9e7ab29c10c5f8dc"><enum>(K)</enum><text>set clear and transparent selection criteria for target countries, regions, and intended beneficiaries of assistance provided under this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c7ff7b37cdc4b96bbf7beca19ba8e0b"><enum>(L)</enum><text>set specific and measurable goals, benchmarks, timetables, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans that reflect international best practices relating to transparency, accountability, food and nutrition security, and agriculture-led economic growth, consistent with the policy objectives described in the Feed the Future Strategy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0D39A9FA08B848D6AE03ABD8774ABA5F"><enum>(M)</enum><text>include criteria and methodology for graduating countries from United States assistance provided under this Act once the countries have achieved certain benchmarks.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBFFBA2F1384C423AAB8F3F6A8315B1DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Governing law</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in carrying out the purposes of this Act, assistance may be provided to the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development pursuant to sections 103 and 103A, title XII of chapter 2 of part I, and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151a">22 U.S.C. 2151a</external-xref>, 2151a–1, 2220a et seq., and 2346 et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id98ba416f3ac0431f82f273110510e56f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Feed the future coordination</header><text>The President, or a designee of the President, shall coordinate, through a whole-of-government approach, the efforts of relevant Federal departments and agencies in implementing the Feed the Future Strategy by—</text>
 <paragraph id="idd3d0e525c46342488000614abb343fcb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing policy coherence, monitoring and evaluation systems, and coordination across all relevant Federal departments and agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id91DDAC26ED924841A607E40215E1A2AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>aligning linkages with other initiatives and strategies of the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of State, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, the Peace Corps, the United States Trade Representative, the United States Africa Development Foundation, the Department of Commerce, the Department of the Treasury, and the United States Geological Survey;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd588f221096c4af186226a66f901f8aa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing platforms for regular consultation and collaboration with key stakeholders, including—</text> <subparagraph id="idF2D229980B3745629412ED8CC341FF14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>national and local governments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80D7778C71C04D9394CCCCF243EB0178"><enum>(B)</enum><text>multilateral institutions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAEE9332E78FC4AF3956711261F2C16F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>private voluntary organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8FFBB51825F742229860A930B65F8D70"><enum>(D)</enum><text>cooperatives;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9494567C866C4511BDCB12E244994F6F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the private sector;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1AE7FD3A402405989A41D4C1E063A78"><enum>(F)</enum><text>local nongovernmental and civil society organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7CBEE45C0E1D45278EFC60473B374AD7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>faith-based organizations;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFFAC0EAD5A4B4B7B9CA65A0C99D03576"><enum>(H)</enum><text>research and academic institutions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF5E484FBC0A847048D273524D609299D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>congressional committees; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id670DD2DAAC484BFDA2D61341C955AAB6"><enum>(J)</enum><text>other stakeholders, as appropriate;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id28b7bf8dfe1042fa9761499e85f377f6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>leveraging the expertise of the Department of Agriculture in agricultural development, nutrition, trade, research, and education; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFE4C0B25A0E54B11B51E2D8744F9000E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establishing and leading regular public consultations in target countries.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id86bc89cc35624a9cb3997300f6a23ec7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting</header> <subsection id="id8ac69ddd7fff4be3866d34606d7abceb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than December 31 of each year thereafter through 2020, the President, or a designee of the President, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes the status of the implementation of the Feed the Future Strategy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idae4ace641e964dcc9acdd5cc157cf306"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="id49064893d95e49c095cf612ff1f4a49e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contain an appendix of the Feed the Future Strategy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id84C935BFA7DA450CA924F0AE8E58222A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify any substantial changes made in the Feed the Future Strategy during the preceding calendar year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id83e8f2ef5ab741188aea67ef4987067a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify the indicators that will be used to measure results, set benchmarks for progress over time, and establish mechanisms for reporting results in an open and transparent manner;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id93A93284D39D4A2D8730716E3491C292"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describe the progress made in implementing the Feed the Future Strategy;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id83800877015f403bb8da0345888ecec8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess the progress and results of implementing international food and nutrition security programming on the policy objectives set forth in section 3(a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEB7552CBE69746F7992D8ED617CB269B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>indicate how findings from monitoring and evaluation were incorporated into program design and budget decisions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5fb1ca7425fc4658860e272bd97cb3a1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>contain a transparent, open, and detailed accounting of spending under this Act by all relevant Federal agencies, including a disaggregated accounting of assistance provided through different procurement mechanisms;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id805AF792DF5347C38EB76F35C9021587"><enum>(8)</enum><text>identify any United States legal or regulatory impediments that could obstruct the effective implementation of the programming referred to in paragraph (5);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd076630fa7024ee88eff8a1b708de522"><enum>(9)</enum><text>describe how the Feed the Future Strategy relates to other United States food security and development assistance programs on the continuum from emergency food aid through sustainable, agriculture-led economic growth;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0F7AB6F9C33A404DA81869FCFC56197F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>contain a clear gender analysis of programming that includes established disaggregated gender indicators to better analyze outcomes for food productivity, income growth, control of assets, equity in access to inputs, jobs and markets, and nutrition;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0554943617b3493da9fc734239448689"><enum>(11)</enum><text>describe the methodology and criteria for the selection of target countries;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idFE49E680A58A4F879907F10B8FAA6D67"><enum>(12)</enum><text>describe related strategies and benchmarks for graduating target countries and communities from assistance provided under the Feed the Future Strategy over time, including by building resilience, reducing risk, and enhancing the sustainability of outcomes from United States investments in agriculture and nutrition security;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb2c791b7c81e4adaa7e4a5bd11d15ec3"><enum>(13)</enum><text>assess efforts to coordinate United States international food security and nutrition programs, activities, and initiatives with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD44185E8E9274B27920993864F7E52C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other bilateral donors;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B296F8C10514FA2B4E552B641F0EF5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>international and multilateral organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8D357971D7BE4324B35A22E42C4850A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>international financial institutions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3BCAF365D35D4972BFD72064B3ADA85C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>target country governments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32B8F0069A1B4AE8BF9225C4804902D7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>international and local private voluntary, nongovernmental, and civil society organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3BDBB0E37890457283ABE29D1ADB733A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>research and academic institutions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAC7FDA13CAEE42808B93BB45B8F7B4B2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>other stakeholders;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id47014c0a044344d6b70e6367bcf93c4e"><enum>(14)</enum><text>assess the status of institutional capacity building efforts, including higher education;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7B17A54BF19F4D8FAC9DE82964967173"><enum>(15)</enum><text>assess United States Government-facilitated private investment in related sectors in target countries and communities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4C8D02CA5A604F90BE01C9FD1E3A36EA"><enum>(16)</enum><text>assess the impact of private sector investment on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id329dc94db0ba4997b2b5897e18113d70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the economic opportunities available to small-scale producers, especially women;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68e035cdfbb0466c860f50c7a4cceebf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving international food and nutrition security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBAF864263E074373BF5EE86A091EB1F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>local land tenure issues; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAF87C4260F944F0DA9B37D56AF2583F3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enhancing inclusive, sustainable agricultural development;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idce3c65ee18b8419ba197769b78a39a4a"><enum>(17)</enum><text>be prepared in consultation with relevant United States Government agencies; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id04ac313cd1e5466bac22b21ad3daf307"><enum>(18)</enum><text>incorporate a plan for regularly reviewing and updating strategies, partnerships, and programs and sharing lessons learned with a wide range of stakeholders in an open and transparent manner.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id67350d807c5046f48568eb223d59cfd4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability of information</header><text>The information referred to in subsection (b) shall be made publicly accessible in an electronic format and in a timely manner.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8196D3354A7F46EC8E9F6C6E9AF5FF6E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report</header><text>During the 1-year period ending on December 31, 2019, the Comptroller General of the United States shall publish a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id94101E303E8A4F4DB59E9E9E561F2316"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes the progress of the strategy described in section 5(a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5C2F9BA05BA84DEBAF16D17B6633DE38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses the whole-of-government coordination described in section 5(b);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id410698e8233247ffab17cbfcdd223dcf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assesses the mechanisms through which United States assistance authorized under this Act is provided, including a list of the major recipients of United States contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3E9FD42995774DDAB5A525A54E18AD16"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes a review of evaluations conducted on assistance provided under this Act; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF4493DF6C3FD4BBA8E5A93EB00975D1F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assesses the budget decisionmaking process, including the role of monitoring and evaluation in program design.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="ide788ad36ab3a49a9bec29f594309c8bf"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to carry out this Act, for each of the fiscal years 2015 through 2020, an amount equal to the amount of funds made available for food security and agricultural development programs for fiscal year 2014 under section 7060(d) of the <short-title>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2014</short-title> (division K of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 554).</text></section></legis-body></bill>


