<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1172 RS: To improve the process of presidential transition.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 166</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1172</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 114–94]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>July 27, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor>, with amendments</action-desc><action-instruction>Insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve the process of presidential transition.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the “<added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">Edward ‘Ted’ Kaufman and Michael Leavitt</added-phrase> Presidential Transitions Improvements Act of 2015”.</text> </section><section id="id31A3CE2C65B54E8BACC1DB167AB70F30"><enum>2.</enum><header>Presidential transition improvements</header> <subsection id="id266342343272447A9470AEC9811267F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Presidential Transition Act of 1963 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/3/102">3 U.S.C. 102</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idDBFC9888B9E942B89D101EC6A32E2EF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 4, 5, and 6 as sections 5, 6, and 7, respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id82D536CC6373441A9C51E5B2067655D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 3 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4FB1617F7FE14722A1AE0DB7DA0C4938" style="OLC">
						<section id="id99915AEAA3F244C3A67FC37F6E14CA3C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transition services and activities before election</header>
 <subsection id="id8886705e8f644821b4b7246fac232dea"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id91663C6759ED4D848E85F6CE3C9D3FD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of General Services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFC446BE174F9464D90F8708A1EAC01D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> means an Executive agency, as defined in section 105 of title 5, United States Code;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1D2A0454CF794A2980388A96B598A7A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible candidate</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3(h)(4); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA99114506C0A4979839419ED4C622A08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Presidential election</term> means a general election held to determine the electors of President and Vice President under section 1 or 2 of title 3, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id23CCD1F8C9D54143801D1C272882EEF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General duties</header><text>The President shall take such actions as the President determines necessary and appropriate to plan and coordinate activities by the Executive branch of the Federal Government to facilitate an efficient transfer of power to a successor President, including by—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6F3D7E46A19E44AA814E97060DDBDE18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing and operating a White House transition coordinating council in accordance with subsection (d); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7080004F30084286BE33E00C867849F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing and operating an agency transition directors council in accordance with subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id23576649FFC4469DA63B693043F61106"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal Transition Coordinator</header><text>The Administrator shall designate an employee of the General Services Administration who is a senior career appointee to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id31D9ED03A3934F06902B658FF820A1DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out the duties and authorities of the General Services Administration relating to Presidential transitions under this Act or any other provision of law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE4D826E4A0D34B31B6B7CA673BF669FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve as the Federal Transition Coordinator with responsibility for coordinating transition planning across agencies, including through the agency transition directors council established under subsection (e);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id45a108b9eeb2456c84255bab4e8efe41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure agencies comply with all statutory requirements relating to transition planning and reporting; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE44EFE55E1FD45618D31D751FE8CB91C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>act as a liaison to eligible candidates.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBA375B190E4145058B1C2B2B769E8E5A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>White house transition coordinating council</header> <paragraph id="id76073519a9724658a91a2d7f1f7849d5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 6 months before the date of a Presidential election, the President shall establish a White House transition coordinating council for purposes of facilitating the Presidential transition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0DD054C3E2A94B2FAAD70517ABE1B80F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The White House transition coordinating council shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id7959815B871E4055B6A190AC185EA69D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide guidance to agencies and the Federal Transition Coordinator regarding preparations for the Presidential transition, including succession planning and preparation of briefing materials;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id692e7d56c78f4daaa354b5d3d655dd5a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate communication and information sharing between the transition representatives of eligible candidates and senior employees in agencies and the Executive Office of the President; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e6838b0a4af4a9aa9f39e804b9d459b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prepare and host interagency emergency preparedness and response exercises.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEAC27CB4B48646A095CB8967189AB76A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The members of the White House transition coordinating council shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id33852ED310324651B49387C735ED4E1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>senior employees of the Executive branch selected by the President, which may include the Chief of Staff to the President, any Cabinet officer, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Administrator, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, and the Archivist of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC6FB44A33219434B8A6DF887E4C7E06C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Transition Coordinator;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53B0DF8A52DB480181554DB5A7087438"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the transition representative for each eligible candidate, who shall serve in an advisory capacity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e445fd4280e4d8983144a5e418271f9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other individual the President determines appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id161EF453DF9D4152B6E3892C5617E1DF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Chairperson of the White House transition coordinating council shall be a senior employee in the Executive Office of the President, designated by the President.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id72C1E55F5AE549668CFDE9AA15E68EC4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Agency transition directors council</header>
 <paragraph id="id9AF3023F6C60402286AE3A9A65111340"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall establish and operate an agency transition directors council, which shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id6a3df60c3f7049c1908b3fae7bb9e4ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure the Federal Government has an integrated strategy for addressing interagency challenges and responsibilities around Presidential transitions and turnover of noncareer appointees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4E64F25B82F24B8CA1183A2429EBA791"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate transition activities between the Executive Office of the President, agencies, and the transition team of eligible candidates and the President-elect and Vice-President-elect; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC9FC7C10E7264B0883AF2636DFDCED89"><enum>(C)</enum><text>draw on guidance provided by the White House transition coordinating council and lessons learned from previous Presidential transitions in carrying out its duties.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id09629C4C93074F89AE8F3EDC31F6C176"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>As part of carrying out the responsibilities under paragraph (1), the agency transition directors council shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id38D6BF4720864F09A885A6A1639063BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assist the Federal Transition Coordinator in identifying and carrying out the responsibilities of the Federal Transition Coordinator relating to a Presidential transition;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0b5c64e1284f47409c05a62bb7d648dc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide guidance to agencies in gathering briefing materials and information relating to the Presidential transition that may be requested by eligible candidates;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96BCF381F0C145E7AA2B53585C7FADA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure materials and information described in subparagraph (B) are prepared not later than November 1 of a year during which a Presidential election is held;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b18ba708c2643f59ddbcdf6ae300b3e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure agencies adequately prepare career employees who are designated to fill non-career positions under subsection (f) during a Presidential transition; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7BA002CBB718426A9EF159BD580A3313"><enum>(E)</enum><text>consult with the President's Management Council, or any successor thereto, in carrying out the duties of the agency transition directors council.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3DFBA0104BC948B881CBFE825B04C8B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The members of the agency transition directors council shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="id00C362EF2A4A4B8396C32F41F2CCB1A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Transition Coordinator, who shall serve as Chairperson of the agency transition directors council;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3054EFF47ABF46288A80D336D1453F6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a senior employee serving in the Executive Office of the President, who shall be appointed by the President;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2355FC4B425C4371847573D595E1EEBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a senior representative from each agency described in section 901(b)(1) of title 31, United States Code, the Office of Personnel Management, the Office of Government Ethics, and the National Archives and Records Administration whose responsibilities include leading Presidential transition efforts within the agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65BE8DCAA854426F81E2163D62565222"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a senior representative from any other agency determined by the Federal Transition Coordinator to be an agency that has significant responsibilities relating to the Presidential transition process; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3D804810AB614F7EAD03BC88BFC61A3E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>during a year during which a Presidential election will be held, a transition representative for each eligible candidate, who shall serve in an advisory capacity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE8C1B729E78D4DB79B0CD89B5E38C783"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The agency transition directors council shall meet—</text> <subparagraph id="id2DDE42280A9D4555B7A607DC88D2390F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), not less than once per year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43246B11ADCE4D369577EAF32B50A03B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the period beginning on the date that is 6 months before a Presidential election and ending on the date on which the President-elect is inaugurated, on a regular basis as necessary to carry out the duties and authorities of the agency transition directors council.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC1143B4B83B84574A610624A0E25D8CF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Interim agency leadership for transitions</header>
 <paragraph id="id54C9CE6D455E45A3B43E9B1D29A5CBEF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Oversight and implementation of transition</header><text>Not later than 6 months before the date of a Presidential election, the head of each agency shall designate a senior career employee of the agency and a senior career employee of each major component and subcomponent of the agency to oversee and implement the activities of the agency, component, or subcomponent relating to the Presidential transition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE17F2C9A60B34EA986D53AD4CFF8423A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acting officers</header><text>Not later than September 15 of a year during which a Presidential election occurs, and in accordance with subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, for each noncareer position in an agency that the head of the agency determines is critical, the head of the agency shall designate a qualified career employee to serve in the position in an acting capacity if the position becomes vacant.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id29058542e2d9450fb852efd805ec33cf"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Memorandums of understanding</header>
 <paragraph id="id4D145F9CF37A4258AAD8BD609A251D25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than November 1 of a year during which a Presidential election occurs, the President (acting through the Federal Transition Coordinator) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, negotiate a memorandum of understanding with the transition representative of each eligible candidate, which shall include, at a minimum, the conditions of access to employees, facilities, and documents of agencies by transition staff.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9BE88E4B12CB4C14959B234BAC4F0F42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing resources</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the memorandums of understanding negotiated under paragraph (1) shall be based on memorandums of understanding from previous Presidential transitions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD8E4CD976FBA47DC8A7FC248A38F8E51"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Equity in assistance</header><text>Any information or other assistance provided to eligible candidates under this section shall be offered on an equal basis and without regard to political affiliation.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="idc7d326a9eceb4b40895d0e950198e936"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="idb4f7559ca1d448b8bc05a7c05b08389c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, acting through the Federal Transition Coordinator, shall submit to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate reports describing the activities undertaken by the President and agencies to prepare for the transfer of power to a new President.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id204985e2e9a446a3a8f6f258f0e484c3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The reports under paragraph (1) shall be provided 6 months and 3 months before the date of a Presidential election.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA78D3B6C75CD42068C3F89F275C1AC1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other improvements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Presidential Transition Act of 1963 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/3/102">3 U.S.C. 102</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE0282FC0CB6E40769DB922AB7A286661"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8965E0961B114C779322C5379ED394BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id483765573944483F8E2596CD8F438A34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i)—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86D30070AEC743009901475D4BBFCCCF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and during the term of a President</quote> after <quote>during the transition</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8C5C63980274200B5D67967A2C5655D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>after inauguration</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99150ACFDE5D477286C3EF967A889DF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>or Executive agencies (as defined in section 105 of title 5, United States Code)</quote> before the period; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB4588326E80F44DD905EFA36790768DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by inserting <quote>including, to the greatest extent practicable, human resource management system software compatible with the software used by the incumbent President and likely to be used by the President-elect and Vice President-elect</quote> before the period;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5448CDE968D147259CFD52CCD2695D82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>30 days</quote> and inserting <quote>180 days</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25DE33E514344755A97792E2AE287155"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by inserting <quote>except for activities under subsection (a)(8)(A),</quote> before <quote>there shall be no</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44C4036E4C9D45C194DD8CA7F94B16D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB9FC3952E28F4D868D21496F0951908E" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE977FC84E4314609AFF22140F4B8093F" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An eligible candidate shall have a right to the services and facilities described in this paragraph until the date on which the Administrator is able to determine the apparent successful candidates for the office of President and Vice President.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA8F3B90D65694813810469BDAD233F53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id484DACD8F4C147EBBD4771291E53801C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 3 of the Pre-Election Presidential Transition Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/3/102">3 U.S.C. 102</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEB049EEB30334A14B1AEB413487BE830"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Presidential Transition Act of 1963 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/3/102">3 U.S.C. 102</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id941053A09C004EA4A5D389248AE12852"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 3—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB707194B9D1F47BD9FA3A2C274FA73AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(4)(B), by striking <quote>section 6</quote> and inserting <quote>section 7</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8EF2659813F0415C90AA7F66D29CC79D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>section 3 of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>this section</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8F72859AA5504028B55353617DA20BA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(3)(B)(iii), by striking <quote>section 5</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>section 6</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7C3E574DD0E24B4A9EBEDD713BF15A14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 6, as redesignated by subsection (a) of this section, by striking <quote>section 6(a)(1)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>section 7(a)(1)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61B485736CE6466B8C4886787B65F673"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section (7)(a)(2), as redesignated by subsection (a) of this section, by striking <quote>section 4</quote> and inserting <quote>section 5</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id822B93DFF9844AE0BD9E701F683077DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 8331(1)(K) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 4</quote> and inserting <quote>section 5</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCC0A5120970E4762B4150C3E676457D1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 8701(a)(10) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 4</quote> and inserting <quote>section 5</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEDA679C0DCA24007B0FDA7788BF02B09"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 8901(1)(I) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 4</quote> and inserting <quote>section 5</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idEB143B02DFB84C8FBDF2BB61ACB20D26"><enum>3.</enum><header>National archives Presidential transition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2203(g) of title 44, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1300266BCEBC42B69F06EA1B52964085"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC8642DBBBDC547E9AAABC1C9A9AAF742"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id112F25B9EBD3498C853C53E2DC62FA30" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28E6093DB11140FF9C7949D760DFDA44"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When the President considers it practicable and in the public interest, the President shall include in the President's budget transmitted to Congress, for each fiscal year in which the term of office of the President will expire, such funds as may be necessary for carrying out the authorities of this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section changed="added" id="id58423A5959124815A03A23F7E427263C" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports on political appointees appointed to nonpolitical permanent positions</header>
 <subsection id="idB4B24175A9774D26B1BD7CE393D7C31E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id821D45EA69864980B3E043959C9E9F2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Executive agency</term> in section 105 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id91AD47DEC36A4AD9B36677BC302F539F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered civil service position</term> means a position in the civil service (as defined in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code) that is not—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD7D74EB9053945D0BDC84552F14A3CFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a temporary position; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id397A36F60C16420197D2DDF60579E2AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a political position;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id68BA8CD071094B6C912BFB060DB15CFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>former political appointee</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="idC04E74977F82469BAC5697F718FC7EA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not serving in an appointment to a political position; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id174F8ACB29284888A276146E2ACE7809"><enum>(B)</enum><text>served as a political appointee during the 5-year period ending on the date of the request for an appointment to a covered civil service position in any agency;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFC56E44B29004352B334FE4F483FE019"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>political appointee</term> means an individual serving in an appointment to a political position; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idCFE30952E1FF4B27BB2AD17FE68B99DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>political position</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5d3a4013a7d64ce991f8ed0180456822"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5, United States Code (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae1c204714574e2f85d5e9b87b03e60f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a noncareer appointment in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraph (7) of section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd53750445c3341608169254f993e47b9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC686C08898BF450EB8B33E5FB5FC0537"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting on current or recent political appointees appointed to covered civil service positions</header><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a quarterly report regarding requests by agencies to appoint political appointees or former political appointees to covered civil service positions, which shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8807E3725F1A49FCACA3A563D85C892D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for each request by an agency that a political appointee be appointed to a covered civil service position during the period covered by the quarterly report, provide—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4bd0ca352a094921af97b9dccc78a5cd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the request was received by the Office of Personnel Management;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94f9ab90ed114583a75f6d806315c2d7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to subsection (c), the name of the individual and the political position held by the individual, including title, office, and agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idda26ab3fc4534dfeb7c78547bf942ada"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date on which the individual was first appointed to a political position in the agency in which the individual is serving as a political appointee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6422d03749e48af9d3e8cbff24ff231"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the grade and rate of basic pay for the individual as a political appointee;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id829d9b6539164348904f253f1d042c01"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the proposed covered civil service position, including title, office, and agency, and the proposed grade and rate of basic pay for the individual;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94206702adce462cb156955ba2e4527e"><enum>(F)</enum><text>whether the Office of Personnel Management approved or denied the request; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb48876bcc79a4c0b96bd898febcf191f"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the date on which the individual was appointed to a covered civil service position, if applicable; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB40FD3B977DC4452A4804FCC8A23FEC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each request by an agency that a former political appointee be appointed to a covered civil service position during the period covered by the quarterly report, provide—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6936b14c1b914f3db3f5867f4caaa96b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the request was received by the Office of Personnel Management;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c705017ff6845e0b733ccc6c6bb6d64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to subsection (c), the name of the individual and the political position held by the individual, including title, office, and agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89d31bbb09704c29a04f7914acdedc87"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date on which the individual was first appointed to any political position;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb63652254234bad9280c8a915f6e8cc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the grade and rate of basic pay for the individual as a political appointee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21111d54b88c43a78fd9f714931f2c20"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the date on which the individual ceased to serve in a political position;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01bfbe7bd92b453aaf0756b8da2f680d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the proposed covered civil service position, including title, office, and agency, and the proposed grade and rate of basic pay for the individual;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3bf7063eadc497fb3d960308cd13eb7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>whether the Office of Personnel Management approved or denied the request; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c971c6094434c8f89f4176e7aa28eb2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the date on which the individual was first appointed to a covered civil service position, if applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCF4AA7FDD1AC4E3EACF60705F02D1D6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Names and titles of certain appointees</header><text>If determined appropriate by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, a report submitted under subsection (b) may exclude the name or title of a political appointee or former political appointee—</text>
 <paragraph id="id42C4CAC30CBF4FEEA796E0F159800D3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who—</text> <subparagraph id="idF7F3B4B1ECA64F9DBB6D73C87FB11589"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was requested to be appointed to a covered civil service position; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13A42494B73742029233EBD37DBF39AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was not appointed to a covered civil service position; or</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF232EE4D3B744A6E807DDACA27D57BDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relating to whom a request to be appointed to a covered civil service position is pending at the end of the period covered by that report.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section changed="added" id="id3906E49CA4CD47D9B69960F08414D654" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on regulations promulgated near the end of presidential terms</header>
 <subsection id="id01E9968EB98848C58771EE5C8F704959"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id1B23BC0463474101AF454A145E2FA7A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered presidential transition period</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC5D1F0BDF9504E77A9AD1764632842B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the 120-day period ending on January 20, 1993.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE0E38BA921B74A16B46BAD50A166F483"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 120-day period ending on January 20, 2001;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id151EC442FEDB4C93AB23B611210DACAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the 120-day period ending on January 20, 2009; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0EB6DAE4FE7645D989AAC2E791BDF750"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the 120-day period ending on January 20, 2017;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id940B3ED75BDB4B1D828EF5C2914BA7C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered regulation</term> means a final regulation promulgated by an Executive department; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idAC06F56C0E6F4D68A9C1BB795E052A48"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Executive department</term> has the meaning given that term under section 101 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA946D2190C414E5DA29BFBC73A07E7C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="id18DD33784558467686AF7A8EC0C3A3E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report regarding covered regulations promulgated during the covered presidential transition periods described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3DB636661F844254A3A0AFA62B3FF391"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Next presidential transition</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report regarding covered regulations promulgated during the covered presidential transition period described in subsection (a)(1)(D).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDAA5668BA815499580AEB1470076FA84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of reports</header><text>The reports required under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall, for each covered presidential transition period covered by the report—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id12245E2FBF7E4A8298C981F65B491F8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>compare the number, scope, and cost (if possible) of, and type of rulemaking procedure used for, covered regulations promulgated during the covered presidential transition period to the number, scope, and cost of, and type of rulemaking procedure used for, covered regulations promulgated during the 120-day periods ending on January 20 of each year after 1988, other than 1993, 2001, and 2009;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ebf6dfbd4044abc8a7fc96c8a92d4e2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine the statistical significance of any differences identified under subparagraph (A) and whether and to what extent such differences indicate any patterns;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7DF9CE6B3B5346D99B69CEFD2EA58D96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluate the size, scope, and effect of the covered regulations promulgated during the covered presidential transition period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC83A47DE06FF40A0BF2FB91CB22C145B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assess the extent to which the regularly required processes for the promulgation of covered regulations were followed during the covered presidential transition period, including compliance with the requirements under—</text>
 <clause id="id85E713C3B73B415C9347A400E2D1CE90"><enum>(i)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Congressional Review Act</quote>);</text> </clause><clause id="id318EE9E1E4B541949F964793ACE8220E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note);</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD5E817FB420249EB945A36A17AEBB551"><enum>(iii)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Regulatory Flexibility Act</quote>); and</text> </clause><clause id="id5143f75ba1674aedb90d792a8df0d70c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section changed="added" id="id30A2EA2D2FE945A493B08CE67C4F47D3" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>6.</enum><header>Analysis of threats and vulnerabilities</header>
 <subsection id="id085387DA199A422780685E2957ECE32C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than February 15, 2016, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report analyzing the threats and vulnerabilities facing the United States during a presidential transition, which—</text>
 <paragraph id="id90BE48B7DD3B4F9AB99048F009BEF512"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall identify and discuss vulnerabilities related to border security and threats related to terrorism, including from weapons of mass destruction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idABE5D6E35B91444CB5CAF7BD8F64BB0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall identify steps being taken to address the threats and vulnerabilities during a presidential transition; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE3D486B69AC44F7BB9F872ADFF5A32FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include recommendations for actions by components and agencies within the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id46EAAA1ADB8B429F8E8AAB8E361CF44C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall be prepared in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>July 27, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported with amendments</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


