<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S871 IS: Helping Expand Lending Practices in Rural Communities Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 871</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for an
			 application process for interested parties to apply for an area to be
			 designated as a rural area, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H83293A8784884EE6B7F4E8DBFDD3CA15" style="OLC">
 <section id="H20C24F2925564E5AA4B105A3F2F79087" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Expand Lending Practices in Rural Communities Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HELP Rural Communities Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA307348F6C974BAF992B63CC02E9B2AA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of rural area</header> <subsection id="H37DF3DCF1A324E11BD7D8733BC59243E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall establish an application process under which a person who lives or does business in a State may, with respect to an area identified by the person in such State that has not been designated by the Bureau as a rural area for purposes of a Federal consumer financial law (as defined under section 1002 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010), apply for such area to be so designated.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC3D0238E531740FDA511DFB6218F3E51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When evaluating an application submitted under subsection (a), the Bureau shall take into consideration the following factors:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD74AC0B48EA0478C9194CE14FDC82ACA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Criteria used by the Director of the Bureau of the Census for classifying geographical areas as rural or urban.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3911918945974FE69D0C4C69E1CE4FA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Criteria used by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to designate counties as metropolitan or micropolitan or neither.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6B27FD56A0B43B6A76EA20991CBA4CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Criteria used by the Secretary of Agriculture to determine property eligibility for rural development programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93DB66E256A84BC5BBEEF5E6ECB10122"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture rural-urban commuting area codes.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BE8940F11D94D6EA574C137A964B930"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A written opinion provided by the State’s bank supervisor, as defined under section 3(r) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(r)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6EAC869D72145D69070BF94576B7B6C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Population density.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8FBD1647C4744A429DA36189EE885E66"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>If, at any time prior to the submission of an application under subsection (a), the area subject to review has been designated as nonrural by any Federal agency described under subsection (b) using any of the criteria described under subsection (b), the Bureau shall not be required to consider such designation in its evaluation.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H45B564E9F96244B5823814ABAAD54864"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public comment period</header>
 <paragraph id="HBE67823958184973BE66BBF69266E11F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after receiving an application submitted under subsection (a), the Bureau shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBD17413D038447D2A377910473A70CDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish such application in the Federal Register; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H757C340A7F1A4A0DB8B088C093BA2BD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such application available for public comment for not fewer than 90 days.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37C74AA47ECB4336A8306781F3677165"><enum>(2)</enum><header> Limitation on additional applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the Bureau, during the public comment period with respect to an application submitted under subsection (a), to accept an additional application with respect to the area that is the subject of the initial application.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE09997B4146A46CCB4A48C3FCE62F037"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Decision on designation</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of the public comment period under subsection (d)(1) for an application, the Bureau shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9EB09EE155DD491DB1B770DC075DF2B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>grant or deny such application, in whole or in part; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C61768458E440A6AE5457C3DABE8E04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish such grant or denial in the Federal Register, along with an explanation of what factors the Bureau relied on in making such determination.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D8A11C3858148C7899C7D3B477E6AF8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subsequent applications</header><text>A decision by the Bureau under subsection (e) to deny an application for an area to be designated as a rural area shall not preclude the Bureau from accepting a subsequent application submitted under subsection (a) for such area to be so designated, so long as such subsequent application is made after the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date that the Bureau denies the application under subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE94C5D9DD98446608D8302E557C24A02"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall cease to have any force or effect after the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id04267CA5719F4893B1E33DB8AA1170EB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Operations in rural areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1601">15 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idB9C96F9AADAF4C4F8050C3C95FBAF439"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 129C(b)(2)(E)(iv)(I), by striking <quote>predominantly</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6FBE973F2BDA4B7390AEDA37CCE3F961"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 129D(c)(1), by striking <quote>predominantly</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

