<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S224 IS: Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 224</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150121">January 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To ensure that the United States promotes women's meaningful inclusion and participation in
			 mediation and negotiation processes undertaken in order to prevent,
			 mitigate, and resolve violent conflict and implements the United States
			 National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><subsection id="id571CC098931647C384EB5818DE1C398D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1A8B81BED0BB4456A6C13D751BEF9854"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="ida9b972d0fae44a5e8e8412f0b15bfb7f" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id4e65ff757fb24f97ac1cec5cd4703030" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id2231a00c111f4246915c547623158b26" level="section">Sec. 4. Sense of Congress regarding the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7cf17b697b5a407c8432a482bbb06f0b" level="section">Sec. 5. Statement of United States policies.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id156f34695e9e49e6870bb8040c268e92" level="section">Sec. 6. United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id26b0b9bad80a4cb9a9aeeb696dd59d03" level="section">Sec. 7. Monitoring and evaluation.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id1ccbb883b3c046f3bbaf0f485948abb9" level="section">Sec. 8. Engaging women in the full range of conflict prevention, peace negotiation, peace-building, and security initiatives.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id491c1c13697044c693c88bee2cd11422" level="section">Sec. 9. Consultations with stakeholders.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idf332aaa67c4d47989ed11e46d0ffbbcc" level="section">Sec. 10. Reports to Congress.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section><section id="ida9b972d0fae44a5e8e8412f0b15bfb7f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id08926b0c1265499b987db18269e9c78b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security, rooted in United Nations Security Council Resolution 1325 (2000) and its six follow-up resolutions 1820 (2008), 1888 (2009), 1889 (2009), 1960 (2010), 2106 (2013), and 2122 (2013), seeks to address the disproportionate impact of modern warfare on civilians, particularly women and girls, and the necessity of substantively including <quote>women as equal partners in preventing conflict and building peace in countries threatened and affected by war, violence, and insecurity in all efforts to promote peace and security</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ae46cace7e947cc9d51b861939797e3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Fundamental to the affirmations described in paragraph (1) is the full and equal participation of women as decisionmakers, planners, implementers, and beneficiaries in all efforts to achieve solutions for just conflict resolution, lasting stability, and inclusive democratic governance, including in—</text><subparagraph id="id328c8805b0174851be23ccf873a71b98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conflict prevention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a39b357bbce4fd09107eafc8ec28205"><enum>(B)</enum><text>countering violent extremism and terrorism;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ed5518851214e08afaf2a8d729534eb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mediation, transition processes, and peace and security negotiations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb82376799f754f0aa6bce2d52f39a82c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>peacekeeping and peace-building efforts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29d74e2b3dcb46fcbc3bb1ac35d91df8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>humanitarian response; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id240ee76ce3c04a28be7784d509550146"><enum>(F)</enum><text>post-conflict reconstruction and governance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf462fde226c48c89c438862de60eaea"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security, issued in December 2011—</text><subparagraph id="ida1d201d6256b4b29adbb47aeff66fe96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>builds upon the goals for gender integration articulated in—</text><clause id="id65a1954cbc4b4b9696ece4329807fc5c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States 2006 National Security Strategy: <quote>No nation can be free if half its population is oppressed and denied fundamental rights. We affirm the inherent dignity and worth of women, and support vigorously their full participation in all aspects of society.</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="ide36c6c94aa9847ca930548dfbd03a932"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the United States May 2010 National Security Strategy: <quote>Experience shows that countries are more peaceful and prosperous when women are accorded full and equal rights and opportunity. When those rights and opportunities are denied countries often lag behind.</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="ida23341b0eea345d081f27ea283cfad9b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the 2010 Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review: <quote>The protection and empowerment of women and girls is key to the foreign policy and security of the United States.</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a19252596be403f801e720079d5d1e7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>asserts that <quote>evidence from around the world and across cultures shows that integrating women and gender considerations into peace-building processes helps promote democratic governance and long-term stability</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd42918e803e34d0394ec9d0803e514dd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As directed by Executive Order 13595, <quote>State, DoD, and USAID will designate one or more officers, as appropriate, as responsible for coordination and implementation, and will supplement this Plan, by submitting to the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor agency-specific Women, Peace, and Security implementation plans. These implementation plans will establish a full range of time-bound, measurable, and resourced actions State, DoD, and USAID will take to realize their commitments, and will include meaningful strategies for monitoring implementation and evaluating results.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbcc19f98f9054c50bf3719308d0f501e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On April 5, 2012, the Department of Defense (DoD) issued a Secretary of Defense Memorandum directing the Department to incorporate the concepts from the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security into programs, policies and daily activities, stating <quote>that the goal of the National Action Plan is critical to national security</quote> and in June 2012, introduced the Department of Defense Implementation Guide for the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security to integrate the objectives of the National Action Plan into the <quote>strategic, operational, and tactical environment and aims</quote> of the United States Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd69938d21b9443ada615677155ae6a24"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In March 2012, the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) released a new, agency-wide Gender Equality and Female Empowerment Policy, the first such policy since 1982. According to this policy, <quote>Gender equality and female empowerment are core development objectives, fundamental for the realization of human rights and key to effective and sustainable development outcomes. No society can develop successfully without providing equitable opportunities, resources, and life prospects for males and females so that they can shape their own lives and contribute to their families and communities.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19b4951ec1ab42728504b8cdaad487a3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In August 2012, the Department of State Implementation of the National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security was introduced. The plan states, <quote>The Department recognizes that promoting women's participation in conflict prevention, management and resolution, as well as in post-conflict relief and recovery, advances core U.S. national interests of peace, national security, economic and social development and international cooperation.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id717fb68a123242e38fc6f6d8547196b0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In August 2012, the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) introduced its Implementation of the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security, asserting, <quote>Ensuring the meaningful participation and protection of women and girls affected by crisis and conflict is critical to building lasting peace and achieving long-term development objectives.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f4a458cd24547c0a100ce42e698d8e2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>As directed by Executive Order 13595, the interagency process for coordinating the implementation of the United States National Action Plan shall <quote>coordinate a comprehensive periodic review of, and update to, the National Action Plan</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa89772204cf400c8297bd0fdbbd7d20"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Comprehensive periodic reviews of the United States National Action Plan should include an assessment of all current metrics utilized for the monitoring and evaluation of individual agencies’ implementation plans and evaluate the feasibility of enhancing the systems utilized to track spending related to current Women, Peace, and Security programming.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d9790de3d7e4478b92bcfb6d3e14981"><enum>(11)</enum><text>During continued United States efforts in Afghanistan, support for the strengthening of Afghanistan’s constitutional guarantees on women’s equality, meaningful female participation in political processes, and the protection of women’s security and ability to move freely throughout the country is critical.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecacea9aeedf4039a9d7ab420a873b47"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In the Democratic Republic of Congo and South Sudan, ongoing impunity for violations of human rights, particularly women's human rights, continues to undermine all efforts to bring lasting peace to the country and the region.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id4e65ff757fb24f97ac1cec5cd4703030"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id95d11e428fe540b28c8be150226e1755"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id28e5694aea7d454aa98c36642d650a8b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idafb5076742464fcd97dbfc3a46bf7e69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06020c447e894d428124aa6cff54cf34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae390f43ae3346dd8a621fbdc8ae8af7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae1d376751b44d09b40fc154bb6e49c7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb268f6124b6b4bac875dcd57e5d18e5d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id203e90a50b8c4d0db43f147afda2dccf"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf55180f13ee04d71b40fe21778ba7f72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decisionmaking processes</header><text>The term <term>decisionmaking processes</term> means formal or informal processes related to, or a part of, negotiations or mediations addressing conflict prevention and stabilization, peace-building, protection, or appropriate security initiatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0523dec362f34a8d89f9e84ee8c8a71b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>NAP</header><text>The term <term>NAP</term> means the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security, which was instituted by Executive Order 13595 on December 19, 2011.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1553ccf9b7e84030abe24ea413386394"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5b371f32a004acf84c88224a0187d51"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Stakeholders</header><text>The term <term>stakeholders</term> means nongovernmental and private sector entities engaged in or affected by conflict prevention and stabilization, peace-building, protection, security, transition initiatives, humanitarian response, or related efforts, including—</text><subparagraph id="id99272cf614fb48879b3c81d1b98c5b1b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>registered or nonregistered nonprofit organizations, advocacy groups, business or trade associations, labor unions, cooperatives, credit unions, relief or development organizations, community and faith-based organizations, philanthropic foundations, and tribal leaders or structures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e866f64ff734355b644e6e25f2a9005"><enum>(B)</enum><text>independent media, educational, or research institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18db2ad3155b47b09d8175b5ac23618c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>private enterprises, including international development firms, banks, and other financial institutions, and particularly small businesses and businesses owned by women or disadvantaged groups.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id03b6dece053742f6ab1c06dda8bac1a7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Women's meaningful inclusion and participation</header><text>The term <term>women's meaningful inclusion and participation</term> means ensuring women have safe, genuine, and effective access and are present and actively involved in the full range of decisionmaking processes, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id18056b968653477f9896e2510b9dc40a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conflict prevention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c929442e70a47dc85ff80798994546b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mediation or negotiation efforts to resolve, mitigate, and transition from violent conflict;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41693102d0044019a39e83ae23bd8fe2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>peacekeeping and peace-building efforts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide6c7b4cdd2b741cf8e40683ceadb515b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>post-conflict reconstruction, transition initiatives, and governance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6ad3968ed344ce583370c33e75f982b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>humanitarian response.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id2231a00c111f4246915c547623158b26"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="idcb620c99d7da461aab52483b27e3c159"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implementation of the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security (NAP) is paramount in improving the lives of women and girls around the world and increasing overall global stability and prosperity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ADD0439278140ED95B1D3FD5BA91D58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress supports the statement in the NAP of the United States <quote>unqualified commitment to integrating women's views and perspectives fully into our diplomatic, security, and development efforts—not simply as beneficiaries, but as agents of peace, reconciliation, development, growth, and stability</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf54335fdb26248168cdfa5e4e1f88f35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress is strongly committed to advancing the principles of the NAP, as instituted by Executive Order 13595 of December 19, 2011;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb000fc6e2e524f7baffadcf967976e5c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States should coordinate with the international community and civil society to develop criteria for eligibility to ensure that appropriate civil society representatives with relevant experience in gender sensitivity, peacemaking, or the promotion of human rights and security are identified for inclusion in all peace-building processes and activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf15f904d78a145048667ae5c9b1ab7f8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the President, in coordination with the Secretary, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator, should—</text><subparagraph id="id1a3e977cc6bd4ec7af043bcaef25f258"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure the NAP's robust, transparent, comprehensive, and coordinated implementation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id029955e7032646e988f31015b6db842a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate with the international community to utilize the commitments outlined in the NAP as a diplomatic means to encourage other countries to—</text><clause id="id56d108828b534baeba54d99f2ecfa9b6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advance women's inclusion in peace negotiations, peace-building activities, and conflict prevention;</text></clause><clause id="idfcf5a1fdac6541a49c10c374892b8bd6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>protect all civilians, specifically women and girls, from sexual and gender-based violence; and</text></clause><clause id="ided93038a821f4675bb30abc4c1982f64"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensure equal access to relief and recovery assistance in areas of conflict and insecurity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id7cf17b697b5a407c8432a482bbb06f0b"><enum>5.</enum><header>Statement of United States policies</header><subsection id="id6a85d385f0cc48efb459bc4cbd6c2abd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to implement the United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security (NAP), as instituted by Executive Order 13595 on December 19, 2011, to ensure that the United States effectively promotes and supports women in conflict-affected and post-conflict regions through clear, measurable commitments to—</text><paragraph id="ideb368db0e92e4de382a6587f8b471f75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote the active and meaningful participation of women in affected areas in all aspects of conflict prevention, management, and resolution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3321c7ab588b40cba584f6efbdad7afc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrate the perspectives and interests of affected women into conflict-prevention activities and strategies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd71af10441bf4ef3a426f6be38e96b35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote the physical safety, economic security, and dignity of women and girls;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd72d7dc1401e450aab1b7563aad201b2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support women's equal access to aid distribution mechanisms and services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e3e485ed9704519840a15a52f49c51a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>monitor, analyze, and evaluate implementation efforts and the impact of such efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id84359e05769b44da8265e6dfbe19ccb9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>adjust policies and programs to improve outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id03eb8a06b8d9432596d8c9863ceab267"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of Congress</header><text>Congress—</text><paragraph id="id8062a9f93b7140c2ac2d9de7b76bd034"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the invaluable contributions that United States and international civil society groups have made to United States policies and programs on women, peace, and security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a27f295287b45798ac39f6fdbd1b51c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the Secretary, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator to continue to consult and utilize the networks and expertise of these stakeholders to strengthen the implementation of the NAP.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3d7a1b16b6744a8d9f6bdb460249bd48"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Integration</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="id592ca97c121841298201392540dc6136"><enum>(1)</enum><text>integrate gender as fully as applicable into all diplomatic and development efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1b07a3a53104602a654c3e55c9174ff"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include gender in strategic and budget planning processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idefa98f8f3a524229a005b2d6017c0bce"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continue to use and improve upon performance indicators and evaluation mechanisms to account for ongoing results and measure the impact of United States policies and programs on women and girls in foreign countries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec476995e54d48b98bd3fe55b209e49f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review existing United States policies and programs on women and girls in foreign countries from a gender perspective, and revise such policies and programs to address any unintended harm.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id91be9ec19e984d2b81328bb1a20b55f1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Integration of gender goals in agency guidance and contracting</header><paragraph id="id055fa51af7804cceb0157e898d923b62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department of State</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations and issue guidance specifying key goals of the NAP with a view to fully integrating such goals into the operations of the Department of State in the United States and overseas, and shall ensure that such regulations and guidance call for compliance by all Department personnel and contractors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d4744abcaf142a99d701e471d503755"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States agency for international development</header><text>The Administrator shall prescribe regulations and issue guidance specifying key goals of the NAP with a view to fully integrating such goals into the operations of the United States Agency for International Development in the United States and overseas, and shall ensure that such regulations and guidance call for compliance by all Agency personnel and contractors.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9882b5a5fa5344a7a59f21a5924bdf26"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tenets</header><text>The Secretary, the Administrator, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Health and Human Services acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the United States Permanent Representatives to the United Nations, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the United States Trade Representative, and the heads of other appropriate Federal departments and agencies shall ensure, as appropriate, that the tenets of the NAP are incorporated into all programs administered by each department and agency specified in this subsection related to—</text><paragraph id="id793d7c79dd6340508a58b4634cea2387"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conflict prevention;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7944b2bfc9c44fffa22e33c1bb6ed594"><enum>(2)</enum><text>humanitarian and disaster response;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d3ea9073ef44812957675515e5b0a4e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conflict mediation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id950906ce05684dac9c75daca403e01b1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>peacekeeping;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf7c229db15b40329c251b6b068b700d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>post-conflict reconstruction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87ea699fbb8a44ca9b124043c8f05f77"><enum>(6)</enum><text>institution building; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85814cd5b284425099f4789e5ae1b542"><enum>(7)</enum><text>democracy promotion.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id156f34695e9e49e6870bb8040c268e92"><enum>6.</enum><header>United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security</header><subsection id="idfa3a7fd329744288b0f8abc62cc8d0fe"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, the Administrator, the Secretary of Defense, and the heads of other appropriate Federal departments and agencies shall, subject to subsection (b), develop or update and implement a National Action Plan. The National Action Plan shall be transmitted to the appropriate congressional committees and made publicly available.</text></subsection><subsection id="id32a65ca80dfa44fab5eb4bc19271cc40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial NAP</header><text>For the purposes of this section, the <quote>United States National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security</quote>, issued in December 2011, shall be deemed to fulfill the initial requirement of subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="idab581a5ddc314274b84f90fcb9bfffb7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training</header><paragraph id="id1e6adf6e88454fc08114927ddbce814d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign Service Act of 1980</header><text>Section 704 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4024">22 U.S.C. 4024</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFEF1D4591625487C9AA8917B28D868A5" style="OLC"><subsection id="id1a05728b5e924b07a703be984c612b67"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The Secretary, in conjunction with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall ensure that all appropriate personnel, including special envoys, members of mediation or negotiation teams, relevant members of the Civil Service or Foreign Service, and contractors responsible for, or deploying to, countries or regions considered to be at risk of, undergoing, or emerging from violent conflict, obtain substantive knowledge and skills through—</text><paragraph id="idedddb8437135463b9414d91cc95c5a1a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriate advanced training in conflict prevention, peace processes, mitigation, resolution, and security initiatives that specifically addresses the importance of women's meaningful inclusion and participation (as defined in section 3 of the Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2015);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8284f9849af64d83be0645c16c9654d4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>training on gender considerations and women's meaningful inclusion and participation, including training regarding—</text><subparagraph id="id33a7955ee01d486aa43fbfc538fc334f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>international human rights law and international humanitarian law, as relevant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf77de039012e4b6d95d5b79a38f16e58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protecting civilians from violence, exploitation, and trafficking in persons; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id899dd9378d904d778d0c9126d087b0fc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>training on effective strategies and best practices for ensuring women's meaningful inclusion and participation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5fb9b6bc74347ec983c9bd8f97616e3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Title 10, United States Code</header><subparagraph id="id66d9466122284589a28f71be8be58dc3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/107">Chapter 107</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2263D348E8E649138A80BB1E3913AB1F" style="USC"><section id="idc60ad129faf141a3bf8742f90cae161b"><enum>2158.</enum><header>Training for ensuring women's meaningful inclusion and participation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that all appropriate personnel, including members of the Armed Forces, members of mediation or negotiation teams, relevant members of the Civil Service, and contractors responsible for, or deploying to, countries or regions considered to be at risk of, undergoing, or emerging from violent conflict, obtain substantive knowledge and skills through—</text><paragraph id="id6b2d569b857246e39f431a2a590fd083"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriate advanced training in conflict prevention, peace processes, mitigation, resolution, and security initiatives that specifically addresses the importance of women's meaningful inclusion and participation (as defined in section 3 of the Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2015);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35affe78f8c8410b8876bdf0450f2f09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>training on gender considerations and women's meaningful inclusion and participation, including training regarding—</text><subparagraph id="id7aa5da1d608e4e638ae2b559c27024ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>international human rights law and international humanitarian law, as relevant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2cb9e83cbade4fc7a0ac8432f4572895"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protecting civilians from violence, exploitation, and trafficking in persons; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idda8711c882ab43e3bcfb450cae4fc938"><enum>(3)</enum><text>training on effective strategies and best practices for ensuring women's meaningful inclusion and participation.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id364b6308d87c4c0c8aa39aaf5926f192"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 107 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><quote>2158. Training for ensuring women's meaningful inclusion and participation.</quote>.</toc-entry></toc></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id777ac384456a4f8abccb3ee6cc8f1d08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United Nations</header><text>The Secretary is strongly encouraged to work with the United Nations and the international community to promote training that provides international peacekeeping personnel with substantive knowledge and skills needed to effectively ensure women's meaningful inclusion and participation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id26b0b9bad80a4cb9a9aeeb696dd59d03"><enum>7.</enum><header>Monitoring and evaluation</header><subsection id="id9beaab5a603f45278978edc70a33a620"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The implementation of the NAP under section 6 shall include the establishment or improvement of monitoring and evaluation tools to ensure accountability and effectiveness of policies, programs, projects, and activities undertaken to support the objectives specified in the NAP.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc0f4f60a3f0b492eb6025ebb9c4bf4d4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monitoring and evaluation plans</header><text>The Secretary, the Administrator, the Secretary of Defense, and representatives of other relevant Federal agencies and departments, as appropriate, shall develop a plan for monitoring and independent evaluation of programs, projects, and activities carried out under this Act. The plan shall—</text><paragraph id="idd3830f2acf72479dad420fdc2263453e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apply rigorous monitoring and evaluation methodologies to focus on learning, accountability, and policymaking, choosing from among a wide variety of qualitative, quantitative, summative, and formative methods common in the field of social scientific inquiry, including impact evaluations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0bf0d285b32542a8a918b02ced8813a8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be included in the NAP under section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1c553d2d5dc84354b6810b1a47682e71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Foreign assistance coordination, planning, data collection, and tracking systems</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, as appropriate, shall—</text><paragraph id="id0f70004c948549129164637dcd8b7796"><enum>(1)</enum><text>utilize appropriate foreign assistance coordination, planning, data collection, and tracking systems to—</text><subparagraph id="idbf5fdfc594394ebc8ca5c1190860554d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>analyze the impact of staff training, management systems, and organizational structures on program results;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5da890a38714f8fb3efa8d8fbfecbfa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve collection of sex- and age-disaggregated data in conflict-affected areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0350406444e24be28894cdc994f641f7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure proper targeting of programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e420a3b139540b9b7e56bc2b79e7a37"><enum>(D)</enum><text>collect and analyze gender data for the purpose of developing and enhancing early warning systems of conflict and violence;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b95c5b482774909bdeeca7ba6d630a3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop programming in accordance with the NAP's principles and that is responsive to women's needs and perspectives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a4d97ff93e44efe92c394084933ba3a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>revise policies and programming as data is collected and analyzed to ensure improved outcomes for women and girls;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9df16a3eae4648a4a8a3baaa03f900e7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support budgeting, operational and programmatic planning, and performance management, related to women's meaningful inclusion and participation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idedb061ec456e462ca3953c0159d44b24"><enum>(5)</enum><text>post to the Foreign Assistance Dashboard up-to-date data on United States foreign assistance by account, bureau or office, as the case may be, and country where gender equality and women's empowerment is a primary or secondary goal; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ca88fa23cd544a7ab0ba768a5f5ecb3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop or improve upon existing data collection mechanisms that—</text><subparagraph id="idc6433bbeb38441bb980d5f9b519a417e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>track and report progress on the objectives specified in the NAP;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7b35f8a779da457f8bb17ddcc608a2af"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess lessons learned; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25e72fcce3cf45f0b105e97f3ea2c012"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify best practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbacd8575ae4841a6a5de4e1fc03fb44c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Indicators</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator, in cooperation with the Secretary of Defense, as appropriate, shall identify common indicators to evaluate the impact of United States foreign assistance on women's meaningful inclusion and participation and revise approaches to ensure improved outcomes.</text></subsection></section><section id="id1ccbb883b3c046f3bbaf0f485948abb9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Engaging women in the full range of conflict prevention, peace negotiation, peace-building, and
 security initiatives</header><subsection id="idfbae5120642d4d969f9797873bd65aa8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator are strongly encouraged to work to facilitate women's meaningful inclusion and participation in informal and formal peace negotiations, including, as appropriate, by—</text><paragraph id="id57902253297b49ddb7191fde16bfc7f1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing technical assistance, training, and logistical support to female negotiators, peace-builders, and stakeholders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9485ab2389da4640b0a9eded1f4e8660"><enum>(2)</enum><text>utilizing technology, such as cell phones or social media tools, that assist the work of organizers, negotiators, communicators, peace-builders, and other civil society actors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6725e6c78e634a49b416e247369cc308"><enum>(3)</enum><text>addressing security-related barriers to women's participation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e1e4fd921b84451a533157804f6be64"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expanding and applying gender analysis to improve program design and targeting; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde549bd3fbfd4f8885631fd4fe6b06cc"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting appropriate local organizations, especially women's peace-building organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0049dd945717494f9317795c1f80858b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary is encouraged to promote the meaningful inclusion and participation of women in coordination and consultation with international partners, including multilateral organizations, stakeholders, and other relevant international organizations, particularly in circumstances in which direct engagement is not appropriate or advisable.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3e3dbe63355c46fca422af867bacb192"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessments</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, and in cooperation with the Secretary of Defense, as appropriate, shall conduct assessments that include the perspective of women before implementing new projects or activities in support of assistance related to—</text><paragraph id="id1e571ea6d33b4ee0a088fef3a77ecaac"><enum>(1)</enum><text>peace negotiations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id938ec100ac40450cb753468b7767bc23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transitional justice and accountability processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec66db3a658f4af2bfd4aa5c6827a9fd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>efforts to combat violent extremism; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddfdb9bfb60fb460a8edf808ddc767652"><enum>(4)</enum><text>security sector reform.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id62eb164a69954b418c516d3d36f1fa34"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Government efforts</header><paragraph id="idc6e68c3653a048f9b022ce00cd7e8188"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, and in cooperation with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies and departments, as appropriate, shall encourage and facilitate the efforts of partner governments to improve women's meaningful inclusion and participation in peace and security processes, conflict prevention, peace-building, transitional processes, and decisionmaking institutions in conflict-affected environments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc25d72b11a054a2c9af1c4d2a8c672b1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Government efforts</header><text>The efforts of partner governments to be encouraged and facilitated under paragraph (1) include—</text><subparagraph id="id1f26f75859154f868f462077894f225c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the recruitment and retention of women (including minorities) in leadership roles;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca03e3c2d9a749d484f5032a458e7345"><enum>(B)</enum><text>capacity building of legislative, judicial, defense, and law enforcement institutions to develop and implement policies which support women's meaningful inclusion and participation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id83e8fa84c1804177a7b4d7e6bccc631d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increased women's participation in programs funded by the United States Government that—</text><clause id="id24fcb57abeb540bd9dd1abfb6eab9ddc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide training to foreign nationals regarding law enforcement, the rule of law, and professional military education; and</text></clause><clause id="idafdbdfd8e5d94e83827ec51219467f00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>offer foreign nationals opportunities to participate in educational exchanges, conferences, and seminars;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb670a38db184305b7472d97536e5d6d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>training, education, and mobilization of men and boys as partners in support of women's meaningful inclusion and participation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33a51b82327b49ce90902d8766b9dbfe"><enum>(E)</enum><text>development of transitional justice and accountability mechanisms that are inclusive of the experiences and perspectives of women and girls; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a9c4c77c80f43be9f509f2f82259a8a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>measures to ensure that relief and recovery planning and assistance are informed by effective consultation with women and girls.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id491c1c13697044c693c88bee2cd11422"><enum>9.</enum><header>Consultations with stakeholders</header><subsection id="id68e1c5c93aa346dead0b28f9374f47aa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator shall establish guidelines for overseas United States personnel to consult with stakeholders regarding United States efforts to—</text><paragraph id="id746abdc365af44cfa70aea62fec1423e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent conflict; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde88b89ad1a44fbc94f0f867221b9b48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance the success of mediation and negotiation processes by ensuring women's meaningful inclusion and participation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1b12f2fa5c9149c0a8b1006e65774681"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Frequency and scope</header><text>Consultations under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="ide157d47412f74a719529360cfb255fe1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take place not less frequently than once every 180 days, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id198a98d6001c4014b64a34607d5b0a08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a range and representative sample of local stakeholders, including women, youth, ethnic and religious minorities, and other politically under-represented or marginalized populations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf332aaa67c4d47989ed11e46d0ffbbcc"><enum>10.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subsection id="id3523ee72463749a3830d26284820004e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training briefing</header><text>The Secretary, in conjunction with the Administrator and the Secretary of Defense, shall designate appropriate officials to brief the appropriate congressional committees, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, on—</text><paragraph id="id88e25c1b9a8e44cfb347ec86daed3575"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the existing, enhanced, and newly established training carried out pursuant to section 6(c) and the amendments made by such section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4abede77c4654105bc6e03f1ed5d52a6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the guidelines established for overseas United States diplomatic and consular personnel to engage in consultations with United States and international stakeholders pursuant to section 9.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida4e8f5989e2a408396ecc47aff68b681"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report on women, peace, and security</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary, in conjunction with the Administrator and the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text><paragraph id="id4fbfc0a051684a0aa045354a44b510de"><enum>(1)</enum><text>outlines the monitoring and evaluation tools, mechanisms, and common indicators established under section 7 to assess progress made on the objectives of the NAP;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd277c7e6bbc14e5f8c6f104a7285dadc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>summarizes United States diplomatic efforts and foreign assistance programs, projects, and activities to promote women's meaningful inclusion and participation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id563fd4ff6aff417fbd4710256ffa4926"><enum>(3)</enum><text>summarizes and evaluates the impact of the NAP initiatives.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

