<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" public-print="no" public-private="public" stage-count="1" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S635 IS: Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">S. 635</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20150303">March 3, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type display="yes">A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to provide guidance and limitations regarding
			 the integration of unmanned aircraft systems into United States airspace,
 and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H91E3A8A9D5D445EF9A674399AA67E69C" style="OLC"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62633EFE777C412A86B0DD8CD9DF2A38" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H085B5A112F2F494F9F5657936386402C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA44274D26B894BD3A76C58B73F787464"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 14, 2012, President Obama signed the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/95">Public Law 112–95</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note) into law, and sections 331 through 336 of such Act require the Federal Aviation Administration to fully integrate government, commercial, and recreational unmanned aircraft systems, commonly known as <term>drones</term>, into United States airspace by October 2015.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF989CEC8546482C8877C024444ADE4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unmanned aircraft systems have traditionally been used almost exclusively overseas by military and security organizations; however, State and local governments, businesses, and private individuals are increasingly using unmanned aircraft systems in the United States, including deployments for law enforcement operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84BDE990DECD4EB189666C262D800D71"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the technology advances and the cost decreases—unmanned aircraft systems are already orders of magnitude less expensive to purchase and operate than piloted aircraft—the market for Federal, State, and local government and commercial unmanned aircraft systems is rapidly growing.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34A97DB70BF944219F57EDB70874334A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It has been estimated there could be as many as 30,000 unmanned aircraft systems in the sky in the United States by 2020.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AABF43A12DB4EFB914827AF9445DF3E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There will no doubt be many beneficial applications of this technology, for as Secretary of Transportation Ray LaHood said in a statement on March 7, 2012, <quote>Unmanned aircraft can help us meet a number of challenges, from spotting wildfires to assessing natural disasters.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92447A231E1D406A91E42999DBC60947"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">However, there also is the potential for unmanned aircraft system technology to enable invasive and pervasive surveillance without adequate privacy protections, and currently, no explicit privacy protections or public transparency measures with respect to such system technology are built into the law.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60579B7BD4FD416AA800B4E8AF653941"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal standards for informing the public and protecting individual privacy with respect to unmanned aircraft systems are needed.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68F67AB4DF9846EFA1B436D21C3790DD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Guidance and limitations regarding unmanned aircraft systems</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC700C2CD3034448D8CA8F63DB18EF869"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle B of title III of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/95">Public Law 112–95</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3707858A3394AB5BEEECE35385B70D6" style="OLC"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD07D4FA0D63443BCBB871825A4C9B5F0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>337.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Privacy study and report</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4CDC5C377B249BEB76F23CFE4110955"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission, and the Chief Privacy Officer of the Department of Homeland Security, shall carry out a study that identifies any potential threats to privacy protections posed by the integration of unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system, including any potential violations of the privacy principles.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC3C656C089A4B439B389FCDD838F571"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit a report on the study conducted under subsection (a) to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56E07FB5BAEC4AAC81DA1051A0484BA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1334B14EAB8A49E19449DCF39D6DE5C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Environment and Public Works, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A64E01131494DAF9DDF3310CB608029" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>338.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As part of the rulemaking process required under section 332(b)(1) and the final rule adopted under such section, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish procedures to ensure that the integration of unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system is done in compliance with the privacy principles.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H374186893C29402586A5452DC37A0D83" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>339.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data collection statements and data minimization statements</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA49F2C432F940DCB2B68F376BF6B9F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Transportation may not approve, issue, or award any certificate, license, or other grant of authority to operate an unmanned aircraft system in the national airspace system unless the application for such certificate, license, or other grant of authority includes—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C143809B4BD4F91A5A80FFCBB3677B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a data collection statement in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b) that provides reasonable assurance that the applicant will operate the unmanned aircraft system in accordance with the privacy principles; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H685DECE5481A43AEB58F7A6D931A54F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of such an unmanned aircraft system that is to be operated by a law enforcement agency or a law enforcement agency contractor or subcontractor, a data minimization statement in accordance with the requirements of subsection (c) that provides reasonable assurance that the applicant will operate the unmanned aircraft system in accordance with the privacy principles.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB1606DED3AC410B91097DCB6B0ABA2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data collection statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A data collection statement under subsection (a), with respect to an unmanned aircraft system, shall include information identifying—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3411D5A2C4A405DB1B912007D0C88A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individuals or entities that will have the power to use the unmanned aircraft system;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16AF138E9D944A639AC1A7D45F2A83EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the specific locations in which the unmanned aircraft system will operate;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E4BB0BD0952405797E987BF0C8F77E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the maximum period for which the unmanned aircraft system will operate in each flight;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H269B251E74EB4C7F8AF628B22D0B27E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the unmanned aircraft system will collect information or data about individuals or groups of individuals, and if so—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA82588BC66964EECB8962F00FF91728A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the circumstances under which the system will be used; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AB1D53B6D60465FAF8C6B2C3346F535"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the specific kinds of information or data the system will collect about individuals or groups of individuals and how such information or data, as well as conclusions drawn from such information or data, will be used, disclosed, and otherwise handled, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7BF49DDBD1B43078E1C837A8E7D1A7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the collection or retention of such information or data that is unrelated to the specified use will be minimized;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81D8CBC24FA5407BBDF5FB6C5788B040"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether such information or data might be sold, leased, or otherwise provided to third parties, and if so, under what circumstances it might be so sold or leased;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C11916701F9477B9CF4678BCDEACF5B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the period for which such information or data will be retained; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39A22B61D9464C6184B2F8FC065BAF7C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when and how such information or data, including information or data no longer relevant to the specified use, will be destroyed;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F625BEE453741D9AE8EFCD5EED0375E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the possible impact the operation of the unmanned aircraft system may have upon the privacy of individuals;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H331EA6EB1A7A49678292C7DD0CCBDD5B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the specific steps that will be taken to mitigate any possible impact identified under paragraph (5), including steps to protect against unauthorized disclosure of any information or data described in paragraph (4), such as the use of encryption methods and other security features that will be used;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H567A3A38FC25456EB369C1DD552AA46A"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a telephone number or electronic mail address that an individual with complaints about the operation of the unmanned aircraft system may use to report such complaints and to request confirmation that personally identifiable data relating to such individual has been collected;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33C9F79FFA174A73B40DE3C36E443718"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case in which personally identifiable data relating to an individual has been collected, a reasonable process for the individual to request to obtain such data in a timely and an intelligible manner;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E35BE59124144E9A5FE91F8068B0231"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case in which a request described in paragraph (8) is denied, a process by which the individual may obtain the reasons for the denial and challenge the denial; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55095AAEA00B4B35A1CDAE3EFB507C10"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case in which personally identifiable data relating to an individual has been collected, a process by which the individual may challenge the accuracy of such data and, if the challenge is successful, have such data erased or amended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD92F79F1F4CF4182826A47F8BACF5D87"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data minimization statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A data minimization statement described in this subsection, with respect to an unmanned aircraft system operated by a law enforcement agency, contractor, or subcontractor described in subsection (a)(2), shall detail the applicable—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA20FF529EFBF4F20AA8A4C83D7732A86"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policies adopted by the agency, contractor, or subcontractor, as the case may be, that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3465FDB68CE8462FB57587522E8FF0D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minimize the collection by the unmanned aircraft system of information and data unrelated to the investigation of a crime under a warrant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A0F27A8FC48406FBD1DBA06160A61DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the destruction of such information and data, as well as of information and data collected by the unmanned aircraft system that is no longer relevant to the investigation of a crime under a warrant or to an ongoing criminal proceeding; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC0D501940DF4EF5B18011170FE116A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish procedures for the method of such destruction; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4AB6BAC45D9403BAC3684CCF9C74094"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">audit and oversight procedures adopted by the agency, contractor, or subcontractor, as the case may be, that will ensure that the agency, contractor, or subcontractor, as the case may be, uses the unmanned aircraft system in accordance with the parameters outlined in the data collection statement and the statement required by this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF04FE7CD5074D11853FEF33CF952E4D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>340.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disclosure of approved certificates, licenses, and other grants of authority</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36775B4C89A94E02A388867FCDB46E83"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall make available on the public Internet website of the Federal Aviation Administration in a searchable format—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0202F4C528EA4B95988F8C992DA1D177"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the approved certificate, license, or other grant of authority for each unmanned aircraft system awarded a certificate, license, or other grant of authority to operate in the national airspace system, including any such certificate, license, or other grant of authority awarded prior to the date of the enactment of this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F971E28383A4EA3B82C5E2FF9E5D30E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information detailing where, when, and for what period each unmanned aircraft system will be operated;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4210443529424ADF90E72BA3A155F0A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information detailing any data security breach that occurs with regard to information collected by an unmanned aircraft system; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03AE23B5C5924158B9F06F063658F8D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a certificate, license, or other grant of authority awarded on or after the date of the enactment of this section to operate an unmanned aircraft system in the national airspace system, the data collection statement described in section 339(b) and, if applicable, the data minimization statement described in section 339(c) required with respect to such unmanned aircraft system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B1EE383FB4247A7BBC4C40B0AAEF898"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall complete the requirements under subsection (a) with regard to each unmanned aircraft system—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5790900CF5749F986855E0681B76F96"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a certificate, license, or other grant of authority awarded before the date of the enactment of this section, not later than 90 days after such date of enactment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9363037099F43079C98324BEC311C8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a certificate, license, or other grant of authority awarded on or after the date of the enactment of this section, as soon as is practicable after the date of approval of such certificate, license, or other grant of authority.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04A30010FE604CED9DFDCAFD5518F9FB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>341.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Warrants required for generalized surveillance</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA43D0C5210894F0D82D756DE092633CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A governmental entity (as defined in section 2711 of title 18, United States Code) may not use an unmanned aircraft system or request information or data collected by another person using an unmanned aircraft system for protective activities, or for law enforcement or intelligence purposes, except pursuant to a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) by a court of competent jurisdiction, or as permitted under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5869A5B8E3F142C6B75B522C44214856"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5547E6483294B4E93B93712D640A117"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply in exigent circumstances (as defined in paragraph (2)).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAABF749D6F24BF8BDA5326D551A0052"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exigent circumstances defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exigent circumstances exist when—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54661DD8B3EA43F283CA3443A145EE5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a law enforcement entity reasonably believes there is an imminent danger of death or serious physical injury; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE8847C710CD4FD08A0B1F9A11F0D949"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a law enforcement entity reasonably believes there is a high risk of an imminent terrorist attack by a specific individual or organization and the Secretary of Homeland Security has determined that credible intelligence indicates there is such a risk.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FA0ADE4B9C74FF0811F94E712913385"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Required documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a person operating an unmanned aircraft system under the exception for exigent circumstances under paragraph (1), documentation justifying the exception shall be submitted to the Secretary of Transportation not later than 7 days after the date of the relevant unmanned aircraft system flight.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43E4409889D24845A00117EABE8BB347"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information or data unrelated to exigent circumstances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person operating an unmanned aircraft system under the exception for exigent circumstances under paragraph (1) shall minimize the collection by the unmanned aircraft system of information and data unrelated to the exigent circumstances. If the unmanned aircraft system incidentally collects any such information or data while being operated under that exception, the person operating the unmanned aircraft system shall destroy the information and data.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC84975C76534D499AC01145099DD646"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person may not intentionally divulge information collected in accordance with this section with any other person, except as authorized by law.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H666A2D3540C2494D868CCF0C3468B3AE"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on use as evidence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If information has been collected by means of use of an unmanned aircraft system, no part of the contents of that information and no evidence derived from that information may be received in evidence in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, officer, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision thereof unless that information is collected in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF5C99038FECC45EDBAFC2476D48CECF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 331 of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/95">Public Law 112–95</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBB9E2EF74DC5403CA7FABAD519FDC186"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (9) as paragraphs (7) through (13);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2639CB068E94462DA986CBD24447D76E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59D8763F94AC4B2AB9DF8709DAC04153"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7497257DAFE143F093F91AC55EC74F48" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD72DE8FAB8948A79D07C4623C71DB96"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>law enforcement</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FBFFD8BE24B4C379B63A7045AF7E990"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity of the United States or of a State, or political subdivision thereof, that is empowered by law to conduct investigations of or to make arrests for offenses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8260C705689F4BA0A5515E219D7E9B62"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity or individual authorized by law to prosecute or participate in the prosecution of such offenses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD18C29FA59C942E49C99319F00C44F1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (4), as redesignated by paragraph (2), the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id456E16BCFCDF4A278B40C4BE43630956" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB29B6CB473A94ACC98A18461DA736284"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Privacy principles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>privacy principles</term> means the principles described in Part Two of the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development guidelines titled <term>Annex to the Recommendation of the Council of 23rd September 1980: Guidelines Governing The Protection Of Privacy And Transborder Flows Of Personal Data</term>, adopted by the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development on September 23, 1980.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99B008A2368D4BDAAAE483E800AA01D6"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Privacy protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>privacy protections</term> means protections that relate to the use, collection, and disclosure of information and data about individuals and groups of individuals.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E24A65A972D413CA234557747E1E9F9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H427F47BC69924C649C1C61FDE090FFD3"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibited conduct</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D498E78337A4CF5B809287A03A67C42"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for a person to operate an unmanned aircraft system in a manner that is not in accordance with the terms of a data collection statement submitted under section 339(a)(1) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, as added by section 3, or in a manner that violates any portion of the final rule required under section 332(b)(1) of such Act insofar as such portion relates to the procedures described in section 338 of such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA260A4470AF14A22AAFEDDE78E9D23EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may promulgate regulations in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to carry out paragraph (1) with respect to persons, partnerships, and corporations described in subsection (b)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52FAF6C4A27247F59716FDED979992AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1079363A2357448DA77E610BCCFEB769"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subsection (a) or the regulations promulgated under such subsection shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68219FB04854418E8F26A691234135F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce subsection (a) and the regulations promulgated under such subsection in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same powers and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act, and any violator shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC8A9B59D4334D86B8EFE167DDA7C625"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (1) and (2) shall apply—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBDF37BA489640799D493550CF873E32"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to persons, partnerships, and corporations over which the Commission has jurisdiction under section 5(a)(2) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>) (except to the extent such person, partnership, or corporation is a law enforcement contractor or subcontractor); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E39197954E146E1BD19CD3DE4CAAE25"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding such section, with respect to air carriers and foreign air carriers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H091ACA50ACF24D359A03867AF3CD6CE5"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Actions by States</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBADD3C8FCC0B480E97F854D11E604586"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Civil actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of that State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated under such subsection, or by the operation of an unmanned aircraft system in violation of the terms of a data minimization statement submitted under section 339(a)(2) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, as added by section 3, the State may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B6CB020949A4FA699128886D17099C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enjoin the violation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57AC94835898406BA0E60153C2C88703"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforce compliance with such subsection, regulation, or statement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D47C968D79F47FEADF52C690BF87C0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EE401F93906425B838408F4E8E27B44"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain such other legal and equitable relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC260AC0CF9E4CDBAB7155169E7C9012"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before filing an action under this subsection against a person, partnership, or corporation over which the Commission has jurisdiction under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>) (except to the extent such person, partnership, or corporation is a law enforcement contractor or subcontractor) or an air carrier or foreign air carrier, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State involved shall provide to the Commission a written notice of that action and a copy of the complaint for that action. If the attorney general, official, or agency determines that it is not feasible to provide the notice described in this paragraph before the filing of the action, the attorney general, official, or agency shall provide written notice of the action and a copy of the complaint to the Commission immediately upon the filing of the action.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB82DA5B9ECD469D83E270F049020CCD"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authority of the Commission</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D5457667F244B63871D1C28BC2FD419"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On receiving notice under paragraph (2) of an action under this subsection, the Commission shall have the right—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC92DF0E9D2E4D91A94D69DCB832EE0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to intervene in the action;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD89538CD65846138DFCBBD9C69509CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H615E07D5A2E94122B9D83CA47B6002AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to file petitions for appeal.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD55B9ABEDD3428485B77C8F3C0C2926"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission or the Attorney General of the United States has instituted a civil action for violation of subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated under such subsection (referred to in this subparagraph as the <term>Federal action</term>), no State attorney general, official, or agency may bring an action under this subsection during the pendency of the Federal action against any defendant named in the complaint in the Federal action for any violation as alleged in that complaint.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H898A7E79C7194BD5B5395382AFE2939F"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of bringing a civil action under this subsection, nothing in this Act or any amendment made by this Act shall be construed to prevent an attorney general, official, or agency of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general, official, or agency by the laws of that State to conduct investigations, administer oaths and affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01D3258B78E7448A990EA3D6A0476912"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Private right of action</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H934D06315C01471DB40C62918C351C87"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person injured by an act in violation of subsection (a) or the regulations promulgated under such subsection, or by the operation of an unmanned aircraft system in violation of the terms of a data minimization statement submitted under section 339(a)(2) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, as added by section 3, may bring in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EFF22BEF7E24CE592CC344F5A4E7C64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an action to enjoin such violation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EA653BA7E974FF1B1BDE4ADE9CBDB2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an action to recover damages for actual monetary loss from such violation, or to receive up to $1,000 in damages for each such violation, whichever is greater; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60E6C851F6F748FDB6E96383D8A7DD59"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">both such actions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B02FE174B2E402CAF3FABACDCB376E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Intentional violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the defendant committed a violation described in paragraph (1), and intended to do so, the court may increase the amount of the award to an amount equal to not more than 3 times the amount available under paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FCC2148C51E4D6A88D4BEFC77DF7706"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall award to a prevailing plaintiff in an action under this subsection the costs of such action and reasonable attorney’s fees, as determined by the court.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB90EA83FB864D79BB6D90E689303298"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action may be commenced under this subsection not later than 2 years after the date on which the person first discovered or had a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H472985E6DD554F0C958E2A80FAA5961F"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonexclusive remedy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The remedy provided by this subsection shall be in addition to any other remedies available to the person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7ABEEE21CF94F51B1DC7C02234741B8"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Suits against governmental entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>), a suit under subsection (c) or (d) may be maintained against a governmental entity.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02EB9E493A6D41B2B554FC52FA84FC2C"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">License revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Aviation Administration shall revoke the certificate, license, or other grant of authority to operate an unmanned aircraft system if such system is operated in a manner that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A46283441BB45C2BBC1A0842D26775F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not in accordance with the terms of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H876FEB4B188F4FFB81F56FC2199824E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a data collection statement submitted under subsection (a)(1) of section 339 of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, as added by section 3; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB7D73C24D334B62B6D854F40B0BC7B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a data minimization statement submitted under subsection (a)(2) of such section; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4078A9C21DB4708A7B985665875B9CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">violates any portion of the final rule required under section 332(b)(1) of such Act insofar as such portion relates to the procedures described in section 338 of such Act, as added by section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3615FBCC8533466CB400D23162CEC496"><enum>(g)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each day on which each unmanned aircraft system is operated in violation of subsection (a), or the regulations promulgated under such subsection, or the terms of a data minimization statement submitted under section 339(a)(2) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, as added by section 3, shall be treated as a separate violation.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B15F52870ED4231994D63C908E60D4A"><enum>(h)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E73D907A325483FBD5C4F85F5A42155"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Air carrier; foreign air carrier</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>air carrier</term> and <term>foreign air carrier</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7B4B3A4D6D614021AE3BCC30AFC9BDC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2843CFEDD9AB4FD691B28AC25D32886F"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>law enforcement</term> has the meaning given such term in section 331 of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, as amended by section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9A77B3B2A9D48B886F7A77C2C7FEB18"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF22B052CEB72412395850A21404AA9D4"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unmanned aircraft system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> has the meaning given such term in section 331 of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DA04F37119841E7A60116906C4DA9C1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Model aircraft provision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to apply to model aircraft (as defined in section 336(c) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/95">Public Law 112–95</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/40101">49 U.S.C. 40101</external-xref> note)).</text></section></legis-body></bill>


