<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1029 IS: To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to prohibit the Secretary of Energy from prescribing a final rule amending the efficiency standards for residential non-weatherized gas furnaces or mobile home furnaces until an analysis has been completed, and for other purposes. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1029</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150421">April 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to prohibit the Secretary of Energy from
			 prescribing a final rule amending the efficiency standards for residential
			 non-weatherized gas furnaces or mobile home furnaces until an analysis has
			 been completed, and for other purposes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id5D22F6B19AF6408CAB4B3E04C7E11B0C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Standards for certain furnaces</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 325(f)(4) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(f)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF5EBC1DA7E944EFABCCA0D48959E0510" style="OLC">
				<subparagraph id="id05EB4F5373E74664BEBB5F2DF77704FD"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Restriction on final rule for residential non-weatherized gas furnaces and mobile home furnaces</header>
 <clause id="id6B6ECF54BCCA4B8FAE106A115E90A5A9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary shall not prescribe a final rule amending the efficiency standards for residential non-weatherized gas furnaces or mobile home furnaces until each of the following has occurred:</text>
 <subclause id="id5d9b222e4ed543abb4708947d0b5ec46"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Secretary convenes a representative advisory group of interested stakeholders, including the manufacturers, distributors, and contractors of residential non-weatherized gas furnaces and mobile home furnaces, home builders, building owners, energy efficiency advocates, natural gas utilities, electric utilities, and consumer groups.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id6e3cd69884934463927f081161cac502"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the advisory group described in subclause (I) completes an analysis of a nationwide requirement of a condensing furnace efficiency standard including—</text>
 <item id="id7d2cc405af4145b0b8f85827989c4c46"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a complete analysis of current market trends regarding the transition of sales from non-condensing furnaces to condensing furnaces;</text>
 </item><item id="id898a1d5cdd754253842020eaedd35f4a"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the projected net loss in the industry of the present value of original equipment manufacturers after adoption of the standard;</text>
 </item><item id="idedde4ec21c5344c3a5115f8c05808875"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the projected consumer payback period and life cycle cost savings after adoption of the standard;</text> </item><item id="idaa74608b90344482955a000693056ddb"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>a determination of whether the standard is economically justified, based solely on the definition of energy under section 321); and</text>
 </item><item id="id165d1383487144168058b792a62a3cec"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>other common economic principles.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="id40a805a28ed74218a02519d8624c3c85"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The advisory group described in subclause (I) reviews the analysis and determines whether a nationwide requirement of a condensing furnace efficiency standard is technically feasible and economically justified.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id284131f5dd3b45cbbfabc891b6481c46"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The final determination of the advisory group under subclause (III) is published in the Federal Register.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id3a4cba0444e24942b9323dcb4620779c"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amended standards</header><text>If the advisory group determines under clause (i)(III) that a nationwide requirement of a condensing furnace efficiency standard is not technically feasible and economically justified, the Secretary shall, not later than 180 days after the date on which the final determination of the advisory group is published in the Federal Register under clause (i)(IV), establish amended standards through the negotiated rulemaking procedure provided for under subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Negotiated Rulemaking Act of 1990</quote>).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


