<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1859 IS: Assuring Contracting Equity Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To assure equity in contracting between the Federal Government and small business concerns, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBEF183EB53054AF785758648B0F43AA7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H66B6FD56E1744AA6A38AEEF3D9BCA8B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Assuring Contracting Equity Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF9F2FB52B3FC4AA58084DE122B5D942B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal contracting goals</header> <subsection id="H6AFA647040094D8EA07375161DB3455B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase in certain goals</header><text>Section 15(g)(1)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(g)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2748FD3416704851B4E29E65831388A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>not less than 23 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than 25 percent</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H13976A68A5EB4B418A3A01EA7D8ABCE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not less than 5 percent</quote> each place that term appears and inserting <quote>not less than 10 percent</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A2F9CF689F146F489E0E6DA9371E6E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not less than 3 percent</quote> each place that term appears and inserting <quote>not less than 6 percent</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAFE3F71FB6004767B05D1FE6670EFC27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on number of categories for which a small business may qualify</header><text>Section 15(g) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43A2DB69A018419D9353F3E9C230ADD5" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HAFC2C038338D4345A3176299CCC5F174"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on number of categories for which a small business may qualify</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF024EDAC2F06469BBC969BABFF9919C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>specified category</term> means small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, qualified HUBZone small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, and small business concerns owned and controlled by women.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD65E945A22A1428F9B47D083796FDD74"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), a Federal agency may include a business concern in not more than 2 specified categories for purposes of determining whether the Federal agency has met the Government-wide goals under this subsection for the award of contracts to business concerns in specified categories.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FAEDC18E353473C9F12942BC3F230B6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>A Federal agency may not include a small business concern that is participating in the program under section 8(a) in any specified category except the category <term>small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals</term> for purposes of determining whether the Federal agency has met the Government-wide goals under this subsection for the award of contracts to business concerns in specified categories.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H61E53D2B00464B0CB80671274AF7CC13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving transparency to assist small business concerns</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(h)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(h)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H97F767E4C017427997FBCC00D691A36C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E)(viii)(VIII), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD33916781FDC4F8D825753F6ED30DCAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H018091146CCA4F95A63168AF83F2AAE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7AF000C33C3E49B68FB2BD3AA04A1FC2" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H17B019E056434FAD9D12C30EF03FC640"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the Federal Government, the percentage of participation by small business concerns for the total value of all prime contract awards and subcontract awards for a fiscal year, including the value of each prime contract and subcontract awarded for the fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H25BCB64A1C9D48968CC2D7F1FD391ED3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compliance with small business subcontracting goals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall consult with the heads of other Federal agencies to develop and implement standards for procurement officers to take into consideration the past compliance of potential contractors with small business subcontracting goals when making contract awards.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


