<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S784 IS: Microlab Technology Commercialization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 784</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S377">Mr. Gardner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish microlabs to improve regional engagement with
			 national laboratories.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Microlab Technology Commercialization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id93C970DBC6B64D57B57654627C7307F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 </section><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idABAC01732D6B4030B0F918887E21B382" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idCF336BE9E98546B4B2DE1485180372A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Microlab</header><text>The term <quote>microlab</quote> means a small laboratory established by the Secretary under section 3.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id891427E03207407A95E71AEBBF5B539C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text>The term <quote>national laboratory</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idF779282A76C0476C9BF6147BD647CD28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a National Laboratory, as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id789DF74136DB432597B0E206633F8990"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a national security laboratory, as defined in section 3281 of the National Nuclear Security Administration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2471">50 U.S.C. 2471</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4495CC8E3C3F46829371F025263EC42B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="id4CFA2B9DE09648989BA574275AB27AFB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of microlab program</header> <subsection id="idBEAC2C8D903843E390A4D3C07F65528D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the directors of national laboratories, may establish a microlab program under which the Secretary establishes microlabs that are located in close proximity to national laboratories and that are accessible to the public for the purposes of—</text>
 <paragraph id="id922357DAE3524CA08D58EF35F22F28A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhancing collaboration with regional research groups, such as institutions of higher education and industry groups;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEFCC1F9908CB432E873944EE0B00C173"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accelerating technology transfer from national laboratories to the marketplace; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB710ECAF4E1E4EBCA5DB638E9D794CED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promoting regional workforce development through science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (<quote>STEM</quote>) instruction and training.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3B09D80A86C04681A189C9160CB2A08E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In determining the placement of microlabs under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="idA6C76558712240F2B1E27D73C757B2A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the commitment of a national laboratory to establishing a microlab;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idACD7659BDB6C41A1A3981580F1AAED88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the existence of a joint research institute or a new facility that—</text> <subparagraph id="idE1CF90C728774634BE55E1A37E9C820B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not on the main site of a national laboratory;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFDEEDE7297C349C8A7A8F2BFB4A7C29B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in close proximity to a national laboratory; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE6A3149E9FAD4B3BBFC28DCD650F4BCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has the capability to house a microlab;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id263198E6607A4AE689E95E5819B089D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether employees of a national laboratory and persons from academia, industry, and government are available to be assigned to the microlab; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBF2F283AF9874D97A129CAC6AD31C1F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>cost-sharing or in-kind contributions from State and local governments and private industry.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE12ABDAFAB864B56B37F01B6F317CBC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>If the Secretary, in collaboration with the directors of national laboratories, elects to establish a microlab program under this section, the Secretary, in collaboration with the directors of national laboratories, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2F75968ED8664F28856612F91AF512CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, begin the process of determining the placement of microlabs under subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id79CCAA697D9B4544A75B681F48B88474"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, implement the microlab program under this section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id459D2766F0044BADBB767238E8FC9CF2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subsection id="idD05A7473EEE64DD599084C957F752A11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of implementation of the microlab program under section 3, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report that provides an update on the implementation of the microlab program under section 3.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idEEF1510A0DF14DC5812BDE39FC203996"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Progress report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of implementation of the microlab program under section 3, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the microlab program under section 3, including findings and recommendations of the Secretary.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idF65919159B6D415EBFBA4654008FD887"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 </section><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id7AF0763E93E840309515A6B575914864" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2016.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

