<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1162 IS: Federal Law Enforcement Self-Defense and Protection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1162</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure Federal law enforcement officers remain able to ensure their own safety, and the safety
			 of their families, during a covered furlough.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Law Enforcement Self-Defense and Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id7ae4e4361732420889d8808570ca09a9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="id1846B40949DE4E48945CB7A7FC0EE77D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Too often, Federal law enforcement officers encounter potentially violent criminals, placing officers in danger of grave physical harm.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2ab64fddf53d451cbd9ef0cbbbdb987e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 2012 alone, 1,857 Federal law enforcement officers were assaulted, with 206 sustaining serious injuries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddc96e4ff04ba4425bd4aa80370324d6b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>From 2008 through 2011, an additional 8,587 Federal law enforcement officers were assaulted.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7d0a60b97b1246bfb99fc0d16bee095d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Federal law enforcement officers remain a target even when they are off-duty. Over the past 3 years, 27 law enforcement officers have been killed off-duty.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9bce756df0f1497f962bfe98d0b90089"><enum>(5)</enum><text>It is essential that law enforcement officers are able to defend themselves, so they can carry out their critical missions and ensure their own personal safety and the safety of their families whether on-duty or off-duty.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc644d8291c1a48f8a3d9865206f91719"><enum>(6)</enum><text>These dangers to law enforcement officers continue to exist during a covered furlough.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idd1805b22ae9f425ba09b57e39355cce8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBE3CB50C27AF477EBA985019A356AC59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> means each authority of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Government of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id21527c50d3284423b30074313432dca5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered Federal law enforcement officer</term> means any individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="idDB5097C71D1D48BF8531DA0178EC5F36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an employee of an agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09db69f973114d54a34d1cdf3b2c18f5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the authority to make arrests or apprehensions for, or prosecute, violations of Federal law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida680d4117c4f40538914cee7263b5d30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on the day before the date on which the applicable covered furlough begins, is authorized by the agency employing the individual to carry a firearm in the course of official duties;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c0a3e96a5674defacef14847e96ddcb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered furlough</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id927c0130137246b6824e776bb56e5e35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a planned event by an agency during which employees are involuntarily furloughed due to downsizing, reduced funding, lack of work, or any budget situation other than a lapse in appropriations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0951252459164FE0A4C17FBAC78FE3E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an event during which employees of an agency are involuntarily furloughed due to a lapse in appropriations; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBD2D1AF0AB31466E8F03E6CFE27FA669"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>firearm</term> has the meaning given that term in section 921 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idafef19d6933148c1a1fbd7701dc980fa"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protecting Federal law enforcement officers who are subjected to a covered furlough</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During a covered furlough, a covered Federal law enforcement officer shall have the same rights to carry a firearm issued by the Federal Government as if the covered furlough was not in effect, including, if authorized on the day before the date on which the covered furlough begins, the right to carry a concealed firearm, if the sole reason the covered Federal law enforcement officer was placed on leave was due to the covered furlough.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


