<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1956 IS: Great Lakes Maritime Heritage Assessment Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1956</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere to conduct an assessment of cultural and
			 historic resources in the waters of the Great Lakes, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Great Lakes Maritime Heritage Assessment Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idB817BDE2CBF5498BB5A5533E8C3FAE20"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessment of cultural and historic resources in waters of Great Lakes</header>
 <subsection id="idFFA38BF787EA4A75B00C4B6B2FB3C985"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idF0DF5B2985824E3E9D8F36362CBFB109"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of cultural and historic resources in the waters of the Great Lakes; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE34FF088784E49C2B4EACD9B796CE682"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the findings of the Under Secretary with respect to such assessment.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id55DEF32F3EC94A578CE673C6BAFC5EA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a)(2) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="id0889a937675544dbb384f68ae8747a53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identification of underwater geographic areas in the Great Lakes that possess historical and archaeological resources of sufficient value and density to make them nationally significant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1dbf3f6214f14625a8899717571ffbb2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the historical and archaeological resources in such geographic areas.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ide4fbf3c0a8ab4d12b967f96ecb8f52b9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An evaluation of community interest in preserving and interpreting such resources.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida90231b5140240edb72053926fd5e730"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations regarding whether such geographic areas should be designated as national marine sanctuaries to protect resources of historical and archeological significance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6c0943a9a7d4994814f6a2c3d1f92a2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recommendations regarding whether the designation of a network of underwater Great Lakes areas that protect resources of historical and archeological significance, including the existing successful Thunder Bay National Marine Sanctuary, could bring significant educational opportunities, economic development, jobs, and tourism to the Great Lakes region.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBB78DBF26D344E18B11E9EB608D138FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Under Secretary shall collaborate with local communities.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

