<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1636 IS: Just Google It Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1636</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150618">June 18, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S379">Mr. Perdue</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To streamline the collection and distribution of Government information.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="idE00D30EB8EED4B6F83F42C2DEC0BDE6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Just Google It Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id97409AFB17134FC1AED3CCA3414C8920" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id76BAE9F422F34662A177E1E66D63F308"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Technical Information Service (referred to in this Act as <quote>NTIS</quote>), the National Archives and Records Administration, the Government Accountability Office (referred to in this section as <quote>GAO</quote>), and the Library of Congress are all tasked with collecting, categorizing, and distributing Government publications to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1B5A30B5BCC8436AB0DE8A0DA2F15C63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>GAO has found that—</text> <subparagraph id="id9687C1D227AE4D9683F07A242C50A2DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>NTIS costs have exceeded its revenues during a recent 11-year period by an average of $1,300,000 per year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE435A2DF0EF64414BB14B65C6443E2F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>of the reports in the NTIS repository that are available elsewhere, 95 percent are available for free and most could be found using a web search engine like google.com.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE1A8BD7579034C44A675DF52235D7957"><enum>(3)</enum><text>NTIS is a relic of the pre-Internet era and duplicates the products and services offered by multiple Government agencies.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id575CCFF83431489EA140A32BDBE99754" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Technical Information Service</header>
 <subsection id="id9D93A330E2E04AE7B1A86E008FB8FCB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the National Technical Information Act of 1988 (subtitle B of title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/519">Public Law 100–519</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3704b">15 U.S.C. 3704b</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idFDF6193FF6544BB1A23224494BE56A78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of critical functions</header>
 <paragraph id="idBF27CC4073C34B1699604B5B5F2A3524"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation requirement</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, the Archivist of the United States, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the Commissioner of Social Security shall consult with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to determine if any function of NTIS is critical to the economy of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE0855EB46B5F478EB84E315751891710"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO certification</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall determine which of the critical functions identified pursuant to paragraph (1) are not being carried out by any other agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id6C0392B3F8B74E908B19830BA9D017A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfers authorized</header>
 <subparagraph id="id02A6124C98FE44B0A457E8D37EDFE678"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary of Commerce, before the effective date set forth in subsection (a), may transfer the responsibility for any critical function of NTIS (as identified under paragraph (1)) that is not otherwise being carried out (as determined under paragraph (2)) to another office within the Department of Commerce.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4D405D031E6C441C8385B64B851E5163"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary may not transfer any fee-based services offered by NTIS to another office within the Department of Commerce.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD2D52024839A48DC95517803066E7C2A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Services by contractor</header><text>If fee-based services determined to be critical to the economy of the United States under paragraph (1) are being carried out by a contractor through a contract with NTIS, such contract may not be renewed, but the Federal agency receiving such services, or the General Service Administration, may enter into a new contract with the contractor or another qualified entity to continue such services after the expiration of the contract with NTIS.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDB3C6D6117C844A599F8F18F46CF723B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Abolition of functions</header><text>Except for the functions transferred pursuant to subsection (b), all functions of the NTIS immediately before the repeal date described in subsection (a) are abolished on such repeal date.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1A9CC5363B724901A364669099111580"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transfer of unexpended balances</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, after consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idA92E2711C94044EBA1CCEB26201A2F61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transfer all unexpended balances in the National Technical Information Service Revolving Fund, established pursuant to the Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3704b">15 U.S.C. 3704b</external-xref> note), to the general fund of the Treasury for the purpose of deficit reduction; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id41F91AB067F64B4EAE8C2E2C71DE57D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after the transfer is completed pursuant to paragraph (1), dissolve the National Technical Information Service Revolving Fund.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id40980E7247504FAEB415DD82394E3255"><enum>4.</enum><header>Secretary of Commerce certification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Before the effective date set forth in section 3(a), the Secretary of Commerce shall submit a written certification to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that all of the operations of the National Technical Information Service have been terminated.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


