<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-print="no" public-private="public" stage-count="1" star-print="no-star-print">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1632 : To require a regional strategy to address the threat posed by Boko Haram. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
<distribution-code>IC</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">S. 1632</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20150924">September 24, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Select Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require a regional strategy to address the threat posed by Boko Haram. </official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H1C0233A7547447A5B95F0F3091047335">
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5220b9ea-0d5b-4806-a0ab-4f39840cd143" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regional strategy to address the threat posed by Boko Haram</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdb7a93b-4ebc-4b6d-ba7f-5b88870d3875"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strategy required</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4ed2155-5dad-4e7c-94de-0bb6319fbe99"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a five-year strategy to help enable the Government of Nigeria, members of the Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram (MNJTF) authorized by the African Union, and relevant partners to counter the regional threat of Boko Haram and assist the Government of Nigeria and its neighbors to accept and address legitimate grievances of vulnerable populations in areas affected by Boko Haram.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18e9d1e9-7af5-439d-84dc-754035c1e98f"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At a minimum, the strategy must address the following elements:</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id157f60a0-c49a-4f2c-a11a-b0215276f972"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhance, pursuant to existing authorities and restrictions, the institutional capacity, including military capabilities, of the Government of Nigeria and partner nations in the region, as appropriate, to counter the threat posed by Boko Haram.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dce1ba3-ff75-455d-8a3d-255b4641bae6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide humanitarian support to civilian populations impacted by Boko Haram's activity.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05367bca-6a02-4cf2-8d07-df0fb5e14b91"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specific activities through which the United States Government intends to improve and enhance the capacity of Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram partner nations to investigate and prosecute human rights abuses by security forces and promote respect for the rule of law within the military.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd39367ff-12f8-4c21-8a46-2d87ce9aed7e"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A means for assisting Nigeria, and as appropriate, Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram nations, to counter violent extremism, including efforts to address underlying societal factors shown to contribute to the ability of Boko Haram to radicalize and recruit individuals.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc549f88-e7c1-44c8-9ad1-aa944dca1afe"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to strengthen and promote the rule of law, including by improving the capacity of the civilian police and judicial system in Nigeria, enhancing public safety, and responding to crime (including gender-based violence), while respecting human rights and strengthening accountability measures, including measures to prevent corruption.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id157171ec-6eb6-40b5-a034-9ee86e31f688"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthen the long-term capacity of the Government of Nigeria to enhance security for schools such that children are safer and girls seeking an education are better protected, and to combat gender-based violence and gender inequality.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d2c7150-3eb5-48b4-8985-4f40df36a3a3"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify and develop mechanisms for coordinating the implementation of the strategy across the inter-agency and with the Government of Nigeria, regional partners, and other relevant foreign partners.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5605516f-82e3-4c77-b0ea-9b648057540f"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify the resources required to achieve the strategy’s objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id6DE045EBD0004C39A211E407DF23F99D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The Director of National Intelligence shall submit, to the appropriate committees of Congress, an assessment regarding—</text> <paragraph id="id8C9FD73D7C854E4E98C7EF24390CDA0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the willingness and capability of the Government of Nigeria and regional partners to implement the strategy developed under subsection (a), including the capability gaps, if any, of the Government and military forces of Nigeria that would need to be addressed to enable the Government of Nigeria and the governments of its partner countries in the region—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id5CA0754DA1A24618AC636250D7653823"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to counter the threat of Boko Haram; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD0DDFC3465E149258F7FBF52FEF7DCF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to address the legitimate grievances of vulnerable populations in areas affected by Boko Haram; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id7A20243AD6DF4345A903D697AF15DDE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>significant United States intelligence gaps concerning Boko Haram or on the willingness and capacity of the Government of Nigeria and regional partners to implement the strategy developed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC698178C9EF147EA98D57E44855F46BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that lack of economic opportunity and access to education, justice, and other social services contributes to the ability of Boko Haram to radicalize and recruit individuals.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb402d6c2-eb63-4b22-8179-5d092755e1d5"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f2dcd42-6cc3-4198-9455-c0e54882728a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8dc454ca-e71c-47e8-a7f8-248f242108e8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="Senate" date="20150922">Passed the Senate September 22, 2015.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Julie E. Adams,</attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

