<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S516 IS: Every Child Counts Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 516</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to permit alternate standards and
			 assessments for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Every Child Counts Act </short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idB3D5451C023343EC95D79C2E86CAA4A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternate standards and assessments for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1111 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id5F801D5BE2154C16814ADEF2C7ED21EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC07F85BBAEB349D2AB7ED11DF595C3CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="id86DD9841ED664EF4BE4DDF65CBF81F06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>The</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subparagraph (G), the</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3BAE44BFABE543709F529F8BE8FFE7C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4A8406E0795E4FD5B6850665A1048F91" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98321a64-7608-4703-aae1-6e896a850876"><enum>(G)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alternate academic achievement standards for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb28b4d4-11a7-49f4-9e9e-41ae5c10b397"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State may, through a documented and validated standards-setting process, adopt alternate academic achievement standards in any subject included in the State's accountability system under paragraph (2) for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities, if such alternate academic achievement standards—</text>
 <subclause id="idc11c99d0-aafe-415e-8f86-6e502c8cbe2e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are aligned with the State challenging academic content standards and challenging student academic achievement standards;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id6e1e86bc-d3ba-4790-82bf-de45ccb83b59"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide access to the general curriculum for the grade in which the student is enrolled;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idf55776a7b79a4708a02dca70ecaf1cae"><enum>(III)</enum><text>are vertically aligned to ensure that a student who achieves at the on-target or advanced level under subclause (VI) signifies that the student is on track to access a postsecondary education or achieve competitive integrated employment, as defined under section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/128">Public Law 113–128</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 1425);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id705f131ce6284d29829f8154b964b698"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>are supported by evidence-based learning progressions to age and grade-level performance;</text> </subclause><subclause id="idd6d338d8eb0545739fd2a459c084e0a8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>are designated in the individualized education program developed under section 614(d)(3) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act for each such student as the academic achievement standard that will be used for the student; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id7DD08392FD4D4CA4B6935FE6216F6088"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>establish, at a minimum—</text> <item id="ida23ee8ddb52d4d9c84c679ecba5c2bfe"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>2 levels of high achievement (on-target and advanced) that indicate that a student with the most significant cognitive disabilities meets or exceeds the State's proficient level of academic achievement under paragraph (2)(L) as measured by performance on alternate assessments under paragraph (3)(E); and</text>
 </item><item id="id12d335fd93ee4ff6a0ba82a188689f10"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a third level of achievement (catch-up) that provides information about the progress of a student with the most significant cognitive disabilities toward meeting the State's proficient level of academic achievement under paragraph (2)(L) as measured by performance on alternate assessments under paragraph (3)(E).</text>
										</item></subclause></clause><clause id="id4d5d7193-784c-4989-b843-708d50ad57c2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition on any
 other alternate or modified standards</header><text>A State shall not develop, or implement for use, under this part any alternate or modified academic achievement standards for students who are children with disabilities that are not alternate academic achievement standards that meet the requirements of clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id91D284B6C88444EEAD8D6CCB5DD3B0C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD411595FCD674F92BAA8A491653BF666" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0bf5a5bd-4a02-4566-a76b-fa200ee63a5a"><enum>(L)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Students with the most significant cognitive disabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the percentage of students meeting or exceeding the State's proficient level of academic achievement on the State assessments, a State educational agency may include, for all schools in the State, the performance of the State's students with the most significant cognitive disabilities on alternate assessments as described in paragraph (3)(E) in the subjects included in the State’s accountability system, consistent with the 1 percent limitation of paragraph (3)(E)(i).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4683BDC062F14B2E858042AC08FA4A6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37E8D31F64C541C8919B092ADB4486CA" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45b36b74-4403-48c7-a6f8-e0803fd2b8e5"><enum>(E)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alternate assessments for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may provide alternate assessments that are aligned with alternate academic achievement standards described in paragraph (1)(G) for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities, if the State—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffceba95-1a78-439c-ae03-5f131c95233d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensures that for each subject, the total number of students in each grade level assessed in such subject using the alternate assessments does not exceed 1 percent of the total number of all students in such grade level in the State who are assessed in such subject;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8D8732BC34434F9D8C19808F479BBAA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>certifies, consistent with section 612(a)(16)(A) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, that the State’s regular academic assessments are universally designed to be accessible to students, including students with sensory, physical, and intellectual disabilities, through the provision of accommodations that produce valid results; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90A001896DAA49BA82CE0342A85CF075"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensures that such alternate assessments are peer reviewed and based on the best available evidence.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id654CD35DDF7B47389FD3006B6D259E9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(1)(C)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id858FA215A3FF4F2397177D0B2B6929FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA82A89CD7B364E0E94FC868205305055"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (viii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB82BD6213C304E9AAD648337958E396D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1203D1661FE049ECA880DE09A4F6382B" style="OLC"> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92acaecf-e801-42a5-9a91-bb33f27bb531"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of students with disabilities who take an alternate assessment under subsection (b)(3)(E), by grade, subject, and type of disability, as outlined in section 602(3) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


