<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2019 IS: Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2019</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150909">September 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prohibit brand name drug companies from compensating  generic drug companies to delay the entry
			 of a generic drug into the market. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id6947cbf03ae243c291bff12f2cd73c01"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings and declaration of purposes</header>
 <subsection id="idc1bea8ea82f148e2af5b4001a0f4bfaa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="idff90a3e76c004c07abfff99e5e4e4f43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In 1984, the Drug Price Competition and Patent Term Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/417">Public Law 98–417</external-xref>) (referred to in this Act as the <quote>1984 Act</quote>), was enacted with the intent of facilitating the early entry of generic drugs while preserving incentives for innovation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9cc3a44ed88e4c29a732ca69d37fb12e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Prescription drugs make up approximately 10 percent of the national health care spending.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4a78f775b17647b184b7d683da479ae6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Until recently, the 1984 Act was successful in facilitating generic competition to the benefit of consumers and health care payers, although 86 percent of all prescriptions dispensed in the United States are generic drugs, they account for only 27 percent of all expenditures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id14b8498f7315440f88e87f78f101c64a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Generic drugs cost substantially less than brand name drugs, with discounts off the brand price averaging 80 to 85 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8ef6e6678e5b49ff8075f6f5b78cf126"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Federal dollars currently account for an estimated 38.6 percent of the $271,000,000,000 spent on prescription drugs, and this share is expected to rise to 47 percent by 2023.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1a5efc8c2a6644fca4da2d92ed72960a"><enum>(6)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD53981A15E4942769844A16C3457DAD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In recent years, the intent of the 1984 Act has been subverted by certain settlement agreements in which brand name companies transfer value to their potential generic competitors to settle claims that the generic company is infringing the branded company’s patents.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAEAB6C3B2CA940F9AECF4EAA2222008B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>These <quote>reverse payment</quote> settlement agreements—</text> <clause id="id032FA9A4B78C439A800F8CA0D6EFD654"><enum>(i)</enum><text>allow a branded company to share its monopoly profits with the generic company as a way to protect the branded company’s monopoly; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id618336436E694F02ACF9006435D40DC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have unduly delayed the marketing of low-cost generic drugs contrary to free competition, the interests of consumers, and the principles underlying antitrust law.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6C8C1743FD0A44219173586BFA41803D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Because of the price disparity between brand name and generic drugs, such agreements are more profitable for both the brand and generic manufacturers than competition and will become increasingly common unless prohibited.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2CDA8068306F48B7B41BF0FB3C26FAAB" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>These agreements result in consumers losing the benefits that the 1984 Act was intended to provide.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id05251ecada6744a98ebe435c8507d9ca"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text>
 <paragraph id="id78492cfbe9854dfa8b7a3ec6f1551d68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to enhance competition in the pharmaceutical market by stopping anticompetitive agreements between brand name and generic drug manufacturers that limit, delay, or otherwise prevent competition from generic drugs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id58922296775d42539fc75cd22f8fbe2f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support the purpose and intent of antitrust law by prohibiting anticompetitive practices in the pharmaceutical industry that harm consumers.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3be4fa7ea5d248acb67253dd4731616b"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unlawful compensation for delay</header>
 <subsection id="idDCE2EDA18DC249BF9ABF1E3C09DC96C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 26 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57c-2">15 U.S.C. 57c–2</external-xref>) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida419b06e6ec748448c2c87864ecb8334" style="OLC">
					<section id="id66464B1C7BC44E3A9CA7727877FC9456"><enum>27.</enum><header>Preserving access to affordable generics</header>
						<subsection id="id1f9c5b5a6ebe4458973bb58236f58449"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="id456760ce84554ba3981af2db37361fea"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement proceeding</header><text>The Commission may initiate a proceeding to enforce the provisions of this section against the parties to any agreement resolving or settling, on a final or interim basis, a patent infringement claim, in connection with the sale of a drug product.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="id375b6e78b07d40c2a0e31a89ee2b2de1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Presumption and violation</header>
 <subparagraph id="id2012a1f7676d4beaba80fddae8b0a57a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), in such a proceeding, an agreement shall be presumed to have anticompetitive effects and be a violation of this section if—</text>
 <clause id="idd9a7ba2dd37e4eca872efb642ab7f33f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an ANDA filer receives anything of value, including an exclusive license; and</text> </clause><clause id="id09c15b713c08419380fb77c7483b7284"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ANDA filer agrees to limit or forego research, development, manufacturing, marketing, or sales of the ANDA product for any period of time.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id710271a8291f42dc8126c574851c5a6e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the parties to such agreement demonstrate by clear and convincing evidence that—</text>
 <clause id="id19e926f9a3074ce78b66c86409c9417d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the value described in subparagraph (A)(i) is compensation solely for other goods or services that the ANDA filer has promised to provide; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc2fbfa0d9d274642846eb83b44ead585"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the procompetitive benefits of the agreement outweigh the anticompetitive effects of the agreement.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8a13370edf9849a69e7f4e430eca1117"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>In determining whether the settling parties have met their burden under subsection (a)(2)(B), the fact finder shall not presume—</text>
 <paragraph id="idde3e598c381f431299eb92f5c05bd933"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that entry would not have occurred until the expiration of the relevant patent or statutory exclusivity; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8d079f34463a497ea00cdb8d0e17355a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that the agreement’s provision for entry of the ANDA product prior to the expiration of the relevant patent or statutory exclusivity means that the agreement is procompetitive.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5e6b3637152b46c4afc3505b84271a85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Nothing in this section shall prohibit a resolution or settlement of a patent infringement claim in which the consideration granted by the NDA holder to the ANDA filer as part of the resolution or settlement includes only one or more of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id0eab7f8af80d4dbbb065c181c5f44fb3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The right to market the ANDA product in the United States prior to the expiration of—</text> <subparagraph id="idf4cb4139d0e54f70bac5176c668a636b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any patent that is the basis for the patent infringement claim; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c9ac31bf6f545ac9a69902efd5f3492"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any patent right or other statutory exclusivity that would prevent the marketing of such drug.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ed16d4c2b1447ef9b8af14b14237486"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A payment for reasonable litigation expenses not to exceed $7,500,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5697a834e62f4f8fbd38f3dbe461ac04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A covenant not to sue on any claim that the ANDA product infringes a United States patent.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf0ebcd7e5fdd45b59f53f7ad39a18028"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="id913d42ac37f54a489193913b7e8880b5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>A violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of section 5.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="idee3e5a92ddd14a2491e54bed44ac18d6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Judicial review</header>
 <subparagraph id="idd6d5e40f9f01464dae0c0d8b1f588601"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any party that is subject to a final order of the Commission, issued in an administrative adjudicative proceeding under the authority of subsection (a)(1), may, within 30 days of the issuance of such order, petition for review of such order in—</text>
 <clause id="idf37a0696c74340b19410070437d17525"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit;</text> </clause><clause id="iddf382d4d3ff244fc9795af0b3a4e5734"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the ultimate parent entity, as defined in section 801.1(a)(3) of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto, of the NDA holder is incorporated as of the date that the NDA is filed with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc80cf83943b84ee597ff37356ae300f1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the ultimate parent entity of the ANDA filer is incorporated as of the date that the ANDA is filed with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfacdd383158340e380e65a81797188ab"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of findings</header><text>In a proceeding for judicial review of a final order of the Commission, the findings of the Commission as to the facts, if supported by evidence, shall be conclusive.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4376d736a19840c1b209f69c50e63b86"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify, impair, or supersede the applicability of the antitrust laws as defined in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12(a)</external-xref>), and of section 5 of this Act to the extent that section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition. Nothing in this section shall modify, impair, limit, or supersede the right of an ANDA filer to assert claims or counterclaims against any person, under the antitrust laws or other laws relating to unfair competition.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="id5a6f29e6cac942b5986c26cb640426ae"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <paragraph id="id592a3a07f96444efb332c07bc94d6155"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header><text>Each party that violates or assists in the violation of this section shall forfeit and pay to the United States a civil penalty sufficient to deter violations of this section, but in no event greater than 3 times the value received by the party that is reasonably attributable to the violation of this section. If no such value has been received by the NDA holder, the penalty to the NDA holder shall be sufficient to deter violations, but in no event greater than 3 times the value given to the ANDA filer reasonably attributable to the violation of this section. Such penalty shall accrue to the United States and may be recovered in a civil action brought by the Commission, in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, in a district court of the United States against any party that violates this section. In such actions, the United States district courts are empowered to grant mandatory injunctions and such other and further equitable relief as they deem appropriate.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="id8fe857913bf749b1b27f0197731e91ef"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cease and desist</header>
 <subparagraph id="id00f050c31bf54ea3b905a459c9a9808c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Commission has issued a cease and desist order with respect to a party in an administrative adjudicative proceeding under the authority of subsection (a)(1), an action brought pursuant to paragraph (1) may be commenced against such party at any time before the expiration of 1 year after such order becomes final pursuant to section 5(g).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb4314ad13b864b3aa7355d9593d14956"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In an action under subparagraph (A), the findings of the Commission as to the material facts in the administrative adjudicative proceeding with respect to the violation of this section by a party shall be conclusive unless—</text>
 <clause id="id3f3aa1088a1343df8bf83c033076db75"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the terms of such cease and desist order expressly provide that the Commission’s findings shall not be conclusive; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf2e9f0314f9249168e799c9e4145ed24"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the order became final by reason of section 5(g)(1), in which case such finding shall be conclusive if supported by evidence.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d2c1a9d532841de9f5d1ca8e3878f36"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>In determining the amount of the civil penalty described in this section, the court shall take into account—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id440c47c4b7ec4a59a294fe4a0a52a81b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57015c6ceb37418a9a7cfb86b2e0b129"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of violations, the ability to pay, any effect on the ability to continue doing business, profits earned by the NDA holder, compensation received by the ANDA filer, and the amount of commerce affected; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95de8d5e70f04b06851fde5575d7d2b4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other matters that justice requires.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf825ceaecfb4dc4ac5d6526ef5ae468"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Remedies in addition</header><text>Remedies provided in this subsection are in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other remedy provided by Federal law. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to affect any authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida302a6989ae2447fb643c9d0153142f6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id75ae50e91a84433a9834faffb4d1fb47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>The term <term>agreement</term> means anything that would constitute an agreement under section 1 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>) or section 5 of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbacdc9f94b46472cb79f8f981df3ddd0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agreement resolving or settling a patent infringement claim</header><text>The term <term>agreement resolving or settling a patent infringement claim</term> includes any agreement that is entered into within 30 days of the resolution or the settlement of the claim, or any other agreement that is contingent upon, provides a contingent condition for, or is otherwise related to the resolution or settlement of the claim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1a2edb50df9642fdb361662acf270f2b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>ANDA</header><text>The term <term>ANDA</term> means an abbreviated new drug application filed under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)</external-xref>) or a new drug application filed under section 505(b)(2) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc6fb0aca67ce4a82b60897a23ad695ec"><enum>(4)</enum><header>ANDA filer</header><text>The term <term>ANDA filer</term> means a party that owns or controls an ANDA filed with the Commission of Food and Drugs or has the exclusive rights under such ANDA to distribute the ANDA product.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc99e97004fa4409cb081219548d47cbf"><enum>(5)</enum><header>ANDA product</header><text>The term <term>ANDA product</term> means the product to be manufactured under the ANDA that is the subject of the patent infringement claim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1ecfacb5a59c4eb8ad96782a3407dac4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Drug product</header><text>The term <term>drug product</term> has the meaning given such term in section 314.3(b) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id08e7214c41004e1fb8172e60682d0d98"><enum>(7)</enum><header>NDA</header><text>The term <term>NDA</term> means a new drug application filed under section 505(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id07f5075b59b74ae399639ababc6da88e"><enum>(8)</enum><header>NDA holder</header><text>The term <term>NDA holder</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id3cf8f45382d346b19ffbe2bf8630f39c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the holder of an approved NDA application for a drug product;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2bd5109c972041aa810c343bf57803cd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person owning or controlling enforcement of the patent listed in the Approved Drug Products With Therapeutic Equivalence Evaluations (commonly known as the <quote>FDA Orange Book</quote>) in connection with the NDA; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide76ef68a819e46f0981ddd5626fcbd12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the predecessors, subsidiaries, divisions, groups, and affiliates controlled by, controlling, or under common control with any of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) (such control to be presumed by direct or indirect share ownership of 50 percent or greater), as well as the licensees, licensors, successors, and assigns of each of the entities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id834d27e96de44673bf5e6d7878b42fe9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Party</header><text>The term <term>party</term> means any person, partnership, corporation, or other legal entity.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8c559f48785f46cc98af23a4baf9f305"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Patent infringement</header><text>The term <term>patent infringement</term> means infringement of any patent or of any filed patent application, extension, reissue, renewal, division, continuation, continuation in part, reexamination, patent term restoration, patents of addition, and extensions thereof.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1ef89b6c5082427db025fc768a88ad6e"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Patent infringement claim</header><text>The term <term>patent infringement claim</term> means any allegation made to an ANDA filer, whether or not included in a complaint filed with a court of law, that its ANDA or ANDA product may infringe any patent held by, or exclusively licensed to, the NDA holder of the drug product.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc26dcab4782344f0bb52e6e735378a75"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Statutory exclusivity</header><text>The term <term>statutory exclusivity</term> means those prohibitions on the approval of drug applications under clauses (ii) through (iv) of section 505(c)(3)(E) (5- and 3-year data exclusivity), section 527 (orphan drug exclusivity), or section 505A (pediatric exclusivity) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(c)(3)(E)</external-xref>, 360cc, 355a).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69d48caa01fb4dcfa28f7d258bb5e8e9"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 27 of the Federal Trade Commission Act, as added by this section, shall apply to all agreements described in section 27(a)(1) of that Act entered into after June 17, 2013. Section 27(f) of the Federal Trade Commission Act, as added by this section, shall apply to agreements entered into on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idf10cb52f57a9484695dfc6b0514c1866"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notice and certification of agreements</header>
 <subsection id="ida864af6422e3415db846ad5f63b7bf5d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice of all agreements</header><text>Section 1112(c)(2) of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref> note) is amended by—</text>
 <paragraph id="id416722e5613e4bdd9fc383f5b9207c2f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>striking <quote>the Commission the</quote> and inserting the following: “the Commission—</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id107C44E7D58C4359BA3C5878754ADD71" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idf75f304183c54f4d8e069bc3c2728303"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9ac73356595e406a875380baee644621"><enum>(2)</enum><text>striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f8bceb53c9c4368a3b103c183a30505"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inserting at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd649e6674a1045e0a14d2f2eec15b828" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id350c6affb2d8445aaf6714057b793284"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other agreement the parties enter into within 30 days of entering into an agreement covered by subsection (a) or (b).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id88dd056d68bf43b796057ef209d69077"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification of agreements</header><text>Section 1112 of such Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide68e0551516c475ca5386b9f8899e829" style="OLC"> <subsection id="ide26e4889f45b4bbb9b411e2800399783"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer or the company official responsible for negotiating any agreement under subsection (a) or (b) that is required to be filed under subsection (c) shall execute and file with the Assistant Attorney General and the Commission a certification as follows: ‘I declare that the following is true, correct, and complete to the best of my knowledge: The materials filed with the Federal Trade Commission and the Department of Justice under section 1112 of subtitle B of title XI of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, with respect to the agreement referenced in this certification—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6FCB13630A2D4C71AF4A6F6FBE36B091"><enum>(1)</enum><text>represent the complete, final, and exclusive agreement between the parties;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9D1EFBFC79EF481582C435587FA1D93C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include any ancillary agreements that are contingent upon, provide a contingent condition for, or are otherwise related to, the referenced agreement; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9E378CEC73C3416D96839A9C69079F5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include written descriptions of any oral agreements, representations, commitments, or promises between the parties that are responsive to subsection (a) or (b) of such section 1112 and have not been reduced to writing.’.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="id11580cf3aee744278cf3557a2db68baa"><enum>5.</enum><header>Forfeiture of 180-day exclusivity period</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 505(j)(5)(D)(i)(V) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)(5)(D)(i)(V)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>section 27 of the Federal Trade Commission Act or</quote> after <quote>that the agreement has violated</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idca349ac17bb3404eabfca15423833298"><enum>6.</enum><header>Commission litigation authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 16(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/56">15 U.S.C. 56(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idfb4b87b147694ff9973017436605a207"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id218b82b69df140229d9218f35b65ca1b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ida390c602e9c340819610d2ff1a09aa41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inserting after subparagraph (E) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac68614a8232418f8ae1285b6b8b18e5" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="idfcd12725f01643579ca91675695f0edf"><enum>(F)</enum><text>under section 27;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="id7eb5b413cef34a759943a2b34968fe91"><enum>7.</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall commence any enforcement proceeding described in section 27 of the Federal Trade Commission Act, as added by section 3, except for an action described in section 27(f)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act, not later than 6 years after the date on which the parties to the agreement file the Notice of Agreement as provided by sections 1112(c)(2) and (d) of the Medicare Prescription Drug Improvement and Modernization Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref> note).</text>
 </section><section id="id31490481b6034653afeb60b347c8c6ec"><enum>8.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and the application of the provisions of such Act or amendments to any person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


