<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1733 IS: Forest Incentives Program Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1733</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150709">July 9, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a forest incentives program to keep
			 forests intact and sequester carbon on private forest land of the United
			 States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id49CEDD2E088C4797A6BDF70F534E1E3D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Forest Incentives Program Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idA42F7266F06346F3B9F1BDCF423802F8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="idc287c6f3af60476ca90bf8788d5592c1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>public and private forest land in the United States plays a crucial role in sequestering carbon and otherwise contributes to mitigation of greenhouse gas emissions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id69F4F3A79342484A8116A760216773FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency has reported in the annual greenhouse gas inventory that United States forests and forest products sequester as much as 12 to 14 percent of annual United States carbon emissions, which makes forests one of the largest carbon sinks in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida1a01eb7a6ec491aa96147ed6447a11d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>according to the Environmental Protection Agency, carbon sequestration from forests and other land uses has grown by approximately 14 percent since 1990, largely as a result of afforestation and improved forest management;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id26cb71b303cf44cd85a1c650a2a601e7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the use of forests products, such as wood products, in buildings and biobased products can also reduce carbon emissions when used in place of other, more carbon-intensive products;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida610885fc2d14bc6b144f9a0e026abbf"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9AFAEC91FFD9477E8A9F786736C7B3A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in addition to the significant carbon mitigation benefits of using forests and forest products for carbon sequestration, the economic and societal cobenefits of forest carbon solutions are extraordinarily valuable; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04133C064D46443EADA9980E32FF27E8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incentivizing forest carbon activities, including through working forests, has the potential to provide timber and other forest commodities, improve air quality, enhance watershed function and water supply, create and sustain fish and wildlife habitat, contribute to scenic and aesthetic qualities, support historical and cultural resources, provide hunting, fishing, and recreational opportunities, and increase forest resiliency, while also supporting rural jobs and local economies;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id677da4e94d40449b8ea576cf7370b566"><enum>(6)</enum><text>despite positive recent trends in forest carbon, as documented by the annual greenhouse gas inventory of the Environmental Protection Agency, projections of the Forest Service indicate those forest carbon and other benefits are at risk in future decades due to development pressures and other factors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2dc29735a57c4127b172ca1361647a44"><enum>(7)</enum><text>while the majority of the productive forest land of the United States is under private ownership, private landowners are facing increased pressure to convert their forest land to other uses;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2345147bc2ca4f6d8866a196e0454d27"><enum>(8)</enum><text>while some landowners are able to participate in various carbon markets, the transaction costs and restrictions of those programs are often prohibitive for private landowners, particularly smallholders; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id183570012f4c471fbcb0eea85b807c6f"><enum>(9)</enum><text>creating incentives for private forest landowners to adopt best practices to maintain and increase carbon benefits from forest land through a streamlined program that avoids excessive transaction costs will help <quote>keep forests as forests</quote> and enhance forest carbon benefits by providing incentive payments for a suite of eligible practices throughout the lifecycle of forest management, including forest products that provide long-term carbon storage benefits.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id041ED3D7588C47408D942E5326A5C61D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Forest incentives program</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90D52D4B52544CD99F57F8E06F281373"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58F5FE6029CB40EB85D537E93A7F4E1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Carbon incentives contract; contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>carbon incentives contract</term> or <term>contract</term> means a 15- to 30-year contract that specifies—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62DE97CF5DB148D8AB103DA3C3349898"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the eligible practices that will be undertaken;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8A16A1881CA04CB6916400167ED90A38"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the acreage of eligible land on which the practices will be undertaken;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12D2E60D100347149D2DA30A3881485D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agreed rate of compensation per acre;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5D927542A3EA4C43BEE41F2A1E5E3818"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a schedule to verify that the terms of the contract have been fulfilled; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD0230E626B884025968F0A466A5DA644"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other terms as are determined necessary by the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7E88F008B4D4C72948C7A1863F05549"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conservation easement agreement; agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>conservation easement agreement</term> or <term>agreement</term> means a permanent conservation easement that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC2DEAA53211D4B428BE38D7D0123397C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covers eligible land that will not be converted for development;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD41AC2BD122F4A709B508E2655FA4737"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is enrolled under a carbon incentives contract; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8D4FD8F28E19495CAD3574F284D5D61C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is consistent with the guidelines for—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56DA93885A9A4ADE90A7D71FC564A5FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Forest Legacy Program established under section 7 of the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2103c">16 U.S.C. 2103c</external-xref>), subject to the condition that an eligible practice shall be considered to be a conservation value for purposes of such consistency; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9E7A81222C1542119904BB489406DDC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other program approved by the Secretary for use under this section to provide consistency with Federal legal requirements for permanent conservation easements.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EFC244112294FDC9468D7E1633F53C7"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible land</term> means forest land in the United States that is privately owned at the time of initiation of a carbon incentives contract or conservation easement agreement.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID386044e65dcd4130a61286cc50abc81e"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible practice</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13A49442D80945FB878AE71253B42167"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible practice</term> means a forestry practice, including improved forest management that produces marketable forest products, that is determined by the Secretary to provide measurable increases in carbon sequestration and storage beyond customary practices on comparable land.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idebf149e9063142dbb41e7fd4e0ba51fe"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>eligible practice</term> includes—</text> <clause id="id01e7f6ffb3cd4f5899dcaa11516a2778"><enum>(i)</enum><text>afforestation on nonforested land, such as marginal crop or pasture land, windbreaks, shelterbelts, stream buffers, including working land and urban forests and parks, or other areas identified by the Secretary;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id89a56eadc6b544378c28af673ea940e8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reforestation on forest land impacted by wildfire, pests, wind, or other stresses, including working land and urban forests and parks;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3887c71943eb4cfe8bf615bd938884c2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improved forest management through practices such as improving regeneration after harvest, planting in understocked forests, reducing competition from slow-growing species, thinning to encourage growth, changing rotations to increase carbon storage, improving harvest efficiency or wood use; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id88A394D6263E4E4C8E1448C7EA74DB69"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such other practices as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8817B22A7E747E297F228F10C33059A"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Forest incentives program; program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>forest incentives program</term> or <term>program</term> means the forest incentives program established under subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A2EBFCDD777452EA786746A494633A3"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F9CE2C5F1EB4028B55F96FB7AC21BC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions in United States</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07BCFB8B924943A092E4328E5AAC8694"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a forest incentives program to achieve supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions and carbon sequestration on private forest land of the United States through—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57350AF5E6C649869F7D9AA90AFBF8A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carbon incentives contracts; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC7D2FC9992C74AAA864BA6E2B8316BC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conservation easement agreements.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9B76212648DF413D99F80685B3BF616A"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting projects under this subsection, the Secretary shall provide a priority for contracts and agreements—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id700DDAF921234CF88A6BE5C97EA4A424"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that sequester the most carbon on a per acre basis; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF0B03AA36CA54DF6A96BE37A5DAB6DB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that create forestry jobs or protect habitats and achieve significant other environmental, economic, and social benefits.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID21f07ff372624c91a895075e54bb0d77"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligibility</header>
 <subparagraph id="idbbcc3c094bf44f0f8137a684cb1501a7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To participate in the program, an owner of eligible land shall—</text> <clause id="idFB46F754644C4586952E6DFBAD4149CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enter into a carbon incentives contract; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFF8780F631034A3F9B8878541E383F1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fulfill such other requirements as the Secretary determines to be necessary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45966DAC19E74A6AA8DDB3CA5846884A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Continued eligible practices</header><text>An owner of eligible land who has been carrying out eligible practices on the eligible land shall not be barred from entering into a carbon incentives contract under this subsection to continue carrying out the eligible practices on the eligible land.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ED5E10793C04B309F68C0A138127E92"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration of contract</header><text>A contract shall be for a term of not less than 15 nor more than 30 years, as determined by the owner of eligible land.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF7F165C5BB144E0CB2F0CF77885F87E7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Compensation under contract</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the rate of compensation per acre under the contract so that the longer the term of the contract, the higher rate of compensation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0C9C11DDAB51412EAD3A99CB55B6170D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Relationship to other programs</header><text>An owner or operator shall not be prohibited from participating in the program due to participation of the owner or operator in other Federal or State conservation assistance programs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDe8f0b02197c54dc790a14c2d66ae55b5"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing regulations for carbon incentives contracts under this subsection, the Secretary shall specify requirements to address whether the owner of eligible land has completed contract and agreement requirements.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C93844B7B82486BA40A5AC45370B3A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Incentive payments</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78CE155DC5934F259D4C1CEE2575DFBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to owners of eligible land financial incentive payments for—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID9fcb7db74696443695a3f4055ea5d92e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligible practices that measurably increase carbon sequestration and storage over a designated period on eligible land, as specified through a carbon incentives contract; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID5a8ac1aee1d34b9f9228d257e06f1ae7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to paragraph (2), conservation easements on eligible land covered under a conservation easement agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1fe1246c5327454e8ef66a9ef5c18dbf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the amount of compensation to be provided under a contract under this subsection based on the emissions reductions obtained or avoided and the duration of the reductions, with due consideration to prevailing carbon pricing as determined by any relevant or State compliance offset programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA4C5572ACA014A09ADE4ADCEA154CC93"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">No conservation easement agreement required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligibility for financial incentive payments under a carbon incentives contract described in paragraph (1)(A) shall not require a conservation easement agreement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02651E59380B4AACBA72C0DEFAAD3AA2"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue regulations that specify eligible practices and related compensation rates, standards, and guidelines as the basis for entering into the program with owners of eligible land.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4971FD7C616943408DE90DEBEA06C7C1"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Set-Aside of funds for certain
			 purposes</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88BAD2E60F0E4E1296E29BC964D99BFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the discretion of the Secretary, a portion of program funds made available under this program for a fiscal year may be used—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID73f435a5ae914cdab7a69201b86e1acd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop forest carbon modeling and methodologies that will improve the projection of carbon gains for any forest practices made eligible under the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H812D83908CEC48C3A8AA88D286C8BC53"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide additional incentive payments for specified management activities that increase the adaptive capacity of land under a carbon incentives contract; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBABFF6D8B3DF423B803BAFAD5334ACEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the Forest Inventory and Analysis Program of the Forest Service to develop improved measurement and monitoring of forest carbon stocks.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE4C176970664255BBAB60873B638005"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the program, the Secretary shall provide that funds provided under this section shall not be substituted for, or otherwise used as a basis for reducing, funding authorized or appropriated under other programs to compensate owners of eligible land for activities that are not covered under the program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB9ECBBF90254F59AE57034D7439BEB7"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program measurement, monitoring,
			 verification, and reporting</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BA83096B9E34927A7C61B1DCBD2A8E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Measurement, monitoring, and
 verification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and implement protocols that provide monitoring and verification of compliance with the terms of contracts and agreements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14F71488D81C451282BAB636BE4C78FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least annually, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that contains—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77FE771BF1AC45E58177288A916EDD7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of annual and cumulative reductions achieved as a result of the program, determined using standardized measures, including measures of economic efficiency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88363C2A2D8C4A10A48C250E0B99F4E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of any changes to the program that will be made as a result of program measurement, monitoring, and verification;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id389d433648684d13a0c9c7da741601f3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total number of acres enrolled in the program by method; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDD07BFF5514345C49897C1D5C36FC4C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a State-by-State summary of the data.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99F48EC25D154290A6EDCC14EEF276CB"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Availability of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required by this subsection shall be available to the public through the website of the Department of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDe194bc47d6294d0eb11272d9c2d97c47"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least once every 2 years the Secretary shall adjust eligible practices and compensation rates for future carbon incentives contracts based on the results of monitoring under paragraph (1) and reporting under paragraph (2), if determined necessary by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id992c3e085fbf46ec83d1dbd69881a5ec"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Estimating carbon benefits</header><text>Any modeling, methodology, or protocol resource developed under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="id93DCABAC3690425CA72CD1EA68BA589C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be suitable for estimating carbon benefits associated with eligible practices for the purpose of incentives under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42B6908E080B4D69A23F12A7E22CEE11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be used for netting by States or emission sources under Federal programs relating to carbon emissions.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5034313588E400991B1A6124C5CEF40"><enum>(g)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of
 appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as are necessary.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idfdfdba5ba67745508174530bcee3a39b"><enum>4.</enum><header>Material choices in buildings for supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions in United States</header>
 <subsection id="id96f6d73992da4162a1fd8a83e20363d9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idaad638664a60495e8c7a949438392eb6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible building</header><text>The term <term>eligible building</term> means a nonresidential building used for commercial or State or local government purposes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf6cb9c8584df4dcdb82f3c4ee8ad18bf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible product</header><text>The term <term>eligible product</term> means a commercial or industrial product, such as an intermediate, feedstock, or end product (other than food or feed), that is composed in whole or in part of biological products, including renewable agricultural and forestry materials used as structural building material.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id36d2693eec4d498d9bb0a92d6c2821fb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the greenhouse gas incentives program established under this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc632277dc69148c994054c29a0fc4b4f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4de981b355174ac88d6bfc3ecb5d2f55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions in buildings</header>
 <paragraph id="id0c27b6ae0e8c4626873d3a715da3cd7e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a greenhouse gas incentives program to achieve supplemental greenhouse gas emission reductions from material choices in buildings, based on the lifecycle assessment of the building materials.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc928f6981a5340feae4a2da027800e65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial incentive payments</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to owners of eligible buildings incentive payments for the use of eligible products in buildings for sequestering carbon based on a lifecycle assessment of the structural assemblies, as compared to a model building as a result of using eligible products in substitution for more energy-intensive materials in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc890bdf9bf89496db3d3aada901036f6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>new construction; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id004bd674cf95490fb8d252d8488804bb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>building renovation.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide22b7ce336934d0880105ff3d1393ce4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="id3b4cf09c10ca4dd79ce0584b53241762"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to participate in the program, the owner of an eligible building shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id66ea71f6c6704b23accf4a6235563006"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Components</header><text>In establishing the program, the Secretary shall require that payments for activities under the program shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6A8C58EAFF7B4ED48FCCA99D4F479D7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>established at a rate not to exceed the net estimated benefit an owner of an eligible building would receive for similar practices under any federally established carbon offset program, taking into consideration the costs associated with the issuance of credits and compliance with reversal provisions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1188a13f14d641b49d5e19f6f74754a6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provided to owners of eligible buildings demonstrating at least a 20-percent reduction in carbon emissions potential, based on a lifecycle assessment of the structural assemblies, as compared to the structural assemblies of a model building, subject to the requirements that—</text>
 <clause id="id37cfdc56371c4fdb8dfbf41bfbbbeea8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary shall identify a model baseline nonresidential building—</text> <subclause id="id71C696349B6E4EC7AA33090139982D55"><enum>(I)</enum><text>of common size and function; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id50C6D992E8A748CFBCEBED4E17944BD5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>having a service life of not less than 60 years; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id3f594f53bb694fe2a50cd7ade76cf54f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>applicants shall evaluate the carbon emissions potential of the baseline building and the proposed building using the same lifecycle assessment software tool and data sets, which shall be compliant with the document numbered ISO 14044; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4682b594dbf34bc98078f8e4a35d2f27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provided on certification by the owner of an eligible building and verification by the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Energy, that—</text>
 <clause id="id1A629B8CDAE247F3BDF6A0F2367478E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the eligible building meets the requirements of the applicable State commercial building energy efficiency code (as in effect on the date of the applicable permit of the eligible building); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id10433CE6448943608DEE896F3B597A14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the State has made the certification required pursuant to section 304 of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6833">42 U.S.C. 6833</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id88c4645f5d284ea5a99f816abb6f3009"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incentive payments</header><text>A participant in the program shall receive payment under the program on completion of construction or renovation of the applicable eligible building.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6da449b35f684e28b3753efc6a251169"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that contains—</text>
 <paragraph id="id91d3880a20a4479eab392f1f1bd648b4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an estimate of annual and cumulative reductions achieved as a result of the program—</text> <subparagraph id="idD85BE53B96A9467E84F3B21F38231188"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determined by using lifecycle assessment software that is compliant with the document numbered ISO 14044; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF3FA6679E3E843708836BC3D8F94084F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expressed in terms of the total number of cars removed from the road;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2ffae2168c64cc6b694e168b7213a02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of any changes to the program that will be made as a result of past implementation of the program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idde746e98cc8d49df850e8ec9b0e9133b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total number of buildings under carbon incentives contracts as of the date of the report.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC1B6A1A594FA454A8020F71A80F24F20"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Analytical requirements</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="id672f8ec1bf3045a6b6bf83fd3005f3fe"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any carbon emissions potential calculation shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id5C620E8CB1BF473EBD292652B2DC22B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be performed in accordance with standard lifecycle assessment practice; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6EF46A0756634E5BBFC4FDCCB966F9D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include removal and sequestration of carbon dioxide from the use of biobased products, as well as recycled content materials;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9dfdd2cc711947c8911d080994bbe85c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a full lifecycle assessment shall be conducted taking into consideration all lifecycle stages, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idFE75BB5A31324661ABDAE1AF0B3613EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resource extraction and processing;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id205CE703651F423981F64F5DAB2368B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>product manufacturing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4E434103331944E388FC6B8D497FB645"><enum>(C)</enum><text>onsite construction of assemblies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idED325B49032345E19B0A440ABB4BB8C7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transportation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE02D4BB277CB402DA627836A73425F2B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>maintenance and replacement cycles over an assumed eligible building service life of 60 years; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD71E50D3219A4742AA55AEC864D87180"><enum>(F)</enum><text>demolition;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1a6e88adf36480e828039d8a974e799"><enum>(3)</enum><text>structural assemblies shall be considered to include columns, beams, girders, purlins, floor deck, roof, and structural envelope elements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf6bb9488a334452b957e43d50da285a3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>primary materials shall be considered to include common products used as the structural system, such as wood, steel, concrete, or masonry; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ebc92bba32240bc87438ee1c3dced69"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the effects of recycling, reuse, or energy recovery beyond the boundaries of an applicable study system shall not be taken in account.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf17cdd0e3c184994a3ec559eb4a27324"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

