<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S704 IS: Community Based Independence for Seniors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 704</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150311">March 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a Community-Based Institutional Special Needs Plan demonstration program to target
			 home and community-based care to eligible Medicare beneficiaries.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Based Independence for Seniors Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id3e5fa303f66d46c798013d3678dcb649"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="id2160f0ff2f194df2bdf07d9c9708b731"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Community-based services play an essential role in keeping individuals healthy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb8ca7a6e6aa24f44bccfa93fba4dccbc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Without community-based long-term services and supports, which are not typically covered by Medicare, seniors frequently experience negative health outcomes and lose their ability to live independently.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida2685a3a17a0452995dcdad020d5fd7d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Seniors who deplete their resources often have no option but to turn to Medicaid for coverage of long-term care expenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida136df4f68a14560ad9c656f9a6ce8a8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Targeting community-based services and supports to at-risk seniors can help these individuals avoid depleting their assets and becoming Medicaid dependent.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id79793c7adb8b423a878da04d45fe4ecb"><enum>3.</enum><header>Community-based institutional special needs plan demonstration</header>
 <subsection id="ida272a5ffe86a482ebd78e6cab950ae87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a Community-Based Institutional Special Needs Plan demonstration program (in this section referred to as the <quote>CBI-SNP demonstration program</quote>) to target home and community-based care to eligible Medicare beneficiaries.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id0df5960c4e0b425da0c487a3a669e984"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="id2373a825b30a4c9eaa80523bad3191ac"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into agreements with up to 5 Medicare Advantage plans to conduct the CBI-SNP demonstration program. Each such MA plan may enroll up to 1,000 eligible Medicare beneficiaries (including new enrollees) in such program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF2D5B5F70BA940C8844204E7DB8967E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Benefits</header><text>Under the CBI-SNP demonstration program, eligible Medicare beneficiaries shall receive benefits, in addition to those under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (including benefits under section 1852(a)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w22">42 U.S.C. 1395w22(a)(3)</external-xref>)) and notwithstanding any waivers under section 1915(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396n">42 U.S.C. 1396n(c)</external-xref>), including long-term care services and supports, that the Secretary determines appropriate for the purposes of the CBI-SNP demonstration program, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id59b237d7b7c54508adbdbf8ded0350c2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>homemaker services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43cd55d9c8f34562a984160eaf23eaf9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>home delivered meals;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id687000aa835b426f9265d30af082f8d3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transportation services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7170d00b8aa841f691c6e56a6212530b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>respite care;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide682f7ac67f8456b8a03bd00d3fb6311"><enum>(E)</enum><text>adult day care services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddbb4f9e4260345d49ce316b488d6ba09"><enum>(F)</enum><text>non-Medicare-covered safety and other equipment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc01f953785a74605ab44e32ad8f5539c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payments</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a benchmark payment amount for reimbursing Medicare Advantage plans participating in the CBI-SNP demonstration program for benefits provided to eligible beneficiaries under such program. Such payments shall be in addition to payments made to such plans under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc0420659d2fd449a9f848f01b00edca1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible plans</header><text>To be eligible to participate in the CBI-SNP demonstration program, a Medicare Advantage plan must—</text> <paragraph id="id591ff00c95794352a74c19dfa1e01b2a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have experience in offering special needs plans for nursing home-eligible, non-institutionalized Medicare beneficiaries who live in the community;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd32a09a1ce5e4f91a0d3c8da5454c216"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have experience working with low income seniors groups;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id968173aef7c842d1ad5f0a9fe0660d6d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be located in a State that the Secretary has determined will participate in the CBI-SNP demonstration program by agreeing to make available data necessary for purposes of conducting the independent evaluation required under subsection (h); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id831c68b115ea43feb6cbebe4bdbdf86b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>meet such other criteria as the Secretary may require.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida0c2f120e97e4dabb59b3ce2b2789cb7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible Medicare beneficiary defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible Medicare beneficiary</term> means a Medicare beneficiary who—</text>
 <paragraph id="ided0daf327b4c48c2a2dc444396f2916f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is enrolled or eligible to enroll in a Medicare Advantage plan that has been selected to participate in the CBI-SNP demonstration program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6bd558a42dde499cbe11421b65ecda6a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is a subsidy eligible individual (as defined in section 1860D–14(a)(3)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w114">42 U.S.C. 1395w114(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3f9d649368b44f1cb289ded1487d4439"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is not eligible to receive benefits under title XIX of the Social Security Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idb0e26c2216ad4d1196c3791d46df71fc"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is unable to perform 2 or more activities of daily living (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7702B">section 7702B(c)(2)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id748d98bc335a4022b055cea92bb1e9e3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is age 65 or older.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idf7f4d0cd2ae344f9b48a585675aa9c4d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special election period</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 1852(e)(2)(C) and 1860D–1(b)(1)(B)(iii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-21">42 U.S.C. 1395w–21(e)(2)(C)</external-xref>; 1395w–101(b)(1)(B)(iii)), an eligible Medicare beneficiary may, other than during the annual, coordinated election periods under such sections—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide83b7a6024a94d92b660ecd280516a15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>discontinue enrollment in a Medicare Advantage plan not participating in the CBI-SNP demonstration program and enroll in a Medicare Advantage plan participating in such program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3291FF283FDE44D3B66C4E6503FE0E6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>discontinue enrollment under the original medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B of such title and the enrollment in a prescription drug plan under part D of such title and enroll in a Medicare Advantage plan participating in the CBI-SNP demonstration program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcc3df213bb97436b8612c904bac272e6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Beneficiary education</header><text>The Secretary shall help to educate eligible Medicare beneficiaries on the availability of the CBI-SNP demonstration program through State Health Insurance Assistance Programs and other organizations dedicated to assisting seniors with Medicare benefits and enrollment.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idfcce2e56fe354560bf077eef38d7af9d"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Implementation</header>
 <paragraph id="idC4C5C918B65E40D89A85DB5DD1023252"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The CBI-SNP demonstration program shall be implemented not later than January 1, 2017.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0BDAAB49B4044B218B67C11C5926A0BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), the CBI-SNP demonstration program shall be conducted for a period of 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb0079147870640e3ac3b94f3a761cdbb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension or expansion</header><text>Taking into account the report under subsection (h)(2), the Secretary may, through rulemaking, expand (including implementation on a nationwide or permanent basis) the duration or the scope CBI-SNP demonstration program to the extent determined appropriate by the Secretary, unless the Secretary determines that such expansion is expected to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5b622106173c4556ae759a97ce9d0233"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase expenditures under titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act with respect to eligible Medicare beneficiaries participating in the CBI-SNP demonstration program; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58aba6164914479e8344b601c757fbf5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>decrease the quality of health care services furnished to eligible Medicare beneficiaries participating in the CBI-SNP demonstration program.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcee60c64a1c5402ea1922d59fa603fb6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Independent evaluation and reports</header>
 <paragraph id="idfc523acc01154981b72eba68d4429960"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Independent evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for the evaluation of the CBI-SNP demonstration program by an independent third party. Such evaluation shall be completed using evaluation criteria that are clearly articulated prior to the implementation of such program. Such criteria shall include specific goals of such program, hypotheses being tested, clear data collection and reporting requirements, recognizing that definitions, benefits and program requirements for long-term care services and supports vary across States. Such evaluation shall determine whether the CBI-SNP demonstration program has—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb294baa739654c479e45145c6ebb12a6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improved patient care;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id395ef278e4c8409baea970c485c9a0bb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduced hospitalizations or rehospitalizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7d76384cc2c4bfe9984ad8806cad328"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduced or delayed Medicaid nursing facility admissions and lengths of stay;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00d580cadf764668a5c4bd94443fdae4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reduced spend down of income and assets for purposes of becoming eligible for Medicaid; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe53123342914c2d8348c32ee4f99c24"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improved quality of life for the demonstration population and beneficiary and caregiver satisfaction.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id01e166eca4a24473bba9f800db4727c8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the implementation of the CBI-SNP demonstration program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1), together with such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate. In preparing such report, the Secretary shall use at least 3 years worth of data under the demonstration program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbdb694ceb0b948019cb951e36165fd43"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Budget neutrality</header><text>By the end of the third year of the CBI-SNP demonstration program, the Secretary shall ensure that the aggregate payments made under titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act, including under the demonstration program, for subsequent periods do not exceed the amount which the Secretary estimates would have been expended under such titles during such a period if the CBI-SNP demonstration program had not been implemented.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id56678838f1424b69945999d2b592eb7d"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Paperwork reduction act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to the testing and evaluation of the CBI-SNP demonstration program.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


