<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S719 IS: To rename the Armed Forces Reserve Center in Great Falls, Montana, the Captain John E. Moran and Captain William Wylie Galt Armed Forces Reserve Center.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 719</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150311">March 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To rename the Armed Forces Reserve Center in Great Falls, Montana, the
			 Captain John E. Moran and Captain William Wylie Galt Armed Forces Reserve
			 Center.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Renaming of the Armed Forces Reserve Center in Great Falls, Montana, as the
			 Captain John E. Moran and Captain William Wylie Galt Armed Forces Reserve
			 Center</header>
 <subsection id="idF7A723746B9547E995E181024C8AFD9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Renaming</header><text>The Armed Forces Reserve Center in Great Falls, Montana, shall hereafter be known and designated as the <quote>Captain John E. Moran and Captain William Wylie Galt Armed Forces Reserve Center</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id047AF340222941C8B6D45173BCB5EADB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any law, map, regulation, map, document, paper, other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be considered to be a reference to the Captain John E. Moran and Captain William Wylie Galt Armed Forces Reserve Center.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


