<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1334 IS: Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing Enforcement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1334</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150513">May 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To strengthen enforcement mechanisms to stop illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, to amend
			 the Tuna Conventions Act of 1950 to implement the Antigua Convention, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing Enforcement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id63A18C3332604BC287477FA0A260D913"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id63A18C3332604BC287477FA0A260D913" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H93787793C50748E5AF581759C96FAA94" level="title">TITLE I—Strengthening Fisheries Enforcement Mechanisms</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H37CA2E067B85474BB89776DF15C0A8B3" level="section">Sec. 101. Amendments to the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2895D134B18B4DFC89DEADFB708252DD" level="section">Sec. 102. Amendments to the High Seas Driftnet Fisheries Enforcement Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HCAE187F853484370A872A88238B18606" level="section">Sec. 103. Amendments to North Pacific Anadromous Stocks Act of 1992.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2C804134474E4CC4B4C4DB5630329A99" level="section">Sec. 104. Amendments to the Pacific Salmon Treaty Act of 1985.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H361AF7D433594388899D1B32057A95C6" level="section">Sec. 105. Amendments to the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H9920AD1BBA074DB68BE6894C5184B83B" level="section">Sec. 106. Amendments to the Antarctic Marine Living Resources Convention Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H83C91A77158D44EAAF33BCF309EC1747" level="section">Sec. 107. Amendments to the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H0EF9B4D8E8D74925A8C66D30E87EF15E" level="section">Sec. 108. Amendments to the High Seas Fishing Compliance Act of 1965.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H6445EE81C29A45B795D485D894AFDA56" level="section">Sec. 109. Amendments to the Dolphin Protection Consumer Information Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HBAD7223DC2F9463AAE04E36A076C449B" level="section">Sec. 110. Amendments to the Northern Pacific Halibut Act of 1982.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H6B838C27D3A4489D9CF50EFBDBA4E9A5" level="section">Sec. 111. Amendments to the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H1DACC72BD5FB4771AF60E5E4F8A6871C" level="section">Sec. 112. Amendment to the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H253BC1C03B3F49C49FB4F8EC1E9DA95D" level="title">TITLE II—Implementation of the Antigua Convention</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8C6E787204CF421C9C08DF9BE0877996" level="section">Sec. 201. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H7966C32EF3BA4D9F84C4FB0DFA6CB5E0" level="section">Sec. 202. Amendment of the Tuna Conventions Act of 1950.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H0A5EDA09689C42C98A851D23EB75FFBF" level="section">Sec. 203. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4C736EAE9BA94B889A0FBF1706853E39" level="section">Sec. 204. Commissioners; number, appointment, and qualifications.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HE85660002B3E437285282CE603CBCA6A" level="section">Sec. 205. General Advisory Committee and Scientific Advisory Subcommittee.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H94944A8DD0C2481C8E3B54F31BAD9044" level="section">Sec. 206. Rulemaking.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H7DD0CDA1F90847ED9FC1F4BFB9654743" level="section">Sec. 207. Prohibited acts.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H3B6D5505A5BF4417A08895CF15859288" level="section">Sec. 208. Enforcement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H840E5DAA12CB4ACDB1E24AC7BD77AE9E" level="section">Sec. 209. Reduction of bycatch.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2A80102E38CC4E9CA763CAE8FEBC51A1" level="section">Sec. 210. Repeal of Eastern Pacific Tuna Licensing Act of 1984.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H22B613932A2A4DF79A60E7C640355001" level="title">TITLE III—Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HDEF442798DCE44F7881D881282E53B42" level="section">Sec. 301. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HDFAD6600238E435DA91D472E5916321D" level="section">Sec. 302. Purpose.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H22B2B75790BF4D42BF8DA89A8541A4D9" level="section">Sec. 303. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H20E80C1F3FB149048A37055D0ABBD9D2" level="section">Sec. 304. Duties and authorities of the secretary.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H6E41DFD97AAA4452BD1770B25CD03A44" level="section">Sec. 305. Authorization or denial of port entry.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H382E3D45D53D4C8FA42CDAA31BA5428D" level="section">Sec. 306. Inspections.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5CAE1EC26B924A818BD59595448D358B" level="section">Sec. 307. Prohibited acts.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HB413F5D43ECE43DC96EAF1EE931F4140" level="section">Sec. 308. Enforcement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H6C3F80F0815D46678CE7D4A7AC9A4C70" level="section">Sec. 309. International cooperation and assistance.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H357F0C493B1040D18948102E5B952B29" level="section">Sec. 310. Relationship to other laws.</toc-entry> </toc> </section><title id="H93787793C50748E5AF581759C96FAA94"><enum>I</enum><header>Strengthening Fisheries Enforcement Mechanisms</header> <section id="H37CA2E067B85474BB89776DF15C0A8B3"><enum>101.</enum><header>Amendments to the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act</header> <subsection id="H668FBDBAFD794E95AA1FBA74D004A750"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administration and enforcement</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9879A8AB0D4F45DBB4947322E2B413A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>The President</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H01B2C428BB454D11988827A6D7109928" style="OLC">
 <subsection commented="no" id="H31750EC038C440D6A4CB90F1E70B4469"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall enforce this Act, and the Acts to which this section applies, in accordance with this section. Each such Secretary may, by agreement, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, utilize the personnel services, equipment (including aircraft and vessels), and facilities of any other Federal agency, and of any State agency, in the performance of such duties.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H18F93D49D5DE429BB99CE685D0835D64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acts to which section applies</header><text>This section applies to the following Acts:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H16FFF7C84C6E43619B488597B32ED151"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Pacific Salmon Treaty Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3631">16 U.S.C. 3631 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H43B6886180A34FD39E3551E684439875"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Dolphin Protection Consumer Information Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1385">16 U.S.C. 1385</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H39B89BECC9034BA19CA002CBB89794F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Tuna Conventions Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/951">16 U.S.C. 951 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC812B55C2F6A44C2A71DF45E08A8539C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The North Pacific Anadromous Stocks Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5001">16 U.S.C. 5001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE89BAE98D05F4228895AAF5C5A747802"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/971">16 U.S.C. 971 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC391CF1EED604D27BFEC68DDD1CE9DDF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5601">16 U.S.C. 5601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3E43E3F92C614B1692DC0B1D7E7C3C9E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6901">16 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id99f454c6c52144c0aa58afe356e08c9c"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Antigua Convention Implementing Act of 2015.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8CE677751EE840CAABA2180E7E03760E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration and enforcement</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H757DA53E1ABC422FAE976467196D8008"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prevent any person from violating this Act, or any Act to which this section applies, in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though sections 308 through 311 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1858">16 U.S.C. 1858</external-xref>, 1859, 1860, and 1861) were incorporated into and made a part of and applicable to this Act and each such Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2EF1DB895F7C44B487384D560120DA98"><enum>(2)</enum><header>International cooperation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, subject to appropriations and in the course of carrying out the Secretary’s responsibilities under the Acts to which this section applies, engage in international cooperation to help other nations combat illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing and achieve sustainable fisheries.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H416A3D9449F9469F83EB2CBD0410B97A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HCDF72469D55F4FF69DFE84616D25258F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional enforcement authority</header><text>In addition to the powers of officers authorized pursuant to subsection (c), any officer who is authorized by the Secretary, or the head of any Federal or State agency that has entered into an agreement with the Secretary under subsection (a), may enforce the provisions of any Act to which this section applies, with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though section 311 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1861">16 U.S.C. 1861</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of each such Act.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBC41A550D43B48B591C7E1A2250E55F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure of enforcement information</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H69531B830EDE445BA8656424CFB5DD0A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, subject to the data confidentiality provisions in section 402 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1881a">16 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>), may disclose, as necessary and appropriate, information, including information collected under joint authority of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/971">16 U.S.C. 971 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6901">16 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.</external-xref>) or other statutes implementing international fishery agreements, to any other Federal or State government agency, the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, the secretariat or equivalent of an international fishery management organization or arrangement made pursuant to an international fishery agreement, or a foreign government, if—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HE043EE386D094D64A39255DAA21814DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such government, organization, or arrangement has policies and procedures to protect such information from unintended or unauthorized disclosure; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA8EF475129FE4DB9ADD6CAE41AEFB09C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such disclosure is necessary—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HCCA01A205449484EB3FDDDE99D79C8FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with any law or regulation enforced or administered by the Secretary;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HA13EFD10FA15476EBB0D421E7DD1F339"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to administer or enforce any international fishery agreement to which the United States is a party;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H43EC4491AECA4899994681927159C8F9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to administer or enforce a binding conservation measure adopted by any international organization or arrangement to which the United States is a party;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H5CC775B2F6DC40D5ACCCF526A5687206"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to assist in any investigative, judicial, or administrative enforcement proceeding in the United States; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HBDBB7D76459145BBA172F5DDB9DF086B"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assist in any law enforcement action undertaken by a law enforcement agency of a foreign government, or in relation to a legal proceeding undertaken by a foreign government to the extent the enforcement action is consistent with rules and regulations of a regional fishery management organization that the United States is a member of, or the Secretary has determined that the enforcement action is consistent with the requirements under Federal law for enforcement actions with respect to illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBCF7DE3555194052A5E325AC4F3119DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data confidentiality provisions not Applicable</header><text>The data confidentiality provisions of section 402 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1881a">16 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>) shall not apply with respect to this Act with respect to—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H458951ECFD3C437A92C2EF0E8F6C0FE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any obligation of the United States to share information under a Regional Fishery Management Organization to which the United States is a party; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB3BC4A6DD35C4333A16DBCE3276DB94A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to any information collected by the Secretary regarding foreign vessels.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB5D86FF6250E4E488E9109ADBDA8E69D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text>It is unlawful for any person—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HA525F5FDB03F40BAA8BC3ADC819AA8CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to violate any provision of this Act or any regulation or permit issued pursuant to this Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF302F2832C4741919B96872C53848F66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to refuse to permit any officer authorized to enforce the provisions of this Act to board, search, or inspect a vessel, subject to such person’s control for the purposes of conducting any search, investigation, or inspection in connection with the enforcement of this Act, any regulation promulgated under this Act, or any Act to which this section applies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7E0538D3CD9E4D29B0FBA77D14A1B67F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to forcibly assault, resist, oppose, impede, intimidate, or interfere with any such authorized officer in the conduct of any search, investigation, or inspection described in paragraph (2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H26A301A920CB4FF4A7CBB5A69779226C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to resist a lawful arrest for any act prohibited by this section or any Act to which this section applies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H89ACB6B10A064100B92CA2573C800786"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to interfere with, delay, or prevent, by any means, the apprehension, arrest, or detection of an other person, knowing that such person has committed any act prohibited by this section or any Act to which this section applies; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFB4C6FD882724DF3ADC9FE0E6A0A1A1A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to forcibly assault, resist, oppose, impede, intimidate, sexually harass, bribe, or interfere with—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE7A7288AD4EB45D8A7C0600AA382A1A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any observer on a vessel under this Act or any Act to which this section applies; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H64242D7472D4450083AF4CFBC076FBB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any data collector employed by the National Marine Fisheries Service or under contract to any person to carry out responsibilities under this Act or any Act to which this section applies.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9552B4F654EF45F6B65CCF60E47EDFAB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>Any person who commits any act that is unlawful under subsection (e) shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty, and may be subject to a permit sanction, under section 308 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1858">16 U.S.C. 1858</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD805A2D675864979BDE43AF663D0F943"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Criminal penalty</header><text>Any person who commits an act that is unlawful under paragraph (2), (3), (4), (5), or (6) of subsection (e) is deemed to be guilty of an offense punishable under section 309(b) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1859">16 U.S.C. 1859(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5C6FE0130291441FB46F2786A534419B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Utilization of Federal agency assets</header><text>The President</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2BF85D21F1B047FD8877978804864F10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions To improve the effectiveness of international fishery management organizations</header><text>Section 608 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act ( (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826i">16 U.S.C. 1826i</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB601525648D541459186391EA6CF40E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general.—</header-in-text></quote> before <quote>The Secretary, in</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB82F87542F1842429BAAC5BE74DB06FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a) (as designated by paragraph (1) of this subsection) in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>, or arrangements made pursuant to an international fishery agreement,</quote> after <quote>organizations</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4E1C76C63B64FF8BEBC60BFCBC03DBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block id="H90F64F9F3B5B42A09B31C001809FE541" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HED25D506AC8F41AB87F9A3CD0A454CDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, subject to the data confidentiality provisions in section 402 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1881a">16 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>), may disclose, as necessary and appropriate, information, including information collected under joint authority of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/971">16 U.S.C. 971 et seq.</external-xref>), the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6901">16 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.</external-xref>), any other statute implementing an international fishery agreement, to any other Federal or State government agency, the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, or the secretariat or equivalent of an international fishery management organization or arrangement made pursuant to an international fishery agreement, if such government, organization, or arrangement, respectively, has policies and procedures to protect such information from unintended or unauthorized disclosure.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H58CC1D89B67345EFBBB796B1F016D3AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>IUU vessel lists</header><text>The Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="H2D41536D1F764B6AAE07B4FFA5B9AD97"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop, maintain, and make public a list of vessels and vessel owners engaged in illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing or fishing-related activities in support of illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing, including vessels or vessel owners identified by an international fishery management organization or arrangement made pursuant to an international fishery agreement, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0C1FAD8A447244F59D31901FE909D41E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States is party to; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4BBD5180A524504B3CF890226A09824"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States is not party to, but whose procedures and criteria in developing and maintaining a list of such vessels and vessel owners are substantially similar to such procedures and criteria adopted pursuant to an international fishery agreement to which the United States is a party; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A121C8FCEDE4462884FF08220D25D6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take appropriate action against listed vessels and vessel owners, including action against fish, fish parts, or fish products from such vessels, in accordance with applicable United States law and consistent with applicable international law, including principles, rights, and obligations established in applicable international fishery management agreements and trade agreements.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FAAF4FDB3AC40E99992467A88DDC4EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may promulgate regulations to implement this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31B7AD97E3D8436397A66EFC54B52999"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification regarding identification of nations</header><text>Section 609(b) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HBE40F67C43584521AD196E3550E1FF9F" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H19F361FF66C5401391B85E6685C42B3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary shall notify the President and that nation of an identification made under subsection (a).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H64C6D9E9C48143A9B14DBCF7147A9E0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nations identified under section 610</header><text>Section 610(b)(1) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826k">16 U.S.C. 1826k(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H656E0648F8B040B98C39D71B9984A640" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H32E3ED811D284F3FA0463DEDEF771C48"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify, as soon as possible, the President and nations that have been identified under subsection (a), and other nations whose vessels engage in fishing activities or practices described in subsection (a), about the provisions of this section and this Act;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBFA79069997148788556C09F18BA247B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect of certification under section 609</header><text>Section 609(d)(3)(A)(i) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)(3)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>that has not been certified by the Secretary under this subsection, or</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H64B45188C74B4AE894017D240E47020E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect of certification under section 610</header><text>Section 610(c)(5) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826k">16 U.S.C. 1826k(c)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>that has not been certified by the Secretary under this subsection, or</quote>.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H73C927D8897C41369C39CE28B635F908"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Identification of nations</header>
 <paragraph id="HE27537CC7B734F9599783E76E950A69C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scope of identification for actions of fishing vessels</header><text>Section 609(a) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H97C5AC773BE54823AEAC4499B6660A0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H4DD9236AD3924AE5862EE628963CACDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>, based on a cumulative compilation and analysis of data collected and provided by international fishery management organizations and other nations and organizations,</quote> after <quote>shall</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H68AACE385092481E818C3E92626F7A89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2 years,</quote> and inserting <quote>3 years,</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4529BF83AD8F4D4F9B47F828E9503D06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="id4B77D89E361041059C4FA03E8411FFE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>that undermines the effectiveness of measures required by an international fishery management organization, taking into account whether</quote> after <quote>(1)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H420E58E6C2D94302AF7CBAFE289B610F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>vessels of</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70F7D4010D9F4108868285B1232DF32D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional grounds for identification</header><text>Section 609(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(a)</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1), is further amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H865389D8F183470CB07CBE0DCDA1A93C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) in order as subparagraphs (A) and (B) (and by moving the margins of such subparagraphs 2 ems to the right);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2482073E2AEB4614B6A9208528CED1B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the first sentence the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2233CF282E9B4175BB36C59AB0E71F56" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC4BE8CC8E1674810BE0E6CAC5A5F82C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification for actions of fishing vessels</header></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EEFE514F5B243FF9393C8ED82BAD515"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H998AE7F50B414BCA9640320047AADF10" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H9E0D855D085946E78CA4459401FA3FB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification for actions of nation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taking into account the factors described under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall identify, and list in such report, a nation—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0BC621FA1A4B4ED48CE2F67767BB2CCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if it is violating, or has violated at any point during the preceding three years, conservation and management measures required under an international fishery management agreement to which the United States is a party and the violations undermine the effectiveness of such measures; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H729B60B1A4DB466C979C164544114648"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if it is failing, or has failed in the preceding 3-year period, to effectively address or regulate illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing in areas described under paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE64B721FC0C14C5B91EE83552C3B851E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application to other entities</header><text>Where the provisions of this Act are applicable to nations, they shall also be applicable, as appropriate, to other entities that have competency to enter into international fishery management agreements.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A6E879BA55F48FA82BFDA5BE3B6A859"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period of fishing practices supporting identification</header><text>Section 610(a)(1)(A) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826k">16 U.S.C. 1826k(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>calendar year</quote> and inserting <quote>3 years</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6673964CF24A45A1912D9F160F827AA8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce $450,000 for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2019 to implement the amendments made by subsections (b) and (g).</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H2DAA9AE6160F4096A92152A8FB36D751"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical corrections</header>
 <paragraph id="HD6DFE47471BE422E940EE68E0287A961"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section 607</header><text>Section 607(2) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826h">16 U.S.C. 1826h(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>whose vessels</quote> and inserting <quote>that</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AE8BCE943D842308CE7B9B8DC78E9E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Section 609</header><text>Section 609(d) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id313267D39A2341099EC684266F6F251F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="id0B5F2D540FD04C52B750D9AC80B275F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>of its fishing vessels</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B8C1F1B63EE4F8F900854E69B0C3DE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), is amended by striking <quote>of its fishing vessels</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD2C3D5D379B4CE1AE3F06E7297C5219"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In paragraph (2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="H08E65C9D7C4D4E81BA12BCC354681567"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>for certification,</quote> and inserting <quote>to authorize,</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H7A1BF1D45194469E942FB5CE5607E892"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>the importation</quote> after <quote>or other basis</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF6D10EA4DFE74792B0FE9655944843BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>harvesting</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4EA69AE4EFA949288B8718B91066AFD5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not certified under paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>issued a negative certification under paragraph (1)</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0A820F36EA34BC7B8E234B6DE773635"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Section 610</header><text>Section 610 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826k">16 U.S.C. 1826k</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H871D6BDEC8A146EEADFFF42C887EFBAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>practices;</quote> and inserting <quote>practices—</quote>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78CD1F7D1A424B9989A8014284046AA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In subsection (c)(4), by striking all preceding subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block id="H434274F6BA2B45D8A295224DF2E3AA75" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HEF91EBC2B12C449490F7F8DEF9A9DAC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Alternative procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may establish a procedure to authorize, on a shipment-by-shipment, shipper-by-shipper, or other basis the importation of fish or fish products from a vessel of a nation issued a negative certification under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that such imports were harvested by practices that do not result in bycatch of a protected marine species, or were harvested by practices that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1068D53755FF468CAE06A36357396A24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are comparable to those of the United States, taking into account different conditions; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2895D134B18B4DFC89DEADFB708252DD"><enum>102.</enum><header>Amendments to the High Seas Driftnet Fisheries Enforcement Act</header> <subsection id="H88C894CE94FD4021AE1300D6262A7E32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Negative certification effects</header><text>Section 101 of the High Seas Driftnet Fisheries Enforcement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826a">16 U.S.C. 1826a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE118C61B4CC7487EB084A25A28359609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="id13E4633FEF26401E8831282D765E30C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>recognized principles of</quote> after <quote>in accordance with</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A7737BD18834687B48BE34612AF6F82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>(1);</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) or, as appropriate, for fishing vessels of a nation that receives a negative certification under section 609(d) or section 610(c) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)</external-xref> and 1826k(c));</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72D3970E24B44B758EA2806E06D58AD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>, except for the purposes of inspecting such vessel, conducting an investigation, or taking other appropriate enforcement action</quote> before the period at the end; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF783D334FBE4BDE858E022DCD8E495C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="id89CAF2103674461B87654885CEB4D662"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraphs (1)(A)(i), (1)(B), and (2), by striking <quote>or illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing</quote> each place that term appears;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91411AA3B72A4BDE864F86FBC834D9F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A)(i), by striking <quote>(1)(A);</quote> and inserting <quote>(1)(A) or a negative certification under section 609(d) or section 610(c) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)</external-xref> and 1826k(c));</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51600657D7BB42DB9A6BD8929385C58C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A)—</text> <clause id="id6C2D836EC936481C9B4814CB1254228D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>paragraph (1),</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1) or issues a negative certification under section 609(d) or section 610(c) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)</external-xref> and 1826k(c)),</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD961CEB0113B4EEDB9DBF9C2772A76A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="idE6BB7E3832F24233AB481AB90C0DCCF7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H07DBF41E8DF743FB95285B32CF5745D3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>nation;</quote> and inserting <quote>nation, or to address the offending activities for which a nation received a negative certification under section 609(d) or 610(c) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)</external-xref>, 1826k(c))</quote>.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D3931B06C3D458AB853D34618F5DCC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration of negative certification effects</header><text>Section 102 of the High Seas Driftnet Fisheries Enforcement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826b">16 U.S.C. 1826b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD1BBE86644AF4C6C8F2AAAA8B298B171"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD69B0A793AAE4B52B493D5FB894262AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>or effectively addressed the offending activities for which the nation received a negative certification under 609(d) or 610(c) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)</external-xref>, 1826k(c))</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCAE187F853484370A872A88238B18606"><enum>103.</enum><header>Amendments to North Pacific Anadromous Stocks Act of 1992</header>
 <subsection id="HE889E0DB54D843D9825D162C40870166"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unlawful activities</header><text>Section 810 of the North Pacific Anadromous Stocks Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5009">16 U.S.C. 5009</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA7F71EDAB36B4952B31E29AA41393215"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> after <quote>search</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AAC0A9F16AF46E19AA3588594A89972"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> after <quote>search</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2407DF34444498EB1EC7D7ED2260ABB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional prohibitions and enforcement</header><text>Section 811 of the Northern Pacific Anadromous Stocks Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5010">16 U.S.C. 5010</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42FD8D33B83D4A3BA59C72423F2FF6E2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H110E66E3644B49CC8AE4F65DD36FB328"><enum>811.</enum><header>Additional prohibitions and enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For additional prohibitions relating to this Act and enforcement of this Act, see section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>).</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2C804134474E4CC4B4C4DB5630329A99"><enum>104.</enum><header>Amendments to the Pacific Salmon Treaty Act of 1985</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8 of the Pacific Salmon Treaty Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3637">16 U.S.C. 3637</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD335E97D848F481DB790311B6C2ACF78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idFD823DCEC0B847C5987147A8C34CA87B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HF36930469B614A2ABF49288656374F7F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> after <quote>search</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEF0D9CEC2DE443BEAFF9D9DAE21621FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>this title;</quote> and inserting <quote>this Act;</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB1B944F25CB4D6C9BA4CCCDBE964C37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text>
 <clause id="H7DCD89B92969404D984F6F4B58018E49"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> after <quote>search</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5B86A422AE774167A2866096E1D409AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (2);</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (2);</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2410A2FB1A36489CA57EEE47BDCD81F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>this title; or</quote> and inserting <quote>this Act;</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A8DCBA2C0CA4664B6A9799E497D786B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b) through (f) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H82619CD30D6B44DF87CCA8D57216A1E0" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H8CD4B726D8A442108B45B240656DD7B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional prohibitions and enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For additional prohibitions relating to this Act and enforcement of this Act, see section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H361AF7D433594388899D1B32057A95C6"><enum>105.</enum><header>Amendments to the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H632166F9B5054118825CF74144B8A014"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending section 506(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6905">16 U.S.C. 6905(c)</external-xref>) to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HCCC1994215CE4E1DAB64822BF04C9449" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H088DBEBB16C848D0AE9A7106AE423002"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional prohibitions and enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For additional prohibitions relating to this Act and enforcement of this Act, see section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD56F7B5272F04457A245F6EA91BE574A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 507(a)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6906">16 U.S.C. 6906(a)(2)</external-xref>) by striking <quote>suspension, on</quote> and inserting <quote>suspension, of</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H9920AD1BBA074DB68BE6894C5184B83B"><enum>106.</enum><header>Amendments to the Antarctic Marine Living Resources Convention Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Antarctic Marine Living Resources Convention Act of 1984 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H88CAAE1DE72B444183E673239054D7DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 306 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2435">16 U.S.C. 2435</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A567C43B2C84B55B268E2DA4D8B1E4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>which he knows, or reasonably should have known, was</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BBC9823708841299C2F0F98BF1CE393"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> after <quote>search</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CBA840523B04AF8B567DB341E794D2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> after <quote>search</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED8339E7D5CB45E89EC3FB85DAE3978A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 307 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2436">16 U.S.C. 2436</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="HABE2BB1703704E6491321397E0D247CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general.—</header-in-text></quote> before <quote>The Secretary of Commerce</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H642E8B8687F0493097913AB7F08DA105"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HF1C594D208214910B57D4B583F95EB7A" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HF26FBBD32C5B4FE8B2EDA8F84702B824"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations To implement conservation measures</header> <paragraph id="H840AA5F03E3246F7ACF5A65F81EC6ADF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subsections (b), (c), and (d) of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, the Secretary of Commerce may publish in the Federal Register a final regulation to implement any conservation measure for which the Secretary of State notifies the Commission under section 305(a)(1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD00031910579496096DAEA1A94079342"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that has been in effect for 12 months or less;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0231B6FB4BD54FB98539D8D57D813B08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is adopted by the Commission; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFE9D8F3278D4DE4BD6ED3BEF29692AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to which the Secretary of State does not notify Commission in accordance with section 305(a)(1) within the time period allotted for objections under Article IX of the Convention.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D2B0915A0CF451A9255938F67469CF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Entering into force</header><text>Upon publication of such regulation in the Federal Register, such conservation measure shall enter into force with respect to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H83C91A77158D44EAAF33BCF309EC1747"><enum>107.</enum><header>Amendments to the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1BF5599ACE59456F9D450793B0B9331B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 6(c)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/971d">16 U.S.C. 971d(c)(2)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDDDA2793C3B34ECAA1E5805171DC01A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>(i)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F5C6B45955A49668CA695F6DB65B614"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>(ii)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22A493AA7336435AAB6DCFB66637542D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(A)</quote> after <quote>(2)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB661F2C0A1D4C939E5FAEB15D2FD2AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H9C0E965EDDFD4ED894FA0E14ACE1EAFA" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HFB84F264F97346DABA1F1AD3A8AA545A" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of subparagraph (A) and subsections (b) and (c) of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, the Secretary may issue final regulations to implement Commission recommendations referred to in paragraph (1) concerning trade restrictive measures against nations or fishing entities.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70F7362AD91C4EABAE079660C8E926AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/971e">16 U.S.C. 971e</external-xref>) by striking subsections (e) and (f) and redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (e);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC232C8C918D41889F6E49F6CCACDC34"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 8 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/971f">16 U.S.C. 971f</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H88BCFEF6C5FF42FAA75FBC863674BF86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a) and (c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1160BCAC7AA4EE98E9570101140E2BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before subsection (b) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFC637A29A79B437C8BACEFBBA3A1D311" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H6A19CC7E6C814F8ABCEE65EE0EEB5FA8"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For additional prohibitions relating to this Act and enforcement of this Act, see section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1E4F03A461AC409F9A422F194CF21D38"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 8(b) by striking <quote>the enforcement activities specified in section 8(a) of this Act</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>enforcement activities with respect to this Act that are otherwise authorized by law</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE345CE1245F4AA7BE13547AFAD69150"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking section 11 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/971j">16 U.S.C. 971j</external-xref>) and redesignating sections 12 and 13 as sections 11 and 12, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H0EF9B4D8E8D74925A8C66D30E87EF15E"><enum>108.</enum><header>Amendments to the High Seas Fishing Compliance Act of 1965</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 104(f) of the High Seas Fishing Compliance Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5503">16 U.S.C. 5503(f)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HCE92B99B36F14E4EB0EF4BE3CDBFFDF7" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H896A2CF6CD3F4C6CB55EF520DC24D356"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Validity</header><text>A permit issued under this section for a vessel is void if—</text> <paragraph id="HECC0C33E93D0414BA751516D3E748E2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any other permit or authorization required for the vessel to fish is expired, revoked, or suspended; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB217EE32A00E4EA3997AF240AD512256"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the vessel is no longer documented under the laws of the United States or eligible for such documentation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H6445EE81C29A45B795D485D894AFDA56"><enum>109.</enum><header>Amendments to the Dolphin Protection Consumer Information Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Dolphin Protection Consumer Information Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1385">16 U.S.C. 1385</external-xref>) is amended by amending subsection (e) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H904BDF5BAA7740DCBD841E7432801486" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HECB787BC13E341CC8C7E12E9D5DB95F3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional prohibitions and enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For additional prohibitions relating to this Act and enforcement of this Act, see section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HBAD7223DC2F9463AAE04E36A076C449B"><enum>110.</enum><header>Amendments to the Northern Pacific Halibut Act of 1982</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of the Northern Pacific Halibut Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/773e">16 U.S.C. 773e</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB1567B935D674AC6B07C99FCCD68D658"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a) by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (6) as subparagraphs (A) through (F);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25FD81B867B34044B063427C4B4F6CD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (a) and (b) as paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5961A1187154C219A03DBA028BE3B3D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> before <quote>or inspection</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE30887BD37A4FE5A4ABAF4438A2D05C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(C), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> before <quote>or inspection</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0273504EDBB14182A5AD2FD6838A32ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(E), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FACACE8BC4C436EA2D0557D6C6733CF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(F), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>section.</quote> and inserting <quote>section; or</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H6B838C27D3A4489D9CF50EFBDBA4E9A5"><enum>111.</enum><header>Amendments to the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 207 of the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5606">16 U.S.C. 5606</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H726F6CD0CE814BA8B7E4E807402646D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and penalties</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and enforcement</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H34E6A30F5CC74F8B9E7AC4C071C3EA3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> before <quote>or inspection</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC7F375AEA7B439585A4CEB8FD8C8214"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3), by inserting <quote>, investigation,</quote> before <quote>or inspection</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H139B01B7FACA489F9F7078657650879C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b) through (f) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HB4AC520851F94CA4BA8A40E39CA66382" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H33D987622BCB44FD8FE33490CA302D95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional prohibitions and enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For additional prohibitions relating to this Act and enforcement of this Act, see section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1DACC72BD5FB4771AF60E5E4F8A6871C"><enum>112.</enum><header>Amendment to the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 307(1)(Q) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1857">16 U.S.C. 1857(1)(Q)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>or any treaty or in contravention of any binding conservation measure adopted by an international agreement or organization to which the United States is a party</quote>.</text>
			</section></title><title id="H253BC1C03B3F49C49FB4F8EC1E9DA95D"><enum>II</enum><header>Implementation of the Antigua Convention</header>
 <section id="H8C6E787204CF421C9C08DF9BE0877996"><enum>201.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Antigua Convention Implementing Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7966C32EF3BA4D9F84C4FB0DFA6CB5E0"><enum>202.</enum><header>Amendment of the Tuna Conventions Act of 1950</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this title an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Tuna Conventions Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/951">16 U.S.C. 951 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="H0A5EDA09689C42C98A851D23EB75FFBF"><enum>203.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/951">16 U.S.C. 951</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H0B6FB9112A144C85BE1A84DCB544E775" style="OLC"> <section id="HC3C80CEA4CF74669B6BE170C901A56B0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6489D3825DA04315BFAD163F9FB828DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Antigua convention</header><text>The term <term>Antigua Convention</term> means the Convention for the Strengthening of the Inter-American Tropical Tuna Commission Established by the 1949 Convention Between the United States of America and the Republic of Costa Rica, signed at Washington, November 14, 2003.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC205399517CF4A12979250E18C027933"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Inter-American Tropical Tuna Commission provided for by the Convention.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B56DE895E4745FC8FCC8DD1214BCC7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Convention</header><text>The term <term>Convention</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4BFEEEA0414C4C988182F0B85EC86A7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Convention for the Establishment of an Inter-American Tropical Tuna Commission, signed at Washington, May 31, 1949, by the United States of America and the Republic of Costa Rica;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30343DBA13574939B8ACF54525E3EF5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Antigua Convention, upon its entry into force for the United States, and any amendments thereto that are in force for the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46B7DEC06EA54E5DA428E66E66EA8EF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>both such Conventions, as the context requires.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H606AD7C4B81C44AA898D2D104AD04FA5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual, partnership, corporation, or association subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9173A3D044A643C082BD5338DEA553D8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United states</header><text>The term <term>United States</term> includes all areas under the sovereignty of the United States.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEFB7EADD4AF4B3EAC77570392FD43C8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States commissioners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States commissioners</term> means the individuals appointed in accordance with section 3(a).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H4C736EAE9BA94B889A0FBF1706853E39"><enum>204.</enum><header>Commissioners; number, appointment, and qualifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/952">16 U.S.C. 952</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HE21FF6213B594A0F952E2530A2C67E09" style="OLC"> <section id="HC7543BEBCBC445809F4E2315C18C9DD8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Commissioners</header> <subsection id="HFCE0D9B756684A998A0DE8353EA2573E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Commissioners</header> <paragraph id="id131696B4571E4B599525FF220B9729C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States shall be represented on the Commission by 5 United States Commissioners.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8F9DE83B62B8418AA472ABBEED1EB1A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The President shall appoint individuals to serve on the Commission at the pleasure of the President. In making the appointments, the President shall select Commissioners from among individuals who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning highly migratory fish stocks in the eastern tropical Pacific Ocean, including the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id95FB7CEDE2FD47C693209A2E91B765DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One Commissioner shall be an officer or employee of the Department of Commerce.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3AA677061D0E44CFA7A7004280160B86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One Commissioner shall be the chairman or a member of the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76E5D56BAF62446895EDAE9010A0C413"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One commissioner shall be the chairman or a member of the Pacific Fishery Management Council.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB8496A3C6C92480082AC5E1B175C35EE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No more than two Commissioners may reside in a State other than a State whose vessels maintain a substantial fishery in the area of the Convention.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03B47E0001B848528C0BF673882F8AED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Alternate Commissioners</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary, may designate from time to time and for periods of time deemed appropriate Alternate United States Commissioners to the Commission. Any Alternate United States Commissioner may exercise, at any meeting of the Commission or of the General Advisory Committee or Scientific Advisory Subcommittee established pursuant to section 4(b), all powers and duties of a United States Commissioner in the absence of any United States Commissioner appointed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section for whatever reason. The number of such Alternate United States Commissioners that may be designated for any such meeting shall be limited to the number of United States Commissioners appointed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section who will not be present at such meeting.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H6D02CD468D5C4F9993043D7E6AB98212"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative Matters</header>
 <paragraph id="H02D50A4BDD7941D4ACEC6AFA33EB2AE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employment status</header><text>Individuals serving as United States Commissioners, other than officers or employees of the United States Government, shall not be considered Federal employees except for the purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E1538654D84205852F1B412B16A8C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The United States Commissioners or Alternate Commissioners, although officers of the United States while so serving, shall receive no compensation for their services as United States Commissioners or Alternate Commissioners.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HD1B902BF29234CA5AC83BCB4979BAB2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header>
 <subparagraph id="H19A1E0EAA49E4E0583893C7DDF137B9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall pay the necessary travel expenses of United States Commissioners and Alternate United States Commissioners to meetings of the Inter-American Tropical Tuna Commission and other meetings the Secretary of State deems necessary to fulfill their duties, in accordance with the Federal Travel Regulations and sections 5701, 5702, 5704 through 5708, and 5731 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DD3C621FCA7449F822D87DAC47A70AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary may reimburse the Secretary of State for amounts expended by the Secretary of State under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1EAD645C87014D51BE8F4C85019C8904"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supervision</header><text>United States Commissioners and alternative commissioners shall be subject to the supervision of the Secretary of Commerce.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HE85660002B3E437285282CE603CBCA6A"><enum>205.</enum><header>General Advisory Committee and Scientific Advisory Subcommittee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/953">16 U.S.C. 953</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0FAFD00A7DFE40C0ADB1384C988F746D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HD97599FD10444C6DB563F40E1F0C96BF" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H336244D0315B4BFF9520CAD32115B434"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General Advisory Committee</header>
							<paragraph id="H25D5E7D77433463592BBE87DE973123A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointments; public participation; compensation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6E6D9EF881904544929102A3EACCAE1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint a General Advisory Committee which shall consist of not more than 25 individuals who shall be representative of the various groups concerned with the fisheries covered by the Convention, including nongovernmental conservation organizations, providing to the maximum extent practicable an equitable balance among such groups. Members of the General Advisory Committee will be eligible to participate as members of the United States delegation to the Commission and its working groups to the extent the Commission rules and space for delegations allow.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29D71C3EA134406696402CA62889FC67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The chair of the Pacific Fishery Management Council’s Advisory Subpanel for Highly Migratory Fisheries and the chair of the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council’s Advisory Committee shall be ex-officio members of the General Advisory Committee by virtue of their positions in those Councils.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B1F79963F464AA9A1088EC448670B00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each member of the General Advisory Committee appointed under subparagraph (A) shall serve for a term of 3 years and is eligible for reappointment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1C7286B8B4149D3946C1A018719E802"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The General Advisory Committee shall be invited to attend all non-executive meetings of the United States delegation and at such meetings shall be given opportunity to examine and to be heard on all proposed programs of investigation, reports, recommendations, and regulations of the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB8EE18EBBD14EC4B430E752292B41EA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The General Advisory Committee shall determine its organization, and prescribe its practices and procedures for carrying out its functions under this title, the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Convention. The General Advisory Committee shall publish and make available to the public a statement of its organization, practices and procedures. Meetings of the General Advisory Committee, except when in executive session, shall be open to the public, and prior notice of meetings shall be made public in timely fashion. The General Advisory Committee shall not be subject to the <act-name parsable-cite="FACA">Federal Advisory Committee Act</act-name> (5 U.S.C. App.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF21DBE24FF8846E697C1018A1841CC66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of State shall furnish the General Advisory Committee with relevant information concerning fisheries and international fishery agreements.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H3F6520DF01354C4D80A3AD3FD59A9564"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative matters</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1829CE197B204BE398FB6E5E9985CAB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide to the General Advisory Committee in a timely manner such administrative and technical support services as are necessary for its effective functioning.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13F942805F604B2897FF50BF77D3CAFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Individuals appointed to serve as a member of the General Advisory Committee—</text> <clause id="HE60BB7756DF84AE6BA30963C071D1EC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall serve without pay, but while away from their homes or regular places of business to attend meetings of the General Advisory Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA025606D566E4D2FB73C22CC422EE4FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not be considered Federal employees except for the purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AAD709F9074406CBAEE3F74CD4009FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking so much of subsection (b) as precedes paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H4DD513023D424FAAAC7BB5D4FE487C32" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HC107AD3E94B043C498A6D92D58EBDCE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scientific Advisory Subcommittee</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H24B15E2D222E41C9B2C7E783F7710C37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint a Scientific Advisory Subcommittee of not less than 5 nor more than 15 qualified scientists with balanced representation from the public and private sectors, including nongovernmental conservation organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H30E6F0EE4CC343B287038B920E71CFA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>General Advisory Subcommittee</quote> and inserting <quote>General Advisory Committee</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H94944A8DD0C2481C8E3B54F31BAD9044"><enum>206.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/955">16 U.S.C. 955</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC263E2018B49444A89D0233A43E5C91A" style="OLC">
					<section id="H4A9C6F9791A54DA183728581C837FCB2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header>
 <subsection id="H16602F8C3B75446296AD006354E1F69C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State and, with respect to enforcement measures, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, may promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the United States international obligations under the Convention and this Act, including recommendations and decisions adopted by the Commission. In cases where the Secretary has discretion in the implementation of one or more measures adopted by the Commission that would govern fisheries under the authority of a Regional Fishery Management Council, the Secretary may, to the extent practicable within the implementation schedule of the Convention and any recommendations and decisions adopted by the Commission, promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the United States international obligations under the Convention and this Act, in accordance with the procedures established by the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA0F681E57444CCA94FAFDD093C5000E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may promulgate regulations as may be necessary to carry out the United States international obligations under the Convention and this Act, applicable to all vessels and persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, including United States flag vessels wherever they may be operating, on such date as the Secretary shall prescribe.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H7DD0CDA1F90847ED9FC1F4BFB9654743"><enum>207.</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/957">16 U.S.C. 957</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H22CE6BA3C4354D2B90646F958CCA50E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>section 6(c) of this Act</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>section 6</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55F4ED8A1C294247BE0318390FE67393"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5218057B11FE4138A4435C62501A5C2A" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H5F009BECDFB94A31812CEF6C09104CB5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Additional prohibitions and enforcement</header><text>For prohibitions relating to this Act and enforcement of this Act, see section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H3B6D5505A5BF4417A08895CF15859288"><enum>208.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/959">16 U.S.C. 959</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H0B373DF6617647069862891A48DEC060" style="OLC"> <section id="H1C694FCCA7394B35AA076F168BA7D002"><enum>10.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For enforcement of this Act, see section 606 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826g">16 U.S.C. 1826g</external-xref>).</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H840E5DAA12CB4ACDB1E24AC7BD77AE9E"><enum>209.</enum><header>Reduction of bycatch</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/962">16 U.S.C. 962</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>vessel</quote> and inserting <quote>vessels</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2A80102E38CC4E9CA763CAE8FEBC51A1"><enum>210.</enum><header>Repeal of Eastern Pacific Tuna Licensing Act of 1984</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Eastern Pacific Tuna Licensing Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/972">16 U.S.C. 972 et seq.</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
			</section></title><title id="H22B613932A2A4DF79A60E7C640355001"><enum>III</enum><header>Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and
			 Unregulated Fishing</header>
 <section id="HDEF442798DCE44F7881D881282E53B42"><enum>301.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Port State Measures Agreement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDFAD6600238E435DA91D472E5916321D"><enum>302.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this title is to implement the Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing.</text>
 </section><section id="H22B2B75790BF4D42BF8DA89A8541A4D9"><enum>303.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="H42128EE05C014603AE7F943702BAA74F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>The term <quote>Agreement</quote> means the Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing, done at the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, in Rome, Italy, November 22, 2009, and signed by the United States November 22, 2009.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2500A360347F4656B8CBD77C739C4F9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fish</header><text>The term <quote>fish</quote> means finfish, mollusks, crustaceans, and all other forms of marine animal and plant life other than marine mammals and birds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9808BA4CD6D6481BAF213787B1B441DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fishing</header><text>The term <quote>fishing</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H8B67D35570044E99B59837075FF7C134"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), means—</text>
 <clause id="H9C14EF4B49054405BD5D790CD066D4D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the catching, taking, or harvesting of fish;</text> </clause><clause id="H270F94BA950C4336A919C3BDD1D6104D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the attempted catching, taking, or harvesting of fish;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF8A79E381DF4566925ADC1E629CCD24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other activity which can reasonably be expected to result in the catching, taking, or harvesting of fish; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7507DDAA988447C4B2F69BA560448179"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any operations at sea in support of, or in preparation for, any activity described in clauses (i) through (iii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54CA98349E354CBD85EE45BE5AD49AF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any scientific research activity that is conducted by a scientific research vessel.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6C0D3772FC2415FBD63D3434FC14362"><enum>(4)</enum><header>IUU fishing</header><text>The term <quote>IUU fishing</quote> means any activity set out in paragraph 3 of the 2001 FAO International Plan of Action to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE3C9B8F200845A8BC6CEE7CFCC6095F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Listed IUU vessel</header><text>The term <quote>listed IUU vessel</quote> means a vessel that is included in a list of vessels having engaged in IUU fishing or fishing-related activities in support of IUU fishing that has been adopted by a regional fisheries management organization of which the United States is a member, or a list adopted by a regional fisheries management organization of which the United States is not a member if the Secretary determines the criteria used by that organization to create the IUU list is comparable to criteria adopted by RFMOs of which the United States is a member for identifying IUU vessels and activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEFB4B9AD8844BF0AEECAF5FFA0B45F8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Magnuson-Stevens Act</header><text>The term <quote>Magnuson-Stevens Act</quote> means the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H458FB737539B4C7B8FF2CC4198ED7E20"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <quote>person</quote> has the same meaning as that term has in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87F89E65AB1E42BE9835E63E4F54086E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>RFMO; regional fisheries management organization</header><text>The terms <quote>RFMO</quote> and <quote>regional fisheries management organization</quote> mean a regional fisheries management organization (as that term is defined by the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing) that is recognized by the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46A111FAC26045EF87B563CD79F9FABB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E534219D98A40C580EE4EAA8638F99C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Vessel</header><text>The term <quote>vessel</quote> means any vessel, ship of another type, or boat used for, equipped to be used for, or intended to be used for, fishing or fishing-related activities, including container vessels that are carrying fish that have not been previously landed.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H20E80C1F3FB149048A37055D0ABBD9D2"><enum>304.</enum><header>Duties and authorities of the secretary</header>
 <subsection id="H4CD1ADACC86048B6BB839A8DE1B3E81E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may, as needed, promulgate such regulations, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, and consistent with the provisions of this title, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this title to the extent that such regulations are not already promulgated.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H10F6B955F0A84E0CB1CC10CEB4820D92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ports of entry</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and, when the Coast Guard is not operating in the Department of Homeland Security, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, may designate and publicize the ports to which vessels may seek entry. No port may be designated under this section that has not also been designated as a port of entry for customs reporting purposes pursuant to section 1433 of title 19, United States Code, or that is not specified under an existing international fisheries agreement.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE885B8E71104563820C19C7EC86EC0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary shall provide notification of the denial of port entry or the use of port services for a vessel under section 305, the withdrawal of the denial of port services for a foreign vessel, the taking of enforcement action pursuant to section 306 with respect to a foreign vessel, or the results of any inspection of a foreign vessel conducted pursuant to this title to the flag nation of the vessel and, as appropriate, to the nation of which the vessel’s master is a national, relevant coastal nations, RFMOs, the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, and other relevant international organizations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D554CB0B3BB42B9BFDB137BC8F6B199"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Confirmation that fish were taken in accordance with conservation and management measures</header><text>The Secretary may request confirmation from the flag state of a foreign vessel that the fish on board a foreign vessel in a port subject to the jurisdiction of the United States were taken in accordance with applicable RFMO conservation and management measures.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H6E41DFD97AAA4452BD1770B25CD03A44"><enum>305.</enum><header>Authorization or denial of port entry</header>
 <subsection id="H88EB6EA7D1E24C39AE7C4C2A27817447"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission of information required under agreement</header><text>All foreign vessels seeking entry to a port subject to the jurisdiction of the United States must submit to the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating information as required under the Agreement in advance of its arrival in port.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8D5BFD74AEFD4833862FB52F99F75025"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Decision To authorize or deny port entry</header><text>The Secretary shall decide, based on the information submitted under subsection (a), whether to authorize or deny port entry and shall communicate this decision to the foreign vessel or to its representative. The Secretary may deny entry to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFDD66EFBD43C48CDB0A7F60A7D26E964"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any foreign-listed IUU vessel; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H70B72C93B510445596091E8BAE26306F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any foreign vessel the Secretary has reasonable grounds to believe has engaged in IUU fishing or fishing-related activities in support of such fishing or has violated the Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57714D17425B4D7E84A7B6FEFF7ED3FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Denial of use of port</header><text>If a foreign vessel is in a port subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, the Secretary shall deny such vessel the use of the port for landing, transshipment, packaging and processing of fish, refueling, resupplying, maintenance and drydocking, if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8624B21179E940149FE6EB5875AF7DB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the vessel entered without authorization under subsection (b);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE95D30A3FF64DAC839A221A16AF0197"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the vessel is a listed IUU vessel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB75CFDF717149EA84279B5010385425"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the flag nation of the vessel has failed to provide confirmation requested by the Secretary that the fish on board were taken in accordance with applicable RFMO conservation and management measures; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3516FD5EA6940C48E7E7424B3B12FA5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary has reasonable grounds to believe—</text> <subparagraph id="H32A9B970CE1F452FA0EB8D1071ED38AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the vessel lacks valid authorizations to engage in fishing or fishing-related activities as required by its flag nation or the relevant coastal nation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B088DECB7AF4848AFCAE8185FB8BC30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the fish on board were taken in violation of foreign law or in contravention of any RFMO conservation and management measure; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07FCAFA379DF46DF80656201A7086EF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the vessel has engaged in IUU fishing or fishing-related activities in support of such fishing, including in support of a listed IUU vessel, unless it can establish that—</text>
 <clause id="H10CA082537FA4CF196FA5FC25C4DDBB8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it was acting in a manner consistent with applicable RFMO conservation and management measures; or</text> </clause><clause id="H54DC742E35F84A37BB27727B37A4386C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of the provision of personnel, fuel, gear, and other supplies at sea, the vessel provisioned was not, at the time of provisioning, a listed IUU vessel.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB079DBA0B3C74A90B9AD9856ED393AD7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary may allow port entry or the use of port services—</text>
 <paragraph id="H69D8361BF666402D84222DDFA9B6ECB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if they are essential to the safety or health of the crew or safety of the vessel;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H91CFBED2573D499AAE6A2CE61135817D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to allow, where appropriate, for the scrapping of the vessel; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEDBEC6B170543C2A2B36D1CAD01AB1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pursuant to an inspection or other enforcement action.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H382E3D45D53D4C8FA42CDAA31BA5428D"><enum>306.</enum><header>Inspections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall conduct foreign vessel inspections in ports subject to the jurisdiction of the United States as necessary to achieve the purposes of the Agreement and this title. If, following an inspection, the Secretary has reasonable grounds to believe that a foreign vessel has engaged in IUU fishing or fishing-related activities in support of such fishing, the Secretary may take enforcement action under this title or other applicable law, and shall deny the vessel the use of port services, in accordance with section 305.</text>
 </section><section id="H5CAE1EC26B924A818BD59595448D358B"><enum>307.</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is unlawful for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States—</text> <paragraph id="HDB79208944EA4DBF99491FEEA924D7E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to violate any provision of this title or the regulations issued under this title;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22F14A60456844AABDA5FED9C6E03145"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to refuse to permit any authorized officer to board, search, or inspect a vessel that is subject to the person’s control in connection with the enforcement of this title or the regulations issued under this title;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDBB9C14F3544E98BB2876142E0443BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to submit false information pursuant to any requirement under this title or the regulations issued under this title; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBF9CC32D11A42EAAF3BF49050D75B6A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to commit any offense enumerated in paragraph (4), (5), (7) or (9) of section 707(a) of the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6906">16 U.S.C. 6906(a)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="HB413F5D43ECE43DC96EAF1EE931F4140"><enum>308.</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
				<subsection id="H6EB4C2CFA0E74585A3592FF39E80E820"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Existing authorities and responsibilities</header>
 <paragraph id="HBB34FE7517A648BEA43B2E3209F4735A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorities and responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authorities and responsibilities under subsections (a), (b), and (c) of section 311 and subsection (f) of section 308 of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1861">16 U.S.C. 1861</external-xref>, 1858) and paragraphs (2), (3), and (7) of section 310(b) of the Antarctic Marine Living Resources Convention Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2439">16 U.S.C. 2439(b)</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to enforcement of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H29BDDC68A8554FF497407A5FB1A6D3C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Included vessels</header><text>For purposes of enforcing this title, any reference in such paragraphs and subsections to a <quote>vessel</quote> or <quote>fishing vessel</quote> includes all vessels as defined in section 303 of this title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HADBE8796EFA3415682772A083B552534"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of other provisions</header><text>Such paragraphs and subsections apply to violations of this title and any regulations promulgated under this title.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C8A65DE770E43208571FD6B0D936BC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil enforcement</header>
					<paragraph id="HD7271BA6062B45AE85A745023F905EBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil administrative penalties</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8B455D1386E44975BD19E161C31C5D30"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who is found by the Secretary (after notice and opportunity for a hearing in accordance with section 554 of title 5, United States Code) to have committed an act prohibited under section 307 shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty. The amount of the civil penalty shall be consistent with the amount under section 308(a) of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1858">16 U.S.C. 1858(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC02BFCB79C7479989C6420FAB5934A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compromise or other action by secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall have the same authority as provided in section 308(e) of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1858">16 U.S.C. 1858(e)</external-xref>) with respect to a violation of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19D84567A9B149D2B0549302557A7332"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In rem jurisdiction</header><text>For purposes of this title, the conditions for in rem liability shall be consistent with section 308(d) of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1858">16 U.S.C. 1858(d)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D84DDBBAB5B4F998318F06C74C2B2CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Action upon failure to pay assessment</header><text>If any person fails to pay an assessment of a civil penalty under this title after it has become a final and unappealable order, or after the appropriate court has entered final judgment in favor of the Secretary, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorney General, who shall recover the amount assessed in any appropriate district court of the United States. In such action, the validity and appropriateness of the final order imposing the civil penalty shall not be subject to review.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD37B41C390E243B895EBC4A03E4D6994"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header>
 <paragraph id="H1735A058FCEF4AFB83B5495F61974D6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any foreign vessel (including its fishing gear, furniture, appurtenances, stores, and cargo) used, and any fish (or the fair market value thereof) imported or possessed in connection with or as result of the commission of any act prohibited by section 307 of this title shall be subject to forfeiture under section 310 of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1860">16 U.S.C. 1860</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H154A6FFE828647BF82E25C347E3A6895"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of the customs laws</header><text>All provisions of law relating to seizure, summary judgment, and judicial forfeiture and condemnation for violation of the customs laws, the disposition of the property forfeited or condemned or the proceeds from the sale thereof, the remission or mitigation of such forfeitures, and the compromise of claims shall apply to seizures and forfeitures incurred, or alleged to have been incurred, under the provisions of this title, insofar as applicable and not inconsistent with the provisions hereof. For seizures and forfeitures of property under this section by the Secretary, such duties as are imposed upon the customs officer or any other person with respect to the seizure and forfeiture of property under the customs law may be performed by such officers as are designated by the Secretary or, upon request of the Secretary, by any other agency that has authority to manage and dispose of seized property.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8DEDE759DD44FE08B37AF6627EDD981"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Presumption</header><text>For the purposes of this section there is a rebuttable presumption that all fish, or components thereof, found on board a vessel that is used or seized in connection with a violation of this title (including any regulation promulgated under this Act) were taken, obtained, or retained as a result of IUU fishing or fishing-related activities in support of IUU fishing.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB085F06332D4435D9283756C46C6552C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criminal enforcement</header><text>Any person (other than a foreign government agency, or entity wholly owned by a foreign government) who knowingly commits an act prohibited by section 307 shall be subject to subsections (b) and (c) of section 309 of the Magnuson-Stevens Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1859">16 U.S.C. 1859</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEF59282B1DFD404CBB74B9BDF3F7AF6B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Payment of storage, care, and other costs</header><text>Any person assessed a civil penalty for, or convicted of, any violation of this title (including any regulation promulgated under this title) and any claimant in a forfeiture action brought for such a violation, shall be liable for the reasonable costs incurred by the Secretary in storage, care, and maintenance of any property seized in connection with the violation.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H6C3F80F0815D46678CE7D4A7AC9A4C70"><enum>309.</enum><header>International cooperation and assistance</header>
 <subsection id="H7BB845B00DAF41BFB3A6579C89F6D015"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assistance to developing nations and international organizations</header><text>Consistent with existing authority and the availability of funds, the Secretary shall provide appropriate assistance to developing nations and international organizations of which such nations are members to assist those nations in meeting their obligations under the Agreement.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H72A20B7E9DAD40518229455B9F5EF6CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personnel, services, equipment, and facilities</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may, by agreement, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, utilize the personnel, services, equipment, and facilities of any Federal, State, local, or foreign government or any entity of any such government.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H357F0C493B1040D18948102E5B952B29"><enum>310.</enum><header>Relationship to other laws</header>
 <subsection id="H39310A22A7C04D56983FC7BD024C5515"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this title shall be construed to displace any requirements imposed by the customs laws of the United States or any other laws or regulations enforced or administered by the Secretary of Homeland Security. Where more stringent requirements regarding port entry or access to port services exist under other Federal law, those more stringent requirements shall apply. Nothing in this title shall affect a vessel’s entry into port, in accordance with international law, for reasons of force majeure or distress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5A9E7BCAFA74BAAA7AF802306D2116D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United States obligations under international law</header><text>This title shall be interpreted and applied in accordance with United States obligations under international law.</text>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


