<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S738 IS: Genetically Engineered Salmon Risk Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 738</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150312">March 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To reduce the risks associated with genetically altered salmon in the United States, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Genetically Engineered Salmon Risk Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id4A354D142146461BAF88EC446EF45565"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to—</text> <paragraph id="id12E7CA326AC84C4B99BF927D12ABA372"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minimize the risk that genetically engineered salmon will be introduced into the marine environment off the coasts of Alaska, Washington, Oregon, and California; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6D60A1016244470A8E1DF17B9F977AED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that consumers in the United States can make informed decisions when purchasing salmon.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idFF2FE02733A64958AAF1FA725BD52768"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</header> <subsection id="idCFFC61E4451648D8935832DC1E4366A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Labeling requirement</header><text>Section 403 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68FD9130E6584C06915D7D6DA9E3CA74" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id5BD1866B706F4EB582FAF1902D65E41C"><enum>(z)</enum><text>If it contains genetically engineered salmon unless the food bears a label stating that fact.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9D7E73BB95704FEBA93B5D2B6038467B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for environmental impact statement</header><text>Section 512 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360b">21 U.S.C. 360b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4D90268ECF1E40B2A87AFF7A8F1B113D" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" id="id2D86D1CAC7994D149C9F6510294EF20A"><enum>(q)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idAB444B00EE6D4885843F4F9FDEC317D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Prior to the approval of any application filed under this section for genetically engineered salmon intended for human consumption, the Secretary, in consultation with the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere of the Department of Commerce, shall prepare an environmental impact statement (focused on the coast of the United States from California to Alaska) in accordance with section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id5001E03B4E5840AFB4474BB548033C34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an environmental risk analysis that assesses the potential direct and indirect impacts from escapement of covered fish on wild and cultured fish stocks and environments that may be exposed to such covered fish;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idF356B17A027642C6A5B260814F5FBEB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a failure mode and effects analysis that quantitatively assesses the best- and worst-case probabilities of failure of each applicable confinement technique;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE54197545C07495982B0217E0A2385B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of the costs of control or eradication of escaped covered fish; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id73A4D5000D9B43B7B49A85EA9FDB69B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of the potential economic damage in terms of loss of production and sales to relevant wild and cultured fish stocks and environments from the escapement of covered fish.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id3AC0DE684A63492AB680728E965FCB44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term “covered fish” means a salmon or other anadromous or marine fish, live or dead, including the gametes, fertilized eggs, offspring, and descendants thereof, that is modified or produced using DNA from an organism’s own genome or that of another species, which overcome natural physiological reproductive barriers and which are not techniques used in traditional breeding and selection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


