<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S856 IS: Stop Sexual Abuse by School Personnel Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 856</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150324">March 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require criminal background checks
			 for school employees.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id82DDEEEDA06F409FACEC4A8F2C965DE8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Sexual Abuse by School Personnel Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idF08D7504E8E841CBB8F89F963542CB22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Criminal background checks for school employees</header> <subsection id="idF307EB0BAB744F528FB35EC57512D873"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart 2 of part E of title IX of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7901">20 U.S.C. 7901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ddb3802dd88483dbaaf2255555fcd47" style="OLC">
					<section id="idf9c7158df3cb448cac7fac7abf870cd8"><enum>9537.</enum><header>Criminal background checks for school employees</header>
						<subsection id="id2dcf5f79357c4cf382b13f3b9db23a86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criminal background check requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="id03ff6ea212604f1aaed2a55573c88d7e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State educational agency and local educational agency that receives funds under this Act shall have in effect policies and procedures that require a criminal background check for each school employee in each covered school served by such State educational agency and local educational agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idad61d7c427c04fb28f2a009cc843d97b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A background check required under paragraph (1) shall be conducted and administered by—</text> <subparagraph id="id4e9940fe0e58400982f327c16670985b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23171d99b7ca499ca2c1125040d9d167"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State educational agency; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc93a0fdba2e4d049873fe3779ae38aa"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the local educational agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id010c50c87581446c9c1c51a8b90eac61"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State and local uses of funds</header><text>A State, State educational agency, or local educational agency that receives funds under this Act may use such funds to establish, implement, or improve policies and procedures on background checks for school employees required under subsection (a) to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id38615d6a7d8040eaa86339f89b11f779"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expand the registries or repositories searched when conducting background checks, such as—</text> <subparagraph id="id00b45f0c89564185a784f01f9eca4275"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State criminal registry or repository of the State in which the school employee resides;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id767f95a3020841f5a72c726de2d82fa3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State-based child abuse and neglect registries and databases of the State in which the school employee resides;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ed5354cb4d5411491d50bf9fa68c48d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation fingerprint check using the Integrated Automated Fingerprint Identification System; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b08323390ec4826ad84a3ad4b78007f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the National Sex Offender Registry established under section 119 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16919">42 U.S.C. 16919</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5d604a8e9934749abfb19f54af36ada"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide school employees with training and professional development on how to recognize, respond to, and prevent child abuse;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd555e234e13d4e11b396b6234e35f558"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop, implement, or improve mechanisms to assist covered local educational agencies and covered schools in effectively recognizing and quickly responding to incidents of child abuse by school employees;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id54d56493d9124c2db65249c4779a57c6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop and disseminate information on best practices and Federal, State, and local resources available to assist local educational agencies and schools in preventing and responding to incidents of child abuse by school employees;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf3f91aea5cc54060a127523236202522"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop professional standards and codes of conduct for the appropriate behavior of school employees;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb2705366b1044ad4b4f02f2a31d3ec5f"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establish, implement, or improve policies and procedures for covered State educational agencies, covered local educational agencies, or covered schools to provide the results of background checks to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id071dfe7b5b464d9f967dfe2699061e3c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals subject to the background checks in a statement that indicates whether the individual is ineligible for such employment due to the background check and includes information related to each disqualifying crime;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49a4a2b25b6f4e1ab2170e23d3e4b421"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the employer in a statement that indicates whether a school employee is eligible or ineligible for employment, without revealing any disqualifying crime or other related information regarding the individual;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3d04ee902fb4884bff31ee7710f0db7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>another employer in the same State or another State, as permitted under State law, without revealing any disqualifying crime or other related information regarding the individual; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d2073a8d59b464da9a7b8ecd7779084"><enum>(D)</enum><text>another local educational agency in the same State or another State that is considering such school employee for employment, as permitted under State law, without revealing any disqualifying crime or other related information regarding the individual;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1db5f5f63cc648e29a223fc4bde4afeb"><enum>(7)</enum><text>establish, implement, or improve procedures that include periodic background checks, which also allows for an appeals process as described in paragraph (8), for school employees in accordance with State policies or the policies of covered local educational agencies served by the covered State educational agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc6881cc3ed9b4b6cbc9af66f2bdd4083"><enum>(8)</enum><text>establish, implement, or improve a process by which a school employee may appeal the results of a background check, which process is completed in a timely manner, gives each school employee notice of an opportunity to appeal, and instructions on how to complete the appeals process;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc7fed848cc8142aea274ebefc25bfae7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>establish, implement, or improve a review process through which the covered State educational agency or covered local educational agency may determine that a school employee disqualified due to a crime is eligible for employment due to mitigating circumstances as determined by a covered local educational agency or a covered State educational agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id34046ad58f7942828bbe378722f8fec7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>establish, implement, or improve policies and procedures intended to ensure a covered State educational agency or covered local educational agency does not knowingly transfer or facilitate the transfer of a school employee if the agency knows that employee has engaged in sexual misconduct, as defined by State law, with an elementary school or secondary school student;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id253c65b932924e7e89c688c60cece388"><enum>(11)</enum><text>provide that policies and procedures are published on the website of the covered State educational agency and the website of each covered local educational agency served by the covered State educational agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id402c7fab4405408384a6c72781443aa3"><enum>(12)</enum><text>provide school employees with training regarding the appropriate reporting of incidents of child abuse under section 106(b)(2)(B)(i) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106a">42 U.S.C. 5106a(b)(2)(B)(i)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfff6a34ccfb34e59a4a7be3a8f751d1b"><enum>(13)</enum><text>support any other activities determined by the State to protect student safety or improve the comprehensiveness, coordination, and transparency of policies and procedures on criminal background checks for school employees in the State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd509c6050bd44f79aa58fe6a1eadc4a4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No private right of action</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to create a private right of action if a State, covered State educational agency, covered local educational agency, or covered school is in compliance with State regulations and requirements concerning background checks.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idbd571d894d784453b2abd9a32fadd2c2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Background check fees</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting States or local educational agencies from charging school employees for the costs of processing applications and administering a background check as required by State law, provided that the fees charged to school employees do not exceed the actual costs to the State or local educational agency for the processing and administration of the background check.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf86f858c51aa47728ca9195e06d8f6c4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State and local plan requirements</header><text>Each plan submitted by a State or local educational agency under title I shall include—</text> <paragraph id="id64870fafcf9a402b9dbafa4a4c105e1c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assurance that the State and local educational agency has in effect policies and procedures that meet the requirements of this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddcd15d082ea84f9eae079b4f5f1d5957"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of laws, regulations, or policies and procedures in effect in the State for conducting background checks for school employees designed to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idf3d9a83f59aa4da3b2da546de9d398a5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>terminate individuals in violation of State background check requirements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2fcef5c5e1ea4257aaaa7bfedfce47a2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve the reporting of violations of the background check requirements in the State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id044e1e5c59814029ae8e0b8dc973d2ca"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduce the instance of school employee transfers following a substantiated violation of the State background check requirements by a school employee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc21c96f9691541cca4fe3fa55cf9c71c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide for a timely process by which a school employee may appeal the results of a criminal background check;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87b01d25a801433bac98080257b6f5c0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide each school employee, upon request, with a copy of the results of the criminal background check, including a description of the disqualifying item or items, if applicable;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45e1005bb0a242c7a422267280a49aa9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide the results of the criminal background check to the employer in a statement that indicates whether a school employee is eligible or ineligible for employment, without revealing any disqualifying crime or other related information regarding the individual; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id697f9c60a7764c669db10ea9bb3b869b"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provide for the public availability of the policies and procedures for conducting background checks.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6c518ed92ab34118a4692bcd485f0ead"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical assistance to states, school districts, and schools</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Attorney General, shall provide technical assistance and support to States, local educational agencies, and schools, which shall include, at a minimum—</text>
 <paragraph id="id0babbf703e8a407db1d2329e100d0420"><enum>(1)</enum><text>developing and disseminating a comprehensive package of materials for States, State educational agencies, local educational agencies, and schools that outlines steps that can be taken to prevent and respond to child sexual abuse by school personnel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1d526271ea0e4917880bbec41d01858c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determining the most cost-effective way to disseminate Federal information so that relevant State educational agencies and local educational agencies, child welfare agencies, and criminal justice entities are aware of such information and have access to it; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8245b685faab4a00b33e774c9a63e39c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying mechanisms to better track and analyze the prevalence of child sexual abuse by school personnel through existing Federal data collection systems, such as the School Survey on Crime and Safety, the National Child Abuse and Neglect Data System, and the National Crime Victimization Survey.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2bf252d591b74521a91471daebcf9c88"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="id07f6bd64f62944c59d18619cc4c26107"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to the secretary</header><text>A covered State educational agency or covered local educational agency that uses funds pursuant to this section shall report annually to the Secretary on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1a0e1c9e910f432693e119efe27fa009"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of funds used; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1aa73c06c6f44a3bbc555c5971e89e30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the purpose for which the funds were used under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id41ea7657066243498c0de76a7be4952b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary’s report card</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2017, and annually thereafter, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall transmit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives a national report card that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id54fa33ff135d456a882d57a56826dc72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>actions taken pursuant to subsection (f), including any best practices identified under such subsection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d9e252f9af74c03b9e33264aa3b7f6e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incidents of reported child sexual abuse by school personnel, as reported through existing Federal data collection systems, such as the School Survey on Crime and Safety, the National Child Abuse and Neglect Data System, and the National Crime Victimization Survey.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf8357eb1641d49a1879005caf8f7330e"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rules of construction regarding background checks</header>
 <paragraph id="id2f16a4d6ead64b75bddd2cc0869486bd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No Federal control</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize an officer or employee of the Federal Government to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id88fb2a40a9654ff3b40e91f636320d52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mandate, direct, or control the background check policies or procedures that a State or local educational agency develops or implements under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id971995760dad46ab9de2aa1d3ddcd2b6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish any criterion that specifies, defines, or prescribes the background check policies or procedures that a State or local educational agency develops or implements under this section; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id595d70b98e5a4712a201f31882d7c12a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require a State or local educational agency to submit such background check policies or procedures for approval.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id924bca9ec6464dbc85e5086ac77ab9bb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on regulation</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Secretary to establish any criterion that—</text> <subparagraph id="idaddaef993434418c9cf11484105c1253"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prescribes, or specifies requirements regarding, background checks for school employees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7b88d165edd45df9479480c50713ac3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>defines the term <term>background checks</term>, as such term is used in this section; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA6D2043A9DFC4420B2327AA65C3237D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requires a State or local educational agency to report additional data elements or information to the Secretary not otherwise explicitly authorized under this section or any other Federal law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id16562a17b5e441bca3fc8b49a9b003ef"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id2ab45bda3cdc450db7d9d125b1f696d7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency that receives funds under this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb6351b45c917489c971053e917008b04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered school</term> means a public elementary school or public secondary school, including a public elementary or secondary charter school, that receives funds under this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id118c314f636c4a39be443ab95a2ceb04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered State educational agency</term> means a State educational agency that receives funds under this Act; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id583217f8601d4f6d84ad52d65b366c39"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>school employee</term> includes, at a minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1a71a30e8ada4d44889160364afd60af"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee of, or a person seeking employment with, a covered school, covered local educational agency, or covered State educational agency and who, as a result of such employment, has (or, in the case of a person seeking employment, will have) a job duty that includes unsupervised contact or interaction with elementary school or secondary school students; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a98990287944f16845ce474f4ba4829"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person, or any employee of any person, who has a contract or agreement to provide services with a covered school, covered local educational agency, or covered State educational agency, and such person or employee, as a result of such contract or agreement, has a job duty that includes unsupervised contact or unsupervised interaction with elementary school or secondary school students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idD9BD04D5180D4288ABE3A96DE64594B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 9536 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="idf0018266-8ae6-444a-85b4-810a153bfdb3" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="idf9c7158df3cb448cac7fac7abf870cd8" level="section">Sec. 9537. Criminal background checks for school employees.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


