<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1739 IS: Truck Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1739</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150709">July 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To increase the minimum levels of financial responsibility for transporting property, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Truck Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idFB45C0132FA04E62837126AE476A2663" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minimum amounts</header> <subsection id="id3A93855E3F004DA2A43EB9FCC5F9D013"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transporting property</header> <paragraph id="id8B41524B7D944C54A28B0EDB38511742"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 31139(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idFA4B763574FC444BB552EA6AC1A1F717"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>$750,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,500,000</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8E220576940E433AA49178E54417CA60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6AF68E2167F04A5DBECD62598D60BA23" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id3D86D1A7E0C64F4FBF67BC6A181D0FBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The minimum level of financial responsibility under paragraph (2) shall be adjusted annually by the Secretary to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index—All Urban Consumers.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF19BD6DFB747495FAC73539DCD4F2F59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB981522C49294EF88A26A78D776DADBF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation, by regulation, shall increase any minimum level of financial responsibility required under section 31138 or section 31139 if, after an opportunity for notice and comment, the Secretary determines that the current amount is insufficient to satisfy liability amounts covering the claims described in section 31138 or section 31139, as applicable.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id2DF8BE5DC266417485508577C3144F7F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Collision avoidance technologies</header>
 <subsection id="id41BEE290CD6E4459B75BA085E050E822"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall initiate a rulemaking to establish a Federal motor vehicle safety standard requiring a motor vehicle with a gross vehicle weight rating greater than 26,000 pounds be equipped with crash avoidance and mitigation systems, such as forward collision warning systems, forward collision automatic braking systems, and lane departure warning systems.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3ACC56E55ACD4DC7A5B8CC3A30D68D8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Performance and standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall establish performance requirements and standards to prevent collisions with moving vehicles and stopped vehicles.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id82CE63DB04C544628B41FE4F8FE9B14A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue a final rule not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and the regulations prescribed by the Secretary under this section shall take effect 2 years after the date of publication of the final rule.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id9E7F2C6BA6954D94993137E35C799776"><enum>4.</enum><header>Speed limiting devices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall finalize regulations to require a motor vehicle with a gross vehicle weight rating greater than 26,000 pounds to be equipped with an electronic control module requiring the speed to be set at no more than 70 miles per hour by the manufacturer.</text>
		</section><section id="id25555FBB99CF4BB1A4242F0ECD4853F1"><enum>5.</enum><header>High-risk carrier compliance reviews</header>
 <subsection id="idB5157A7481D94AEBB86D10BDF03B4BE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>High-Risk carrier compliance reviews</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 31104(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>From the funds authorized by this subsection, the Secretary shall ensure that a review is completed on each motor carrier that demonstrates through performance data that it poses the highest safety risk. At a minimum, a review shall be conducted whenever a motor carrier is among the highest risk carriers for 2 consecutive months.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id835775A650BD494E90E22D3F2A8F3684"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall transmit to Congress a report on the actions the Secretary has taken to comply with the review requirement under section 31104(b) of title 49, United States Code, as amended, including the number of high-risk motor carriers identified and the high-risk motor carriers reviewed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id06A9600940CC40099AA3CA361341D458"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4138 of the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/31144">49 U.S.C. 31144</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id708362D3CB5D4010A74DFE9DC9DC04BC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Driver compensation</header>
 <subsection id="idBF2C550398C145B4A349C9A489538595"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/311">Chapter 311</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/31139">section 31139</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA89DD482B5124A24A9683868ECA1B619" style="USC">
					<section id="id21CD304E3C174F2B8753E495D24F13B0"><enum>31140.</enum><header>Driver compensation</header>
 <subsection id="idFD03ED2EA2964744B732D943600991EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation by regulation shall require that a motor carrier—</text>
 <paragraph id="idC7CFE07DD2234CC58E303F46B37AEC75"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">track the on-duty (not driving) time of an employee whose base compensation is calculated in a manner other than an hourly wage and who is required to keep a record of duty status under the hours of service regulations prescribed by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6B4118011A2C4FFBAC2C0116FB338153"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">separately compensate the employee for any on-duty (not driving) time period at an hourly rate not less than the Federal minimum wage rate under section 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idECDC0BC362FB4FFAA191BB749D707610"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to an employee whose employment is governed by a collective bargaining agreement, negotiated by employee representatives certified as bona fide by the National Labor Relations Board, if the agreement governs, and compensates the employee for all hours of on-duty (not driving) time.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id39BC478F568948E2A610B611D081E279"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section or regulations adopted under this section shall affect an employer’s obligations under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>). Compensation of employees under this section and regulations promulgated under this section shall be in addition to other compensation calculated for purposes of determining compliance with the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idD563AAFC49464423A5FE9B9A99183056"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/311">chapter 311</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/31139">section 31139</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2475CE91DC4044DB8DCF4443F4C84141" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">31140. Driver compensation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="idEF98EC65CD6C48DE91D971FAA34DA1F1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Study on commercial motor vehicle driver commuting</header>
 <subsection id="idED43BD0FC2E844F7A0E61FB3765A3878"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effects of excessive commuting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration shall conduct a study of the effects of excessive commuting on safety and commercial motor vehicle driver fatigue.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0F00EF98EA934693B509DC30EB5B30D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study, the Administrator shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="idAA85FE32A76E4E5DBCB3EFBF04D6B353"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the prevalence of excessive driver commuting in the commercial motor vehicle industry, including the number and percentage of drivers who commute;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id344623D228214DEBAD306F11C2CDAE06"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the distances traveled, time zones crossed, time spent commuting, and methods of transportation used;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id56D4320B81C140CCB77D2C477EFE7460"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research on the impact of excessive commuting on safety and commercial motor vehicle driver fatigue;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id77F54D525C244E63911BEF02AC244C51"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the commuting practices of commercial motor vehicle drivers and policies of motor carriers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC0E494D616FF41608446125604F2F1CC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration regulations, policies, and guidance regarding excessive driver commuting; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id994BCEABD9AA439F89AEF116C13C9AD4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other matters the Administrator considers appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF40A95F3E4AD4E1FADA7BB9709AFCFA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report containing its findings under the study and any recommendations for regulatory or administrative action concerning excessive driver commuting.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


