<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2223 IS: Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2223</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151029">October 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain Bureau of Land Management land from the
			 Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for
			 inclusion in the Black Hills National Cemetery, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id8A9469089F6140CFBD20C6F380A3E715"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idd5700745a21a41848f76f90cfcc3a959"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cemetery</header><text>The term <term>Cemetery</term> means the Black Hills National Cemetery in Sturgis, South Dakota.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id316D2B11A7C14B51848EC8027B9FFE9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <quote>Federal land</quote> means the approximately 200 acres of Bureau of Land Management land adjacent to the Cemetery, generally depicted as <quote>Proposed National Cemetery Expansion</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Proposed Expansion of Black Hills National Cemetery-South Dakota</quote> and dated September 28, 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7BBF34A64F2C411DB7916D31A81984C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="id78F215F4E4F048C6B51D776271488DD3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer and withdrawal of Bureau of Land Management land for Cemetery use</header> <subsection id="idE20D21F0630F4254B174E747AD273210"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of administrative jurisdiction</header> <paragraph id="idDB4C3C18AE2549AFA34CD4C30E999800"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, administrative jurisdiction over the Federal land is transferred from the Secretary to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for use as a national cemetery in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/24">chapter 24</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id2C44FB4522D74C0E932E669B78FABAAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Legal descriptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5B627B9653114309A791C6708E136A48"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a notice containing a legal description of the Federal land.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e2ee3f43bb8444fbf96f242ac60da72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>A legal description published under subparagraph (A) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the legal description.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb426522c9cc43db8dd4d410578537ee"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Copies of the legal description published under subparagraph (A) shall be available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of—</text>
 <clause id="idfb3f94b05c3947c6bd743fb2fd8b1af1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management; and</text> </clause><clause id="id45402ab471954ae08a8c3fcb282789ff"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Cemetery Administration.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id826d74271bb54794b194f720d1bbe2f2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall reimburse the Secretary for the costs incurred by the Secretary in carrying out this paragraph, including the costs of any surveys and other reasonable costs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id22c2360ba32f4a14bb2c4462199e26da"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, for any period during which the Federal land is under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Federal land—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1f81c57629834183b80a994a6acc44e8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is withdrawn from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws, the mineral leasing laws, and the geothermal leasing laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1b6a7849af844a95a5ace589a877b5e2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be treated as property as defined under section 102(9) of title 40, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBFB409DCB3F84A629CA82908C10054FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Boundary modification</header><text>The boundary of the Cemetery is modified to include the Federal land.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5CB0B4DFD0CE420088CB3EBBA05EF457"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Modification of public land order</header><text>Public Land Order 2112, dated June 6, 1960 (25 Fed. Reg. 5243), is modified to exclude the Federal land.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id2eb7bac389bc4b7a8b192879043a9496"><enum>4.</enum><header>Subsequent transfer of administrative jurisdiction</header>
 <subsection id="id94d1d99ca9b84bb994f6905e97809fd6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>On a determination by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs that all or a portion of the Federal land is not being used for purposes of the Cemetery, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall notify the Secretary of the determination.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id80E9894B94D74735B725EB168970EAAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of administrative jurisdiction</header><text>Subject to subsections (c) and (d), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall transfer to the Secretary administrative jurisdiction over the Federal land subject to a notice under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id39d7a301efaf409eb255110bfe83146b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Decontaminaton</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall be responsible for the costs of any decontamination of the Federal land subject to a notice under subsection (a) that the Secretary determines to be necessary for the Federal land to be restored to public land status.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idd6ba822c6cb94a52961eb9d7a5dcf05d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restoration to public land status</header><text>The Federal land subject to a notice under subsection (a) shall only be restored to public land status on—</text>
 <paragraph id="id383F255722C249F9BD6AB47A4B544811"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acceptance by the Secretary of the Federal land subject to the notice; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6F83435585F546ABBF277D7266E5BBA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a determination by the Secretary that the Federal land subject to the notice is suitable for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id48E69E42668045E4922A76CC74F972E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restoration to public land status; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id394569280D0D4BB085183C4B120064D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the operation of one or more of the public land laws with respect to the Federal land.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfa36e9c7a6534b5782b3116fbc332149"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Order</header><text>If the Secretary accepts the Federal land under subsection (d)(1) and makes a determination of suitability under subsection (d)(2), the Secretary may—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6E867E9E4A264CB991B347B8E0C3FBB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>open the accepted Federal land to operation of 1 or more of the public land laws; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idFAE25A6CFC874D52A895EDE8AB91C07B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue an order to carry out the opening authorized under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


