<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S244 IS: To require an independent comprehensive review of the process by which the Department of Veterans Affairs assesses cognitive impairments that result from traumatic brain injury for purposes of awarding disability compensation, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 244</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require an independent comprehensive review of the process by which the Department of Veterans
			 Affairs assesses cognitive impairments that result from traumatic brain
			 injury for purposes of awarding disability compensation, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id7CC8DCD7D2C94365B9ED39877D2A203E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Independent review of process by which Department of Veterans Affairs assesses cognitive
			 impairments that result from traumatic brain
 injury for purposes of awarding disability compensation</header><subsection id="id951C2F24AC2F48809C7CB56DB1130B0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agreement</header><paragraph id="id5D78E9F25DA743B7A1E64A914EEBAF50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall seek to enter into an agreement with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies to perform the services covered by this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF9792AC6659842B2BAEAEEFF2AD3A9D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall seek to enter into the agreement described in paragraph (1) not later than the latest date by which the Secretary considers reasonable for the Institute of Medicine to begin performing the services covered by this section and complete them before the date described subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id51A7004555284AFCB0992FA1704D94B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comprehensive review</header><paragraph id="id59BBCADCD594491DADC4D62A5E875DD8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under an agreement between the Secretary and the Institute of Medicine under this section, the Institute of Medicine shall conduct a comprehensive review of examinations provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs to individuals who submit claims to the Secretary for compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for traumatic brain injury to assess the cognitive impairments of such individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2C10BB418A8342798D72D874C45B7637"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The comprehensive review carried out pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id4AB8EFC2EB2143FA95C48F0E61D8C9B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A determination of the adequacy of the tools and protocols used by the Department to provide examinations described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5226760001204EF79C29A16F5A1056FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A determination of which credentials are necessary for health care specialists and providers to perform such portions of such examinations that relate to assessment of cognitive functions, such as a neuropsychological evaluation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id46F169E286734911869CEFFC154B57F8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Group of experienced health care providers</header><text>In carrying out the comprehensive review pursuant to paragraph (1), the Institute of Medicine shall convene a group of experts in clinical neuropsychology and other related disciplines.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA14FD654F13B46D599963B60A09BE6F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="id1959959D4B6F49B7988CE1EDBD543844"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date on which the Secretary enters into an agreement under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the comprehensive review conducted under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2C98AB46BC86442DAFE29B486891C25A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id752CC5580AC641129E97867B704B3F6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The findings of the Institute of Medicine with respect to the comprehensive review conducted under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8532D67872C740F7A594009906783090"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Institute of Medicine may have for the improvement of the adjudication of claims described in subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAB61CB6E70EC4710BC4EDC8251A98D6E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Alternate contract organization</header><paragraph id="id16E5B226AF2243E5B7606CEC710A77EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary is unable within the period prescribed in subsection (a)(2) to enter into an agreement described in subsection (a)(1) with the Institute of Medicine on terms acceptable to the Secretary, the Secretary shall seek to enter into such an agreement with another appropriate organization that—</text><subparagraph id="id95194A84492840DE92250B98E4704701"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not part of the Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86668C0D80E0426CB2EC100B334FE404"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operates as a not-for-profit entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB17ACDA7D78541899284AFF2080A4E9B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has expertise and objectivity comparable to that of the Institute of Medicine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEEC7F5F5697449F593DE81794D6049CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text>If the Secretary enters into an agreement with another organization as described in paragraph (1), any reference in this section to the Institute of Medicine shall be treated as a reference to the other organization.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


