<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2017 IS: To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to recognize Alexander Creek, Alaska, as a Native village, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2017</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150909">September 9, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to recognize Alexander Creek, Alaska, as a Native
			 village, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB8CCCC82D9554ED1B0FAB249E73A72B6" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE60635CE037C4EA294566079EA07C2AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Alexander Creek Village recognition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HE50E4509785B41AEAD5DF3138BA9D53A" style="OLC">
				<section id="HAA31344676074821B1F4F4772E092061"><enum>43.</enum><header>Alexander Creek Village recognition</header>
 <subsection id="H3BCD6258E5DA453B80D8BAE974CB28B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H41E4AC1A0B404B88B558D073E393EDE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H30061C3FC0024C92B609B68606C6894D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any instrumentality of the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF61B698347A94289823225FFB9A2CC23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any element of an agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0864A5C593A7407F95319FEBCBE0261E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any wholly owned or mixed-owned corporation of the Federal Government identified in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/91">chapter 91</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CFD416707864EDDAE4C5DF5D78ED409"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alexander Creek</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Alexander Creek</term> means Alexander Creek, Incorporated, a Village Corporation recognized and organized pursuant to section (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D59DB0F567D44AA8D6ADFD952ABCC25"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Region</header><text>The term <term>Region</term> means Cook Inlet Region Incorporated, a Regional Corporation, which is the appropriate Regional Corporation for Alexander Creek under section 14(h).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A9AD1AA414F4E29AAF3433F77FAEE31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recognition of the village of Alexander Creek</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the limitations of this section and notwithstanding subsection (d) of section 1432 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/487">Public Law 96–487</external-xref>; 94 Stat. 2543) or any conveyance under that section, Alexander Creek, Incorporated, a Group Corporation organized pursuant to this Act located within T. 15 N., R. 7 W., Seward Meridian, Alaska, is recognized as an eligible Native village under section 11(b)(3).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H67F9DC3135F940E0BEAABA2E3E0BEF2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Organization of Alexander Creek</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this section, Alexander Creek shall file in the State—</text>
 <paragraph id="H886E1C1A493048C9B1A135ABF9A65D08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any amendments to the corporate charter of Alexander Creek that are necessary to convert from a Group Corporation to a Village Corporation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7D5EDD7F5C14C8A850A64980B854A77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any amendments to the corporate charter and governing business documents of Alexander Creek that are necessary to fulfill the terms of the agreement authorized under subsection (d).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H196CD4769ED4479BA48536301AE33EA5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Negotiations; agreement</header>
 <paragraph id="id5B0DDC1733B44BAE9EBAD2C62C4D2D62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall commence negotiations with Alexander Creek to fairly and equitably settle any aboriginal land claims and any other claims that Alexander Creek has against the United States.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="idDD279C6D14A040EA818F256CAD2AB808"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agreement</header>
 <subparagraph id="id069D94AA92084426BB57D58E77650B3B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 13 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with Alexander Creek relating to the claims described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2D203260AFD14123A8E1F4EF9795B7BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the prior status of Alexander Creek as a Group Corporation, an agreement under this paragraph shall be in approximate value parity, considering inflation, with agreements of other Village Corporations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB56101F3C77442D486FAA3085E260C33"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds to be provided for Alexander Creek under an agreement entered into under this paragraph shall be available subject to appropriations.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id647BCE2ADC7B4DDE8FD3A0C1F2428627"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Applicable law</header>
 <clause id="idB33626D90DC946F98935EC2ECF3FCFA0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out an agreement entered into under this paragraph—</text> <subclause id="id84FC9F7612F0445D9C3BB9B7CC350835"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with this section and other existing authorities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id48089AB8AD9B4F9B93ED8CF8CE5F5F22"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in coordination with the Administrator of General Services pursuant to section 549 of title 40, United States Code, with respect to property to be transferred to Alexander Creek pursuant to the agreement, subject to clause (ii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id17394AAB4D674AE4870F3C51C0C62DB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consideration as state</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 549(a) of title 40, United States Code, Alexander Creek shall be considered a <quote>State</quote> and a <quote>State agency</quote> under that section for the purposes of the Secretary carrying out an agreement under this paragraph.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB26FA9375CE74D15876C10C9E2F1AB11"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Shareholder participation</header>
 <paragraph id="idFDF2E4EBB2534C8DAA1F3F508785BE7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Alexander Creek shall notify each member of the Village Corporation recognized under subsection (b) that, as of the date of enactment of this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idABCA29ED75414D6A8C93825E604038D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the member shall cease to receive benefits from the Region as at-large shareholders pursuant to section 7(m); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB5AB7D7169264AF38A7E4A478DCEEADF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all future resource payments from the Region shall be made to the Village Corporation pursuant to section 7(j).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id40459106852749038D86E623B7479706"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><text>The Region shall not be liable under any Federal, State, or local law or under Federal or State common law for damages arising out of or related to the cessation of payments to the members of Alexander Creek described in paragraph (1)(A).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FE110C2314C465B9BFF252E169AF791"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Except as provided in this section with respect to Alexander Creek, nothing in this section—</text> <paragraph id="idAB236AD5620E493E826DB0189B117528"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies or amends any land conveyance entitlement or conveyance agreement—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE87073E8A77D4B938C40AF1D015F48A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>between the Region and a Village Corporation (other than Alexander Creek) in the Region;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0D16B36B0ACE43428A3825A8093B988A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>between the Region and the Federal Government; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1B5A2277A6984DD698526C6A3B16462D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>between any party described in subparagraph (A) or (B) and the State; or</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB44FBC969C0346FAADA48DD3CFCB8934"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduces the land entitlement to which Alexander Creek became entitled as a Group Corporation, including the land selected by and conveyed to Alexander Creek on the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


