<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2049 IS: To establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a continuing medical education program for non-Department medical professionals who treat veterans and family members of veterans to increase knowledge and recognition of medical conditions common to veterans and family members of veterans, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2049</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150917">September 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a continuing medical education program for
			 non-Department medical professionals who treat veterans and family members
			 of veterans to increase knowledge and recognition of
			 medical conditions common to veterans and family members of veterans, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Department of Veterans
			 Affairs continuing education program for certain non-Department medical
			 professionals</header>
			<subsection id="id3C672EF456A94AA0B2E4023D9D253BA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment
			 of continuing medical education program</header>
				<paragraph id="idD824980C3C9E4BABB197D6DBC3B987C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a continuing medical education program for non-Department medical professionals with the goal of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE0E86333E2544E04BAEF14223E51791A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing knowledge and recognition of medical conditions common to veterans and family members of veterans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC19C4D6DAC0A481A88897FC311E6E96A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving outreach to veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2EA9819CBD7D42F4AFB4767BBD4EE81A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Education
 provided</header><text>The program shall include education on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5A41DD915E4448A3B3631758DE56EC39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Dealing with patients who are veterans or family members of veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB16694C112E34E98833EABFC8B5A0A7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identifying and treating common mental and physical conditions of veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA0445A3421D04BEBAF409D4946EAD723"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Programs and benefits available to veterans and family members of veterans through the following organizations:</text>
 <clause id="id6DE5C3A26F764AC286949D4898943C1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDE99D913EA8B4DB691DF2A54945DA92E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Department of Labor.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idEB29345901E6444FB9FD5F0C1FF4B337"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Such other Federal agencies and non-Federal organizations as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0C1CB5F22AB94641919A186637638446"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The health care system of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD4402D2E451E433E9F508CB58C204CE7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id46FEA8E015524BD8B6345B8E6C62B242"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration of program</header><text>The program shall be carried out during the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id417E2F337A1C43D092A5BDE8BDB2A775"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration
			 of program</header>
				<paragraph id="id40E89697A27846D8A86FB6D2AACF75C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the program on an Internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idF6CC2E5D65A04B129712F0E0CD484483"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Curriculum and
 credit provided</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the curriculum of the program and the number of hours of credit to provide to participating non-Department medical professionals for continuing medical education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id471B7E98ADE94B78A38E86DA2549C464"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Accreditation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the program is accredited in as many States as practicable.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idC5B454CC0589481D96EB54DAED423BF9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consistency
 with existing rules</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the program is consistent with the rules and regulations of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id25BE866A9BD8402BB6DE36CF50C67C05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The medical licensing agency of each State in which the program is accredited.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9A65AF2F846F4570A44D5C69FB5722BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such medical credentialing organizations as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0917BA94E6B440BD96AEEC48C5C5E779"><enum>(5)</enum><header>User
 cost</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the program at no cost to participating non-Department medical professionals.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB3DCC9C9D089417388D5D57115AAC927"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Non-Department medical
			 professional defined</header>
 <paragraph id="id0AAC8706056249078EBFB06673D4F614"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <term>non-Department medical professional</term> means any individual specified in paragraph (2) who is licensed by an appropriate medical authority in the United States and in good standing, is not an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and provides care to veterans or family members of veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8955AE408A7F4717A4734DE8256068F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individual specified</header><text>An individual specified in this paragraph is any of the following individuals:</text> <subparagraph id="id0CB12E691D8F47538662BBA535618D26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A doctor.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2483D3ED83D04B80A7D3FEC08992D108"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A nurse.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1630A741E81B4CB0B34DD22154307F59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A physician assistant.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC3A8F03E299F4979957033B45DEFA720"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A psychologist.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id098BB6C6F2D0439D90343094171FFD4F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A psychiatrist.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99B5F7D82DB641A3BD1FDE31293E9080"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Such other individuals as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


