<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1379 IS: African Free Trade Initiative Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1379</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150519">May 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the African Growth and Opportunity Act to require the development of a plan for each
			 sub-Saharan African country for negotiating and entering into free trade
			 agreements and for other purposes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>African Free Trade Initiative Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id16CE4770D27D4F69B2489783A0B90EA6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Free trade agreements with sub-Saharan African countries</header>
 <subsection id="idED173FA6698346C9AB6DF9A9E0DE8B51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan requirements and reporting</header><text>Section 116 of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3723">19 U.S.C. 3723</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (b) and (c) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05C69ABF848C46F4BC098AFACEC2074C" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="id6258357E13B84540BF79B39A12E4DBE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan requirement</header>
 <paragraph id="idC24CE622EB9D427987538246D390EDEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall develop a plan for the purpose of negotiating and entering into one or more free trade agreements with all sub-Saharan African countries. The plan shall identify the 15 countries or groups of countries that are most ready for a free trade agreement with the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddef78b1fec2e4dbdba331fedf7b9c5d5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements of plan</header><text>The plan required by paragraph (1) shall include, for each sub-Saharan African country, the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd7f77f777a744b738d6531501281b16e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The steps such sub-Saharan African country needs to be equipped and ready to enter into a free trade agreement with the United States, including the development of a bilateral investment treaty.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide537481f1a934b6fb34db22003398da4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Milestones for accomplishing each step identified in subparagraph (A) for each sub-Saharan African country, with the goal of establishing a free trade agreement with each sub-Saharan African country not later than 10 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>African Free Trade Initiative Act</short-title>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcd90cccfdfe04fca94cdf3620466a17d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the resources required to assist each sub-Saharan African country in accomplishing each milestone described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34e5132f04b847fb9b7db0e4df204fdc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The extent to which steps described in subparagraph (A), the milestones described in subparagraph (B), and resources described in subparagraph (C) may be accomplished through regional or subregional organizations in sub-Saharan Africa, including the East African Community, the Economic Community of West African States, the Common Market for Eastern and Southern Africa, and the Economic Community of Central African States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd67918878beb46baa5f59e7be2efd1c2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Procedures to ensure the following:</text> <clause id="idff53614a04e5476aac57af956f2e640d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Adequate consultation with Congress and the private sector during the negotiations.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idaa32ba5ebfa440edbc45b761b31a2da2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Consultation with Congress regarding all matters relating to implementation of the agreement or agreements.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb471f499d6094f42bd2c121be40eaa68"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Approval by Congress of the agreement or agreements.</text> </clause><clause id="id5929bcad90c2480c8e4f6d71bef32430"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Adequate consultations with the relevant African governments and African regional and subregional intergovernmental organizations during the negotiation of the agreement or agreements.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide71d7b8a94eb48e6a87289aa991ec5ce"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>African Free Trade Initiative Act</short-title>, the President shall prepare and transmit to Congress a report containing the plan developed pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="id3718484E04B04B5EB266D519E447F36D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Millennium Challenge Compacts</header>
 <text>After the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Trade Representative and Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall consult and coordinate with the Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation regarding countries that have entered into a Millennium Challenge Compact pursuant to section 609 of the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7708">22 U.S.C. 7708</external-xref>) that have been declared eligible to enter into such a Compact for the purpose of developing and carrying out the plan required by subsection (b) of section 116 of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3723">19 U.S.C. 3723</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id71951FBC63C04A7C96D4E654020FC67A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coordination of USAID with Free Trade Agreement policy</header>
 <subsection id="id4a2b697ec300407cb96d33f91f5efc4e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of funds</header><text>Funds made available after the date of enactment of this Act to the United States Agency for International Development under section 496 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2293">22 U.S.C. 2293</external-xref>) may be used in consultation with the United States Trade Representative—</text>
 <paragraph id="id7D9DD653620745439FA1EFDB8DAAFD75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to carry out subsection (b) of section 116 of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3723">19 U.S.C. 3723</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(a), including for the deployment of resources in individual eligible countries to assist such country in the development of institutional capacities to carry out such subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id39DDED50CEB54DD68654BE4A84240A95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to coordinate the efforts of the United States to establish free trade agreements in accordance with the policy set out in subsection (a) of such section 116.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2C52B8AA2C1E4F7B8B107AE73FB42916"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id50AE6D3AF80B462FBD1026AA2AA12F93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible country</header><text>The term <quote>eligible country</quote> means a sub-Saharan African country that receives—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8DA4DD5FE77F45EE851A2B3CE1DF44BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>benefits under the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3701">19 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4B115409B6E94421B1CFA1585E01957F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>funding from the United States Agency for International Development.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id983CF1FEBF29438F8634F548F108F2FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sub-Saharan African country</header><text>The term <quote>sub-Saharan African country</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 107 of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3706">19 U.S.C. 3706</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


