<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1201 IS: Clean Distributed Energy Grid Integration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1201</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150506">May 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To advance the integration of clean distributed energy into electric grids, and for other purposes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Distributed Energy Grid Integration Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idE403B377BA384E9D88497020F42AB07D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id540bc6bc2c8946d7bc65aae1625bdc51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>research by the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency has found that clean distributed energy technologies can create important values for both the host facility and the electric grid operator;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBC41ABDB3B0D45238E9EEE1E48291B09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the values described in paragraph (1) can include, for the host facility—</text> <subparagraph id="idF64CB69C13464F6F8C737684C371E2D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>energy bill savings;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFD3A99CACB0D402399CFAB1349859E8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional revenue from offering ancillary services to the electric grid operator;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17BEA77E9C80465CB807C5CB7D0CB339"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increased electric reliability in the event of grid outages; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48D395B572504B46BEAA046EE7B0C244"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improved electric power quality;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5E00B330C6B7418AA8CD14D864EE89E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the values described in paragraph (1) can include, for the electric grid operator—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC5708A050BFF41839B64250ED8FA0E50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>avoiding the need for transmission and distribution upgrade investments;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2783F554632F4B078D7D983D78558A73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhanced grid stability by providing reactive power;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id977EC4B70D73414DA2D072136485857E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>voltage and frequency stabilization; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26524D3BCED643CABA63AC255F789260"><enum>(D)</enum><text>more reliable and stable operation of the grid by providing dispatchable energy to the grid during periods of insufficient capacity or supply; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6310e649fd734c7db6e207d19bd2f5af"><enum>(4)</enum><text>new advances in intelligent sensing and simulation and control technologies offer the potential to enhance the benefits of clean distributed generation to both the host facility and the electric grid operator from dynamic, adaptive, and anticipatory response to changing grid conditions.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="idDAE604C7519C4D4A931A290CE22E587D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id5223f90265a241d191ace1b8c0610171"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ancillary service</header><text>The term <term>ancillary service</term> means those services necessary to support the transmission of electric power from seller to purchaser given the obligations of control areas and transmitting utilities within those control areas to maintain reliable operations of the interconnected transmission system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id034386c383ff406bb63cabb18a794eed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clean distributed energy</header><text>The term <term>clean distributed energy</term> means energy technologies that are located on the customer site operating on the customer side of the electric meter and are interconnected with the electric grid.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id447e89f3a3734db58e43336fe2e79413"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Combined heat and power technology</header><text>The term <term>combined heat and power technology</term> means the generation of electric energy and heat in a single, integrated system that meets the efficiency criteria in clauses (ii) and (iii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48">section 48(c)(3)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, under which heat that is conventionally rejected is recovered and used to meet thermal energy requirements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd42941198805469d958290e9e79cfa9a"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Energy storage</header><text>The term <term>energy storage</term> means technologies that store electric energy and are able to discharge on demand to meet customer or grid needs for electric energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id22a84e24d25d480a9bb6c768a8f5ed3a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fuel cell</header><text>The term <term>fuel cell</term> means a device that produces electric energy directly from a chemical reaction.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idb561ff30ec714a6ba44277507a649fb5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Grid</header><text>The term <term>grid</term> means the electric grid that is composed on both distribution and transmission lines, and associated facilities, including substations, sensors, and operational controls.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4d383e3437b84dd9857c013d826a9bfb"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Intelligence</header><text>The term <term>intelligence</term> means any devices or technologies that manifest adaptive, anticipatory, and dynamic optimization behavior.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id1651149cfc63434ca9a91645d49580ed"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Qualified waste heat resource</header>
 <subparagraph id="id2a97fb0e12094084aecb9922b919252f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified waste heat resource</term> means—</text> <clause id="id76e673d69a244f92a63b2c111ded3a04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exhaust heat or flared gas from any industrial process;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb27716ffba004b5bac5ceba0e27cb06a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>waste gas or industrial tail gas that would otherwise be flared, incinerated, or vented;</text> </clause><clause id="id9885d9797f7a4cddb9b540a821a9a277"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a pressure drop in any gas for an industrial or commercial process; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd7059b8056744d63b6f27a283d426e81"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other form of waste heat resource, as determined by the Secretary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55a5b6a0a1944e1bad9a1fe5a683c3b9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>qualified waste heat resource</term> does not include a heat resource from a process the primary purpose of which is the generation of electricity using a fossil fuel.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id894F546843BF440EBC2E538EB2F19844"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idcefd6b136f424a85a3f29b7b07c704b8"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Waste heat to power technology</header><text>The term <term>waste heat to power technology</term> means a system that generates electricity through the recovery of a qualified waste heat resource.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idAD4177527A544B4E83A49E3DCF12B76B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Research and deployment plan for enhanced integration of clean distributed energy with the grid</header>
 <subsection id="idde432f04dad142519fc1e24f7f64c568"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out efforts for advancing the integration of clean distributed energy into electric grids.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ida20b5789b5704af4a2f4740d07bf7a79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report on the status of grid integration</header>
 <paragraph id="idEE281D502E6D4FE8A8B871C0548A32A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the efforts under subsection (a) and not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a study on the status of integration of clean distributed energy into the grid, identifying any issues that require additional research or regulatory development.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8e31e4153ef5411aa58e0b096daa4cd2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>In conducting the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id1d73e9a114e7471ca03048bb8ae60e9c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify and quantify the benefits to all stakeholders of expanded integration of clean distributed energy resources into the grid;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id600508e3566b45b2b869e8fc875b9d1f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify any technical issues that require research to identify solutions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id439b75f481834525b8d26543406acadf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify any regulatory barriers that inhibit the expanded integration of clean distributed energy resources into the grid.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf248ae044dc4742bb776c96aad7d255"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9761328e3ef440d9ae6aa118542c23f4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary shall use unobligated funds of the Department of Energy to carry out this subsection.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id027677fc262d42f4a263b6c5255347f8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Research into the technical barriers to the integration of clean distributed energy with the grid</header> <paragraph id="id47b34d673f694b78a711b9f3853dad34"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id558456E8989942CFB2C932AD64086156"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a solicitation for research proposals to address the technical barriers identified in the report submitted under subsection (b)(3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCB3641871D814E3CAE57DDA7DDF9D89F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make grants to those applicants with research proposals selected by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id062638572FE44FFC9FF97C5D8305E3A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall select research proposals to receive a grant under this subsection on the basis of merit, using criteria identified by the Secretary, including the likelihood that the research results will address critical barriers identified by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddaff97070a7b4e6b8882bdce5a26fb99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Beginning in the first full fiscal year following the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 2 years, the Secretary may request funding as necessary to carry out this subsection, but in no case shall funding exceed $5,000,000 in any 1 fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id701f4d74c1a74baf853861df32e7308c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Creation of a stakeholder working group</header>
 <paragraph id="id0f5ce52bd8b549d88f8fd94a6f831af7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convene a working group (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Group</quote>) to address regulatory barriers to deployment of intelligent grid integration of clean distributed energy technologies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id495d82a74137492e912d690c06e2a3d6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Group is to provide guidance on how to address the technical, regulatory and economic factors that limit widespread integration of grid-level clean distributed energy use in order to advance the integration of clean distributed energy into electric grids.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idadfe030d257649898597c9fb43e9f7e9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <subparagraph id="id801558C8557244ABBA8441C6FDFC9B25"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Group shall be composed of representatives of all groups determined by the Secretary to have a material interest in the development, implementation, siting, and integration of clean distributed energy technology or systems into the electric grid.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB2E761976EC448378D3EB8E4431AF6EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>Members shall be selected—</text> <clause id="id67E130DDF4444C7392FA18E2726AA763"><enum>(i)</enum><text>from representatives that apply as a result of a public announcement from the Secretary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDAB094C1DBAB40FE81ECBB28A74854A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by the Secretary based on qualifications and balance of interests represented by the selected individuals.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb617ff861b1a4d13ab7feaa547e5116e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Group shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="id0271c78175234304bce4be5f2f1eab1a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to review the regulatory barriers identified in the report prepared by the Secretary under subsection (b)(3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd485d5ed2d814dd88ca43a8fbc392201"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to identify any additional regulatory barriers that inhibit the installation of distributed energy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf01981a0d43743d383e652f357c2a543"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to recommend to the Secretary any actions that should be undertaken to remove these barriers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25c0a2c3ff634ee1b0988f5beef60404"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a report based on the recommendations of the Group under paragraph (4)(C), to be made publicly available.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida236c1d16edc4bb6898d2fb9c7a83e42"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary may request funding as necessary to carry out this subsection, but in no case shall funding exceed $2,000,000 in any 1 fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbaf4bbd477ed44bbb5415a39be987763"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Demonstrations of intelligent grid integration of clean distributed energy systems</header>
 <paragraph id="id6CFC99F3C5454D90919FB32EDA893BC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Based on the findings in the reports conducted under this section and not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a solicitation for demonstration of integration of distributed energy resources into the grid.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFC8D279749AC43549EDF2BD94171E4FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>Any individual entity or group of entities may submit to the Secretary proposals for demonstration projects based on the solicitation described in paragraph (1), including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE11E0A76969F4C099760BAADCEC29382"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State and local agencies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id176DCC395F424A1583863B692E593138"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public institutions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF59BE933576F488A8592AD0ABD173433"><enum>(C)</enum><text>private companies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4BEAA6482A4C41EBB10BC593509C701D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>electric utilities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6F3B2F785F0A4BC0BC9190E4558636B6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>equipment manufacturers.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBA3EFCD1542B43FDBF8A0D8C0A632B5A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Secretary may make grants, in amounts not to exceed a total of $5,000,000, to eligible entities to carry out demonstration projects, to be selected based on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id27F2E6A8E7BC4685B6A3A676C3549240"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the technical merits of the demonstration project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF8C1CB43E6894FD4B007EE5E0D38DE29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the likelihood that the demonstration project will address critical barriers identified by the Secretary under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC755A93A678243E3BAA11D04EDC887ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the share of non-Federal funds for the demonstration project.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id215832A6FF114A8F8DE7368A63961E36"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Beginning in the third full fiscal year following the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Secretary may request funding as necessary to carry out this subsection, but in no case shall funding exceed $15,000,000 in any 1 fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4DA13BC5284D477285156629086ABBF4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary annually shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="id8B5E54AEB073462DB55CF477BE8AFB95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the progress made in carrying out this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8E7C840EA0B04A6886E38917C42679E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifies any technical or regulatory issues that require legislative action.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


