<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1203 RS: 21st Century Veterans Benefits Delivery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 267</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1203</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 114–153]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150506">May 6, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S136">Mr. Cochran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSVA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20151019">October 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, with an amendment and an amendment to the title</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the processing by the Department of Veterans
			 Affairs of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of
			 Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="S1" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="idA95F3C90097649BB9B1FECED4662543D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Veterans Benefits Delivery Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idDE1A0B36B59E4F40AF76B44B2481CA69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id9D6906ACFD6D4B6EB9083F76243118ED" level="title">TITLE I—Benefits claims submission</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id39ABD1E035B24472A19076FA03400D3E" level="section">Sec. 101. Improvements to Transition Assistance Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idEC0D015A7764474FAA92E0DD3E02BF54" level="section">Sec. 102. Requirement that decisions on claims explain advantages of filing appeals within 180 days.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id23C72729B1B84954AB622334A06CD643" level="section">Sec. 103. Determination of manner of appearance for hearings before Board of Veterans' Appeals.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idFDC759902E08404FBE31DD850A111D51" level="title">TITLE II—Practices of regional offices</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idd36a86be2c58471d96b82a81e61c6be6" level="section">Sec. 201. Required Comptroller General audit of regional offices of Veterans Benefits Administration.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idAC4AAEF7B91E4E24B50A055DB64E2904" level="section">Sec. 202. Requirement for management training program for veterans service center managers of Veterans Benefits Administration.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id27CC20F88A5F4A86BDCEA1C955E94EC9" level="section">Sec. 203. Analysis of communication between regional offices of Department of Veterans Affairs and veterans service organizations and Congressional caseworkers.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idd700b4d663ca4c5889c31b6393c7b280" level="section">Sec. 204. Review of practices of regional offices regarding use of suspense dates.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id3BD35AA7738149FEB77861D21C4D82A2" level="section">Sec. 205. Annual report on capacity of Veterans Benefits Administration to process benefits claims.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id7840B8FF330544CDA5C4426595BA79E8" level="section">Sec. 206. Requirement to complete efforts to revise resource allocation model of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id62A0CA4655144FFAB9AD6EC6DDDA186D" level="section">Sec. 207. Semiannual report on progress in implementing Veterans Benefits Management System.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id49E88379EEFB41FF9A34F33EF02B99F3" level="section">Sec. 208. Report on plans of Secretary of Veterans Affairs to reduce inventory of claims for dependency and indemnity compensation and claims for pension.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="iddd5a1d8f7be24a8582a0c571b07fe580" level="section">Sec. 209. Increased transparency in Monday Morning Workload Report.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id65a3d04b28214932b98e0652e787fd13" level="section">Sec. 210. Reports on appeals of decisions on benefits claims.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF34AF2FF67C546DAAE77FF4D61CBC3C3" level="section">Sec. 211. Modification of pilot program for use of contract physicians for disability examinations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idBFF6A6B4528646618BF2E11AF9E13CB7" level="title">TITLE III—Government response</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idb17687d4c7c24efcb3e0373611463c0a" level="section">Sec. 301. Increased cooperation across Government.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idB8C131ACF78F41D0B71DAD6E45C796A9" level="section">Sec. 302. Report on interoperability between electronic health records systems of Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry></toc> </subsection></section><title changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id9D6906ACFD6D4B6EB9083F76243118ED" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Benefits claims submission</header> <section id="id39ABD1E035B24472A19076FA03400D3E"><enum>101.</enum><header>Improvements to Transition Assistance Program</header> <subsection id="id6E84A00D401E43BA848C969D6BD5A2E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification To enable online access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1144 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5F7018DB03BA407495CAE90844E3920D" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id290C4059BDD64FC3A75F22D5ADF923AC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Online access</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id327D490CEBBC4FA5BA3189D7C7789A91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor, in conjunction with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall take such actions and make such modifications to the eBenefits Internet website as may be necessary to ensure that members of the armed forces and spouses described in subsection (a)(1) can access materials from the program carried out under this section through an Internet website.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id39FE04B9D1574AFB9E6BD6A4F2871EF9" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An individual subject to a requirement under subsection (c) may not satisfy such requirement by participating in the program carried out under this section solely through an Internet website.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="id577D29A3282D4FA9925F5D28586CCF16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participation of veterans service organizations</header>
 <paragraph id="id64A84DCE945643C8ADD1F4DA0FAAA4A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense, in collaboration with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, should establish a process by which a representative of a veterans service organization may be present at any portion of the program carried out under section 1144 of title 10, United States Code, relating to the submittal of claims to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for compensation under chapter 11 or 13 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="id4C003C1B19584F55B337F36F4813522B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph id="id1565145ADFE7444BA4CD4E2E77894A96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on participation of veterans service organizations in the program carried out under section 1144 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEE707C56CABB4BADA54BAF2EF8C1944E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="idD80E9BEA98E9444599C923F69B6E2F5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An assessment of the compliance of facilities of the Department of Defense with the directives included in the memorandum of the Secretary of Defense entitled <quote>Installation Access and Support Services for Nonprofit Non-Federal Entities</quote> and dated December 23, 2014.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF3ABD0FD2ACF45999FE90028FBF9BCBF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of military bases that have complied with such directives.</text> </clause><clause id="idEEB202B874A34F40B10B204B5A6A40FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>How many veterans service organizations have been present at a portion of a program as described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE2BB436916044304A76306AA7FE740D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Veterans service organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idEC0D015A7764474FAA92E0DD3E02BF54"><enum>102.</enum><header>Requirement that decisions on claims explain advantages of filing appeals within 180 days</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5104(a) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id4786FD5D888A4B86B0613701202C21A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>In the case</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20750D6DB18C49798667579856036C5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence and inserting the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55A308D8FBC6469ABE2792833EBB9DA0" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idDE882341F7A2468AA181A1259EA7A05C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The notice shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7F14EF0541534A0A8256AD9857336918"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An explanation of the procedure for obtaining review of the decision.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE4C78B5758F9434EABAB783636C79A8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An explanation of the advantages of filing for review of the decision within 180 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section id="id23C72729B1B84954AB622334A06CD643"><enum>103.</enum><header>Determination
			 of manner of appearance for hearings before Board of Veterans' Appeals</header>
				<subsection id="id9531732AF2DF4874BCF450F73957DA07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 7107 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idA84D2124E4F8413AA72325C37D6DA2BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4E0A9B7DA28341B18675EDF36F5C1733"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (f) as subsections (f) and (g), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idECB124C008984C7D9556CA0F7891D6DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsections (d) and (e):</text> <quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1B180A20F17D4CC19EC06B8BD5E115B4" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id935D177D666C40CBB0560A45A15366F2"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD46C52E838AC4AF6AF549FC26D8C4D7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a hearing before the Board shall be conducted, as the Board considers appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id903855C314E242849AB2C03B52E104EF" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in person; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id473FA703E789468F98F5A937127FFAE5" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through picture and voice transmission, by electronic or other means, in such manner that the appellant is not present in the same location as the members of the Board during the hearing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id1BB93F60617C43D9B39BB239B2DEF44C" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon request by an appellant, a hearing before the Board shall be conducted, as the appellant considers appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idAF58A05A7C294693A2803EDBB8635851"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in person; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34C7D8189CD24657AB8D410C2B1F2F17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through picture and voice transmission as described in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id28acdc71747848cb84b6c1275336722c"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD9EE3CAF7402485AACE2EB1462B532CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In a case in which a hearing before the Board is to be conducted through picture and voice transmission as described in subsection (d)(1)(B), the Secretary shall provide suitable facilities and equipment to the Board or other components of the Department to enable an appellant located at an appropriate facility within the area served by a regional office to participate as so described.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id2195d679c1dc4be58145316766e2cc76" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any hearing conducted through picture and voice transmission as described in subsection (d)(1)(B) shall be conducted in the same manner as, and shall be considered the equivalent of, a personal hearing.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCA5D59516D1E472C8F2F45F5D3BF7A04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1), as redesignated by paragraph (2), by striking <quote>An appellant may request</quote> and all that follows through <quote>office of the Department</quote> and inserting <quote>In a case in which a hearing before the Board is to be conducted in person, the hearing shall be held at the principal location of the Board or at a facility of the Department located within the area served by a regional office of the Department.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDACBC5E56B1B49839DC1229DABD41C71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to cases received by the Board of Veterans' Appeals pursuant to notices of disagreement submitted on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="idFDC759902E08404FBE31DD850A111D51" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Practices of regional offices</header>
			<section id="idd36a86be2c58471d96b82a81e61c6be6"><enum>201.</enum><header>Required Comptroller General audit of regional offices of Veterans Benefits Administration</header>
 <subsection id="idA11E713F40C249938577221156B5B968"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall complete an audit of the regional offices of the Veterans Benefits Administration—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5D41325B5E80475799D9BC02966E4EDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to assess the consistency of decisions being made with respect to claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFB73F0B242F2488980AE96FFC2B28C2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify ways in which the consistency of such decisions can be improved.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5177419D6AFC4303963D5DC32AEF2703"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of factors and best practices</header><text>The audit conducted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idD8AA161CD015430998A4A20512E3F9E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identification of the factors, including management practices, that distinguish higher performing regional offices from other regional offices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5613A4D47C0E40DDB4AE0F590879910B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identification of best practices employed by higher performing regional offices that distinguish the performance of such offices from other regional offices.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09B56946365E41C59D00322E159D2AF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Comptroller General completes the audit required by subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the audit.</text>
				</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAC4AAEF7B91E4E24B50A055DB64E2904" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirement for management training program for veterans service center managers of Veterans
 Benefits Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a training program for veterans service center managers, or for employees in successor positions in regional offices of the Veterans Benefits Administration, on matters concerning managerial skills and such other skills as the Secretary considers appropriate for such managers.</text>
			</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27CC20F88A5F4A86BDCEA1C955E94EC9"><enum>203.</enum><header>Analysis of communication between regional offices of Department of Veterans Affairs and veterans
			 service organizations and Congressional caseworkers</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE677D67820F84EBA8E3BECCC1D02DEC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that each systemic analysis of operations that is completed by a veterans service center manager in a regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs includes an analysis of the communication between the regional office and veterans service organizations and caseworkers employed by Members of Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9A987359BCC9478BBAB8961A9C33B488"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Veterans service organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="idd700b4d663ca4c5889c31b6393c7b280"><enum>204.</enum><header>Review of practices of regional offices regarding use of suspense dates</header>
 <subsection id="idB1819FCD7BA7442EA0F66724B3AB0398"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a review of the practices of regional offices of the Department regarding the use of suspense dates during the disability claim assessment process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F634147B77946FBABA66A14054914AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department shall submit to Congress a report on the findings of the Inspector General with respect to the review conducted under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id700FFA6995F04ADF8F89D112F0E3045D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Suspense date defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>suspense date</term> means a measure used by the Veterans Benefits Administration to set incremental deadlines for disability claims as they progress through the disability claim assessment process.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id3BD35AA7738149FEB77861D21C4D82A2"><enum>205.</enum><header>Annual report on capacity of Veterans Benefits Administration to process benefits claims</header>
 <subsection id="idCE3E4816C17743628192084663E14854"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Along with the supporting information included in the budget submitted by the President for fiscal year 2017 pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, and with the supporting information included in each budget submittal under such section thereafter, the President shall include a report that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prepare on the capacity of the Veterans Benefits Administration to process claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary during the fiscal year covered by the budget with which the report is submitted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1AB73937C4294BA4A92F4778EFC4A2F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id0bc54483dbe3470d8194fb9aca8306b1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary that the Secretary expects the Veterans Benefits Administration to process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id756DD61C6477400EADB8219926609D37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of full-time equivalent employees of the Veterans Benefits Administration who are dedicated to processing such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30E2DEDF90984A148DE159D72F3BD963"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An estimate of the average number of such claims a single full-time equivalent employee of the Administration can process in a year, based on a time and motion study that the Secretary shall conduct on the processing of such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id610FC5559E8B48A68B682677106CB5E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of whether the Administration requires additional or fewer full-time equivalent employees to process such claims during the next one-year, five-year, and ten-year periods.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF39C55615D874998BFB268E61C80CB93"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the actions the Secretary will take to improve the processing of such claims.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE1339959408F4BD08B1408E9203A644E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of the actions identified by the Secretary in the previous report submitted under subsection (a) and identification of the effects of those actions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57923036EF3D40CF8E72C915AFFAA169"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make each report required by subsection (a) available to the public on an Internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
				</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7840B8FF330544CDA5C4426595BA79E8"><enum>206.</enum><header>Requirement to complete efforts to revise resource allocation model of Department of Veterans
			 Affairs</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC0B8D3BC97FA44B98514718C1AECDE50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall complete the efforts of the Department of Veterans Affairs to revise the resource allocation model of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCD88052570924AECA684B3D6AFC5AC02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the resource allocation model revised pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id62A0CA4655144FFAB9AD6EC6DDDA186D"><enum>207.</enum><header>Semiannual report on progress in implementing Veterans Benefits Management System</header>
 <subsection id="id0F2C109EFECB47D78E37011B630A0B05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and not less frequently than once every 180 days thereafter until the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on the progress of the Secretary in implementing the Veterans Benefits Management System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id44C627F342814CA58A576BEDB543FEEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="idD306E81970964B20A828FA24996B2AF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the current functionality of the Veterans Benefits Management System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id85AD8CAC67954E22BB54BFD74D5EF993"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recommendations submitted to the Secretary by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs who are involved in processing claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary, including veteran service representatives, rating veteran service representatives, and decision review officers, for such legislative or administrative action as the employees consider appropriate to improve the processing of such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA757B5577E6E4D24AAE7159550D0DC4B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations submitted to the Secretary by veterans service organizations who use the Veterans Benefits Management System for such legislative or administrative action as the veterans service organization consider appropriate to improve such system.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49E88379EEFB41FF9A34F33EF02B99F3"><enum>208.</enum><header>Report on plans of Secretary of Veterans Affairs to reduce inventory of claims for dependency and
 indemnity compensation and claims for pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report that details the plans of the Secretary to reduce the inventory of—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27938399FE02489B8C660BADCA716896"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">claims submitted to the Secretary for compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA471155A1C8846F2BA2C706B059B1EDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>claims submitted to the Secretary for pension under chapter 15 of such title.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="iddd5a1d8f7be24a8582a0c571b07fe580"><enum>209.</enum><header>Increased transparency in Monday Morning Workload Report</header> <subsection id="id787ce500ab3447caba4577bbfdd06b1d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disaggregation of claims by decisions requiring disability rating</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include in each Monday Morning Workload Report published by the Secretary the number of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary that have been received by a regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs and are pending a decision, disaggregated by—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB096A45DEBB04F37B0260C1BC94D3D0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>claims that have been pending for more than 125 days;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0EBE7AD0E599466BA720A1D73C793FCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>claims that have been pending for 125 days or fewer; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id878F0C3DA2214E18BDF64DDE15171146"><enum>(3)</enum><text>claims that do not require a decision concerning a disability rating.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2d2348b59714ff0ab0e07b59e687a8b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of information on assignment of partial ratings</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include in each Monday Morning Workload Report published by the Secretary in the portion of the report entitled <quote>Transformation</quote> and in the portion of the report entitled <quote>Aggregate</quote> the number of partial ratings assigned.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4e52a4ae67b94b79be7356904cae6757"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on fully developed claims</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include in each Monday Morning Workload Report published by the Secretary the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idF4DD741B4DD941159F4F3C62637F099C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total number of fully developed claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3D1AAB9A53AE4AF497747380E98EC006"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have been received by a regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDDA9001CCC9E419AABFFD11E18B5F91F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are pending a decision.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2EB042CC8EE94C9C8D246A35B9081CC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total number of such claims that have been pending for more than 125 days, disaggregated by station.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id536772CD739C4B33A243571930E73139"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Station defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>station</term> means the location of a regional office of the Department where claims for disability compensation are processed.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id65a3d04b28214932b98e0652e787fd13"><enum>210.</enum><header>Reports on appeals of decisions on benefits claims</header>
 <subsection id="id3B9A1D5694534A0A869E08AC982D9841"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make the reports of the Department of Veterans Affairs entitled <quote>Appeals Pending</quote> and <quote>Appeals Workload By Station</quote> available to the public on an Internet website of the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1CFF1C6D2732439497F15B6869022104"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appeals granted by station</header><text>The Secretary shall include in one of the reports described in subsection (a) the percentage of appeals granted by station.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id088E80BA2790456699D2305602B18FD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Claims previously adjudicated by Appeals Management Center</header><text>The Secretary shall include in one of the reports described in subsection (a) the percentage of claims previously adjudicated by the Appeals Management Center that were either subsequently granted or remanded by the Board of Veterans' Appeals.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76861865C67A4B81A5C8E035AA7C8EDF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Station defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>station</term> means the location of a regional office of the Department where claims for disability compensation are processed.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HF34AF2FF67C546DAAE77FF4D61CBC3C3"><enum>211.</enum><header>Modification of pilot program for use of contract physicians for disability examinations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 504 of the Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/275">Public Law 104–275</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5101">38 U.S.C. 5101</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H702E22C2EEEE4244BF6509713B5D2A9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H87F5FF2D74D5486982D04D9590B1DBD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection (c):</text>
					<quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H568C56CFD7DE4DB9AAA407945A26D4CB" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H4EE5006E0A9C4BDCBF7B8F618437E48E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Licensure of contract physicians</header>
 <paragraph id="H9AE35024B19E47AAA603AB118F837F14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any law regarding the licensure of physicians, a physician described in paragraph (2) may conduct an examination pursuant to a contract entered into under subsection (a) at any location in any State, the District of Columbia, or a Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, so long as the examination is within the scope of the authorized duties under such contract.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F86E235530A4A2B8B98B21DE26DF073"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Physician described</header><text>A physician described in this paragraph is a physician who—</text> <subparagraph id="H4D3AD02F290B4BB89C4083A1F0456F1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a current license to practice the health care profession of the physician; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA654B85084F4F48A3BB251F12219633"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is performing authorized duties for the Department of Veterans Affairs pursuant to a contract entered into under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section></title><title changed="deleted" committee-id="SSVA00" id="idBFF6A6B4528646618BF2E11AF9E13CB7" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Government response</header>
			<section id="idb17687d4c7c24efcb3e0373611463c0a"><enum>301.</enum><header>Increased cooperation across Government</header>
				<subsection id="idDAF42D09438A48FFA02139DED3F5A2A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment of liaisons</header>
 <paragraph id="id4FF8290973CD42B98461C012C6A9F2DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department of Defense</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall appoint individuals as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="id51D817296E3B40AAA4748F163EB6409E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>At least one individual to act as a liaison under this section between the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4B7FB04EBC8B4BB5BC7B715630B79C50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>At least one individual for each of the reserve components of the Armed Forces to act as a liaison under this section between the respective component of the Armed Forces and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE486A2FE2D19443B96ED5045980BB396"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Archives and Records Administration</header><text>The Archivist of the United States shall appoint at least one individual to act as a liaison under this section between the National Archives and Records Administration and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0ED3A9C678014C2C94A127B6311C548D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of liaisons</header><text>Each individual acting as a liaison under this section shall expedite the timely provision to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of such information as the Secretary requires to process claims submitted to the Secretary for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="id269BC6019A5C487E8131263D95B0B7F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures</header>
 <paragraph id="idEB7E45CEE9B145E3B5F09CC2CE466BE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Defense, and the Archivist of the United States shall jointly develop and implement procedures to improve the timely provision to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of such information as the Secretary requires to process claims submitted to the Secretary for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3F46F127017A4AE59C03C842280A5CF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timely provision</header><text>The procedures developed and implemented under paragraph (1) shall ensure that the information provided to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs is provided to the Secretary not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary requests the information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8690BB3EFD4944638A65F2DB0DE8FB82"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="idBDA75A69B15F4B60ABDA22DAB429938E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the requests for information made by the Secretary during the most recent one-year period for information from the Secretary of Defense and the Archivist of the United States required by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to process claims submitted to the Secretary for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC17C367B13704F36B0F123D0A02E0670"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the timeliness of responses to such requests.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB8C131ACF78F41D0B71DAD6E45C796A9"><enum>302.</enum><header>Report on interoperability between electronic health records systems of Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly submit to Congress a report that sets forth a timeline with milestones for achieving interoperability between the electronic health records systems of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></section></title></legis-body>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause">
		<section changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id44e454b5-3bb3-4e5b-b633-40779fd4f228" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="id4C0C1EC8F5DD484F921E668D8E062C94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Veterans Benefits Delivery and Other Improvements Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB6A114215697435088ADDE4A8AEE3A6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic"> <toc-entry idref="id44e454b5-3bb3-4e5b-b633-40779fd4f228" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id5ECD6ECD52024E4A9D5ED3B241A27EC2" level="title">TITLE I—Health care matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id450AF6865CC94A11AAA9C5B7ECCA708B" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Expansion and improvement of health care benefits</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5A2DE752F4A642319101625B2BB7F877" level="section">Sec. 101. Improved access to appropriate immunizations for veterans.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idD029ABD17F7445C0B53D9A5D7BBA12BC" level="section">Sec. 102. Expansion of provision of chiropractic care and services to veterans.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id13453D8DB7C54A5AB6BECEFD9B1E2C1D" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Health care administration</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id28896DF44D36484F9A8EB7BAC782AC8D" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">111.</added-phrase> Expansion of availability of prosthetic and orthotic care for veterans.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idD2BC75D30D6149B5B28CC3145582783D" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">112.</added-phrase> Public access to Department of Veterans Affairs research and data sharing between Departments.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id32ED2803575D44D6B46C58E1C6457FFC" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">113.</added-phrase> Revival of Intermediate Care Technician Pilot Program of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id5EFC6DD6B0584853A703FD8651A88ACD" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">114.</added-phrase> Transfer of health care provider credentialing data from Secretary of Defense to Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id188F7EE8A03346898F84FBA13F194752" level="section">Sec. 115. Examination and treatment by Department of Veterans Affairs for emergency medical conditions and women in labor.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id067207BADD6C45F1B3579B8ED15804B7" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Improvement of medical workforce</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id1cb7750a099d44e99c1bb0b1f4f42f89" level="section">Sec. 121. Inclusion of mental health professionals in education and training program for health personnel of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idDABDE6988E944FF79A34185631FB8559" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">122.</added-phrase> Expansion of qualifications for licensed mental health counselors of the Department of Veterans Affairs to include doctoral degrees.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id42F32A568058464D9A83997D4EDC609D" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">123.</added-phrase> Requirement that physician assistants employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs receive competitive pay.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id5c518eaab1c84554820642f09afeb66d" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">124.</added-phrase> Report on medical workforce of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id48B7A799223C4224A3155343A85EC1E6" level="title">TITLE II—Compensation and other benefits matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idADF9A35D5FD04BB68B91CF65E4718B19" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Benefits claims submission</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id1FBF891EC4A643C8B8184C5F73C6AA38" level="section">Sec. 201. Participation of veterans service organizations in Transition Assistance Program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idFBEC240B78D944078AA25E47D9D311DB" level="section">Sec. 202. Requirement that Secretary of Veterans Affairs publish the average time required to adjudicate timely and untimely appeals.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id01B4E263C0A9440DA0BB2212E8FC4731" level="section">Sec. 203. Determination of manner of appearance for hearings before Board of Veterans' Appeals.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id22BD29C25583464CBBC3F5D8D7CB931D" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Practices of regional offices relating to benefits claims</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idA375AC1CFE4848A59530C1206F3D5974" level="section">Sec. 211. Comptroller General review of claims processing performance of regional offices of Veterans Benefits Administration.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idB995DFE25BDE4F1EB98451F5A504C4FE" level="section">Sec. 212. Inclusion in annual budget submission of information on capacity of Veterans Benefits Administration to process benefits claims.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id08588D2359EF4995960427A8F1B2142C" level="section">Sec. 213. Report on staffing levels at regional offices of Department of Veterans Affairs after transition to National Work Queue.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id262D3C9B30A0461CABE37FA43C29A76F" level="section">Sec. 214. Annual report on progress in implementing Veterans Benefits Management System.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id9F8FCC919CA744579B6D9023F6E8EDF5" level="section">Sec. 215. Report on plans of Secretary of Veterans Affairs to reduce inventory of non-rating workload.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id53CA52A65AF04B9AB1D5781ACCA3336F" level="section">Sec. 216. Sense of Congress on increased transparency relating to claims for benefits and appeals of decisions relating to benefits in Monday Morning Workload Report.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idD9EB2FB26D894F0697132371E5B2D579" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Other benefits matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idC3AD095CF7004862BA29EA32E4C40A2E" level="section">Sec. 221. Modification of pilot program for use of contract physicians for disability examinations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id483991D68AFE49DAA878B6874102ED5F" level="section">Sec. 222. Development of procedures to increase cooperation with National Guard Bureau.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idDC122634D05D4C9C874D4226F84745AA" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">223.</added-phrase> Review of determination of certain service in Philippines during World War II.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id09686674D9AE4134924EFB8431C3CD71" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">224.</added-phrase> Reports on Department disability medical examinations and prevention of unnecessary medical examinations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idE410498E57FB410EA5E0BDE1E5262A00" level="section">Sec. <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">225.</added-phrase> Sense of Congress on submittal of information relating to claims for disabilities incurred or aggravated by military sexual trauma.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id1F59533E4A5240149421D360C7E3A4F0" level="title">TITLE III—Education matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idEBDF6BCF144F4DC0A3624278AA5A1A3D" level="section">Sec. 301. Retention of entitlement to educational assistance during certain additional periods of active duty.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id8973e46d56824dea9da450135306cd6d" level="section">Sec. 302. Reports on progress of students receiving Post-9/11 Educational Assistance.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id5248b995e003478ab9c9a94c9b200eef" level="section">Sec. 303. Secretary of Defense report on level of education attained by those who transfer entitlement to Post-9/11 educational assistance.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id3AD3831055C34E45BBCBB8D9F1BB4C59" level="section">Sec. 304. Reports on educational levels attained by certain members of the Armed Forces at time of separation from the Armed Forces.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idE12910AA2BE74E2CB369DAE5DD4113F3" level="title">TITLE IV—Employment and transition matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id0CDCF12B18F3465E8733D2A431C3CBDE" level="section">Sec. 401. Required coordination between Directors for Veterans' Employment and Training with State departments of labor and veterans affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id1C7E4D25438344D5840EF3A805CB6F49" level="section">Sec. 402. Report on job fairs attended by one-stop career center employees at which such employees encounter veterans.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id01630B7B441949F090DCAA8ABE357BEB" level="section">Sec. 403. Review of challenges faced by employers seeking to hire veterans and sharing of information among Federal agencies that serve veterans.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id302014764AC642BBB33A4F0039EE19E4" level="section">Sec. 404. Review of Transition GPS Program Core Curriculum.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id04860F677A6446D393642E321D954C2D" level="section">Sec. 405. Modification of requirement for provision of preseparation counseling.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id02C8D93A111D4AA081327C78A26BDB28" level="title">TITLE V—Veteran small business matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id99B0DB8D6BD842D89BBF7B24092818AE" level="section">Sec. 501. Modification of treatment under contracting goals and preferences of Department of Veterans Affairs for small businesses owned by veterans of small businesses after death of disabled veteran owners.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id183868BF89EA478DB161FBACC5060CCA" level="section">Sec. 502. Treatment of businesses after deaths of servicemember-owners for purposes of Department of Veterans Affairs contracting goals and preferences.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idF48ADD0615D14B1286C9F378E63BE352" level="title">TITLE VI—Burial matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id3C770AA21C4E4BCA98124BFEC8310BC4" level="section">Sec. 601. Department of Veterans Affairs study on matters relating to burial of unclaimed remains of veterans in national cemeteries.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id47BFA596C85446138DC4171C10E92341" level="title">TITLE VII—Other matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idD13BF9B010C84141A17300EEC6EC9C28" level="section">Sec. 701. Honoring as veterans certain persons who performed service in the reserve components of the Armed Forces.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id8014AE3A9939425790230477A4CA5186" level="section">Sec. 702. Report on Laotian military support of Armed Forces of the United States during Vietnam War.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id40A918EBDEDE46639E7821E8E3644DFA" level="section">Sec. 703. Restoration of prior reporting fee multipliers.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><title changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id5ECD6ECD52024E4A9D5ED3B241A27EC2" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Health care matters</header> <subtitle id="id450AF6865CC94A11AAA9C5B7ECCA708B" style="OLC"><enum>A</enum><header>Expansion and improvement of health care benefits</header> <section id="H5A2DE752F4A642319101625B2BB7F877"><enum>101.</enum><header>Improved access to appropriate immunizations for veterans</header> <subsection id="H7FD2A46FACBD469AAEF56415EE6B0176"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion of recommended adult immunizations as medical services</header> <paragraph id="H7D9AC2ADDC904FD8BFCE93C672413F63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered benefit</header><text>Subparagraph (F) of section 1701(9) of title 38, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="H75A2EE8F67564C4A8C5DF82C7415003D" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H4DC5052C73B34F51BBE2494A854FD02C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>immunizations against infectious diseases, including each immunization on the recommended adult immunization schedule at the time such immunization is indicated on that schedule;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C8CD6E22837405E931E710A66419EC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommended adult immunization schedule defined</header><text>Section 1701 of such title is amended by adding after paragraph (9) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="HFB9501E187914AB7A70AB6C879106F06" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB5EC5ED66DC149139026D9EB8206AE51"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The term <term>recommended adult immunization schedule</term> means the schedule established (and periodically reviewed and, as appropriate, revised) by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices established by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and delegated to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FD0285624A44BD9855BD3FE16E1AADE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of recommended adult immunizations in annual report</header><text>Section 1704(1)(A) of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7503D87C598546009F33D8A3D5D33442"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24C3626BD44549118208582C3FDAB7C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA91883975B047718136B4B7169CA8C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ii) the following new clause:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="H53F1CF1E9AD24BBAAADAD8EBD133C936" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HF8C15713195D4346BAFD9E77E6EBFE19"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide veterans each immunization on the recommended adult immunization schedule at the time such immunization is indicated on that schedule.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idED7AD618E3FA48B7BF9FA4F3B9B89073"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="id28CCBE2660C2469DA65FC24EE38F8CC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the development and implementation by the Department of Veterans Affairs of quality measures and metrics, including targets for compliance, to ensure that veterans receiving medical services under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, receive each immunization on the recommended adult immunization schedule at the time such immunization is indicated on that schedule.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id28EB44F22E324B5288D971C66E6AFDB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommended adult immunization schedule defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>recommended adult immunization schedule</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1701(10) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(2).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idD029ABD17F7445C0B53D9A5D7BBA12BC"><enum>102.</enum><header>Expansion of provision of chiropractic care and services to veterans</header>
 <subsection id="id7B48330A5AC44AF783EBF772CE877FE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program for provision of chiropractic care and services to veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 204(c) of the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Care Programs Enhancement Act of 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/135">Public Law 107–135</external-xref>; 115 Stat. 2459; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1710">38 U.S.C. 1710</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H54DD934962B2405B835B19310DDE24D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>The program</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H565448A2FA43495E903DA410EA0C8663"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="HE5E34AE887104CD090A7309E77B9EA44" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H2640AF996F764510AB2ED088A6C145B5" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The program shall be carried out at not fewer than two medical centers or clinics in each Veterans Integrated Service Network by not later than two years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>21st Century Veterans Benefits Delivery and Other Improvements Act</short-title>, and at not fewer than 50 percent of all medical centers in each Veterans Integrated Service Network by not later than three years after such date of enactment.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDFD37FE86AD4DB09EEF86D982F9DC75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expanded chiropractor services available to veterans</header>
 <paragraph id="H6F4B4038EFD04696B9451C3B9DC28E44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medical services</header><text>Paragraph (6) of section 1701 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E139E7449154E2D9AAFBE584C1CA47E" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="HE5D158694B584525A603C2039653099B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Chiropractic services.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H879138211E2D4FF9B0F8ED530E3EC4A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rehabilitative services</header><text>Paragraph (8) of such section is amended by inserting <quote>chiropractic,</quote> after <quote>counseling,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H312EC75462EF4AB3A33DFD10BD09AFDA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preventive health services</header><text>Paragraph (9) of such section is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HDFAED8B19A804C158F5CCCD32B5D818E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (F) through (K) as subparagraphs (G) through (L), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A07F1DB393D4FCBA735189517698C8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following new subparagraph (F):</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAE50FE94D74457AA4C6D2A3DA6D8316" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H9BE552E5481C4CD4847029311461714C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>periodic and preventive chiropractic examinations and services;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="id13453D8DB7C54A5AB6BECEFD9B1E2C1D" style="OLC"><enum>B</enum><header>Health care administration</header>
				<section id="id28896DF44D36484F9A8EB7BAC782AC8D"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">111.</added-phrase></enum><header>Expansion of
			 availability of prosthetic and orthotic care for veterans</header>
					<subsection id="id42E11AD3976D4CA2AD6D8DACBB378486"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment or
			 expansion of advanced degree programs to expand availability of provision
			 of
 care</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall work with institutions of higher education to develop partnerships for the establishment or expansion of programs of advanced degrees in prosthetics and orthotics in order to improve and enhance the availability of high quality prosthetic and orthotic care for veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id13FEAE2EA30442339FA18A596BE6DDD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the effective date specified in subsection (d), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report setting forth a plan for carrying out subsection (a). The Secretary shall develop the plan in consultation with veterans service organizations, institutions of higher education with accredited degree programs in prosthetics and orthotics, and representatives of the prosthetics and orthotics field.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="idD694F07F4BF746AC93A74AE0A2ABB484"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header>
						<paragraph id="idA385320455874499A39D17458BEF1B8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of
 appropriations</header><text>There is hereby authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2017 for the Department of Veterans Affairs, $5,000,000 to carry out this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id825C7AD59F5D46FCBAA0D4005AEE297B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The amount authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1) shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2019.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2E8A6B40104448458C21556F3C6E3CDB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="idD2BC75D30D6149B5B28CC3145582783D"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">112.</added-phrase></enum><header>Public access to Department of Veterans Affairs research and data sharing between Departments</header>
 <subsection id="id9E66AAEC59B44E7D8BBCBBA2A39C0E43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Internet website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make available on an Internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs available to the public the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idDE1CD0292B5048D58B9C1F7E9D19D7FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data files that contain information on research of the Department.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idBD8024336ACB4BAA88E89A9A56636C22"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A data dictionary on each data file.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4F1811AE899A42BF8AD5E01AD792D787"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Instructions for how to obtain access to each data file for use in research.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idba56453bc2794ccd951ded1c323f704d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public access to manuscripts on Department funded research</header> <paragraph id="id54BAF845DA004FEBBCF20E91A9DBC099"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 18 months after the effective date specified in subsection (e), the Secretary shall require, as a condition on the use of any data gathered or formulated from research funded by the Department, that any final, peer-reviewed manuscript prepared for publication that uses such data be submitted to the Secretary for deposit in the digital archive under paragraph (2) and publication under paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8EC5DF12132E448E957FC7DF5F154172"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital archive</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the effective date specified in subsection (e), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idC36393DFA89B4C65A6A364E032A7A4ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a digital archive consisting of manuscripts described in paragraph (1); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1E6A4ECC19B847E9A59003611F4414AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>partner with another executive agency to compile such manuscripts in a digital archive.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id791BCAD9F13F42F993C2B9BED218A0AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header> <subparagraph id="id319566F0E36841AB81ABAF0162873D9F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Availability of archive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the digital archive under paragraph (2) and the contents of such archive are available to the public via a publicly accessible Internet website at no cost to the public.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6B808CD4E0614285B4A2208ADC438286"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of manuscripts</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each manuscript submitted to the Secretary under paragraph (1) is available to the public under subparagraph (A) not later than one year after the official date on which the manuscript is otherwise published.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id46ED62A8B3BD418CB56B3D85030DB812"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consistent with copyright law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out this subsection in a manner consistent with applicable copyright law.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id40806f779eae470d9654109ea94df93a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual report</header> <subparagraph id="idF54719260B324E719FFC3DD63DDE10F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date the Secretary begins making manuscripts available to the public under this subsection and not less frequently than once each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of this subsection during the most recent one-year period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B41B9C9D84E4906B83A2A9AFC7E0FBB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include for the period of the report:</text> <clause id="idCF7E566D14814EB8A6D52B65E5D7B0DC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of manuscripts submitted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA8C3C1FD0FB74721A38B41B9C235CFC9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The titles of such manuscripts.</text> </clause><clause id="id9FE53CA0709B4ED7B316C5BB74C1CC5D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The authors of such manuscripts.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE5593CE6A26E4402B2182BC457314251"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For each such manuscript, the name and issue number or volume number, as the case may be, of the journal or other publication in which such manuscript was published.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE2B32082EA6445C8A71CB3488F7989BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations for data sharing between Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the effective date specified in subsection (e), the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee established by section 320(a) of title 38, United States Code, shall submit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense options and recommendations for the establishment of a program for long-term cooperation and data sharing between and within the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense to facilitate research on outcomes of military service, readjustment after combat deployment, and other topics of importance to the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idFA4E01BBEBF04341B841914A7BCD7556"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id76BB216D2B7F4DC0851730EFFE9718C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA3E70B176BF64773AF5516E33002E196"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Family members of veterans.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idDFC49075FB8A4E539F4875185370E0E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Family members of members of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id869CAC27D74846CAA403E4CE07C38E8F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of communities that have a significant population of veterans or members of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99712F5732314038AD88506E534F9534"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Executive agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1E2D53F31665481A88B68368E9506383"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="id32ED2803575D44D6B46C58E1C6457FFC"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">113.</added-phrase></enum><header>Revival of Intermediate Care Technician Pilot Program of Department of Veterans
			 Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="idF010698F2C534BC6B5280361B412CDA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revival</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall revive the Intermediate Care Technician Pilot Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs that was carried out by the Secretary between January 2013 and February 2014.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="id48275BD3049C46FA9B1405239E50C61E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technicians</header>
 <paragraph id="idD91D20E11FCB47B498A8E42D0F3D0780"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall select not less than 45 intermediate care technicians to participate in the pilot program.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="id7E84E5669BC44C0FA357F178A7290CDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Facilities</header>
 <subparagraph id="idFE97102BA3184EC5A81C77DC6727D84D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any intermediate care technician hired pursuant to paragraph (1) may be assigned to a medical facility of the Department as determined by the Secretary for purposes of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75B62ACDB5E04ED9B5136B1CF5204DD3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In assigning intermediate care technicians under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall give priority to facilities at which veterans have the longest wait times for appointments for the receipt of hospital care or medical services from the Department, as determined by the Secretary for purposes of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id87937F4A56D5469BA10BFC526E2D1D33"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) during the three-year period beginning on the effective date specified in subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9674D046193F4E7DA0C5CA4A5EC9945C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hospital care and medical services defined</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>hospital care</term> and <term>medical services</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 1701 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCFF9178C1D9049EB848B74AA0AB37762"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="id5EFC6DD6B0584853A703FD8651A88ACD"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">114.</added-phrase></enum><header>Transfer of health care provider credentialing data from Secretary of Defense to Secretary of
			 Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="id3662645FCB674FDF84A99288019D2E06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a case in which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs hires a covered health care provider, the Secretary of Defense shall, after receiving a request from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the credentialing data of the Secretary of Defense relating to such health care provider, transfer to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs such credentialing data.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2AE062285116476F880CB2FCA5241195"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered health care providers</header><text>For purposes of this section, a covered provider is a health care provider who—</text> <paragraph id="idC53BC0EDFBDB402689F01DD1166C3E1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is or was employed by the Secretary of Defense;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idACED1F7FEE6E4636A944424A587BCDB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides or provided health care related services as part of such employment; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0F433756B54A485C9E43800BECA9D947"><enum>(3)</enum><text>was credentialed by the Secretary of Defense.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD12AA5F2843F4B9390F3BD97EDC8E4C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Policies and regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall establish such policies and promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8A72544AEE5B4137AFEF3081882CC53A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credentialing defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>credentialing</term> means the systematic process of screening and evaluating qualifications and other credentials, including licensure, required education, relevant training and experience, and current competence and health status.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8C6FE2EFBBD456EA50AFE1BF6783B08"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="id188F7EE8A03346898F84FBA13F194752"><enum>115.</enum><header>Examination and treatment by Department of Veterans Affairs for emergency medical conditions and
			 women in labor</header>
 <subsection id="idBCD3F492538E4F6484FC93477B7B43BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1784">section 1784</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40D27B989995451DABE0048F5D69B1DF" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
							<section id="idC8971DB674424DBD9D0FE7F406B87C6F"><enum>1784A.</enum><header>Examination and treatment for emergency medical conditions and women in labor</header>
 <subsection id="ID91CEAFD53ACA4B059D762FE798C28737"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a hospital of the Department that has an emergency department, if any individual comes to the hospital or the campus of the hospital and a request is made on behalf of the individual for examination or treatment for a medical condition, the hospital must provide for an appropriate medical screening examination within the capability of the emergency department, including ancillary services routinely available to the emergency department, to determine whether or not an emergency medical condition exists.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idE38EC9BFC0A14C8EA7C52262C1219802"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Necessary stabilizing treatment for emergency medical conditions and labor</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6B56B7230D184BD1BCFD61590EF55723"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If any individual comes to a hospital of the Department that has an emergency department or the campus of such a hospital and the hospital determines that the individual has an emergency medical condition, the hospital must provide either—</text>
 <subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="ID8C98C5B210AA4F41AEF29408396A6D07" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within the staff and facilities available at the hospital, for such further medical examination and such treatment as may be required to stabilize the medical condition; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="IDFB179C11E3634FABAA42A82A7D06C06E" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for transfer of the individual to another medical facility in accordance with subsection (c).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="ID7919CC1E8EF74E118CB6FFA1EE086DE2" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A hospital is deemed to meet the requirement of paragraph (1)(A) with respect to an individual if the hospital offers the individual the further medical examination and treatment described in that paragraph and informs the individual (or a person acting on behalf of the individual) of the risks and benefits to the individual of such examination and treatment, but the individual (or a person acting on behalf of the individual) refuses to consent to the examination and treatment. The hospital shall take all reasonable steps to secure the written informed consent of the individual (or person) to refuse such examination and treatment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="ID1DAD4370536B4CBE80631B7E2E1BCCC7" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A hospital is deemed to meet the requirement of paragraph (1) with respect to an individual if the hospital offers to transfer the individual to another medical facility in accordance with subsection (c) and informs the individual (or a person acting on behalf of the individual) of the risks and benefits to the individual of such transfer, but the individual (or a person acting on behalf of the individual) refuses to consent to the transfer. The hospital shall take all reasonable steps to secure the written informed consent of the individual (or person) to refuse such transfer.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDE540D14DD11148868DA15405430D7569"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restricting transfers until individual stabilized</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id88CD55510BFD4E4899069CA56907EA36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If an individual at a hospital of the Department has an emergency medical condition that has not been stabilized, the hospital may not transfer the individual unless—</text>
 <subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="IDA4ED8116DF794917AD449C8177BC20C3" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="IDD1A5EB90BA7540F0BC48396E42FE40D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the individual (or a legally responsible person acting on behalf of the individual), after being informed of the obligations of the hospital under this section and of the risk of transfer, requests, in writing, transfer to another medical facility;</text>
 </clause><clause changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="ID75D72B328B07493C957F09E694DE7F70" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a physician of the Department has signed a certification that, based upon the information available at the time of transfer, the medical benefits reasonably expected from the provision of appropriate medical treatment at another medical facility outweigh the increased risks to the individual and, in the case of labor, to the unborn child from effecting the transfer; or</text>
 </clause><clause changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="IDB0F087768C344820BD11F2CBC99AE457" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if a physician of the Department is not physically present in the emergency department at the time an individual is transferred, a qualified medical person (as defined by the Secretary for purposes of this section) has signed a certification described in clause (ii) after a physician of the Department, in consultation with the person, has made the determination described in such clause, and subsequently countersigns the certification; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="ID1A6AD6270ABC4821BF093C46BA6189E8" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the transfer is an appropriate transfer to that facility.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="idF25D71ED82A149D4950F84514B9DC630" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A certification described in clause (ii) or (iii) of paragraph (1)(A) shall include a summary of the risks and benefits upon which the certification is based.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="IDAF2E9E298E3A4D198CB600089640BDFA" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), an appropriate transfer to a medical facility is a transfer—</text> <subparagraph id="IDFEDBEDC2E956469598E3ABA3F0F1E881"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which the transferring hospital provides the medical treatment within its capacity that minimizes the risks to the health of the individual and, in the case of a woman in labor, the health of the unborn child;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID8EEEA7499A2D4752B8361C4E8A87BE5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in which the receiving facility—</text> <clause id="ID6CAC92FE3D4740A4885CC606DF17D507"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has available space and qualified personnel for the treatment of the individual; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="IDBBD8E5B980ED4EF6BD7D8B3AC7353CE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has agreed to accept transfer of the individual and to provide appropriate medical treatment;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID645918BCEFA64B12AC672C3FFF36AC69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in which the transferring hospital sends to the receiving facility all medical records (or copies thereof) available at the time of the transfer relating to the emergency medical condition for which the individual has presented, including—</text>
 <clause id="id85432E6A224B4FF590160CF6AB3870F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>observations of signs or symptoms;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5F4D2A1C009E495DB6BF1BEC26C6C1A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>preliminary diagnosis;</text> </clause><clause id="id4ED36AF1684E4F768197AEC7383A8492"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>treatment provided;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idAB247EEEB1B0442E98462E34D151EFB4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the results of any tests; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1C0A1B37BE374CC0AE1FDB60CE6F3531"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the informed written consent or certification (or copy thereof) provided under paragraph (1)(A);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID6532F4D005F54263BA3368A718D2E50C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in which the transfer is effected through qualified personnel and transportation equipment, including the use of necessary and medically appropriate life support measures during the transfer; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID78A910BBE4044F289045090ECCE110D1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>that meets such other requirements as the Secretary considers necessary in the interest of the health and safety of individuals transferred.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID7685F8FE738E47F7B2D477ADDF222CF0"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID377DD0ACD9AE44D3B2BBBD35A5470C3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>campus</term> means, with respect to a hospital of the Department—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA60D8DFE6EA044628C009AC8AC262714"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the physical area immediately adjacent to the main buildings of the hospital;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id509FD78CAEE2406FAFAC5D09E43E0ED8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other areas and structures that are not strictly contiguous to the main buildings but are located not less than 250 yards from the main buildings; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17A1CBCEC48F4802A18B0A964065B353"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other areas determined by the Secretary to be part of the campus of the hospital.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61BFD69100A14CA8B06B5491241A6B72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>emergency medical condition</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ID36CFA9F35D1F4635B02AA776C6D3F27B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a medical condition manifesting itself by acute symptoms of sufficient severity (including severe pain) such that the absence of immediate medical attention could reasonably be expected to result in—</text>
 <clause id="IDDCEF89EB90754D22AD40984636E94B6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>placing the health of the individual (or, with respect to a pregnant woman, the health of the woman or her unborn child) in serious jeopardy;</text>
 </clause><clause id="IDBBB2E3D95345485FA40E413C5A865631"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serious impairment to bodily functions; or</text> </clause><clause id="ID57FBB392B7F44227BBF1C28161DA77CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>serious dysfunction of any bodily organ or part; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID746DF2C7FDB442C89D1CA81A4F8B6F72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a pregnant woman who is having contractions—</text> <clause id="IDAE1E573BEE0D411E9787AECE1D6D49B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that there is inadequate time to effect a safe transfer to another hospital before delivery; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="ID5216BEF003094B07A4B3CA6D37DE33B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that transfer may pose a threat to the health or safety of the woman or the unborn child.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID359C6032772746D8AD02F21E98025847"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="IDE0434650ED3943EDAB52D0B7D0D4E6B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>to stabilize</term> means, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (2)(A), to provide such medical treatment of the condition as may be necessary to assure, within reasonable medical probability, that no material deterioration of the condition is likely to result from or occur during the transfer of the individual from a facility, or, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (2)(B), to deliver (including the placenta).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="ID272B337D705349EDBC0BDD8B270B509E" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>stabilized</term> means, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (2)(A), that no material deterioration of the condition is likely, within reasonable medical probability, to result from or occur during the transfer of the individual from a facility, or, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (2)(B), that the woman has delivered (including the placenta).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDB83BD6A0AB234DA98578E6774D8755E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>transfer</term> means the movement (including the discharge) of an individual outside the facilities of a hospital of the Department at the direction of any person employed by (or affiliated or associated, directly or indirectly, with) the hospital, but does not include such a movement of an individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3EF5593AC4474E969368CAF8EF9F3E02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been declared dead; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id800FE769FFA24D06A5D0C849DF7349A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>leaves the facility without the permission of any such person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4421C5AEB9CE456D937F466030E5CF81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 17 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1784 the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id29df1930-d2f0-4c43-ae4d-c590ec608e64" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC"><toc changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic"><toc-entry idref="idC8971DB674424DBD9D0FE7F406B87C6F" level="section">Sec. 1784A. Examination and treatment for emergency medical conditions and women in labor.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="id067207BADD6C45F1B3579B8ED15804B7" style="OLC"><enum>C</enum><header>Improvement of medical workforce</header>
				<section id="id1cb7750a099d44e99c1bb0b1f4f42f89"><enum>121.</enum><header>Inclusion of mental health professionals in education and training program for health personnel of
			 the Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out the education and training program required under section 7302(a)(1) of title 38, United States Code, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include education and training of marriage and family therapists and licensed professional mental health counselors.</text>
				</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDABDE6988E944FF79A34185631FB8559"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">122.</added-phrase></enum><header>Expansion of qualifications for licensed mental health counselors of the Department of Veterans
 Affairs to include doctoral degrees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7402(b)(11)(A) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or doctoral degree</quote> after <quote>master's degree</quote>.</text> </section><section id="id42F32A568058464D9A83997D4EDC609D"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">123.</added-phrase></enum><header>Requirement that physician assistants employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs receive competitive pay</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7451(a)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idBFA0415AEAE94774A410F91847537AA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8763DA0795484A2E8F17FF32A3BFB2D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph (B):</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39AE1BCE6D0A4B89BF75439E5D812CF1" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id209D1435F6D241E4A54DF09602E65345" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Physician assistant.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE700CD02513F4D0D80D8A8A4A1668330"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), as redesignated by paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and registered nurse</quote> and inserting <quote>registered nurse, and physician assistant</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></section><section id="id5c518eaab1c84554820642f09afeb66d"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">124.</added-phrase></enum><header>Report on medical workforce of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="idec5a1f3a22344db9a36492205fe1981d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the medical workforce of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id381627FE5EDF45748D53D6CCAC789778"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="id9a69e1f98663476d9aa1bd962ce10756"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to licensed professional mental health counselors and marriage and family therapists of the Department—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb5e956ba25844991a62d5d06ac48dc2b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how many such counselors and therapists are currently enrolled in the mental health professionals trainee program of the Department;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e902a9909d7464a84d63afa7f0b3b64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how many such counselors and therapists are expected to enroll in the mental health professionals trainee program of the Department during the 180-day period beginning on the date of the submittal of the report;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc0d61f410ba8441aa89105c2795b102c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the eligibility criteria for such counselors and therapists as compared to other behavioral health professions in the Department;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1b545f4138b4d939a5b702b5c6d459e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the objectives, goals, and timing of the Department with respect to increasing the representation of such counselors and therapists in the behavioral health workforce of the Department; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB419993DDBDE441C82C157524E0A1394"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the actions taken by the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, to create an occupational series for such counselors and therapists and a timeline for the creation of such an occupational series.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9bdfdc2fc1d14aab8fa466f9c7ab10c4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A breakdown of spending by the Department in connection with the education debt reduction program of the Department under subchapter VII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/76">chapter 76</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4652a3a686e849c39bacee932db9bd3b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount spent by the Department in debt reduction payments during the three-year period preceding the submittal of the report disaggregated by the medical profession of the individual receiving the payments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5017bfbfa7aa4673a2f2a2c4b8a994d3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the Department prioritizes such spending by medical profession, including an assessment of whether such priority reflects the five occupations identified in the most recent determination by the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs as having the largest staffing shortages in the Veterans Health Administration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida42117f04d8449848640124b43d8980d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the actions taken by the Secretary to increase the effectiveness of such spending for purposes of recruitment of health care providers to the Department, including efforts to more consistently include eligibility for the education debt reduction program in vacancy announcements of positions for health care providers at the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2193ecc6ab24df7882d2ed0cea79ba5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of any impediments to the delivery by the Department of telemedicine services to veterans and any actions taken by the Department to address such impediments, including with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idda3de4dfc2724b5997ddc7a477c752b7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restrictions under Federal or State laws;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id186e74e27f3d46bf9c17ee7d52e415b5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>licensing or credentialing issues for health care providers, including non-Department health care providers, practicing telemedicine with a veteran located in a different State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92eba5f6afa040bda715cf4b60e87ab0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effect of limited broadband access or limited information technology capabilities on the delivery of health care;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabedce57e4b4432eab914d4d0a66d281"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the distance a veteran is required to travel to access a facility or clinic with telemedicine capabilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56f706dcf59e4ff6a13aa7eb580a47c0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the effect on the provision of telemedicine services to veterans of policies of and limited liability protection for certain entities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5b3a6e9d7014447a5a4b2b31e6c3f00"><enum>(F)</enum><text>issues relating to reimbursement and travel limitations for veterans that affect the participation of non-Department health care providers in the telemedicine program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f3ebcfa37ac4c629e8af9e9af8a962f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An update on the efforts of the Secretary to offer training opportunities in telemedicine to medical residents in medical facilities of the Department that use telemedicine, consistent with medical residency program requirements established by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education, as required in section 108(b) of the Honoring America’s Veterans and Caring for Camp Lejeune Families Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/154">Public Law 112–154</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7406">38 U.S.C. 7406</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd8b899b136064bd8a22a533b72995ac9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the development and implementation by the Secretary of succession planning policies to address the prevalence of vacancies in positions in the Veterans Health Administration of more than 180 days, including the development of an enterprise position management system to more effectively identify, track, and resolve such vacancies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc8c2647b7cc4e36aacf895a3c0c7701"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of the actions taken by the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, to address any impediments to the timely appointment and determination of qualifications for Directors of Veterans Integrated Service Networks and Medical Directors of the Department.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id48B7A799223C4224A3155343A85EC1E6" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Compensation and other benefits matters</header>
			<subtitle id="idADF9A35D5FD04BB68B91CF65E4718B19" style="OLC"><enum>A</enum><header>Benefits claims submission</header>
				<section id="id1FBF891EC4A643C8B8184C5F73C6AA38"><enum>201.</enum><header>Participation of veterans service organizations in Transition Assistance Program</header>
 <subsection id="id91C37CE958AE42529945334ABFC0B7C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense, in collaboration with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, should establish a process by which a representative of a veterans service organization may be present at any portion of the program carried out under section 1144 of title 10, United States Code, relating to the submittal of claims to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for compensation under chapter 11 or 13 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="id3214CB9E47674B4A8D5A2505EA63D284"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="id956380D09BAE4ED89ED7E02D686D5C98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on participation of veterans service organizations in the program carried out under section 1144 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id03DDD51CE6714FDF980EF068D382BE19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id5BBC3CC53B3F4AD6B355820E83E66C67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the compliance of facilities of the Department of Defense with the directives included in the memorandum of the Secretary of Defense entitled <quote>Installation Access and Support Services for Nonprofit Non-Federal Entities</quote> and dated December 23, 2014.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF734388089FB4900AC5CDA6374A4D6FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of military bases that have complied with such directives.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB1B581E68F384EB1BFF8E2DC41EE4C02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>How many veterans service organizations have been present at a portion of a program as described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2E0A316BC2A8466DBC99C342C72BC092"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Veterans service organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="idFBEC240B78D944078AA25E47D9D311DB"><enum>202.</enum><header>Requirement that Secretary of Veterans Affairs publish the average time required to adjudicate
			 timely and untimely appeals</header>
					<subsection id="id34C6FCFA06544B31A6F9FE0D5AD9287D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Publication requirement</header>
 <paragraph id="idF6C92AF7C0D946FB83B9C784ED19A027"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an ongoing basis, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make available to the public the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id229121E388D94C62AA64EECBBADA5BF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The average length of time to adjudicate a timely appeal.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB5536A25417F45479183903C4C94FCA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The average length of time to adjudicate an untimely appeal.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFC71CEA199C54858A838E99ADAFDC879"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply until the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id664DD78DA6184F0083F449F39B075825"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="id5A19583001584D678CF5EB6ECF415010"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 39 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on whether publication pursuant to subsection (a)(1) has had an effect on the number of timely appeals filed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id84E738F4A4D74A2EAA63E0E8455ED337"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id4B915B290B584D5F8E9BF91EF627C224"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of appeals and timely appeals that were filed during the one-year period ending on the effective date specified in subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id873A2D1A668B42659B47822849D355FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of appeals and timely appeals that were filed during the one-year period ending on the date that is two years after the effective date specified in subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id65AEBAABD04B4851A9EA0296C78E445A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id363B06B8E7494DEF9D90219E16C27C3F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text>The term <term>appeal</term> means a notice of disagreement filed pursuant to section 7105(a) of title 38, United States Code, in response to notice of the result of an initial review or determination regarding a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id827C7F4909C74E71990C8A961F886AF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timely</header><text>The term <term>timely</term> with respect to an appeal means that the notice of disagreement was filed not more than 180 days after the date of mailing of the notice of the result of the initial review or determination described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD6716B76B7454A559037891807CEB6D5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Untimely</header><text>The term <term>untimely</term> with respect to an appeal means the notice of disagreement was filed more than 180 days after the date of mailing of the notice of the result of the initial review or determination described in paragraph (1).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id01B4E263C0A9440DA0BB2212E8FC4731"><enum>203.</enum><header>Determination
			 of manner of appearance for hearings before Board of Veterans' Appeals</header>
					<subsection id="id042DC03DF7A34E2CAD3429B40174D5B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 7107 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id0F520BBC3BE54C5792EBA092E9D0AB96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idD1512A1FE8924984BF7AE4A84A105CF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (f) as subsections (f) and (g), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id432879F7A73C4B1FB1EFB55118723F32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsections (d) and (e):</text> <quoted-block changed="added" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9936AA8138774952BFEAB8907433D212" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id5C05090EBDAE4C75B167C7EC9016EF52" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id98B731DCD9EF4E45B59A7660D54A8470"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a hearing before the Board shall be conducted, as the Board considers appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id2F917A9BB8A644A1B975926069E7AD4B" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in person; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="idFFA5B1FB2D174654A79A6929A73F05E2" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through picture and voice transmission, by electronic or other means, in such manner that the appellant is not present in the same location as the member or members of the Board during the hearing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="idC5F5AFC24B124839A9802FBAB77D69B2" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon request by an appellant, a hearing before the Board shall be conducted, as the appellant considers appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id153E27530B57482EAE48E4B86ED7393E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in person; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0F1B4AF1A78B420C8BA7A6664998B9A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through picture and voice transmission as described in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id1C8CD6799F6247E89CD432436099AD64" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id555740D10B6A47BAAAAFA2822614F778"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In a case in which a hearing before the Board is to be conducted through picture and voice transmission as described in subsection (d)(1)(B), the Secretary shall provide suitable facilities and equipment to the Board or other components of the Department to enable an appellant located at an appropriate facility within the area served by a regional office to participate as so described.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="idED5DE3D1A3F74BAC924FCA68B0B344FF" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any hearing conducted through picture and voice transmission as described in subsection (d)(1)(B) shall be conducted in the same manner as, and shall be considered the equivalent of, a personal hearing.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9D6DF0AB4129420FB2099F402333B6A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1), as redesignated by paragraph (2), by striking <quote>An appellant may request</quote> and all that follows through <quote>office of the Department</quote> and inserting <quote>In a case in which a hearing before the Board is to be conducted in person, the hearing shall be held at the principal location of the Board or at a facility of the Department located within the area served by a regional office of the Department</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAD95D985731540078DF0CE3BE0750DC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Subsection (a)(1) of such section is amended by striking <quote>in subsection (f)</quote> and inserting <quote>in subsection (g)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBE34440BCD204ED792AD24A14CF42BE5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to cases received by the Board of Veterans' Appeals pursuant to notices of disagreement submitted on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subsection></section></subtitle><subtitle id="id22BD29C25583464CBBC3F5D8D7CB931D" style="OLC"><enum>B</enum><header>Practices of regional offices relating to benefits claims</header>
				<section id="idA375AC1CFE4848A59530C1206F3D5974"><enum>211.</enum><header>Comptroller General review of claims processing performance of regional offices of Veterans
			 Benefits Administration</header>
 <subsection id="id1196FFBA22A64299B0617C89BACA43F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 months after the effective date specified in subsection (e), the Comptroller General of the United States shall complete a review of the regional offices of the Veterans Benefits Administration to help the Veterans Benefits Administration achieve more consistent performance in the processing of claims for disability compensation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6A3F0C7DBEFB46299DF4716A895A9AF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The review required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="id2B7CDEC9F553498B94060EEAE702967C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An identification of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6AAD0D4A1D7C4BB8BECA7661ED4FEEA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The factors, including management practices, that distinguish higher performing regional offices from other regional offices with respect to claims for disability compensation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8BDF42B1E6A04103872569D9DFEE65BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The best practices employed by higher performing regional offices that distinguish the performance of such offices from other regional offices.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86FEFCD6FEBE407880CFC4314936D93D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such other management practices or tools as the Comptroller General determines could be used to improve the performance of regional offices.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5B8394B8A5ED4A6FA14B99C26DA62E90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the effectiveness of communication with respect to the processing of claims for disability compensation between the regional offices and veterans service organizations and caseworkers employed by Members of Congress.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5A3F649FA5F24A9B95768B477D8DF168"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 15 months after the effective date specified in subsection (e), the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the review completed under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4E71EDEA72A74EE0B413B1AB3B6CD2DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans service organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBBAFA1416FC64B209C684D0E5473DB98"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="idB995DFE25BDE4F1EB98451F5A504C4FE"><enum>212.</enum><header>Inclusion in annual budget submission of information on capacity of Veterans Benefits
			 Administration to process benefits claims</header>
 <subsection id="idF70334ACF70D4F16A4C345433E6EED8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Along with the supporting information included in the budget submitted to Congress by the President pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, the President shall include information on the capacity of the Veterans Benefits Administration to process claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, including information described in subsection (b), during the fiscal year covered by the budget with which the information is submitted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id96C542FF85F4430E80CA0546ED2BD3B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information described in this subsection is the following:</text> <paragraph id="idDD1AE66EA9C042C2807C3296539C9CE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An estimate of the average number of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary, excluding such claims completed during mandatory overtime, that a single full-time equivalent employee of the Administration can process in a year, based on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3393C7F2BA8C4456ADE62D1892FD3462"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A time and motion study that the Secretary shall conduct on the processing of such claims.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1DB3B259EF7E4F92B034D9BF8DC4FA09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such other information relating to such claims as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB9D93257BD0D4B83AAE27C49C1E7489B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the actions the Secretary will take to improve the processing of such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA43D1F1C91554062BEB72093889938BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the actions identified by the Secretary under paragraph (2) in the previous year and an identification of the effects of those actions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4849459A30CB458B931039BA8CF30667"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to any budget submitted as described in subsection (a) with respect to any fiscal year after fiscal year 2017.</text>
					</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08588D2359EF4995960427A8F1B2142C"><enum>213.</enum><header>Report on staffing levels at regional offices of Department of
 Veterans Affairs after transition to National Work Queue</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 15 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the criteria and procedures that the Secretary will use to determine appropriate staffing levels at the regional offices of the Department once the Department has transitioned to using the National Work Queue for the distribution of the claims processing workload.</text>
				</section><section id="id262D3C9B30A0461CABE37FA43C29A76F"><enum>214.</enum><header>Annual report on progress in implementing Veterans Benefits Management System</header>
 <subsection id="id3DF90033C7254022A2F6A9A9D2104128"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than each of one year, two years, and three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on the progress of the Secretary in implementing the Veterans Benefits Management System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3A20D8676BF44D308C6CA84E31E02EE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="idA9AA0F45BAE3424DB6F7E24BE57342C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the current functionality of the Veterans Benefits Management System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB7D3CB9161C94D6B88344444A8EE96BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recommendations submitted to the Secretary by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs who are involved in processing claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary, including veterans service representatives, rating veterans service representatives, and decision review officers, for such legislative or administrative action as the employees consider appropriate to improve the processing of such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8BCC4D0657234CC99B59A8343A994226"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations submitted to the Secretary by veterans service organizations who use the Veterans Benefits Management System for such legislative or administrative action as the veterans service organizations consider appropriate to improve such system.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDEC3D237BA9A45FDBF12DDB3B9333C12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Veterans service organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9F8FCC919CA744579B6D9023F6E8EDF5"><enum>215.</enum><header>Report on plans of Secretary of Veterans Affairs to reduce inventory of non-rating workload</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that details the plans of the Secretary to reduce the inventory of work items listed in the Monday Morning Workload Report under End Products 130, 137, 173, 290, 400, 600, 607, 690, 930, and 960.</text>
				</section><section id="id53CA52A65AF04B9AB1D5781ACCA3336F"><enum>216.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on increased transparency relating to claims for benefits and appeals of
 decisions relating to benefits in Monday Morning Workload Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should include in each Monday Morning Workload Report published by the Secretary the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id9B142B9BD1B044318CB6D9C648668C27"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id87BD2D0E3BD14E2BAAA15E0F323E3842"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of fully developed claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary that have been received.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0728F24EE9634397AFEB587616A3CCFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of claims described in subparagraph (A) that are pending a decision.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idED5AB72BE379409891A519402B4EAF2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of claims described in subparagraph (A) that have been pending a decision for more than 125 days.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9AC8305FDF8B40BC87E2DA05F7D4D927"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Enhanced information on appeals of decisions relating to claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary that are pending, including information contained in the reports of the Department entitled <quote>Appeals Pending</quote> and <quote>Appeals Workload By Station</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></section></subtitle><subtitle id="idD9EB2FB26D894F0697132371E5B2D579" style="OLC"><enum>C</enum><header>Other benefits matters</header>
 <section id="idC3AD095CF7004862BA29EA32E4C40A2E"><enum>221.</enum><header>Modification of pilot program for use of contract physicians for disability examinations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 504 of the Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/275">Public Law 104–275</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5101">38 U.S.C. 5101</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idBEA2F5FCACF44A6482E9E7A740113B8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB1BA2CC949064FC5916A5F4DD70CBA59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection (c):</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8607CB4D387B49BFBDAE4C060838501F" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
							<subsection changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id422579E92FB54B219DA0F4AC01041DBF" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Licensure of contract physicians</header>
 <paragraph id="id5BF4F3EC46134CC99642570A9020C67F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any law regarding the licensure of physicians, a physician described in paragraph (2) may conduct an examination pursuant to a contract entered into under subsection (a) at any location in any State, the District of Columbia, or a Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, so long as the examination is within the scope of the authorized duties under such contract.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDBE0844BD00443308E896CAB6FAE6903"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Physician described</header><text>A physician described in this paragraph is a physician who—</text> <subparagraph id="idC80A3FDBE7814262A1D30F4C602848A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a current license to practice the health care profession of the physician; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7CE70DB9438F4A68B1AD00970DD6D53A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is performing authorized duties for the Department of Veterans Affairs pursuant to a contract entered into under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></section><section id="id483991D68AFE49DAA878B6874102ED5F"><enum>222.</enum><header>Development of procedures to increase cooperation with National Guard Bureau</header>
 <subsection id="idD05A29D8104344E59FD7E82A710383F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall jointly develop and implement procedures, including requirements relating to timeliness, to improve the timely provision to the Secretary of such information in the possession of the Chief as the Secretary requires to process claims submitted to the Secretary for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id667ACCE247F94180A218E51A9418D6AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the implementation of the procedures under subsection (a), the Secretary and the Chief shall jointly submit to Congress a report describing—</text>
 <paragraph id="id450D367B0DED4A6289681C8D484C87C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the requests for information relating to records of members of the National Guard made by the Secretary to the Chief pursuant to such procedures; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDD1407AD45AD4969ADCBBC1DD8C24A9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the timeliness of the responses of the Chief to such requests.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idDC122634D05D4C9C874D4226F84745AA"><enum><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">223.</added-phrase></enum><header>Review of determination of certain service in Philippines during World War II</header> <subsection id="idFA5276186BE84C02B4AF219A9145D05D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and such military historians as the Secretary of Defense recommends, shall review the process used to determine whether a covered individual served in support of the Armed Forces of the United States during World War II in accordance with section 1002(d) of title X of Division A of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/107">38 U.S.C. 107</external-xref> note) for purposes of determining whether such covered individual is eligible for payments described in such section.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="id4806BFFE5D4C4FE8A23876F8DD61EB9F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered
 individuals</header><text>In this section, a covered individual is any individual who timely submitted a claim for benefits under subsection (c) of section 1002 of title X of Division A of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/107">38 U.S.C. 107</external-xref> note) based on service as described in subsection (d) of that section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id22B668B2E4344879A53C87D693B6A10F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report detailing any findings, actions taken, or recommendations for legislative action with respect to the review conducted under subsection (a).</text>
					</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4934AA7AB07D4949A64703F8090FB068"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on benefits
 for disqualifying conduct under new process pursuant to review</header><text>If pursuant to the review conducted under subsection (a) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines to establish a new process for the making of payments as described in that subsection, the process shall include mechanisms to ensure that individuals are not treated as covered individuals for purposes of such payments if such individuals engaged in any disqualifying conduct during service described in that subsection, including collaboration with the enemy or criminal conduct.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="id09686674D9AE4134924EFB8431C3CD71"><enum><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">224.</added-phrase></enum><header>Reports on
			 Department disability medical examinations and prevention of unnecessary
			 medical examinations</header>
					<subsection id="id4BC808329A324B07A8FADF8623E0B64B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on
			 disability medical examinations furnished by Department of Veterans
			 Affairs</header>
						<paragraph id="idA61698CE631441FDA78E2ADED2F5C540"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the furnishing of general medical and specialty medical examinations by the Department of Veterans Affairs for purposes of adjudicating claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3C7EF72EDF594739BBC99B23A90975F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id596322612f814324b2cc56c6af62e557"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of general medical examinations furnished by the Department during the period of fiscal years 2011 through 2014 for purposes of adjudicating claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id457067001D2B4F65BB853A0E75F0BD56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of general medical examinations furnished by the Department during the period of fiscal years 2011 through 2014 for purposes of adjudicating a claim in which a comprehensive joint examination was conducted, but for which no disability relating to a joint, bone, or muscle had been asserted as an issue in the claim.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17fd5b0358d14d4395e8b160b043e18e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of specialty medical examinations furnished by the Department during the period of fiscal years 2011 through 2014 for purposes of adjudicating a claim.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3AD962B84F0C49D697CB0995DCB2E20C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of specialty medical examinations furnished by the Department during the period of fiscal years 2011 through 2014 for purposes of adjudicating a claim in which one or more joint examinations were conducted.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8dbdaf1c78bb4a84b8f676aa6eb5cd9c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A summary with citations to any medical and scientific studies that provide a basis for determining that three repetitions is adequate to determine the effect of repetitive use on functional impairments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87c82808fe184651be4f218dd3ebb062"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The names of all examination reports, including general medical examinations and Disability Benefits Questionnaires, used for evaluation of compensation and pension disability claims which require measurement of repeated ranges of motion testing and the number of examinations requiring such measurements which were conducted in fiscal year 2014.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28EF2950AFAF4F6899C044D66D798B13"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The average amount of time taken by an individual conducting a medical examination to perform the three repetitions of movement of each joint.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id256edd37923b408e9511400c116e2d77"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A discussion of whether there are more efficient and effective scientifically reliable methods of testing for functional loss on repetitive use of an extremity other than the three time repetition currently used by the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2036866d10a4cf0aba7283a4cae3687"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Recommendations as to the continuation of the practice of measuring functional impairment by using three repetitions of movement of each joint during the examination as a criteria for evaluating the effect of repetitive motion on functional impairment with supporting rationale.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5830A616788C4B84A028DCD80A38A8F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report and
			 plan to prevent the ordering of unnecessary medical examinations</header>
						<paragraph id="id4AA74377312742C7A33D3B3B093CD13B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the efforts of the Secretary in reducing the necessity for in-person disability examinations and other efforts to comply with the provisions of section 5125 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7F3038139F8A4EE8B506150412CE4517"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idCB5800C9CC824F14BDC40BEC48E5C92E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Criteria used by the Secretary to determine if a claim is eligible for the Acceptable Clinical Evidence initiative.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e48d5c11ac74326938c6de7b364625f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of claims determined to be eligible for the Acceptable Clinical Evidence initiative during the period beginning on the date of the initiation of the initiative and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, disaggregated—</text>
 <clause id="id28884193C03C423A8378A1DA3B18DFB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by fiscal year; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD49468FD774F4A1CA0FA0711A973E527"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by claims determined eligible based in whole or in part on medical evidence provided by a private health care provider.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9DA59310A3EC46A89076CF5E42227D1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The total number of claims determined to be eligible for the Acceptable Clinical Evidence initiative that required an employee of the Department to supplement the evidence with information obtained during a telephone interview with a claimant or health care provider.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b82d902db1a46129213464a3ab20740"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information on any other initiatives or efforts, including Disability Benefits Questionnaires, of the Department to further encourage the use of medical evidence provided by a private health care provider and reliance upon reports of a medical examination administered by a private physician if the report is sufficiently complete to be adequate for the purposes of adjudicating a claim.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD2D2AA7E08914B868F5F734862471E63"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A plan—</text> <clause id="idFB9208A3D3624C7E83BBA09B48EB490F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to measure, track, and prevent the ordering of unnecessary medical examinations when the provision by a claimant of a medical examination administered by a private physician in support of a claim for benefits under chapter 11 or 15 of title 38, United States Code, is adequate for the purpose of making a decision on that claim; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBF897D5F43F141F59B83DDC91FE36144"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that includes the actions the Secretary will take to eliminate any request by the Department for a medical examination in the case of a claim for benefits under chapter 11 or 15 of such title in support of which a claimant submits medical evidence or a medical opinion provided by a private health care provider that is competent, credible, probative, and otherwise adequate for purposes of making a decision on that claim.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idE410498E57FB410EA5E0BDE1E5262A00"><enum><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">225.</added-phrase></enum><header>Sense of Congress on submittal of information relating to claims for
			 disabilities incurred or aggravated by military sexual trauma</header>
 <subsection id="H1F2A2DE2C4D34C6980CA83B50E9B0B25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should submit to Congress information on the covered claims submitted to the Secretary during each fiscal year, including the information specified in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE1C7042BE1A0473FAF4229291D050304"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information specified in this subsection with respect to each fiscal year is the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1FF64536C0914ECEB654E18E455CB21E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of covered claims submitted to or considered by the Secretary during such fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EFA80F6C87743658E40FF12312ADFC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Of the covered claims under paragraph (1), the number and percentage of such claims—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC5F9292D9C544E2BA7292A387880F47D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submitted by each gender;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0742F0378A824A098FE21F6B631177C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that were approved, including the number and percentage of such approved claims submitted by each gender; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5629D34C1C942A291390D6781099215"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that were denied, including the number and percentage of such denied claims submitted by each gender.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF4DF87146654704A6DB5C174DBFE49E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the covered claims under paragraph (1) that were approved, the number and percentage, listed by each gender, of claims assigned to each rating percentage of disability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H735BA4E2F91044C3B2E7219D28AC0E8A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Of the covered claims under paragraph (1) that were denied—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HED0B879E9E6A4EB69008720B6676C218"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the three most common reasons given by the Secretary under section 5104(b)(1) of title 38, United States Code, for such denials; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFCEB99F5E9041D490FED9E6EC0F0801"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of denials that were based on the failure of a veteran to report for a medical examination.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9B0FCB76C0C94C87AEA76C50B3ABAA00"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Of the covered claims under paragraph (1) that were resubmitted to the Secretary after denial in a previous adjudication—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7a692f837c074d1e883e1efa5d0398f5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of such claims submitted to or considered by the Secretary during such fiscal year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ea85833987b4037bd75e0b01b27beb9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and percentage of such claims—</text>
 <clause id="id8de40cacb5774ef583a39b00f69a7e04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submitted by each gender;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3c7f0c3dd84f4bce8c1fbd2cf6707afe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that were approved, including the number and percentage of such approved claims submitted by each gender; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id43743f4c0fd246d2a167dbea690588c6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that were denied, including the number and percentage of such denied claims submitted by each gender;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a5f403f2f1f44d4913f655fd74f389c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number and percentage, listed by each gender, of claims assigned to each rating percentage of disability; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c7606a2a47f47e584c624a4616a1eb8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>of such claims that were again denied—</text>
 <clause id="id2CF92384809D47B29D8F3B837359F0BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the three most common reasons given by the Secretary under section 5104(b)(1) of such title for such denials; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id154106cd721541699770467f0f16f64e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of denials that were based on the failure of a veteran to report for a medical examination.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEB1677A161D1491CBBCD8698CB2DFFC6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number of covered claims that, as of the end of such fiscal year, are pending and, separately, the number of such claims on appeal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1732C086327D4DB2B86F2139CA23846A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The average number of days that covered claims take to complete beginning on the date on which the claim is submitted.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CB6C016708C45C8806B6C9F0F98FA68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90ADFADFBD334B1F88DC495AC0EB0E61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered claims</term> means claims for disability compensation submitted to the Secretary based on post-traumatic stress disorder alleged to have been incurred or aggravated by military sexual trauma.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34D8F7E958DB4DC5B1427EC4B8A3FD33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Military sexual
 trauma</header><text>The term <term>military sexual trauma</term> shall have the meaning specified by the Secretary for purposes of this section and shall include <term>sexual harassment</term> (as so specified).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id1F59533E4A5240149421D360C7E3A4F0" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Education matters</header>
			<section id="idEBDF6BCF144F4DC0A3624278AA5A1A3D"><enum>301.</enum><header>Retention of entitlement to educational assistance during certain additional periods of active duty</header>
 <subsection id="id6A6469EA7ABE4C558E5A10B0546FAAE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Educational assistance allowance</header><text>Section 16131(c)(3)(B)(i) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or 12304</quote> and inserting <quote>12304, 12304a, or 12304b</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idECF6BB483F5241738B38C1452F40B709"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expiration date</header><text>Section 16133(b)(4) of such title is amended by striking <quote>or 12304</quote> and inserting <quote>12304, 12304a, or 12304b</quote>.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id8973e46d56824dea9da450135306cd6d"><enum>302.</enum><header>Reports on progress of students receiving Post-9/11 Educational Assistance</header>
 <subsection id="idfe921f0ba2374e71bc48e7939cdd06f0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">Chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id5e128a3879964937ba16f281562dbfcb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection 3325(c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc0d4029e9cfc4e0b90083b0a71ea45ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38614af8fbf14759aad568cf76f4deff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id578f3a3a531647dd95765d3673926ec5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph (3):</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bab6a8e78974b0e9d04e6be53849cb6" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id6f2f12354b8746228fa7dcf70beeac08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the information received by the Secretary under section 3326 of this title; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5f3981074134f70a6e9b67444811d19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35952381be1f4d9ab9fa9c9d0783d307" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC"> <section id="ida1977961483c429696db0396c09007a3"><enum>3326.</enum><header>Report on student progress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As a condition on approval under chapter 36 of this title of a course offered by an educational institution (as defined in section 3452 of this title), each year, each educational institution (as so defined) that received a payment in that year on behalf of an individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter shall submit to the Secretary such information regarding the academic progress of the individual as the Secretary may require.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3b260487c70245d49e0d9314f7333e7f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id31313362-aa85-40dd-aba0-3ef13d67a1f5" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC"><toc changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic"><toc-entry idref="ida1977961483c429696db0396c09007a3" level="section">3326. Report on student progress.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id58EEC649B369413ABC8B65FBDE8849F9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id5248b995e003478ab9c9a94c9b200eef"><enum>303.</enum><header>Secretary of Defense report on level of education attained by those who transfer entitlement to
			 Post-9/11 educational assistance</header>
 <subsection id="idA83E6B652B724F57887CC6FCAF4C8CFC"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">(a)</added-phrase></enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3325(b)(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idad3439f49e2a4454b208e48b7e9efd96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idccc5c60c85024c76a980e8996e5e4a2b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27DF0780F5DF44E8844DDF67CF6B5D59" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idc347a2a519bf41e79fe349030f9fdfe9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>indicating the highest level of education attained by each individual who transfers a portion of the individual's entitlement to educational assistance under section 3319 of this title; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0EF710EE28094158B4732C01FAC5D04A"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">(b)</added-phrase></enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id3AD3831055C34E45BBCBB8D9F1BB4C59"><enum>304.</enum><header>Reports on educational levels attained by certain members of the Armed Forces at time of separation
			 from the Armed Forces</header>
 <subsection id="idB2EAA7BFE595455CB60C9F88443E8E3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual reports required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Secretary concerned shall submit to Congress each year a report on the educational levels attained by members of the Armed Forces described in subsection (b) under the jurisdiction of such Secretary who separated from the Armed Forces during the preceding year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2E54CF7790974803ACCF7509E242404A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Armed Forces described in this subsection are members of the Armed Forces who transferred unused education benefits to family members pursuant to section 3319 of title 38, United States Code, while serving as members of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id567C065E14CD4FB4A5CD118EC0A04099"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Secretary concerned defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Secretary concerned</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71798B6FD3F34C548F6870A4B82EC9FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="idE12910AA2BE74E2CB369DAE5DD4113F3" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Employment and transition matters</header>
			<section id="id0CDCF12B18F3465E8733D2A431C3CBDE"><enum>401.</enum><header>Required coordination between  Directors for Veterans' Employment and Training with State
			 departments of labor and veterans affairs</header>
 <subsection id="idC8147C23328C461EAD7D991C0B915809"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">(a)</added-phrase></enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4103 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBF410A359A9B42C5A4CA673CEEB1AAD6" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idEA9B191854E44EB48878B8120DB9B1DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with State departments of labor and veterans affairs</header><text>Each Director for Veterans' Employment and Training for a State shall coordinate the Director's activities under this chapter with the State department of labor and the State department of veterans affairs.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id91487E8FCF174D16AF47AB27ADE6A81F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id1C7E4D25438344D5840EF3A805CB6F49"><enum>402.</enum><header>Report on job fairs attended by one-stop career center employees at which such employees encounter
			 veterans</header>
 <subsection id="id616A0277DD0D452E93D154DAB4C4DB05"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">(a)</added-phrase></enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 136(d)(1) of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2871">29 U.S.C. 2871(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The report also shall include information, for the year preceding the year the report is submitted, on the number of job fairs attended by One-Stop Career Center employees at which the employees had contact with a veteran, and the number of veterans contacted at each such job fair.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idD103BD09981A489C91E9F4B93793A52C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id01630B7B441949F090DCAA8ABE357BEB"><enum>403.</enum><header>Review of challenges faced by employers seeking to hire veterans and sharing of information among
			 Federal agencies that serve veterans</header>
				<subsection id="idCCC11175E1A14B29B56B4E14F405872A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header>
 <paragraph id="id9A3DBB52B3AD467DB4A112F5A2B39E8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall conduct a review of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idCDC091347C6341838750556A7C199C29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the challenges faced by employers seeking to hire veterans; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4A1CF41E2E64440EA30D8DE1C109A588"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information sharing among Federal departments and agencies that serve veterans and members of the Armed Forces who are separating from service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDF7807A988004DF5B8D2C01096B734FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters reviewed</header><text>In conducting the review required by paragraph (1), the Secretary of Labor shall examine the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6A439F01CD73437194D7F0C14300332D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The barriers employers face in gaining information identifying veterans who are seeking jobs.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEB263002CF6B432DB9BF1AC9F51F24B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The extent and quality of information sharing among Federal departments and agencies that serve veterans and members of the Armed Forces who are separating from service, including how the departments and agencies may more easily connect employers with such veterans and members.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id11B7E7482F91404C9368FB9A7F156798"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="id2611839C36C944A1B00E776F3CD8F3B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the effective date specified in subsection (c), the Secretary of Labor shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the review conducted under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA529B29AE0F94ED5A049842FD8B443BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id86099E3AA1364041BAB61E144F1ED6C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Recommendations for addressing the barriers described in subsection (a)(2)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id268A010F5F1C48288848D74CDCB21AEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recommendations for improving information sharing described in subsection (a)(2)(B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id74A26441D88A4AA3A16AF1B497143DD1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id63E7376F1A6542E79B4790CF09E9EB11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF60B4349F206441FB2B74825D52CDC5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idFCC0C3418A554AFFADAE87A3F6D9A1E7"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSVA00" reported-display-style="italic">(c)</added-phrase></enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id302014764AC642BBB33A4F0039EE19E4"><enum>404.</enum><header>Review of Transition GPS Program Core Curriculum</header>
				<subsection id="idEDDE3E0C88AC4E0CB056B672C3B4BF06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header>
 <paragraph id="idE72A7294262640B1A0A91731B4F39868"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Labor, shall conduct a review of the Department of Defense Transition GPS Program Core Curriculum in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDF1E022BBC044604A0D3CD8347253D9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters reviewed</header><text>The review shall examine the following:</text> <subparagraph id="idDEB7AEE788374028A3D9707C68645559"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of Defense Transition GPS Program Core Curriculum in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFAF639E1ACB04663938500AA51E48F60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The roles and responsibilities of each Federal department participating in the Transition GPS Program and whether the various roles and responsibilities of the Federal departments are adequately aligned with one another.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idED53C735149B4181A998EACA4AEA612E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The allotment of time spent on issues under the jurisdiction of each Federal department participating in the Transition GPS Program and whether the allotment is adequate to provide members of the Armed Forces with all the information the members need regarding important benefits that can assist members in transitioning out of military service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05FBFD74E251463582647ADB4A77251D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether any of the information in the three optional tracks in the Transition GPS Program Core Curriculum should be addressed more appropriately in mandatory tracks rather than optional tracks.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7973075A16B74A768280B05E591A3443"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The benefits of and obstacles to establishing—</text> <clause id="id301F79CDC0BC45A9B7837E0DA2382CD0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a standard implementation plan of long-term outcome measures for the Transition GPS Program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id085C4AC2BCD04B7CAAE24087A20CC896"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a comprehensive system of metrics for such measures.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id45677847DDA34F6282B326B2CE6125E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="id6C39BCB2CABE4C81AED33895B6DCDAC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Labor, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the review conducted under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id727639E902A34FB69C920063134C350F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="idBEE35DAFBE474A56BA747FF0356047E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Recommendations for improving the Department of Defense Transition GPS Program Core Curriculum in order to more accurately address the needs of members of the Armed Forces transitioning out of military service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id743046D3D3654260B86D17B95160A9B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recommendations for improving the roles and responsibilities described in subsection (a)(2)(B).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89C9C06E248B41BE80C80B04ADFF2F0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Recommendations for improving the allotment of time described in subsection (a)(2)(C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13644797EA3542CDB7FFEB512C6ED0CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such recommendations as the Secretary of Defense may have regarding the optional and mandatory tracks in the Transition GPS Program Core Curriculum.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFF1BAC1CD2E9405880CD743ABB681422"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such recommendations as the Secretary of Defense may have with respect to the outcome measures and metrics described in subsection (a)(2)(E).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC096D06702EE42AAB97F2362605234FF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Identification of such other areas of concern as the Secretary of Defense may have with respect to the Transition GPS Program and such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Secretary may have to address such concerns.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id667D8955727C4074934E2A164E7E92E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idD01E06E89D59429BB5ADB85A214DFADD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3C66AD4734CB4AF5896C356501A82776"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id04860F677A6446D393642E321D954C2D"><enum>405.</enum><header>Modification of requirement for provision of preseparation counseling</header>
 <subsection id="id72CE45FDC0564B47A49226780F95F914"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of requirement for 180 continuous days of active duty service</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 1142(a)(4) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>continuous</quote> before <quote>180 days</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id6897940259CB4E938E95D90C669D3148"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion of training from periods of active duty</header><text>Such section is further amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB3E8A980163247EC93EC3DAF7BBD529B" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47F779DDA12349189E4E9BA229250FF8" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>active duty</quote> does not include full-time training duty, annual training duty, and attendance, while in the active military service, at a school designated as a service school by law or by the Secretary concerned.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id02C8D93A111D4AA081327C78A26BDB28" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><enum>V</enum><header>Veteran small business matters</header>
			<section id="id99B0DB8D6BD842D89BBF7B24092818AE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>501.</enum><header>Modification of
			 treatment under contracting goals and preferences of Department of
			 Veterans
			 Affairs for small businesses owned by veterans of small businesses after
			 death
			 of disabled veteran owners</header>
				<subsection id="idBB3A71C8F8B9431FA8A2F1CFDECBB197"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8127(h) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id18886013487B476D81F06AA69C9CEFBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>rated as</quote> and all that follows through <quote>disability.</quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBD138849EEF14AA8AF10270815638848"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by amending subparagraph (C) to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC8D6BBDA6CC94340BB393C903D9EAA44" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id3A0A630A08A04A2480F731DB15DC8481" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The date that—</text> <clause id="id4DFC3600034247EEAE67FC13F2DD6356"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a surviving spouse of a veteran with a service-connected disability rated as 100 percent disabling or who dies as a result of a service-connected disability, is 10 years after the date of the veteran's death; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF9600B6194944502991596CDF51F7148"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a surviving spouse of a veteran with a service-connected disability rated as less than 100 percent disabling who does not die as a result of a service-connected disability, is three years after the date of the veteran's death.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a53d0ac29824acd861100c3fdecdc96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective
 date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to applications received pursuant to section 8127(f)(2) of title 38, United States Code, that are verified on or after such date.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id183868BF89EA478DB161FBACC5060CCA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>502.</enum><header>Treatment of
			 businesses after deaths of servicemember-owners for purposes of Department
			 of
			 Veterans Affairs contracting goals and preferences</header>
				<subsection id="id6F4F8BFB3F804E4E8221B9DD326F9D5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 8127 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id18B57830D31542C9804E7B8F3A3E7042"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (i) through (l) as subsections (j) through (m), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id792CC2CE786D4528BFA1FCC5403AE6C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (h) the following new subsection (i):</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61A7BC128F494CD9A5773718DC8AFC4F" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="id1196F465C8744E3495B948D4A7DE87D0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Treatment of
 businesses after death of servicemember-owner</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3D3449D06B514C18BBD6899F5C025892"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If a member of the Armed Forces owns at least 51 percent of a small business concern and such member is killed in line of duty in the active military, naval, or air service, the surviving spouse or dependent child of such member who acquires such ownership rights in such small business concern shall, for the period described in paragraph (2), be treated as if the surviving spouse or dependent child were a veteran with a service-connected disability for purposes of determining the status of the small business concern as a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans for purposes of contracting goals and preferences under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id94D1EE2AC43B49F69BF0190DFD33DFAE" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The period referred to in paragraph (1) is the period beginning on the date on which the member of the Armed Forces dies and ending on the date as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idA3D35483368C4FD5A129C11E8E593C7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of a surviving spouse, the earliest of the following dates:</text>
 <clause id="id06DEAD4368FC48FE9F6249F8E2A19C7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The date on which the surviving spouse remarries.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDA7B7AFE3AA74B3684B084C26DEC6DB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The date on which the surviving spouse relinquishes an ownership interest in the small business concern and no longer owns at least 51 percent of such small business concern.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id477CEE059CA7421DAAA11804F935D402"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The date that is ten years after the date of the member's death.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79B937FF7D814A148F6DCBBDC06F4280"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a dependent child, the earliest of the following dates:</text> <clause id="id62F38CC447B843D8B4AEBBD37E9D98E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The date on which the surviving dependent child relinquishes an ownership interest in the small business concern and no longer owns at least 51 percent of such small business concern.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8BBA696C0D8E4622B228271C8A348198"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The date that is ten years after the date of the member's death.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFF4B95883D5E48B2906E3932C9AF74E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective
 date</header><text>Subsection (i) of section 8127 of such title, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to the deaths of members of the Armed Forces occurring on or after such date.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="idF48ADD0615D14B1286C9F378E63BE352" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><enum>VI</enum><header>Burial matters</header>
			<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3C770AA21C4E4BCA98124BFEC8310BC4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>601.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department of Veterans Affairs study on matters relating to burial of unclaimed
			 remains of veterans in national cemeteries</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84160B9ABE3E4A8F858C2C9FD08CF1ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study and report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the effective date specified in subsection (d), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2DF3E1E445D74748BFFC8FD2A12275AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complete a study on matters relating to the interring of unclaimed remains of veterans in national cemeteries under the control of the National Cemetery Administration; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4980930C2DB346D5B1E9946288B9DBC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress a report on the findings of the Secretary with respect to the study required under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDA25F333DB114A92A983F1A1B2D18B73"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Matters studied</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The matters studied under subsection (a)(1) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcce24fc4acd34e93bba001fbc6dec2e9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determining the scope of issues relating to unclaimed remains of veterans, including an estimate of the number of unclaimed remains of veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1A51F79732744778B3B2711CDE4B146F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessing the effectiveness of the procedures of the Department of Veterans Affairs for working with persons or entities having custody of unclaimed remains to facilitate interment of unclaimed remains of veterans in national cemeteries under the control of the National Cemetery Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62EA988062BB40DFB16C3DEBEE1DA286"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessing State and local laws that affect the ability of the Secretary to inter unclaimed remains of veterans in national cemeteries under the control of the National Cemetery Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26DE397652BF4B978B7FF6F2B3697D4E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing recommendations for such legislative or administrative action as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDAA30766EEBE48C081B784ABB1899DA6"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Methodology</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1F0014E7C63441FB8944B7A339959EC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Number of unclaimed remains</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In estimating the number of unclaimed remains of veterans under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary may review such subset of applicable entities as the Secretary considers appropriate, including a subset of funeral homes and coroner offices that possess unclaimed veterans remains.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2D2AC46499C445028B9397E802119630"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessment of State and local laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In assessing State and local laws under subsection (b)(3), the Secretary may assess such sample of applicable State and local laws as the Secretary considers appropriate in lieu of reviewing all applicable State and local laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF2EF1CFEFD5640378F61C53DF03C8D14"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSVA00" id="id47BFA596C85446138DC4171C10E92341" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><enum>VII</enum><header>Other matters</header>
			<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD13BF9B010C84141A17300EEC6EC9C28" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>701.</enum><header>Honoring as
			 veterans certain persons who performed service in the reserve components
			 of the
 Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any person who is entitled under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/1223">chapter 1223</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, to retired pay for nonregular service or, but for age, would be entitled under such chapter to retired pay for nonregular service shall be honored as a veteran but shall not be entitled to any benefit by reason of this honor.</text>
			</section><section id="id8014AE3A9939425790230477A4CA5186"><enum>702.</enum><header>Report on
			 Laotian military support of Armed Forces of the United States during
			 Vietnam
			 War</header>
				<subsection id="id744427A1BA2A488685DE09D21A9FEFA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the effective date specified in subsection (c), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and such agencies and individuals as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs considers appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="id08E14E2B46644A149126EB0F154FB490"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which Laotian military forces provided combat support to the Armed Forces of the United States between February 28, 1961, and May 15, 1975;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB2CD0A3E7C734594B9D7FF2E985DBE47"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the current classification by the Civilian/Military Service Review Board of the Department of Defense of service by individuals of Hmong ethnicity is appropriate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBD1067C23A58492FA08E84977FFDCA4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may have for legislative action.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idafe17ecfcf814fabbf1d13e2eedb3e1a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate committees
 of Congress</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2a49f820304346268b93a8622462e1e6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7252b57c36db4e91a41ccfaba017379e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5EDD6D08047545919F10024DD7CA4806"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective
 date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id40A918EBDEDE46639E7821E8E3644DFA"><enum>703.</enum><header>Restoration of prior reporting fee multipliers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During the 10-year period beginning on September 26, 2015, the second sentence of subsection (c) of section 3684 of title 38, United States Code, shall be applied—</text>
 <paragraph id="id926D5E1D014140959D543F522711A1E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>$7</quote> for <quote>$12</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEF15C86DB4B948F2A00B0B46E07C689F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by substituting <quote>$11</quote> for <quote>$15</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></title></legis-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the furnishing of health care to veterans
			 by the
			 Department of Veterans Affairs, to improve the processing by the
			 Department of claims for disability compensation, and for other purposes.</quote>.</official-title-amendment><endorsement><action-date>October 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment and an amendment to the title</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


