<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2338 IS: LIFETIME Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2338</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151201">December 1, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To award grants to States for the development of innovative long-term services and supports
			 programs.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Living Independently for Extended Time Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>LIFETIME Act</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id9B27C24E13C044D188F1F633F0F4211C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="id8b8ceceae4d84a04945459b56a6608e4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of Americans over age 65 or living with a disability is growing, and over 70 percent of these individuals will need some form of long-term services and supports, with a majority of individuals preferring home and community-based care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id76da7645ba0a4472be1d02016e2c36b1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This is a major demographic shift and provides an opportunity for innovative solutions in long-term services and supports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id10FB6D618B9A42858A41E08006317FFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Developing programs to facilitate high-quality independent community-based living, create and improve jobs, and address and improve upon gaps in existing systems will be essential to providing necessary services and supports to these individuals and families.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id81f57b0e7f514a989658e3dcf2ae9348"><enum>(4)</enum><text>It is imperative that Congress act to address the looming long-term services and supports crisis.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idC19D90B6383C491EA7FCB0696937BC12"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to establish a grant program to provide incentives to States for the development of solutions to the increased need of individuals for long-term services and supports and to increase State support and systems in long-term care.</text>
		</section><section id="id6E04B70E31E0408D964E07D85653CAEA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of long-term services and supports innovation grant program</header>
			<subsection id="idAFF18D8908564F2BA5556A9EF59F5F0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State planning grants</header>
 <paragraph id="idffab56415d7a4425ba980c5e2f6c8815"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which grant announcements are made under subsection (d), the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall award grants to eligible States to enable such States to develop innovative programs to meet the unique need for long-term services and supports in the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF787E318C22341A9A1AD68D5275E9FCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idFAFB0CDE41544FC893C5B2266A881B45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an application, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCD4477167BA349C5B39B1EDA243F0BCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate to the Secretary that the State will work in conjunction with both public and private long-term services and supports stakeholder groups described in paragraph (3) to develop a coordinated statewide long-term services and supports program for the State that is not duplicative of other programs providing such services and supports in the State; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2EC404C6C2F246E28F15E4FCBDB5C5F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide assurances that the State will, not later than 1 year after the date on which the grant is awarded, submit to the Secretary a comprehensive plan for the implementation of innovative long-term services and supports program in the State, which shall include the utilization of existing State or local frameworks.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5D64D84B7B6341EE8D5D1F6DDEF11126"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stakeholder groups</header><text>Stakeholder groups described in this paragraph shall be groups that—</text> <subparagraph id="id6b2d1a0285674584ba81919d6e2d6799"><enum>(A)</enum><text>represent the interests of—</text>
 <clause id="ida93dce1ed1cd41edbc2e9bed7ae493b5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consumers of long-term services and supports and related insurance products, as well as their representatives;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id196f39e77d1441e5b310001a99ad499b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>older adults;</text> </clause><clause id="id2f366b5aa79c4f4a999e0ebbc4e1220f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>individuals with cognitive or functional limitations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3dc0018ca16247538050bd4099179d4a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>family caregivers for individuals described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii);</text> </clause><clause id="ida1ba2a01199c479e8004cc9ffc7dcaa1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the health care workforce who directly provide long-term services and supports;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb87e1408e4f84082a6fc3e0639b6107c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>private long-term services and supports insurance providers;</text> </clause><clause id="id58e48619f29548f1b1e80f33a23a17e9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>employers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb5cdfbcd77d64461bab2772d180fd86b"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>State insurance departments;</text> </clause><clause id="idd2c59c9560bc4ca48af6e5e0a12ec790"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>area agency on aging or State agency on aging;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida3bf30d73c4e437daf3a4e4b399c03e5"><enum>(x)</enum><text>direct care workforce; and</text> </clause><clause id="idb94791f051d5444c80a2af99ac126ad7"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>State Medicaid agencies;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id292151940c8a441a83b4edc1f05b5594"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have demonstrated experience in dealing with issues related to long-term services and supports, health care policy, and public and private insurance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e8d544076c94408a07539948c08c656"><enum>(C)</enum><text>represent the health care interests and needs of a variety of geographic areas and demographic groups.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8106A5E8F1C24EA6B41C1500BABA4FDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State implementation grants</header>
 <paragraph id="idb1949f8f476e4489907007235626f87a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible States to enable such States to implement the comprehensive plans submitted under subsection (a)(2)(C) to meet the long-term services and supports needs of such States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id94B5A0A5414541669B7F534E9478B298"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idB24ECF5D95604FF6B99F2AB5986852DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an application, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77F4AEAF774F4E74A6688AD406D841AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have submitted a comprehensive plan under subsection (a)(2)(C) that has been approved by the Secretary or, if the State has not applied for a grant under subsection (a), submit a plan (that is similar to the plans required under subsection (a)(2)(C)) to the Secretary for the implementation of new, or continued operation of existing, long-term services and supports activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id962ABD38D6234234BB648BF329CD1E76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide assurances that the State will provide long-term services and supports under the grant to individuals who demonstrate a need for such services regardless of age;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01BA31147CAC44AA803596A591B4A1A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide assurances that the State will provide matching funds in accordance with paragraph (3); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC2BC03E5E8CB4EA8AD28A99B673A8828"><enum>(E)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary progress and outcomes reports containing uniform data as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFB7351F312FF4B98AF965C8A2A9D34A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall agree, with respect to the costs to be incurred by the State in implementing the comprehensive plan under subsection (a)(2)(C), to make available non-Federal contributions (in cash or in-kind) toward such costs in an amount equal to not less than $1 for each $4 of Federal funds provided under the grant. Such contributions may be made directly or through donations from public or private entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5A8889E71AB445388B270FD2F3D7D0A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give preference to States that demonstrate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDA378860714D44A39E59F9A18281D09D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities to be carried out under the grant will enhances access to quality, affordable long-term services and supports for consumers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id366A8CD7BD8D479786CDD3DE6CF73FAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sustainability and scalability of the program to be carried out under the grant beyond the grant period.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0282AEE234E94AA981BCE3A21DE78943"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A State shall not use in excess of 5 percent of the amount awarded under a grant under paragraph (1) for the administrative expenses associated with carrying out activities under the grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB3F95996E8A04543AA225CBA5EC98006"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance and outcomes data</header><text>The Secretary may use not to exceed 5 percent of the amount appropriated for each fiscal year under subsection (f) to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id98B7FA8806EC4B86A2A709422E10B8B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to States in carrying out programs under this section; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id15BBD9DD895A4AFFB1210304614410CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collect and disseminate data, including from the reports submitted by the States under subsection (b)(2)(D), on improvements to long-term services and supports provided in the States and the effect that grants under this section had on the availability of such services and supports.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id97254FA02655436896C79468BC08BD62"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant announcements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall announce the opportunity to apply for the initial series of grants under this section. Not later than 2 years after such date, the Secretary shall announce the opportunity to apply for the remaining grants under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6834D89CB805481786985E7D9BB9CBA9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which grants are awarded under subsection (b), and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the activities carried out under grants under this section, including a description of improvements to long-term services and supports provided in the States and the effect that grants under this section had on the availability of such services and supports.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idEC2617B8D2294626A58F64A243260DD4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="id479E9EA88D5E4E3690A287054A8A53C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated—</text> <subparagraph id="id834D985823264D0C80B83AD5545C96EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to award grants under subsection (a), $50,000,000, to be used during the first fiscal year for which such grants are awarded; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36CCAED992D44BD69CA67F3271AF2DE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to award grants under subsection (b), $250,000,000, to be available until expended.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id154618942591409F88AD78FC9243D4C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional amounts</header><text>In addition to amounts appropriated under paragraph (1)(B) for a fiscal year, the Secretary may use any amounts appropriated under paragraph (1)(A) and remaining unexpended after fiscal year 2015 to award grants under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6F09A87AC0484584A1F4560723BB5EB1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>long-term services and supports</term> means the services and supports described in section 321(a) of the Older Americans Act of (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3030d">42 U.S.C. 3030d(a)</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


