<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S104 IS: Natural Disaster Fairness in Contracting Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 104</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for full and open competition for Federal contracts related to natural disaster
			 reconstruction efforts. </official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Natural Disaster Fairness in Contracting Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD5CF21264F024476A2316EEB3BB7B50B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idE285B6DC82E74D749FC9AC0937F29CD8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDC45EFBF674A4E558ABE0C491B2B7077"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Full and open
 competitive procedures</header><text>The term <term>full and open competitive procedures</term> has the meaning given the term <term>full and open competition</term> in section 107 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFE083355198E4147BB0D87F1129D7E7E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Natural
 disaster reconstruction efforts</header><text>The term <term>natural disaster reconstruction efforts</term> means reconstruction efforts undertaken in an area subject to a declaration by the President of a major disaster under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id4977B5ABBEA94155ADF2CFB755C72111"><enum>3.</enum><header>Competition
			 requirements</header><subsection id="id945B86D6FFB94C009A102212C7FAE14B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), the head of an executive agency, in entering into a contract to procure property or services in connection with natural disaster reconstruction efforts, shall comply with the requirements under section 3301 of title 41, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2977CB468EBB4443B9751C8845927915"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exceptions to the requirement for competitive procedures provided under paragraphs (3), (4), and (7) of section 3304(a) of title 41, United States Code, shall not apply to a contract described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="id3C9D71E06256457691344D7F2E1B4712"><enum>4.</enum><header>Written approval
			 for use of noncompetitive procedures required for certain contracts</header><subsection id="idFBDF8364D6FE4369992039A7B6EA86CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Approval
 required</header><text>The head of an executive agency may enter into a contract to procure property or services in connection with natural disaster reconstruction efforts using other than full and open competition only upon the written approval of the President or the President’s designee.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9A95956E0F2941718B28401F1D2C7DE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional
			 notification required</header><paragraph id="idBE7D29F68CAA4337A364E835F3AD6871"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>If procedures other than full and open competitive procedures are to be used to enter into a contract described in subsection (a), the head of the executive agency negotiating such contract shall notify the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the standing committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives that have jurisdiction over the executive agency not later than 7 calendar days before the award of the contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC416F75D41F64E858D5EB9E9ECE6AC9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>The notification under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="id8070DA7BECBD40A7B6FE4F9B16398510"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the justification for the use of other than full and open competitive procedures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24A9DF1F90244EC98684834E1FEB064D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a brief description of the contract’s scope;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44EA5FA5553D4FF28B9507DA5C1AF52C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount of the contract;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD6833B3F15F842228BBE6BE052703E46"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a discussion of how the contracting agency identified and solicited offers from contractors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA18C5B20C3D94C83AB2E8BCCAD2B4829"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a list of the contractors solicited; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBEE8EB8152794F7489CF6D597B859297"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the justification and approval documents, required under section 3304(e)(1) of title 41, United States Code, upon which the determination of use of procedures other than full and open competitive procedures was based.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idFB39F281C047467384574BE7AEBB4C1D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of
			 requirements</header><paragraph id="id292CB55D687D44B6BBB15749136616E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Size of
 contracts</header><text>This section shall not apply to contracts of less than $5,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9887083020E84D10B6ED753DEC25A8B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to any extension, amendment, or modification of a contract for the procurement of property or services in connection with natural disaster reconstruction efforts entered into before the date of the enactment of this Act using other than full and open competitive procedures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9CC44FCFDAED435AB4B2E7D0F77EA6B9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Small business
 exception</header><text>This section shall not apply to contracts authorized under the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6507D2C95A4C4BFC954A5743E4AD6F49"><enum>5.</enum><header>Disclosure
			 required</header><subsection id="id32EB4A829ABC464FBA36ECADCB98C2CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Publication and
			 public availability</header><paragraph id="id59FD62F84B3D49CAAF5D09974214354D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The head of an executive agency that enters into a contract for the procurement of property or services in connection with natural disaster reconstruction efforts through the use of other than full and open competitive procedures shall publish in the Federal Register or Federal Business Opportunities, and otherwise make available to the public not later than 7 calendar days before the date on which the contract is finalized—</text><subparagraph id="id36BAC788ECD44636A237D62423D21BED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of the contract;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21882C172DB44CE6BABEA9EE1321B66A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a brief description of the scope of the contract;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF207217CA2B04221A6492F7EE28B096B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an explanation of how the executive agency identified, and solicited offers from, potential contractors to perform the contract, and a list of the potential contractors that were issued solicitations for the offers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57A236CD14F84C4FA43968ACE8D4F4F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the justification and approval documents, required under section 3304(e)(1) of title 41, United States Code, on which was based the determination to use procedures other than competitive procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id960D082B242440BD96396FDBBFC3A5AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of
			 requirements</header><subparagraph id="id70AB3DDBA82D4785AF2856FE8ECABBED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Size of
 contracts</header><text>This section shall not apply to contracts of less than $5,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8D8D6CD2DA0948B08684D73335F81B71"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to any extension, amendment, or modification of a contract entered into before the date of the enactment of this Act using other than full and open competitive procedures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35F14A4425FA4B358E5C73D28864D8CA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Small business
 exception</header><text>This section shall not apply to contracts authorized under the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBC93B6D42A354F62849E2D45EC27E289"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relationship to
 other disclosure laws</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as affecting obligations to disclose United States Government information under any other provision of law.</text></subsection></section><section id="id63D0E1D290DD47CE82326FA623B82D14"><enum>6.</enum><header>Contracts
			 entered into under unusual and compelling urgency exception</header><subsection id="idA9FE7B4B44584CD99DFE4BA807D5517A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for
 performance within 6-Month period</header><text>The head of an executive agency may not rely on the exception under section 3304(a)(2) of title 41, United States Code, to enter into a contract to procure property or services in connection with natural disaster reconstruction efforts using procedures other than competitive procedures unless the contract will be performed within a 6-month period.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5BA5D277642F4503B486AFBDC7A23E4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extended
 notification and disclosure deadlines</header><text>The notification and disclosure deadlines under sections 4(b) and 5(a)(1), respectively, shall be 7 calendar days after the date on which a contract described in subsection (a) is finalized.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


