<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S410 IS: Building upon Unique Indian Learning and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 410</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150209">February 9, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To strengthen Indian education, and for other purposes. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building upon Unique Indian Learning and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idE89C76D26B49413AB212E7E62F98B8FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>In-school
			 facility innovation program contest</header>
			<subsection id="id3D2497CB6B0E47D98828166150B398B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id565FBD0F22854DB1B13C92358927B363"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an in-school facility innovation program contest in which institutions of higher education, including Tribal Colleges and Universities (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>)), are encouraged to consider solving the problem of how to improve school facilities for tribal schools and schools served by the Bureau of Indian Education as part of problem-based learning in their coursework and through extracurricular opportunities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDc8c86d56c48b4292bc10454086ce491f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish an advisory group for the contest described in paragraph (1) that shall include students enrolled at a Tribal College or University, a representative from the Bureau of Indian Education, and engineering and fiscal advisors.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0E5A3298683A4C758E5B33F5AC2020E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of
 finalists to the Indian Affairs Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall submit the finalists to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idA27FCB1514ED4736948FC1B5859918EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Winners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall—</text> <paragraph id="id6A0F1304261C4E4DB37E1F23569B73F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the winners of the program contest conducted under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF066A0FED46441ACBAE14870A51DCA22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>award the winners appropriate recognition and reward.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id29FFE0D6BE534B459C9236E19F963352"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of
			 the Interior and Department of Education Joint Oversight Board</header>
			<subsection id="id776229429C994B9480043239E40FFECC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary of Education and the Secretary of the Interior shall jointly establish a Department of the Interior and Department of Education Joint Oversight Board that shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idD5558089ED9A4C6C9FEB1555BFBD0531"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be co-chaired by both Departments; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id38E1E2F5A3924987844960DD26AA0FD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate technical assistance, resource distribution, and capacity building between the 2 departments on the education of and for Native American students.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3D0644D3D1324197A22AA752FCB93430"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information To
 be shared</header><text>The Joint Oversight Board shall facilitate the communication, collaboration, and coordination between the Department of the Interior and the Department of Education regarding education policies, access to and eligibility for Federal resources, budget and school leadership development, and other issues, as appropriate.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idF157D6504F40499A9A723A409AA42FA7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improve support
 for teachers and administrators of Native American students</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 2 of part A of title VII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7441">20 U.S.C. 7441 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3AFE719D140342ECB14D9123BFE5E0B3" style="OLC">
				<section id="id3A8C968C34774549995A4D96E6644EBC"><enum>7123.</enum><header>Teacher and
				administrator pipeline for teachers and administrators of Native
			 American
				students</header>
					<subsection id="id5314B486FCC84CD78F8ACA17AC6576C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants
 authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to create or expand a teacher or administrator, or both, pipeline for teachers and administrators of Native American students.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="id813612D1A11D43229E29254385958FD4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible
 entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text>
 <paragraph id="id69A57FA655234FFCB713B48DC5D652FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local educational agency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id02CE628FEA5C4BD5A487693FF328F50F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD67DE224FFB24EC1B1BF04CD46F43AC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD81C9640DB044C2A83E9F0C23BD2C518"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id330C4F80DF924A6BBBB1093BBD4568F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to Tribal Colleges and Universities (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idA373F31D99F14581AD5A8508352054DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall create a program that shall prepare, recruit, and provide continuing education for teachers and administrators of Native American students, in particular for teachers of—</text>
 <paragraph id="idFB2FA02FEEAD4DA096C50B3F1D2178FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">science, technology, engineering, and mathematics;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4FAAE327C1844BB89719DC0AC230233E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subjects that lead to health professions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id89C426D2F4A24F508F9531E97A50ECF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">green skills and <quote>middle skills</quote>, including electrical, welding, technology, plumbing, and green jobs.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB602167D9B534A5B9BA4CE9138950930"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Incentives for
 teachers and administrators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may provide incentives to teachers and principals who make a commitment to serve high-need, high-poverty, tribal schools, including in the form of scholarships, loan forgiveness, incentive pay, or housing allowances.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="idF5292D34C7054C188456C213C04B332E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>School and
 community orientation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall develop an evidence-based, culturally-based school and community orientation for new teachers and administrators of Native American students.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="id5E135A6DDE4345238069CDC3DAC214FD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Native American
			 student support</header>
			<subsection id="idBC4D361C3F3B4142A2046A4EF236C0BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standards-Based
 assessments</header><text>Section 1111(b)(3) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46242090BA23447C925086F66EF4A376" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="id0FDFEE98173F4738A17310B3593C31D8"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Standards-based
 education assessments</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, a State, in consultation with Indian tribes or Tribal Colleges and Universities (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965), shall develop standards-based education assessments and classroom lessons to accommodate diverse learning styles, which assessments may be used by the State in place of the general assessments described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9C17C9EE9CE74FD5A288407C04368003"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall expand programs for Native American school children—</text>
 <paragraph id="idDB5DFCA33A7B4AF5B2361A3B19309410"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide support for learning in the children's Native language and culture; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0849A62DA7F747018D07CA9AA99A7F6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide English language instruction.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id31F7D18E781E4ED784436D35A18B0856"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct research on culture- and language-based education to identify the factors that improve education and health outcomes.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id6710FC298A794DADBB6302B418CB28DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Native language
 teaching</header><text>Section 1119 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESEA">Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6319">20 U.S.C. 6319</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF57A518FD0954620932173C88F682903" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="idE8AF9ECA0A42403B8B8F461F496D71EE"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Qualifications
				for Native language teachers</header>
						<paragraph id="id7F9F15AB56E544A1B6F9C9EC7E35FACF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the requirements of subsection (a) for local educational agencies and States with respect to highly qualified teachers shall not apply to a teacher of a Native language.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="IDc6b7fc1e7f744a83b69d020f7966a2ba"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative
 licensure or certification</header><text>Each State educational agency receiving assistance under this part shall, through collaboration with Indian tribes or Tribal Colleges and Universities (as defined in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965), as appropriate, develop a licensure or certification process for teachers of a Native language.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC718861315CB47E795B4075E8FE23D83"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reauthorization of the grant program To ensure the survival and continuing vitality of native
 american languages</header><text>Section 816(e) of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2992d">42 U.S.C. 2992d(e)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2008, 2009, 2010, 2011, and 2012</quote> and inserting <quote>2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, and 2019</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id87BDA4653921427496A67E11ABE832B4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Increased access
			 to resources for tribal schools, schools served by the Bureau of Indian
			 Education, and Native American students</header>
			<subsection id="id601D1DA8439049C382F97FCF18A1DE70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation for
			 Bureau-Funded Schools and Programs and Schools Operated by a Tribe or
			 Tribal
			 Organization</header>
				<paragraph id="id0085A35C834F4633AD7D3119DA1E51EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall ensure that any program administered by the Department of Education that awards grants, contracts, or other assistance to benefit elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) or prekindergarten or early childhood programs, provides a reservation, as described in this subsection, for 1 or more of the following categories of entities, as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Education for each such grant, contract, or assistance program:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3F0DE7EBD59741DD841D333AC1843A05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Bureau-funded schools (as defined in section 1141 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2021">25 U.S.C. 2021</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB8125AFDBA5941BF9518EFF79821707C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Prekindergarten programs or early childhood programs or services operated by a tribe or Indian organization (as defined in such section).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7D36DB77969349F0AB0BF3DF21B1392A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Elementary schools or secondary schools operated by a tribe or Indian organization (as defined in such section).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9AED1ED80BA14A708F94FA866BBD83BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of
			 Reservation</header>
					<subparagraph id="idD89FE9951DBD429E9A103B2BD559C706"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Existing
 Reservation of Funds</header><text>In the case of a grant, contract, or assistance program provided by the Department of Education to benefit elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) or prekindergarten or early childhood programs for which funds are reserved for entities described in paragraph (1), or for a group that may include such entities—</text>
 <clause id="id42EE5BD8A285411F9FB9CEA4DD5C114A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the existing reservation of funds is for an amount that is less than 0.5 percent, the amount of such reservation shall be increased to 0.5 percent; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idAA9C5B9676F64C78A7CB17D1A526FADF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the existing reservation of funds is for an amount that is equal to or greater than 0.5 percent, the amount of such reservation shall be maintained.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6180C0814BBF4395A95C018546FC5BA7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No Existing
 Reservation of Funds</header><text>In the case of a grant, contract, or assistance program provided by the Department of Education to benefit elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) or prekindergarten or early childhood programs for which no funds are reserved for the entities described in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Education shall reserve 0.5 percent of such funds for such entities, as determined by the Secretary of Education in accordance with paragraph (1).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id284808E4EA6742FCA98BE5B8E289701F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of Reserved
 Funds</header><text>Funds reserved under this section shall be used in accordance with the uses of funds described for each particular grant, contract, or assistance program. In addition to program support, such reserved funds may be used, in an amount determined by the Secretary of Education, for technical assistance or capacity building to ensure that the schools or programs described in paragraph (1) are provided the assistance to compete for such grants, contracts, or other assistance.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idED6A6549FF4F479DBB5AA36C8317BB85"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect on Other
 Laws</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall carry out this subsection notwithstanding any other provision of law.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5698F262E78041A2A91BF096E7571B18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safe and
 healthy schools for Native American students</header><text>Subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7131">20 U.S.C. 7131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10C5BE5A807C41EEBE2ED9680F3A3E1E" style="OLC">
					<section id="idB24AEB547A0F44F8BC91DE5D14590183"><enum>4131.</enum><header>Safe and
 healthy schools for Native American students</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">From funds made available to carry out this subpart, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="ID7025bdd2ec98437db57e3ba1e9d65eea"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a program to improve school environments and student skill development for healthy choices for Native American students, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB9CA53AC2896475FADFB9AE6717ABE29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevention regarding—</text>
 <clause id="idC2D8F7DFE3944B6C818957F6BBA4A80F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>alcohol and drug misuse;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5A274426024048D4A114EEAD52BD7716"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>suicide;</text> </clause><clause id="id0C878E159ABE456FB1D4E39B68937A25"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>violence;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id517C3B5CC316447C94D5FE1DD50FC18A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>pregnancy; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id24FDCD8D9C17475F9A63D8B84A26B8B1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>obesity;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1A88000A201348AC926802A3D7F23426"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nutritious eating programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAEBE2A8D140D4801A0A2F3DA15D19A10"><enum>(C)</enum><text>anger and conflict management programs;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDc0c54eef3ce140da94709695ec6c4db1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a program for school dropout prevention for Native American students; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID6a4bd1e1ae8845b6a3f138a6d6f996d8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collaborate with the Secretary of Agriculture to establish tribal-school specific school gardens and nutrition programs that are within the tribal cultural context.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="idA0D1EF553ABC4FD2890DD3D25C23CF19"><enum>7.</enum><header>Funds for Impact
 Aid</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise appropriated to carry out title VIII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7701">20 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.</external-xref>), there are authorized to be appropriated, and there are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to carry out such title VIII the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idADF403B781FA4C37984619F470FD66B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$750,000,000 for fiscal year 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idED2EFF28C7A24830BE96E24757CFF504"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$750,000,000 for fiscal year 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id06C1F979795B4127A302DF857C0DF1FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$750,000,000 for fiscal year 2018.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idF17A183660864AA49E6BAE3F087CEAAD"><enum>8.</enum><header>Forward Funding
 for Tribal Colleges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For carrying out the following programs, there are authorized to be appropriated $31,500,000 for fiscal year 2016 which shall become available on July 1, 2016, and shall remain available through September 30, 2017:</text>
 <paragraph id="idFF04FDA66D4340F0916501E59FA99500"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Programs under title V of the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1861">25 U.S.C. 1861 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0EF59D1344F641BAAE2128C73489D2BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development established under the American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian Culture and Art Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/4401">20 U.S.C. 4401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1E65E56859814152816B21A527841B3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Institutional operations grants for the Haskell Indian Nations University and Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute under the authority of the Act of November 2, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/13">25 U.S.C. 13</external-xref>), popularly known as the Snyder Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4CD4C1497DBB4BCF99F8B722D73E9D04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Scholarships and adult education and special higher education scholarships under the authority of the Act of November 2, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/13">25 U.S.C. 13</external-xref>), popularly known as the Snyder Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id866C75351BAC4D6F917B1CB0F697070E"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definition of
			 Tribal School</header>
			<subsection id="idEA8E6E681C8D4295BFA218086396B2ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>ESEA
 Definition</header><text>Section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id469F9275B55343B698574725F749DF09" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="idAC03A88B75DB44FEA4A768A980004EC2"><enum>(44)</enum><header>Tribal
 School</header><text>The term <term>tribal school</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id6544687965BB4607BDF2368E619F8D04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a school that is a Bureau-funded school, as defined in section 1141 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2021">25 U.S.C. 2021</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1E813DECDA13495780C757AD747E5768"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a prekindergarten program, early childhood program or service, or elementary school or secondary school, operated by an Indian tribe or tribal organization (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD1FC1AF4C6C5409B93D218942F1753D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a school that is located on Indian lands (as defined in section 8013); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1678CDA288B9426EAEECFA5097897FA4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a school in which a predominance of the students who attend the school are Native American or Alaska Native students, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="id99154774DA634936A1E582EF47CEA040"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition for
 this Act</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>tribal school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>) (as amended by subsection (a)).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


