<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1435 IS: Organ Donation Awareness and Promotion Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1435</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to promote awareness of organ donation and the need to
			 increase the pool of available organs.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Organ Donation Awareness and Promotion Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id09917C38460948BB8230B0559DB90F63"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="id7d865f312e974e8c8907e017651ae087"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In May 2015, over 123,400 individuals were on the official waiting list for organ donation managed by the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf15264fd013842008b73d69720f50e02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 2014, the most recent year for which complete data are available, 14,413 individuals became organ donors leading to 29,531 transplants, while 6,198 individuals died while waiting for a transplant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id29ef958429e646efb6732ef45daf5930"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On average, 21 people die every day of every year while waiting for an organ donation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id763aa820bcbb4b61b642e50fbdfe2386"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Over 100,000,000 people in the United States are registered to be organ and tissue donors, yet the demand for donated organs still outweighs the supply of organs made available each day.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb2bdcbf8f9674cc5a5706691abab61bf"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Many people do not know about their options for organ and tissue donation, or have not made their wishes clear to their families.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide5595ad792704c9eb3a0ccf5c94587ae"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Organ and tissue donation can give meaning to the tragic loss of a loved one by enabling up to eight people to receive the gift of life from a single deceased donor.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb4a3724c715492ca4f7f2f10fc52e94"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Living donors can donate a kidney or a portion of a lung or liver to save the life of another individual.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idd18e420fecf74ce6b0ede73ff664e47d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of
			 Congress</header>
			<subsection id="id19ec28c6ddfc483790d1b929e7aafa9d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public
 Awareness of Need for Organ Donation</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Federal Government should carry out programs to educate the public with respect to organ donation, including the need to provide for an adequate rate of such donations.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id4688b2dfb68548dc8409720668c0c9c3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Family
 Discussions of Organ Donations</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that individuals pledging to share their lives as organ and tissue donors should be honored, and the importance of discussing an individual’s wishes regarding organ and tissue donation with family members should be encouraged.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id6ba13caa88b24214869f9dbe84582733"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deceased
 Donations of Organs</header><text>It is the sense of Congress to—</text> <paragraph id="id4aee79227d2242208d7643d7295d2bf3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognize the generous gift of life provided by individuals who indicate their wish to become organ donors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id48c5a987b63b41cabc63d566b0131d7f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledge the grief of families facing the loss of a loved one; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida924c9f0ab3844bf9689527214536fa5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commend those families who, in their grief, choose to donate the organs of their deceased family member.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id65d2d49833ce48cba8c39fcda6ba7d10"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Living
 Donations of Organs</header><text>It is the sense of Congress to—</text> <paragraph id="id557414828ad54a2ab88235890057e7ce"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognize the generous contribution made by each living individual who has donated an organ to save a life;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6f3cdcf8f8764732993b0aec77812314"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledge the advances in medical technology that have enabled organ transplantation with organs donated by living individuals to become a viable treatment option for an increasing number of patients; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idef26a01f5a00455b948562df1fb354d7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commend the medical professionals and organ transplantation experts who have worked to improve the process of living organ donation and increase the number of living donors.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0CEB3FD14143429783D42E7076BBB08F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Organ donation
 public awareness program, studies and demonstrations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 377A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/274f-1">42 U.S.C. 274f–1</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE874650011C245EFADBB47BCC03D5E20" style="OLC">
				<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDA938F0DA545649248E55E35CAD5874CE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>377A.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public awareness; studies and
				demonstrations</header>
					<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDFECEC205F4874764A9AE56255EC43DF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Organ donation
 public awareness program</header><text>The Secretary shall, directly or through grants or contracts, establish a public education program in cooperation with existing national public awareness campaigns to increase awareness about organ donation and the need to provide for an adequate rate of such donations.</text>
					</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDC37603C3A92A415BA6A917E00B7D863B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Studies and
 demonstrations</header><text>The Secretary may make peer-reviewed grants to, or enter into peer-reviewed contracts with, public and nonprofit private entities for the purpose of carrying out studies and demonstration projects to increase organ donation and recovery rates, including living donation.</text>
					</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID3C0044F9DEBF410796BFE5930456C119"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants to
				States</header>
						<paragraph id="ID3A833FECEE95446481007E0FA48247F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary may make grants to States for the purpose of assisting States in carrying out organ donor awareness, public education, and outreach activities and programs designed to increase the number of organ donors within the State, including living donors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID76F128D8C6D14836A950DDD8702F03B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, a State shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="IDFD0EB2F4C2B14E1098BE28388797582B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit an application to the Department in the form prescribed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDD2CB4E74B8384C938E9E0BACA2C4DF5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish yearly benchmarks for improvement in organ donation rates in the State; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDA5814091015E4FE0ABC07DC867628FB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>report to the Secretary on an annual basis a description and assessment of the State's use of funds received under this subsection, accompanied by an assessment of initiatives for potential replication in other States.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDE1B2EEF50A4547DBAA533279BE8E1BE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of
 funds</header><text>Funds received under this subsection may be used by the State, or in partnership with other public agencies or private sector institutions, for education and awareness efforts, information dissemination, activities pertaining to the State donor registry, and other innovative donation specific initiatives, including living donation.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDE58F618B73E94875A095258A61417B95"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Educational
 activities</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network and other appropriate organizations, shall support the development and dissemination of educational materials to inform health care professionals and other appropriate professionals in issues surrounding organ, tissue, and eye donation including evidence-based proven methods to approach patients and their families, cultural sensitivities, and other relevant issues.</text>
					</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDF62C425BDF4B4BC6B2A332935A5AAFDC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization
 of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31CFB04CEE3343468BD430D2218169A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the Organ Donation Public Awareness Program under subsection (a), $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2019;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32A20496E310432B9701A38AF99CA4BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the studies and demonstrations under subsection (b), $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2019;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9786D55AE51140CFB7C232F3E5CAF3EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for the grants to States under subsection (c), $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2019; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC6FAD54D375342F9B411E81ACC17B9E8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for the educational activities under subsection (d), $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2019.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


