<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1294 IS: Bioenergy Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1294</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Agriculture to collaborate in promoting the
			 development of efficient, economical, and environmentally sustainable
			 thermally led wood energy systems.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id6783BF7F1F044D74A50199EA46A17430" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bioenergy Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id771BCA637F9E41B39ED12F3B816CEBA6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id95f7fe26b0f84d72b0a543de8d0736a2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bioheat</header><text>The term <term>bioheat</term> means the use of woody biomass to generate heat.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4c3ab01c87884b11ba24193cc1d0ae2b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biopower</header><text>The term <term>biopower</term> means the use of woody biomass to generate electricity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id08C4A7E713834BE3A93B4D322D166CB9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initiative</header><text>The term <term>Initiative</term> means the Bioheat and Biopower Initiative established under section 3(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idFD5A50F9CC7744B7980F4CBC1B4AFC97"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0b6a7b03a5eb42f09bd153931d7e8083"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State Wood Energy Team</header><text>The term <term>State Wood Energy Team</term> means a collaborative group of stakeholders that—</text> <subparagraph id="id412DE78F922549E38B637E8C9386C6BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out activities within a State to identify sustainable energy applications for woody biomass; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6D6F60D59C2E4D3684031F9DDBA6F7B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been designated by the State and Private Forestry organization of the Forest Service as a State Wood Energy Team.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idBCD445A79A8D4F41B16C6C349FFB09BA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Bioheat and Biopower Initiative</header>
 <subsection id="id1dc971b659a142df94de61f2ebc871f8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary, acting jointly with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall establish a collaborative working group, to be known as the <quote>Bioheat and Biopower Initiative</quote>, to carry out the duties described in subsection (c).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ide0e653955b294397aa672c2eea1a1c47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Board of Directors</header>
 <paragraph id="id0517091076974887943B8D880A72CCC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Initiative shall be led by a Board of Directors.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id498e82155a66494698b2f87b8eae06c0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Board of Directors shall consist of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id84b3922513a34ae9bd3c4e33b272dac9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>representatives of the Department of Energy and the Department of Agriculture, who shall serve as cochairpersons of the Board;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3926fc2956894f1fbd7f353f8136ea50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a senior officer or employee, each of whom shall have a rank that is equivalent to the departmental rank of a representative described in subparagraph (A), of each of—</text>
 <clause id="id507B6411B391424EA52EEB351DB0E7E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text> </clause><clause id="id5608D9642EDB4EE2AEE9AACB294E1922"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id87A334552D114BF0942370B7987BD6D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation; and</text> </clause><clause id="id98290446D61F4A06BC607C0434193CB9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Office of Science and Technology Policy; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34e80443ab824175bd4c34b5331975d7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at the election of the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture, such other members as may be appointed by the Secretaries, in consultation with the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07d70bca2fdc4bbd8a2bfda341432ebf"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Directors shall meet not less frequently than once each quarter.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf6c22baffa1f4299be87373c6e2a4d07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Initiative shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id17a557b1bef0421494de651eb61ecf68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate research and development activities relating to biopower and bioheat projects—</text> <subparagraph id="id03b7eca954c54fdd82fc385f96bf145f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>between the Department of Agriculture and the Department of Energy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d1624e13f0c4b9e846e200510dc4499"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with other Federal departments and agencies;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id81dc0013d2804a479ec2318ca788b9ef"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Department of Agriculture and the Department of Energy concerning the administration of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfc0a97a6281f488790071400cf796a18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="idea780f70025a400e8b6b4a648617e18e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicitations are open and competitive with respect to applicable annual grant awards; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70bb4a897dd447e9b68af71dce845cd0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>objectives and evaluation criteria of solicitations for those awards are clearly stated and minimally prescriptive, with no areas of special interest.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idd5abbb4773614736867bad2b3c4cb7de"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant programs</header>
			<subsection id="id8938ec787954400e81cb6101543687b2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Demonstration grants</header>
 <paragraph id="id929BCD198CB04843A6B9AE0C527D7A08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish, within the Bioenergy Technologies Office, a program under which the Secretary shall provide grants to relevant projects to support innovation and market development in bioheat and biopower.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id983C4C0DA18B442BB647B170F90038B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, the owner or operator of a relevant project shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB9B82F51F55746C5B9F6075FB29E3382"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall allocate—</text> <subparagraph id="ide0ea93dd6e364fb296956685b99da710"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$15,000,000 to projects that develop innovative techniques for preprocessing biomass for heat and electricity generation, with the goals of—</text>
 <clause id="idD4806B905737495494794CD3FCB48852"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lowering the costs of—</text> <subclause id="id319473B470574BC8BE6590A72192CFE5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>distributed preprocessing technologies, including technologies designed to promote densification, torrefaction, and the broader commoditization of bioenergy feedstocks; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id8F96F3A7FEE14BDE8921F052B44A8072"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transportation and logistics costs; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id2E03566AB300448BB307389D35D3DADB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>developing technologies and procedures that maximize environmental integrity, such as reducing greenhouse gas emissions and local air pollutants and bolstering the health of forest ecosystems and watersheds; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida29372a21fe04c81a9dd7edb0f1511c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$15,000,000 to innovative bioheat and biopower demonstration projects, including—</text> <clause id="id9DCB5011180D477F876991746A65F17F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>district energy projects;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF8EC37B8FBB7445E86431C446173DDD9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>innovation in transportation and logistics; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2D5953BC03654E839D33363A5CF386E4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>innovative projects addressing the challenges of retrofitting existing coal-fired electricity generation facilities to use biomass.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4683d25af8f44aa984580705b2b49ac3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional distribution</header><text>In selecting projects to receive grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, diverse geographical distribution among the projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id45a0edbeade44836949cb6148a55f269"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cost share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out using a grant under this subsection shall be 50 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2936724347494c3992fec25d911e7df0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duties of recipients</header><text>As a condition of receiving a grant under this subsection, the owner or operator of a project shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idaa4b7855dc5245e494470ec265297014"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participate in the applicable working group under paragraph (7);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3a1154fc8924c0d810ce0dbe7bba8e0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary a report that includes—</text>
 <clause id="id19763FFBA3AA45438EDD0583F0B2161C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the project and any relevant findings; and</text> </clause><clause id="id2D6842D7F62047A09D96959B63A44DED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary determines to be necessary to complete the report of the Secretary under paragraph (8); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF811838EE81C446C980BEF87FA89E463"><enum>(C)</enum><text>carry out such other activities as the Secretary determines to be necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7995498EB8CA4B249D750481A4060CE6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Working groups</header><text>The Secretary shall establish 2 working groups to share best practices and collaborate in project implementation, of which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD453AC9A77BA4935B8D5707CC6579C47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 shall be comprised of representatives of feedstock projects that receive grants under paragraph (3)(A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4EE782273DC1423AA3CD19CDD3613075"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 shall comprised of representatives of demand and logistics projects that receive grants under paragraph (3)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD4868051AE0342C29D934E2544B3162F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE716921C3CD74CE4803F4B76DA6C1E60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each project for which a grant has been provided under this subsection;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE70C78BF1F264209896F342CC0982A98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any findings as a result of those projects; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B879A8CEB1A4623876476EF9792459C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the state of market and technology development, including market barriers and opportunities.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf1ed218321d7486ba29a20d5ecd3c0ff"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Thermally led wood energy grants</header>
 <paragraph id="id560BD87149E44FE4B52683446269FC89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall establish a program under which the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide grants to support commercially demonstrated thermally led wood energy technologies, with priority given to projects proposed by State Wood Energy Teams.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA6AB666F3127403FA95D9C56C310C417"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, the owner or operator of a relevant project shall submit to the Secretary of Agriculture an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary of Agriculture may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0B5EE2D936BF4D1CB9383D1CE96347FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall allocate $10,000,000 for feasibility assessments, engineering designs, and construction of thermally led wood energy systems, including pellet boilers, district energy systems, combined heat and power installations, and other technologies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id62CCA8122EE745D19A55C6535EB3607E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional distribution</header><text>In selecting projects to receive grants under this subsection, the Secretary of Agriculture shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, diverse geographical distribution among the projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8A1471767F5145928EDC5A2BC369D0AE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cost share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out using a grant under this subsection shall be 50 percent.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id801B0DFDC9CE493FA7893B0CF1DBC2AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="id23E19D6BD0FC4D7587BC8FFA2D69873B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$30,000,000 to the Secretary to provide grants under subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id0465447B110D46E1986B353111019CB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$10,000,000 to the Secretary of Agriculture to provide grants under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id124db441f58a411d8fd37b3a513398f9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Loan programs; strategic analysis and research</header> <subsection id="id2c68777b79b54969addfab99255e47d2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Low-Interest loans</header> <paragraph id="id884C280B226547A1BD9EDEA69E264687"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish, within the Rural Development Office, a low-interest loan program to support construction of thermally led residential, commercial or institutional, and industrial wood energy systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9EB17FD9FED040AA8042A4BF760A9CC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The program under this subsection shall be carried out in accordance with such requirements as the Secretary of Agriculture may establish, by regulation, in taking into consideration best practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id71f7014124ad4af9be215b9f3a90b5fd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out this subsection $50,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4388b1d2308c4334992ffdda54704f10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Energy efficiency and conservation loan program</header><text>In addition to loans under subsection (a), thermally led residential, commercial or institutional, and industrial wood energy systems shall be eligible to receive loans under the energy efficiency and conservation loan program of the Department of Agriculture under section 2 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/902">7 U.S.C. 902</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id9f573ee8e236479c84ea705869814f6b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategic analysis and research</header>
 <paragraph id="id6695F5EF56164375851B288D0399BEFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting jointly with the Secretary of Agriculture (acting through the Chief of the Forest Service), shall establish a bioheat and biopower research program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE308CBCFC8844927B95C0D2FE26C0B14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the costs of which shall be divided equally between the Department of Energy and the Department of Agriculture;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26C801651B3E487F9E587B50B988D198"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to be overseen by the Board of Directors of the Initiative; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD65BFDD904544836BFD1DB907F47C732"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to carry out projects and activities—</text> <clause id="idC16D5993611442DEB4ADAD12FD8B1E92"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idDC088F52A51B4E7F9AD4A14A89C61824"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to advance research and analysis on the environmental, social, and economic costs and benefits of the United States biopower and bioheat industries, including associated lifecycle analysis of greenhouse gas emissions and net energy analysis; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idFA6ED403D2B64BE681316D14EA096DFE" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to provide recommendations for policy and investment in those areas;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idE2293A38F832415BA2D1D6BB53FBFDF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to identify and assess, through a joint effort between the Chief of the Forest Service and the regional combined heat and power groups of the Department of Energy, the feasibility of thermally led district wood energy opportunities in all regions of the Forest Service regions, including by conducting broad regional assessments, feasibility studies, and preliminary engineering assessments at individual facilities; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0be431ff79174d9881fd0ebde68a63f7"><enum>(iii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idF9ABF4D4C2E34520A119DB60574458E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to offer to communities technical assistance to explore thermally led wood energy opportunities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id456303B6CA394899923E51DF24A64D8C" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to provide enhanced services to smaller communities that have limited resources and capacity to pursue new thermally led wood energy opportunities.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5389F6CB0F2D47419D5D380B27264CF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture—</text> <subparagraph id="id03A1F443E1D04FED8975FB6032373DB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$2,000,000 to carry out paragraph (1)(C)(i);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE18481D0BBFD4CB5ABA8B2AE61E21C75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$1,000,000 to carry out paragraph (1)(C)(ii); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9E858BA758164331A3C7AC474B580BCD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$1,000,000 to carry out paragraph (1)(C)(iii).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


