<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1255 IS: Sutton Mountain and Painted Hills Area Preservation and Economic Enhancement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1255</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150507">May 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To designate certain Bureau of Land Management land in the State of Oregon as wilderness, to
			 authorize certain land exchanges in the State of Oregon, and to convey
			 certain Bureau of Land Management land in the State of Oregon to Wheeler
			 County, Oregon, for economic and community development purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id2ecc00554bd547a29371758934dfab9d" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sutton Mountain and Painted Hills Area Preservation and Economic Enhancement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id0B94C62D1ED84CF7A31CAACE3B25C28A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="idc6197d4a337147ceb01f94ff55d4c412"><enum>(1)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <term>County</term> means Wheeler County, Oregon.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc648d399341e4832b3dc1d071a2f76a4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Landowner</header><text>The term <term>landowner</term> means an owner of non-Federal land that enters into a land exchange with the Secretary under section 4(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id55044D4714AB4741BEE7590EB5B1E72A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <quote>Map</quote> means the map prepared by the Bureau of Land Management entitled <quote>Sutton Complex Wilderness Proposal</quote> and dated May 6, 2015.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9af8c76f7df8444d9d08803b4f6aa72f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id010f5cb8fdd347999c1956a7e3ede596"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Oregon.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="id41b1780ead574e92a968161b9a97e6a4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of wilderness areas</header> <subsection id="id4d45633d74d7410daf5fc7895b7fe618"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the following areas in the State are designated as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="id8b85a07d08134ea18caa2fd9637ed755"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sutton Mountain Wilderness</header><text>Certain land in the Prineville District Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 29,675 acres, as generally depicted on the Map as <quote>Sutton Mountain</quote>, which shall be known as the <quote>Sutton Mountain Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6bfb9b7507b24307819da462b58f7353"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pat's Cabin Wilderness</header><text>Certain land in the Prineville District Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 15,951 acres, as generally depicted on the Map as <quote>Pat’s Cabin</quote>, which shall be known as the <quote>Pat’s Cabin Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id566dc64507e54a7eaa4ce91857f471dd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Painted Hills Wilderness</header><text>Certain land in the Prineville District Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 6,900 acres, as generally depicted on the Map as <quote>Painted Hills</quote>, which shall be known as the <quote>Painted Hills Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id76b850bae9db4d6bafaf1dc142230eb1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dead Dog Wilderness</header><text>Certain land in the Prineville District Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 4,939 acres, as generally depicted on the Map as <quote>Dead Dog</quote>, which shall be known as the <quote>Dead Dog Wilderness</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id085f34a1fc814d71af0725d7ab6f515e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="id5d7915686fa14f76936f5f8f686bfcfc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and legal description of each wilderness area designated by subsection (a) with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idf6452e1cb1e949ad8d8f0cb2443a2bea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id381d3b8bdc3840b8be83361d47d7a5a2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide46aa9ff1f454e6da74d90f4ed38ba7b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>Each map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the maps or legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1bbbed8324bb4c9e8ab45d926472f3f7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida831737627d74a4d9938a284f6f6a1d4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration of wilderness areas</header>
 <paragraph id="id14c432450be340bdb8d2637ab8ae8ccd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas established by subsection (a) shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this section and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), except that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id36eb6edcd93e4963bb28fc5976d1d515"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any reference in that Act to the effective date shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9befad1ebb04ae483956fc3b989eee6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any reference in that Act to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be considered to be a reference to the Secretary that has jurisdiction over the wilderness area.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8af9a802095149fb8cb25afa50452c22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas designated by subsection (a) are withdrawn from all forms of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idcaa97262ceb949c198edffb3487c4633"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80986046c5564c93b9f62137af6047ae"><enum>(B)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id305ae2f9c8b449ea9fc50e67da8e8518"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbcc1ed8827c947da9fb5876a24b5080b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grazing</header> <subparagraph id="id85d44385f9434f559ab0cb3a1bd99104"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the wilderness areas designated by subsection (a), if established before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue at current levels, subject to such reasonable regulations as the Secretary considers necessary, in accordance with—</text>
 <clause id="id619292A96E6448E086397BC0897E4CBB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>); and</text> </clause><clause id="idA63E6000B667479FAA4DD57498881EDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in Appendix A of the report of the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress (H. Rept. 101–405).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida03e62b8e9634b5d888612361ad13862"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Voluntary relinquishment of grazing permits or leases</header>
 <clause id="id84ebde834a8440048dc7cd1357e7b45a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Acceptance by secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall accept the voluntary relinquishment of any valid existing permits or leases authorizing grazing on public land, all or a portion of which is within the wilderness areas designated by subsection (a).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idce0df67fd3754f5e9465cd9ae88e3e6b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>With respect to each permit or lease voluntarily relinquished under clause (i), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="idc680a6f7553e4a95929f390066d86d75"><enum>(I)</enum><text>terminate the grazing permit or lease; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id63f8e2cce1ba4ed79751323cc4400971"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ensure a permanent end to grazing on the land covered by the permit or lease.</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="id2000dba423864f8f98aa8dd08215c102"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Partial relinquishment</header>
 <subclause id="ided6f78da18a64ad995f019d397635620"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a person holding a valid grazing permit or lease voluntarily relinquishes less than the full level of grazing use authorized under the permit or lease, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <item id="idd3f72e90559341948260493ff08b09bb"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>reduce the authorized grazing level to reflect the voluntary relinquishment; and</text> </item><item id="id20e139d9308e4eafba566dc855ef3d17"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>modify the permit or lease to reflect the revised level of use.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id81d16c8d5ff8488fae132399ed4f598e"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authorized level</header><text>To ensure that there is a permanent reduction in the authorized level of grazing on the land covered by a permit or lease voluntarily relinquished under subclause (I), the Secretary shall not allow grazing use to exceed the authorized level established under that subclause.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c3eddf7b8204e319336b0e94c22d7b0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribal rights</header><text>Nothing in this section alters, modifies, enlarges, diminishes, or abrogates the treaty rights of any Indian tribe.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="ide02d6c5700bc4a4e8ab15818caefde11"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header>
 <subparagraph id="id6883216ab3e84790a16735bd0e1a61d7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this section affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife management in the State.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7203fc63d51416db7cd2a03e44203e2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Management activities</header>
 <text>In furtherance of the purposes and principles of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary may conduct any management activities in the wilderness areas designated by subsection (a) that are necessary to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and habitats, if the management activities are—</text>
 <clause id="ide550a389514f402a87f32d5b0c26a96a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consistent with relevant wilderness management plans; and</text> </clause><clause id="id1dfb95e344e141cb954238ba3fcbf038"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conducted in accordance with appropriate policies, such as the policies established in Appendix B of the report of the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress (House Report 101–405).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1dad610266504418a2ffa3690f9057bb"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fire management</header>
 <subparagraph id="id581b873e46ab4eaa83191f7d5174c2a8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>), the Secretary may take such measures in the wilderness areas designated by subsection (a) as are necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases (including, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the coordination of the activities with a State or local agency and the use of aircraft or mechanized equipment by Federal, State, or local agencies or agents of the agencies).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f85855bf5c64832aac3f742b974d867"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revision and development of local fire management plans</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the local fire management plans that apply to the Sutton Mountain Wilderness designated by subsection (a)(1) to identify—</text>
 <clause id="idfdd9a2a18e6f4e4fb2408e795d48a378"><enum>(i)</enum><text>best management practices for wildfire prevention and wildfire response in the wilderness area; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3704c4b3b4a5411fb53e7a0b484bc15e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the appropriate State and local officials to carry out the management practices described in clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0548461bc21340b7b4c52719648e27fc"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, to ensure a timely and efficient response to wildfires in the Sutton Mountain Wilderness designated by subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="idfa88fd9b8ad64b71b69a17a148aedb4a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish agency approval procedures for responding to wildfires, including delegations of authority, as appropriate, to the Forest Supervisor, District Manager, Incident Commander, or other agency officials; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3a965f05ef84462f80a3770f273e6de5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enter into agreements, as appropriate, with State and local firefighting agencies to carry out measures for wildfire prevention and response.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bd25e94ef7f40c69bde63e4fa1e2128"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header>
 <subparagraph id="id8044f4d36db24382849174d8eba3317e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress does not intend for the designation of wilderness areas by subsection (a) to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around the wilderness areas.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75edb4105b184c009477b69b07388af5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Activities outside wilderness</header><text>The fact that a non-wilderness activity or use on land outside the wilderness areas designated by subsection (a) can be seen or heard from within the wilderness areas shall not, of itself, preclude the activity or use outside the boundary of the wilderness areas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id27cd6e110a6a402d88fa35b30f242d66"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Military activities</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes—</text> <subparagraph id="id0706de1ca2be4c96a7e5d0c0f0fc8f7f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft over the wilderness areas designated by subsection (a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88ea8574786d484caba6dda58eac0821"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the designation or establishment of new units of special airspace, or the establishment of a military flight training route, over the wilderness areas designated by subsection (a); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8465fc48eb346c391e7fb6c2bf9cddb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>flight testing and evaluation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c4ad731f34e4be8909e844cb7c60a13"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land within the boundary of a wilderness area designated by subsection (a) that is acquired by the United States shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idbc1fa268e718474cbc1c8fd3712fca08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>become part of the wilderness area in which the land is located; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id265da655749742319a1f8ac91a7e886e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with—</text>
 <clause id="id4C8F503BB8914C349C02F88B82AB5876"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section;</text> </clause><clause id="id59420286F3914391B2F15294A5DAAA4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7E3839E83B834BEBB52CFD585D7838EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2adf1581d4c4c92aa961169289794a5"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Outfitting and guide activities</header><text>Consistent with section 4(d)(5) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(5)</external-xref>), commercial services (including authorized outfitting and guide activities) are authorized in wilderness areas designated by subsection (a), to the extent necessary for activities that fulfill the recreational or other wilderness purposes of the areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6bc66c1b243645ff86efe0a98d6e1a44"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Adequate access to private property</header><text>In accordance with section 5(a) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1134">16 U.S.C. 1134(a)</external-xref>), the Secretary shall provide any owner of private property within the boundary of a wilderness area designated by subsection (a) adequate access to the property.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id45c5eb284c1341fd9697ff8ee31cf4b3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Land exchanges</header>
			<subsection id="id05f4c7dc9e3845e09fb8ca6c2e1e1ff3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header>
				<paragraph id="id3f65d4f3f58c4de689cd33aaa08b81fe"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collins exchange</header>
 <subparagraph id="id4d5be61031b74aa78c41225a7560c942"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsections (b) through (h), if the owner of the non-Federal land described in subparagraph (B)(i) offers to convey to the United States all right, title, and interest of the landowner in and to the non-Federal land, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="idd8c9de85f1da4b91a3a68a6f3a95c10c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accept the offer; and</text> </clause><clause id="id2fee1fc2d0de44d49971070ec6a5c7a6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on receipt of acceptable title to the non-Federal land and subject to valid existing rights, convey to the landowner all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land described in subparagraph (B)(ii).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide238176537a546759f074c04cf63c8c9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of land</header>
 <clause id="id694040e5884c4d8c839aa2e304472870"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Non-federal land</header><text>The non-Federal land referred to in subparagraph (A) is the approximately 265 acres of non-Federal land identified on the Map as <quote>Collins to BLM</quote>.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idacda3055a35949eaadd6edee2869c562"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The Federal land referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) is the approximately 279 acres of Federal land identified on the Map as <quote>BLM to Collins</quote>.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id19ad28a8992e455984c7b46e98346c28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Faulkner exchange</header>
 <subparagraph id="id93fd3edaa2134ad390f745c5c0779ba4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsections (b) through (h), if the owner of the non-Federal land described in subparagraph (B)(i) offers to convey to the United States all right, title, and interest of the landowner in and to the non-Federal land, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="id6da9c12a85e5440ca7ed26da3426b056"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accept the offer; and</text> </clause><clause id="ide077b70121cd4a79beeea20c7484e978"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on receipt of acceptable title to the non-Federal land and subject to valid existing rights, convey to the landowner all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land described in subparagraph (B)(ii).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10460159aa354b9ca8b8d9546dbe9c1a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of land</header>
 <clause id="id3e359ca054f247fd827a1bd256aeaddd"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Non-federal land</header><text>The non-Federal land referred to in subparagraph (A) is the approximately 15 acres of non-Federal land identified on the Map as <quote>Faulkner to BLM</quote>.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idae9f5299311641d2970cc84039985b04"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The Federal land referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) is the approximately 10 acres of Federal land identified on the Map as <quote>BLM to Faulkner</quote>.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf70b9d0873d3481c8d8e3c43b0be9b22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quant exchange</header>
 <subparagraph id="idd016eaaf10dc462fbd602f78372e4d8f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsections (b) through (h), if the owner of the non-Federal land described in subparagraph (B)(i) offers to convey to the United States all right, title, and interest of the landowner in and to the non-Federal land, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="idad50c6900c804b54ace0ce59be8481d5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accept the offer; and</text> </clause><clause id="idbca30276d06f4979916b8df43135007f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on receipt of acceptable title to the non-Federal land and subject to valid existing rights, convey to the landowner all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land described in subparagraph (B)(ii).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19c351432fce4e05b54975160331972d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of land</header>
 <clause id="idfd46841683674ba0b0a6aa6118e58e7b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Non-federal land</header><text>The non-Federal land referred to in subparagraph (A) is the approximately 271 acres of non-Federal land identified on the Map as <quote>Quant to BLM</quote>.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id863b3088527f4ee683d79b464ad92d77"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The Federal land referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) is the approximately 277 acres of Federal land identified on the Map as <quote>BLM to Quant</quote>.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3524c0e7f96542febe106642e12a23bc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Twickenham livestock  llc exchange</header>
 <subparagraph id="id672c891095b24f92a6cadff289e348bc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsections (b) through (h), if the owner of the non-Federal land described in subparagraph (B)(i) offers to convey to the United States all right, title, and interest of the landowner in and to the non-Federal land, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="idc448f32acdf54bb29c1f0e57acf38728"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accept the offer; and</text> </clause><clause id="id76cfda51948d4029b1b4dedef18142c5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on receipt of acceptable title to the non-Federal land and subject to valid existing rights, convey to the landowner all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land described in subparagraph (B)(ii).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb03648b5c8f0496b942a3bb6513e19c8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of land</header>
 <clause id="id7752570f46b6490ab45ce305bb790772"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Non-federal land</header><text>The non-Federal land referred to in subparagraph (A) is the approximately 574 acres of non-Federal land identified on the Map as <quote>Twickenham to BLM</quote>.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id76c294044bec424698cceb3e5d07559c"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The Federal land referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) is the approximately 566 acres of Federal land identified on the Map as <quote>BLM to Twickenham</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id84c80f8b46bd485b925c38f41768158e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in sections 202 and 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1713), the Secretary shall carry out each land exchange under subsection (a) in accordance with section 206 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id97a91e64788046d7a223d7e580f3544a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>Each land exchange under subsection (a) shall be subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may require.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id4bc3a9a0d93b485dbda44fc09eda681d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Equal value exchange</header>
 <paragraph id="idac945391e81a4bf798a413ad81505511"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The value of the Federal land and non-Federal land to be exchanged under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="id8b1376dcc1604b3fa2c474df08c2913a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be equal; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9ae7114be964d8b83bbcbd44c896033"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be made equal in accordance with paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf41f3fe77d624c8c9ee5114369e9a8e6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Equalization</header> <subparagraph id="id4c59947e698443adbd0eef746665203a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Surplus of federal land</header><text>If the value of Federal land exceeds the value of non-Federal land to be conveyed under a land exchange authorized under subsection (a), the value of the Federal land and non-Federal land shall be equalized, as determined to be appropriate and acceptable by the Secretary and the landowner—</text>
 <clause id="ide0fcabd83f864e738a510c7c42ba1c72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by reducing the acreage of the Federal land to be conveyed; or</text> </clause><clause id="idcb7a7b9339374dafa826c879b10dc31a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding additional Federal land to the Federal land to be conveyed.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d07c0d78dee4c02bfaf7db2f7986af7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Surplus of non-federal land</header><text>If the value of the non-Federal land exceeds the value of the Federal land, the value of the Federal land and non-Federal land shall be equalized by reducing the acreage of the non-Federal land to be conveyed, as determined to be appropriate and acceptable by the Secretary and the landowner.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id36616c0d4d1647809ba55a7c6d782ece"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appraisals</header>
 <paragraph id="id3f0900c9d49241c5b4ce371e29e69490"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the landowner shall select an appraiser to conduct an appraisal of the Federal land and non-Federal land to be exchanged under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf3652ebd2e22488597aa210dacdc02a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An appraisal under paragraph (1) shall be conducted in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida7f634c6124544d88c4da7fa1f82233d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide935359668b749f9b1377238f1ef4dcf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8fc3698205cc493588857b0813b5b3d6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Surveys</header>
 <paragraph id="id8a960040c2d94c0791a66e30f0b88f8e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The exact acreage and legal description of the Federal land and non-Federal land to be exchanged under subsection (a) shall be determined by surveys approved by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbefc48aa3cdd42a0a0446dc5278d2b15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>The Secretary and the landowner shall divide equally between the Secretary and the landowner—</text> <subparagraph id="id70dcc5520c49410b9dbeded6886318f1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the costs of any surveys conducted under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82ab7aaa3d764026a46c9d4d7edcbe30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other administrative costs of carrying out the land exchange under this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida7d952d6512f4c4e8a683de3f1645f48"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Deadline for completion of land exchange</header><text>It is the intent of Congress that the land exchanges under subsection (a) be completed by the date that is not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idef2971dae7254be9a7e4d800891bd70f"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Addition to wilderness areas</header><text>On completion of the land exchanges under subsection (a), the non-Federal land shall—</text> <paragraph id="id89a6d3d89cd34de2a64cd5e4e0db6e79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the adjacent wilderness area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id518ad00818284232b4e88d70dd6f9559"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="id92d759601c6c4669a3acf072cd7e3f58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide1ebe6be046a46e483571d0b392025e4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb3d6f1339e546dea25ff6136ebe2243"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5888cbfcf753458081ab6c3839dd9cf7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Conveyances of Bureau of Land Management land to Wheeler County, Oregon</header>
 <subsection id="ide718e249f40a4069a690c06365352ae7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, subject to valid existing rights and this section, and notwithstanding the land use planning requirements of sections 202 and 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1713), the Secretary shall convey to the County, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to each parcel of Federal land described in subsection (b) for which the County has submitted to the Secretary a request for conveyance by the date that is not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4fa7c2ca16c84c0bb647db6f0c3fbf94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of land</header><text>The parcels of Federal land referred to in subsection (a) consist of—</text> <paragraph id="idb79886559ac84b43959b7f17f3d82a70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the approximately 1,950 acres of land managed by the Bureau of Land Management, Prineville District, Oregon, depicted on the Map as <quote>Wheeler County Conveyance 1</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9b5b046e34ea4b84abe20e9b3b72183a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the approximately 120 acres of land managed by the Bureau of Land Management, Prineville District, Oregon, depicted on the Map as <quote>Wheeler County Conveyance 2</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6d15fddc3cb340a181f11a6f43712fdb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The Map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id13f17b69053d446fae44fe2662ca5ba8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of conveyed land</header>
 <paragraph id="id24554ee1a34348fbb79f2b3b1513b216"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Consistent with the Act of June 14, 1926 (commonly known as the <quote>Recreation and Public Purposes Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/869">43 U.S.C. 869 et seq.</external-xref>), the Federal land conveyed under subsection (a) shall be used for a purpose consistent with that Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id486e65ab19044df7ae20c2dc89b4fe48"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, each parcel of land described in subsection (b) is withdrawn from—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id753a488c77ea48818f1bbd0dec0965ca"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all forms of location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7fd20a0377914d258ddf15b31d0dbb18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disposition under all laws relating to mineral leasing and geothermal leasing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ab79059bc2e461189e934aed1369c51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text>The Secretary may require such additional terms and conditions for the conveyances under subsection (a) as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id291b09a84508456180c7feb1a36c76f0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>The Secretary shall require the County to pay all survey costs and other administrative costs associated with the conveyances to the County under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0d407c7f42444df7a01764015b31bfb4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>If the land conveyed under subsection (a) ceases to be used for the public purpose for which the land was conveyed, the land shall, at the discretion of the Secretary, revert to the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ida0ac1910253349609629751715aeee93"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Tribal rights</header><text>Nothing in this section alters, modifies, enlarges, diminishes, or abrogates the treaty rights of any Indian tribe.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idf66b5b3d582e4fb788598b79b4fa59bc"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

